BABY'S CRIB.
NOW BLIZZARD WARNINGS ARE UP, AS
A MAJOR STORM IS SET TO SNARL
HOLIDAY TRAVEL ACROSS THE
MIDWEST.
SAM IS TRACKING IT ALL.
♪ YOU'RE THE ONE THAT I WANT YOU
ARE THE ONE I WANT ♪
>>> AND TWO OF THE MOST FAMOUS
STARS IN THE WORLD SAY "YOU'RE
THE ONE THAT I WANT" AGAIN.
>> WHY DON'T WE DO A WHOLE
ALBUM?
>> THAT'S A FANTASTIC IDEA.
>> THE DYNAMIC DUO.
TRAVOLTA AND NEWTON-JOHN,
REUNITING JUST IN TIME FOR THE
HOLIDAYS, ONLY ON "GMA."
>>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
HELLO TO ROBIN, RECOVERING AT
HOME.
ELIZABETH VARGAS IS HERE.
AND, OF COURSE, SO MUCH OF OUR
ATTENTION STILL ON NEWTOWN THIS
MORNING.
MORE FUNERALS ARE PLANNED FOR
TODAY.
AS WE LOOK AT THOSE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS.
>> IT'S UNCLEAR WHEN THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SURVIVORS WILL
BE ABLE TO GO BACK TO THE
CLASSROOM.
THIS SCHOOL IN A NEARBY TOWN IS
BEING READIED FOR THEM BY
VOLUNTEERS.
AND TEACHERS HAVE ALREADY BEEN
MEETING TO FIND A WAY TO START
THAT NORMAL ROUTINE BACK FOR
THEM AGAIN.
IT'S SO IMPORTANT.
>> IT IS.
WE'RE GOING TO GO TO AMY ROBACH
THERE IN JUST A MOMENT.
>>> FIRST, BREAKING NEWS
OVERNIGHT.
NBC'S CHIEF FOREIGN
CORRESPONDENT, RICHARD ENGEL,
HELD CAPTIVE IN SYRIA SINCE
THURSDAY HAS BEEN FREED AFTER A
FIREFIGHT.
MARTHA RADDATZ HAS DETAILS FROM
WASHINGTON.
WHAT A DRAMATIC ESCAPE.
>> Reporter: IT CERTAINLY IS.
RICHARD IS A VERY EXPERIENCED
FOREIGN CORRESPONDENT.
AND HE HAD BEEN INSIDE SYRIA
BEFORE.
HE AND HIS CREW WERE GRABBED
AFTER CROSSING INTO NORTHWEST
SYRIA LAST THURSDAY.
THERE HAD BEEN NO COMMUNICATION
WITH THEM, NO CONTACT, NO RANSOM
DEMANDS.
THEY WERE THROWN IN THE BACK OF
A TRUCK, BOUND AND BLINDFOLDED,
ALTHOUGH NOT PHYSICALLY HARMED.
THEN YESTERDAY, AS THE CAPTORS
WERE MOVING THEM TO A NEW
LOCATION, THEY WERE STOPPED AT A
REBEL CHECKPOINT.
THERE WAS A CONFRONTATION.
AND THEN, THE FIREFIGHT BROKE
OUT.
IN THAT FIREFIGHT, TWO OF THE
CAPTORS WERE KILLED AND SEVERAL
OTHERS ESCAPED.
BUT RICHARD AND HIS CREW WERE
RESCUED.
THE SYRIAN REBELS THEN DROVE HIM
TO THE BORDER TO SAFETY.
ALL ARE IN GOOD HEALTH,
FORTUNATELY.
GEORGE?
>> THANK GOODNESS FOR THAT.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE GROUP
THAT TOOK THEM HOSTAGE?
>> WE KNOW VERY LITTLE ABOUT THE
GROUP.
BUT THEY WERE NOT BELIEVED TO BE
LOYAL TO THE ASSAD REGIME, NOR
WERE THOSE WHO RESCUED HIM.
THERE'S SO MANY REBEL GROUPS IN
THAT AREA.
THIS WAS KEPT QUIET BECAUSE
RICHARD IS A VERY HIGH-PROFILE
REPORTER.
AND THEY DID NOT WANT TO
INCREASE HIS VALUE TO THE
CAPTORS.
>> FOR FEAR THAT SOMETHING WOULD
HAPPEN TO HIM.
AND, OF COURSE, THERE'S BEEN SO
MUCH VIOLENCE IN SYRIA OVER THE
LAST 18 MONTHS, 40,000 KILLED.
>> 40,000.
>>> LET'S TURN TO THE NEWTOWN
SHOOTINGS.
THE NATION IS STILL IN SHOCK.
AND A TOWN MUST BID GOOD-BYE TO
ITS VICTIMS AND TRY TO GET LIFE
BACK TO NORMAL IF THEY CAN FOR
THE CHILDREN WHO SURVIVED.
AMY ROBACH HAS BEEN REPORTING ON
THIS STORY FROM THE VERY START.
AND SHE JOINS US THIS MORNING
FROM NEWTOWN.
GOOD MORNING, AMY.
>> Reporter: ELIZABETH, THIS IS
CERTAINLY A POWERFUL SIGHT
BEHIND ME.
THESE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS HAVE
POPPED UP ALL THROUGHOUT TOWN.
THIS ONE IS STRETCHING AS FAR AS
THE EYE CAN SEE.
PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER HAVE COME
TO HONOR THE LIVES LOST AND TO
SHOW SUPPORT FOR THIS COMMUNITY,
SUPPORT IT SO DESPERATELY NEEDS
WITH TWO FUNERALS YESTERDAY,
FOUR TODAY, AND SO MANY, MANY
MORE TO COME.
THIS MORNING, AMIDST THE
TRAGEDY, A SMALL STEP TOWARDS
NORMALCY, AS STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN
ARE HEADING BACK TO SCHOOL.
ALL, EXCEPT, OF COURSE, SANDY
HOOK, WHICH POLICE SAY COULD
REMAIN A CRIME SCENE FOR MONTHS.
UP TO 100 VOLUNTEERS IN THE
NEIGHBORING TOWN OF MONROE, ARE
HARD AT WORK GETTING THIS UNUSED
MIDDLE SCHOOL READY FOR SANDY
HOOK STUDENTS TO ATTEND.
IT COULD BE READY THIS WEEK.
BUT THERE'S NO WORD ON WHEN
CLASSES WILL RESUME.
>> DEFINITELY, AT THE VERY
LEAST, WANT TO GIVE THE CHILDREN
THE OPPORTUNITY TO SEE THEIR NEW
SCHOOL AND TO BE -- AS
COMFORTABLE AS THEY POSSIBLY CAN
IN THAT NEW AREA.
>> Reporter: MEANWHILE, THE
FIRST TWO VICTIMS WERE LAID TO
REST ON MONDAY.
JACK PINTO, THE 6-YEAR-OLD BOY
WHO LOVED THE NEW YORK GIANTS,
WAS BURIED IN THE JERSEY OF HIS
FAVORITE PLAYER, VICTOR CRUZ.
>> HIS FAVORITE TEAM WAS THE
GIANTS.
HE TALKS ABOUT HOW GOOD HE IS.
AND I'M WITH HIM.
HE'S REALLY GOOD.
>> Reporter: JACK'S FRIENDS FROM
THE WRESTLING TEAM HONORED THEIR
FRIEND BY WEARING THEIR LITTLE
UNIFORMS.
JUST A FEW MILES AWAY, WHITE
BALLOONS.
A SYMBOL OF PURITY AND HOPE LINE
THE STREET FOR ANOTHER FUNERAL.
THIS ONE FOR 6-YEAR-OLD NOAH
POZNER, WHO WAS REMEMBERED FOR
HIS LOVE OF SUPER MARIO BROTHER
VIDEO GAMES AND TACOS.
HIS MOTHER'S EULOGY MOVING THE
ENTIRE SERVICE TO TEARS.
>> WHEN SHE SAID I LOVE YOU, HIS
ANSWER WAS, NOT AS MUCH AS I
LOVE YOU.
>> Reporter: NOAH LEAVES BEHIND
HIS TWIN SISTER, ARIEL, WHO WAS
IN A DIFFERENT CLASSROOM AND
SURVIVED THE MASSACRE.
AND THIS MORNING, NEWTOWN
PREPARES FOR ANOTHER DIFFICULT
DAY, WITH SERVICES FOR FOUR MORE
VICTIMS.
INCLUDING CHARLOTTE BACON,
JESSICA REKOS, DANIEL BARDEN AND
VICKI SOTO.
WHILE EMILIE PARKER'S FAMILY
TRAVELS TO THEIR HOME STATE OF
UTAH, WHERE THEY WILL BURY THEIR
6-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER IN THE
COMING DAYS.
DIFFICULT DAYS HERE IN NEWTOWN.
POLICE WILL BE OUT IN FULL FORCE
TODAY AS SCHOOLS HERE REOPEN,
TWO HOURS AHEAD OF SCHEDULE.
YESTERDAY, HUNDREDS OF NEWTOWN
TEACHERS RECEIVED EXPERT
TRAINING ON CHILDREN AND
BEREAVEMENT.
THOSE ARE SKILLS THEY'LL
CERTAINLY NEED IN THE DAYS,
WEEKS, AND MONTHS TO COME.
ELIZABETH?
>> THINK MONTHS IS PROBABLY MORE
LIKE IT, YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT, AMY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> A LOT OF HEALING TO GO.
THEY SURE DO.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO TURN TO THE
PUNISHING WEATHER SWEEPING
ACROSS THE COUNTRY, THREATENING
HOLIDAY TRAVEL.
BLIZZARDS, RAIN, HIGH WINDS
RIGHT NOW.
SAM IS HERE WITH THE LATEST.
I TAKE IT THAT TORNADOES ARE A
POSSIBILITY, TOO?
>> YEAH.
WHEN THIS STORM GETS EAST, IT'S
GOING TO HAVE COMPONENTS OF
ROUGH WEATHER.
STRONG TO SEVERE WEATHER IN
PARTS OF THE DEEP SOUTH.
WE'LL START WITH THE PICTURES
COMING IN FROM PORTLAND, OREGON,
AREA.
WHEN THIS STORM SLAMMED THE
COASTLINE, 25-FOOT WAVES ALONG
THE SHORELINE.
MORE THAN A FOOT OF SNOW IN THE
MOUNTAINS.
TWO FEET OF SNOW, IN WASHINGTON
AND THE CASCADES.
TAKE THIS STORM INLAND.
IT BRINGS HURRICANE-FORCE WINDS
TO LAKE ERIE AND LAKE MICHIGAN.
UP TO A FOOT OF SNOW IN PATH
THAT GOES FROM DENVER ALL THE
WAY TOWARD GREEN BAY, WISCONSIN.
AND THEN, THAT STORM CONTINUES
EAST, RIGHT AT THE WRONG TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
THE STRONGEST NORTHWEST STORM OF
THE SEASON BLEW IN MONDAY, WITH
WINDS REACHING 100 MILES PER
HOUR.
KNOCKING OUT POWER LINES,
BRINGING DOWN TREES AND CREATING
BLIZZARD CONDITIONS IN THE
WASHINGTON AND OREGON CASCADE
MOUNTAINS.
JUST SOUTH OF TACOMA,
WASHINGTON, A TREE FELL INTO
THIS HOUSE.
PUNCTURING THE CEILING OF A
BABY'S ROOM AND NARROWLY MISSING
HIS CRIB.
THE BABY WAS UNHARMED.
HIGHER ELEVATIONS FROM
WASHINGTON TO UTAH ARE NOW
FEELING THE COLD AIR OF THIS
WINTER STORM, AND EXPECTING UP
TO THREE FEET OF SNOW.
17 STATES ARE IN WINTER WEATHER
WARNINGS AND WATCHES.
FROM THE NORTHWEST TO ARIZONA
AND ALL THE WAY INTO MINNESOTA
AND WISCONSIN.
BY WEDNESDAY, THE STORM IS
EXPECTED TO MOVE FURTHER EAST
AND COVER PARTS OF THE MIDWEST,
FROM DENVER TO CHICAGO, WITH 4
TO 12 INCHES OF SNOW.
AND LATER IN THE WEEK, THE SAME
STORM WILL PRODUCE SEVERE
WEATHER IN SOUTHERN STATES, WITH
POSSIBLE TORNADOS.
AND BY FRIDAY, THE NORTHEAST
COULD BE HIT WITH ONE TO TWO
INCHES OF HEAVY RAIN AND GUSTY
WINDS.
IT'S PART OF THE STORM PATTERN
WE TOLD YOU ABOUT TO EXPECT FOR
THIS WEEK.
AND THE STORMS WILL CONTINUE TO
MOVE ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
WE'LL TELL YOU EXACTLY WHAT TO
EXPECT IN THOSE AREAS THAT GET
SNOW AND GET STORMS THROUGHOUT
THE DAY TODAY.
REMEMBER, THIS WILL TAKE US ALL
THE WAY THROUGH THE WEEKEND,
WHERE ABOUT 93 MILLION PEOPLE
ARE EXPECTED TO TRAVEL FOR THE
HOLIDAYS.
>> WOW.
OH, MY GOSH.
>> THIS IS GOING TO BE A
SLOWDOWN SITUATION.
>> SAM, THANKS.
>>> LET'S GET TO JOSH WITH THE
OTHER TOP STORIES.
>> WE'RE GOING TO BEGIN WITH
YOUR MONEY AND NEW SAVINGS AT
THE GAS STATION.
NEW NUMBERS OUT THIS MORNING
SHOW PRICES ARE PLUNGING JUST AS
MILLIONS OF US, AS WE JUST
HEARD, GET READY TO HIT THE
ROADS.
ALBEIT SNOWY FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
PAULA FARIS HERE TO SHOW US WHAT
WE MIGHT BE SAVING.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU, PAULA.
>> GOOD MORNING, JOSH.
I GUESS YOU COULD SAY SANTA HAS
AN EARLY CHRISTMAS PRESENT FOR
US.
GAS RIGHT NOW IS THE CHEAPEST
THAT IT HAS BEEN ALL YEAR,
DROPPING EACH DAY THIS MONTH,
TEN CENTS IN THE LAST WEEK
ALONE.
THIS MORNING, THE AVERAGE PRICE
PER GALLON ACROSS THE COUNTRY IS
$3.24.
THAT'S A CONTRAST TO WHAT IT WAS
THIS PAST FALL, WHEN WE WERE
APPROACHING ROUGHLY $4 PER
GALLON.
THE MOST INEXPENSIVE GAS IN THE
COUNTRY IS GOING TO BE THE
SHOW-ME STATE.
SHOW ME THE MONEY.
MISSOURI, JUST $2.95.
MOST EXPENSIVE IS IN HAWAII.
A SIGNIFICANT DEVELOPMENT, JOSH.
FOR THE FIRST TIME THIS YEAR,
GAS IS UNDER $4 PER GALLON IN
ALL 50 STATES.
AND THAT'S A LITTLE BIT OF
RELIEF, CONSIDERING THIS IS
GOING TO BE THE WORST HOLIDAY
TRAFFIC SEASON ON RECORD IN SIX
YEARS.
A LITTLE BIT OF A BREAK FOR OUR
WALLETS.
>> AS WE JUST HEARD, PAULA,
THANK YOU FOR THAT.
>>> MEANWHILE, HE'S BEEN CALLED
THE GIANT OF THE SENATE AND A
TRUE AMERICAN HERO.
TRIBUTES POURING IN FOR HAWAII
SENATOR DANIEL INOUYE.
HE WON THE MEDAL OF HONOR FOR
BRAVERY IN WORLD WAR II AND THEN
OVERCAME RACIAL PREJUDICE TO
BECOME THE FIRST
JAPANESE-AMERICAN IN CONGRESS.
HE WENT ON TO SERVE 50
DISTINGUISHED YEARS IN THE
SENATE.
A FELLOW HAWAIIAN, PRESIDENT
OBAMA, TWEETED THIS.
ALOHA, DANNY.
SENATOR DANIEL INOUYE DIED
MONDAY.
HE WAS 88 YEARS OLD.
>>> AND HAZING CHARGES ARE BEING
FILED AFTER THE DEATH OF A
FRESHMAN STUDENT AT NORTHERN
ILLINOIS UNIVERSITY.
POLICE SAY 19-YEAR-OLD DAVID
BOGENBERGER WAS FORCED TO DRINK
DURING A PARTY AT THE PI KAPPA
ALPHA FRATERNITY HOUSE.
HIS BLOOD-ALCOHOL LEVEL, FIVE
TIMES THE LEGAL LIMIT.
22 FRATERNITY MEMBERS NOW FACE
HAZING-RELATED CHARGES, FIVE OF
THEM HELDFELONY CHARGES.
A FAMILY ATTORNEY SAYS
BOGENBERGER JUST WANTED TO FIT
IN.
>>> A FEDERAL JUDGE HAS DENIED A
REQUEST BY APPLE TO BAN THE SALE
OF DOZENS OF SAMSUNG PHONES IN
THE U.S.
THE REQUEST CAME AFTER A JURY
RULED 26 SAMSUNG PHONES
INFRINGED UPON APPLE'S PATENTS.
BUT A JUDGE SAID BANNING THEIR
SALE WOULD BE HARSH, BECAUSE THE
TECHNOLOGY COPIED FROM APPLE
REPRESENTS BUT A SMALL PORTION
OF THE PHONE'S OVERALL
FUNCTIONALITY.
>>> AND A COMPUTER HACKER HAS
BEEN SENTENCED TO TEN YEARS IN
PRISON.
CHRISTOPHER CHENEY TAPPED INTO
THE PERSONAL E-MAILS OF MILA
KUNIS, AND DOZENS OF OTHERS,
MOSTLY IN THE ENTERTAINMENT
INDUSTRY.
JOHANSSON TOLD THE JUDGE SHE HAD
BEEN TRULY HUMILIATED.
>>> FINALLY, TAKE IT FROM ME.
DO NOT LOOK DOWN.
THE WORLD'S HIGHEST, AND THUS,
SCARIEST PEDESTRIAN BRIDGE, HAS
OPENED IN THE SWISS ALPS.
>> NO WAY.
>> PASS.
>> NOT A FAN.
>> IT IS THREE FEET WIDE.
IT IS SUSPENDED 1,500 FEET ABOVE
A GLACIER.
>> NO.
>> VISIBILITY SO POOR ON OPENING
DAY --
>> WHY?
>> -- THEY SAY YOU COULDN'T SEE
WHAT WAS UNDER YOUR FEET.
PERHAPS THE MOST UNUSED BRIDGE
IN HUMAN HISTORY IS THERE.
>> AT LEAST BY OUR TEAM.
>> NO TO AND FROM.
>> WHEREVER IT NEEDS TO GO, I
HOPE YOU DON'T NEED ANYTHING
OVER THERE.
>> YOU DON'T NEED ANYTHING
THERE.
>> SOMEBODY'S GOT A SPECIAL
ASSIGNMENT COMING UP.
>> NO WAY.
>>> WE TURN TO WHAT MAY BE A
MAJOR BREAKTHROUGH IN THE
STALEMATE OVER THE FISCAL CLIFF.
EVERYONE'S TAXES GO UP.
EVERY GOVERNMENT PROGRAM SET TO
GET CUT IN JUST 14 DAYS.
AFTER A NEW OFFER FROM THE WHITE
HOUSE LAST NIGHT, THE TWO SIDES
MAY HAVE A DEAL IN SIGHT.
ABC'S JON KARL IS ON CAPITOL
HILL.
A CRUCIAL TEST TODAY, WHEN HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER WILL TALK
TO HIS TROOPS ABOUT WHERE THINGS
STAND.
>> Reporter: THE SPEAKER WILL
SPEAK WITH THE RANK AND FILE
HOUSE REPUBLICANS LATER THIS
MORNING ABOUT THIS LATEST OFFER
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
ALTHOUGH, THERE ARE SIGNIFICANT
DIFFERENCES, WE'RE NOW SEEING,
FOR THE FIRST TIME, REAL SIGNS
OF PROGRESS.
THE PRESIDENT IS MAKING SOME
SIGNIFICANT CONCESSIONS,
OFFERING MORE SPENDING CUTS,
ASKING FOR LESS IN THE WAY OF
TAX INCREASES.
THE OFFER INCLUDES $1.2 TRILLION
IN TAX INCREASES.
THAT'S DOWN FROM $1.6 TRILLION
THE PRESIDENT HAD INITIALLY
ASKED FOR.
HE IS TALKING ABOUT RAISING
TAXES ON THOSE MAKING OVER
$400,000 A YEAR INSTEAD OF
$250,000 A YEAR.
AND HE IS TALKING ABOUT LIMITING
THE AMOUNT OF COST OF LIVING
INCREASES FOR SOCIAL SECURITY
RECIPIENTS.
AND ASKING FOR A TWO-YEAR
EXTENSION OF THE DEBT LIMIT, NOT
AN INDEFINITE EXTENSION OF THE
DEBT LIMIT.
GEORGE, THERE ARE STILL PROBLEMS
FROM THE REPUBLICANS ON THIS.
THEY STILL THINK IT'S TOO MUCH
IN TAX INCREASES, NOT ENOUGH IN
SPENDING CUTS.
BUT THE SPEAKER CALLED IT A STEP
IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION.
>> IT SEEMS LIKE A PROBLEM OF
MATH.
DOES THE WHITE HOUSE HAVE ANY
MORE ROOM TO MANEUVER?
OR IS THIS THEIR BOTTOM LINE?
>> Reporter: WHITE HOUSE
OFFICIALS TOLD ME LATE LAST
NIGHT, THIS IS NOT A FINAL
OFFER.
THEY DO CONSIDER IT A GOOD FAITH
EFFORT TO MEET THE SPEAKER
HALFWAY.
IT'S CLOSE TO A FINAL OFFER.
BUT THERE'S STILL WIGGLE ROOM.
AND YES, GEORGE, NOW THEY'RE
QUIBBLING ABOUT NUMBERS, NOT
TALKING ABOUT FUNDAMENTAL
DISAGREEMENTS.
>> OKAY, JON KARL, THANKS VERY
MUCH.
>>> WE TURN TO OUR ABC NEWS
ONGOING COMMITMENT TO THE SEARCH
FOR SOLUTIONS TO GUN VIOLENCE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA PROMISED ACTION
ON SUNDAY AT THAT INTERFAITH
VIGIL FOR THE VICTIMS OF THE
NEWTOWN SHOOTINGS.
AT LEAST ONE PRO-GUN RIGHTS
ADVOCATE IN THE SENATE SAID
EVERYTHING SHOULD BE ON THE
TABLE.
ABC'S PIERRE THOMAS HAS THE
LATEST ON THE CALL TO ACTION.
GOOD MORNING, PIERRE.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
ELIZABETH.
MANY AMERICANS ARE DEMANDING
THAT SOMETHING BE DONE TO STOP
NIGHTMARES LIKE WHAT WE SAW IN
NEWTOWN.
WHAT THAT SOMETHING SHOULD BE IS
WHERE THE FIGHT BEGINS.
>> All: SHAME ON THE NRA.
>> Reporter: AT NRA HEADQUARTERS
IN VIRGINIA ON MONDAY, AN ANGRY
CROWD.
>> All: SHAME, SHAME, SHAME.
>> Reporter: HORDES OF ACTIVISTS
PROTESTING THE GUN LOBBY.
AND THE DEBATE IGNITED AGAIN.
BUT THOSE IN SUPPORT OF THE NRA
QUESTIONED WHETHER THE ASSAULT
RIFLE USED IN THE NEWTOWN
MASSACRE WAS REALLY THE ISSUE.
CONSERVATIVE COLUMNIST
JOHN FUND CALLED IN YESTERDAY.
>> THE BOTTOM LINE IS, THE LAWS
DON'T WORK.
THESE MASS KILLINGS ARE BECAUSE
OF PSYCHOTIC OR MENTALLY ILL
INDIVIDUALS.
>> Reporter: BUT SOME POLITICAL
LEADERS ARE FED UP WITH THE
NATION'S GUN VIOLENCE.
34 AMERICANS ARE KILLED EVERY
DAY BY FIREARMS.
>> THIS IS JUST RIDICULOUS.
THIS IS AN OUTRAGE.
WE ARE KILLING EACH OTHER.
AND WE'RE THE ONLY
INDUSTRIALIZED COUNTRY IN THE
WORLD DOING IT.
>> Reporter: THE NATION HAS
FOUGHT THIS BATTLE BEFORE.
IN 1994, CONGRESS PASSED AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN, AFTER A
SURGE IN GUN VIOLENCE ACROSS THE
NATION.
THE LAW BANNED 18 TYPES OF
RIFLES.
BUT AFTER TEN YEARS, IT EXPIRED,
AS THE GUN LOBBY'S POWER HAD
GROWN.
ACCORDING TO A UNIVERSITY OF
PENNSYLVANIA STUDY, THE NUMBER
OF MASS SHOOTINGS DID DECLINE
DURING THAT DECADE, EXCEPT FOR
THE YEAR 1999.
THAT WAS THE YEAR OF COLUMBINE.
13 STUDENTS AND FACULTY KILLED
IN A MURDEROUS RAMPAGE.
SINCE THE BAN ENDED, THE COUNTRY
HAS SEEN A SPATE OF MASS
SHOOTINGS.
INCLUDING THE SPREE IN TUCSON,
AND THE COLORADO MOVIE THEATER
MASSACRE, BUT LITTLE IN THE WAY
OF SIGNIFICANT GUN CONTROL.
SUPPORTERS OF GUN CONTROL POINT
TO AUSTRALIA.
IN 1996, AFTER A MASS SHOOTING
THERE, THAT COUNTRY BANNED
CERTAIN TYPES OF RIFLES AND
LAUNCHED A MASSIVE GUN BUYBACK
CAMPAIGN.
SINCE THEN, AUSTRALIA HAS NOT
HAD A SINGLE MASS SHOOTING.
IS THERE THE WILL OR THE DESIRE
TO DO SOMETHING LIKE THAT IN THE
U.S.?
WE DON'T YET KNOW.
ELIZABETH?
>> THE NRA HAS BEEN NOTABLY
SILENT SINCE THE ATTACKS ON
FRIDAY.
WHAT ABOUT RETAIL STORES?
SPORTING GOODS STORES THAT SELL
THESE GUNS?
ANY MOVES?
ANY ACTIONS OR STATEMENTS FROM
THEM?
>> Reporter: WE'RE HEARING THIS
MORNING THAT DICK'S SPORTING
GOODS, A MAJOR CHAIN, IS BANNING
CERTAIN TYPES OF RIFLES.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S ONE STEP.
WE'LL KEEP OUR EARS POSTED TO
SEE IF ANYTHING CHANGES.
PIERRE THOMAS, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
GEORGE?
>> WE'RE GOING TO STAY ON THIS.
>>> BUT WE'RE GOING TURN TO THE
HEALTH SCARE FOR HILLARY
CLINTON.
SHE SUFFERED A CONCUSSION AFTER
FAINTING IN HER HOME LAST WEEK.
ON THE MEND NOW, SHE MAY BE OUT
OF ACTION FOR MOST OF HER
REMAINING TIME AS SECRETARY OF
STATE.
REENA NINAN HAS THE DETAILS.
>> HOW ARE YOU, MINISTER?
>> Reporter: HILLARY CLINTON HAS
EARNED A NEW TITLE UNDER THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION.
MOST TRAVELED SECRETARY OF
STATE.
BUT IT'S ONE SHE'S NOW PAYING
FOR.
CLINTON IS RECOVERING AFTER
EFFECTS FROM A MILD CONCUSSION.
THIS IS THE SECOND TIME IN EIGHT
YEARS CLINTON HAS FAINTED
BECAUSE OF A STOMACH BUG.
BUT IN AN INTERVIEW WITH ABC'S
BARBARA WALTERS, BEFORE THE
CONCUSSION, CLINTON INSISTED
THAT HER AGE AND HEALTH DO NOT
CONCERN HER.
>> IT REALLY ISN'T.
I'M THANKFULLY, KNOCK ON WOOD --
I'M NOT ONLY HEALTHY BUT HAVE
INCREDIBLE STAMINA AND ENERGY.
>> Reporter: ACCORDING TO THE
STATE DEPARTMENT, THE
65-YEAR-OLD CLINTON BECAME ILL
EARLY LAST WEEK.
WHILE SUFFERING FROM A STOMACH
VIRUS, SHE BECAME EXTREMELY
DEHYDRATED AND FAINTED AT HOME.
THAT'S WHEN SHE SUSTAINED THE
CONCUSSION.
BUT NOW, INSTEAD OF RETURNING
FROM A DIPLOMATIC TRICK FROM
MOROCCO AND THE PERSIAN GULF,
SECRETARY CLINTON IS UNDER
DOCTOR'S ORDERS TO REST AT HOME.
>> THE MOST IMPORTANT THING IS
FOR HER TO GET REST.
NO E-MAILS.
NO WORKING.
NO STRESSFUL SITUATIONS.
THAT'S REALLY THE BEST PROVEN
WAY TO GET OVER THESE SYMPTOMS.
>> Reporter: REST IS HARD FOR
CLINTON.
IN THE LAST FOUR YEARS, SHE'S
AMASSED MORE THAN 950,000 TRAVEL
MILES, WHILE VISITING 112
DIFFERENT COUNTRIES.
AND AS IT LOOKS MORE AND MORE
LIKELY SENATOR JOHN KERRY WILL
REPLACE CLINTON AS SECRETARY OF
STATE, ALL OF THAT JET-SETTING
MAY FINALLY BE COMING TO AN END.
FOR "GOOD MORNING AMERICA,"
REENA NINAN, ABC NEWS,
WASHINGTON.
>> HOPE SHE'S DOING BETTER.
>>> LET'S GET THE WEATHER FROM
SAM CHAMPION.
>> QUICK IMPROVEMENT IN THE
NORTHEAST, AFTER THE ICING THAT
WENT ON IN MASSACHUSETTS
YESTERDAY.
SOME PARTS OF NORTHERN NEW
ENGLAND PICKED UP SIX TO NINE
INCHES OF SNOW.
WE'LL PULL THE LOW OUT OF THE
WAY.
WE'VE GOT MOST OF THE RAIN OUT
OF THE SOUTHERN SECTIONS.
THERE WILL BE A TOUCH MORE SNOW
IN EXTREME NORTHERN MAINE TODAY.
IT'S DRIER, NICER, AND BEAUTIFUL
IN A GOOD PART OF THE COUNTRY.
EVERYBODY NEEDS TO KNOW.
65 DEGREES, KANSAS CITY.
OKLAHOMA, LOOKING PRETTY GOOD.
KANSAS CITY, IN THE 40s.
MEMPHIS, ABOUT 62.
ATLANTA, 60 DEGREES.
LOOK AT TEXAS SHOWING OFF IN THE
70s AND 80s.
THIS IS IN ADVANCE OF THE SYSTEM
THAT STEPS INTO THE NORTHWEST
AND THEN SWEEPS ACROSS FOR DAYS
NOW, MAKING IT A MESS IN A GOOD
MIDDLE PART OF THE COUNTRY, ALSO
INTO THE NORTHEAST AS WE GET TO
THE WEEKEND.
ENJOY THIS MOMENT BECAUSE ALL
THAT RIGHT THERE, IS HEADED THAT
WAY.
>> I DON'T KNOW.
IF I HAD TO PICK, MAYBE ATLANTA,
ALL THE WAY TO ORLANDO, 60 TO 80
DEGREES TODAY.
>> THAT'S PRETTY NICE.
>> TAKING CARE OF THE SOUTHEAST,
ARE YOU, SAM?
>> THANK YOU, SAM.
>>> COMING UP ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA," WE'LL HAVE NEW DETAILS
IN THE SANDY HOOK INVESTIGATION.
NOW, ADAM LANZA'S BABYSITTER
DESCRIBES WHAT COULD HAVE BEEN
WRONG WITH HIM FROM A VERY YOUNG
AGE.
>>> THEN, A BIG SHIFT IN GEARS.
WE'RE GOING TO TELL YOU ABOUT
THE NEW STAR OF THE BECKHAM
FAMILY.
10-YEAR-OLD ROMEO IS THE NEW
FACE OF A MODELING CAMPAIGN.
>>> PLUS, WHAT HAPPENS WHEN TWO
ICONS REUNITE?
JOHN TRAVOLTA, OLIVIA
NEWTON-JOHN.
BEHIND THE SCENES OF THE CLASSIC
MUSICAL, "GREASE."
COME ON BACK.
♪ THE ONE THAT I WANT
♪ YOU ARE THE ONE I WANT
♪ THE ONE I NEED
for reading a.
Your favorite magazines and
catalogs look better than ever.
And with scrapbooking,
you can save the
things you love,
bring them all together,
And be inspired like
never before.
Scrapbooking. Create
yours with Nook HD -
and even bigger with HD+.
Find yours at Barnes & Noble.
THEY'RE WHOLE GRAIN GOOD...
AND YUMMY GOOD.
REAL FRUIT PIECES.
12 GRAMS OF WHOLE GRAINS
AND A CREAMY
YOGURT FLAVORED COATING.
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
TREAT YOURSELF GOOD.
For thos...this...ions of doing
this...
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
Whatever it takes, get to
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
Don't judge me!
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
HELLO?
[ Sea ] HI!
THIS IS THE SEA CALLING.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU VISITED ME?
WHEN I WENT SURFING.
I LOVE TO SURF.
CAN YOU IMAGINE
SURFING IN THE MIDDLE OF ME?
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOU?
OH YES!
[ giggles ] NICE MOVES!
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
OUR BIGGEST DECEMBER
SALES EVENT EVER.
GOING ON NOW.
CALL 1-800-ROYAL-CARIBBEAN.
>> GOOD MORNING.
DEVELOPING NEWS IN THE EAST
BAY THE SEARCH IS ON FOR A
THIEF WHO USED A CAR TO BREAK
INTO A STORE.
THE DRIVER USED THIS CAR TO
PLOW INTO THE GAMESTOP STORE.
THE DRIVER TOOK MERCHANDISE
INCLUDING USED CELL PHONES
WHICH INVESTIGATORS SAY THEY
COULD BE ABLE TO TRACE.
THE CRASH HAPPENED 4:00 THIS
MORNING.
POLICE THINK THE CAR MAY HAVE
BEEN STOLEN.
>>> WE HAVE A COUPLE OF
ACCIDENTS RIGHT NOW JUST
CLEARED NORTH 87 AT KURTNER,
VERY SLOW FROM HIGHWAY 85
NORTHBOUND.
NORTH 680 McKEY NEW ACCIDENT
STILL HAS TRAFFIC JAMMED FROM
101, 680 AND 280 SAN JOSE,
ALVARADO NILES ACCIDENT
BLOCKING LANES, SLOW OUT OF
HAYWARD.
>> WHEN WE C
>>> WELCOME BACK.
IS OUT, FROM MOUNT TAMALPAIS
WE HAVE A STORM NEARING SEA
RANCH AND MENDOCINO COUNTY
COAST TO THE SONOMA COUNTY
COAST THE BEST AREA OF SEEING
SHOWERS AS THEY SIDE SOUTH
SOUTHEAST.
CLEAR EVERYWHERE ELSE, IN THE
30s INLAND, 40s FOR THE REST
OF US, COOLER TODAY.
COLDER TONIGHT WATCH OUT FOR
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> NICE CROWD OUT IN TIMES
SQUARE THIS MORNING, AMONG ALL
THE POINSETTIAS.
SOME SAY POINSETTIA.
>> WHICH DO YOU SAY?
>> I SAY BOTH.
>> ALL OF THE PEOPLE, ALL
OVER --
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO UPSET JOSH.
>> BUT YOU SAY POINSETTIA.
RIGHT?
I THOUGHT I HAD A COMRADE.
>> I THINK WE'VE SPENT ENOUGH
TIME ON THAT RIGHT NOW.
HI TO ROBIN AT HOME.
ELIZABETH, RIGHT HERE.
>> EXACTLY.
THANK YOU.
GOOD TO BE HERE.
>>> AND THIS MORNING, WE'RE
GOING TO TAKE A CLOSER LOOK AT
ADAM LANZA, THE GUNMAN IN THE
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE HAVE NEW DETAILS THAT MAY
BEGIN TO EXPLAIN HOW THOSE GUNS
GOT INTO HIS HANDS.
AND DR. MICHAEL WELNER'S ALSO
HERE, WITH HIS TAKE ON WHAT
DROVE THE YOUNG MAN TO TAKE SO
MANY LIVES.
IT'S A BIG MYSTERY.
PEOPLE WILL BE STRUGGLING FOR
DEFINITIVE ANSWERS.
WE MAY NEVER GET THEM, TO BE
HONEST.
>>> TO LIGHTEN THINGS UP JUST A
BIT.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT YOUNG
MR. BECKHAM.
THAT'S ROMEO BECKHAM,
10-YEAR-OLD SON OF DAVID AND
VICTORIA.
HE'S FOLLOWING IN HIS PARENTS'
STYLISH FOOTSTEPS AND HAS LANDED
A MODELING GIG.
WE'LL SHOW YOU OUTTAKES.
>>> AND WE'LL LOOK AT THE
COLLABORATION BETWEEN JOHN
TRAVOLTA AND OLIVIA NEWTON-JOHN.
"YOU'RE THE ONE THAT I WANT,"
THE TOP DUET ALL-TIME.
I KNEW IT FOR ME, PERSONALLY.
>> WE HAD OUR HAIR BRUSHES.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> THAT'S COMING UP.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO MAKE A
TRANSITION AND GET TO THE NEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE SANDY HOOK
GUNMAN.
INVESTIGATORS HAVE BEEN COMBING
EVERY INCH OF ADAM LANZA'S LIFE.
THEY ARE LOOKING FOR ANY CLUES
THAT COULD HELP EXPLAIN A MOTIVE
BEHIND THE TRAGIC SHOOTING THIS
PAST FRIDAY.
ABC'S BRIAN ROSS HAS BEEN
FOLLOWING THE STORY FROM THE
VERY START.
AND HE JOINS WITH US THE LATEST
ON THE INVESTIGATION.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
ELIZABETH.
POLICE SAY THEY WILL GO BACK TO
THE DAY THAT ADAM LANZA WAS BORN
IN THEIR EFFORTS TO FIGURE OUT
THE TWISTED MOTIVE BEHIND THIS
RAMPAGE.
AND WHY A YOUNG MAN SO TROUBLED
WOULD BE GIVEN ACCESS TO SUCH
POWERFUL WEAPONS BY HIS MOTHER.
EVEN TAKEN TO TARGET PRACTICE BY
HER.
EVERY GUN SHOP AND RANGE WITHIN
15 MILES OF THE CRIME SCENE IS
BEING CANVASSED BY POLICE AND
FEDERAL AGENTS.
>> THEY WANT TO LOOK AT THE LAST
COUPLE MONTHS TO SEE WHAT WAS
GOING ON.
>> Reporter: AUTHORITIES WANT TO
KNOW WHY NANCY LANZA BOUGHT THE
BUSHMASTER RIFLE THAT HER SON
WOULD USE TO KILL HER AND OTHER
VICTIMS.
>> THAT WEAPON, FROM THE DAY IT
WAS BUILT, TO THE DAY IT WAS
HERE, WE'LL LOOK AT IT FROM STEM
TO STERN, WHO HAS HAD IT.
ALL OF THE CLIPS, AMMUNITIONS.
>> Reporter: DEMONSTRATED HERE
ON THE COMPANY YOUTUBE CHANNEL,
THE BUSHMASTER RIFLE CAN FIRE 45
ROUNDS IN A MINUTE, SLIGHTLY
MODIFIED SO IT IS LEGAL FOR
SALE, DESPITE A CONNECTICUT BAN
ON ASSAULT-STYLE RIFLES.
>> IT'S JUST AS DEADLY.
WHAT MAKES IT DANGEROUS, OF
COURSE, IS THE ABILITY TO TAKE
UNLIMITED AMOUNTS OF AMMUNITION
AND A PISTOL GRIP.
>> Reporter: THE WEAPON WAS
PURCHASED LEGALLY IN 2010, AFTER
THE TIME ADAM'S MOTHER KNEW OF
SERIOUS ISSUES.
EVEN TELLING A BABYSITTER YEARS
EARLIER, NEVER TO LEAVE HIM
ALONE.
>> NANCY TOLD ME TO ALWAYS KEEP
AN EYE ON HIM.
>> Reporter: YET, FOR SOME
REASON, SHE FELT COMFORTABLE
INTRODUCING ADAM TO ONE OF THE
MOST DANGEROUS WEAPONS A
CIVILIAN CAN OWN.
>> IT IS JUST AN EXTREMELY POOR
DECISION ON HER PART.
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT SORT OF A
PSYCHOLOGICAL SWITCH THAT I
THINK GOT TURNED ON FOR HIM,
WITH THE ACCESS OF THE WEAPONS.
AND THEN, THE READY
AVAILABILITY.
>> Reporter: THIS MORNING, A
NEW YORK INVESTMENT COMPANY
TELLS ABC NEWS, IT WILL SELL ITS
STAKE IN BUSHMASTER'S PARENT
COMPANY AS A RESULT OF THE SANDY
HOOK TRAGEDY, WHICH IT CALLED A
WATERSHED EVENT THAT'S RAISED
THE NATIONAL DEBATE ON GUN
CONTROL TO AN UNPRECEDENTED
LEVEL.
AT THE TIME NANCY LANZA BOUGHT
THAT WEAPON, THE COMPANY WAS
MARKETING THE BUSHMASTER AS A
GUN FOR A MAN'S MAN.
>>> WE'RE JOINED BY ONE OF
AMERICA'S LEADING PSYCHOLOGISTS.
MICHAEL WELNER.
HE CONSULTS ON HOMICIDES AROUND
THE U.S.
AND THANKS FOR COMING BACK TO
JOIN US.
THAT'S INTERESTING THAT SELLING
BUSHMASTER, CALLING IT A
WATERSHED MOMENT.
YOU SAY WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THE
MASS KILLINGS AS A SOCIAL
PHENOMENON.
>> YEAH.
I THINK IT'S EASY TO TARGET THE
GUN ISSUE.
AND THE GUN ISSUE IS VULNERABLE.
BUT I THINK ONLY FROM ONE
VANTAGE POINT.
AND THAT IS, IF YOU TAKE
ASSAULT, HIGH-CAPACITY,
HIGH-RAPID FIRE WEAPONS AND TAKE
THEM OUT OF THE EQUATION.
AND LOOK AT ALL THE MASS
SHOOTINGS THAT HAPPENED THIS
YEAR, WE SEE THIS IS HAPPENING
WITH GREATER FREQUENCY THAN EVER
BEFORE.
WHAT I'M TELLING YOU IS, WE'RE
DEALING WITH A POPULATION, THE
MASS KILLER.
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT
DISTINGUISHES THAT PERSON IS,
ONCE HE DECIDES HE'S GOING TO DO
IT, HE'S GOING TO DO IT.
IF YOU CAN KEEP AN ASSAULT RIFLE
OUT OF HIS HANDS, THE BODY COUNT
WILL DROP.
AND THAT'S GREAT.
BUT THE MASS KILLINGS WILL
CONTINUE TO HAPPEN UNLESS
SYSTEMICALLY WE ADDRESS IT AS A
SOCIAL PHENOMENON.
AND RECOGNIZE THERE'S THINGS
THAT PROMOTE IT.
FOR EXAMPLE, HIS PICTURE ON OUR
SCREEN AND US EVEN CARING TO GO
ALL THE WAY BACK TO FIND OUT
WHAT HIS GRIEVANCE IS.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT IN A
MOMENT.
AND THINGS THAT ENABLE AND
FACILITATE IS ISOLATING,
ALIENATING FROM THE WORLD, AND
KILLING CHILDREN LIKE HE'S IN AN
ARCADE GAME.
>> YOU SAY THERE'S NO QUESTION
THAT THE SEARCH FOR CELEBRITY IS
PART OF THIS.
GOING OUT IN A BLAZE OF GLORY.
YOU'RE ACTUALLY RECOMMENDING NOT
COVERING THIS AT ALL?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, WORDS ARE
IMPORTANT.
I THINK CELEBRITY, FOR SOME,
LIKE A BREIVIK, IN NORWAY.
HE WANTS CELEBRITY.
HE TAKES THE PICTURES.
HE'S READY FOR HIS CLOSE-UP.
YOU CAN'T SAY THIS ABOUT THIS
MAN.
WHAT YOU CAN SAY, WHAT'S THE
COMMON THREAD OF BOTH?
IRRELEVANCE.
WHAT'S THE COMMON THREAD OF THE
MASS KILLER?
A GRIEVANCE.
BUT IT'S A GRIEVANCE THAT'S
THEIR GRIEVANCE.
THAT DOESN'T MAKE IT LEGITIMATE.
I COULD SAY I HAVE A GRIEVANCE
WITH YOU.
I COULD JUST CONJURE SOMETHING
UP BECAUSE I'M RESENTFUL AND
ALIENATED AND YOU'RE LOOKING AT
ME FUNNY.
THAT DOESN'T LEGITIMIZE IT.
WHAT MASS KILLERS HAVE LEARNED,
BY WATCHING A STORY SUCH AS
OURS, SAYING WE'RE GOING TO FIND
OUT EVERYTHING ABOUT THEIR LIFE.
WE WANT TO KNOW WHY.
WHY?
WHEN HE WAS ALIVE, HIS MOTHER
AND OTHER PEOPLE PAID ATTENTION
TO HIS GRIEVANCE.
HE HAS IT.
THE POLICE KNOW IT.
>> IT'S A SOCIAL PHENOMENON.
>> MY POINT IS, WHAT HE'S AFTER
IS LEGITIMACY.
THEY WANT TO GO FROM IRRELEVANCE
TO HYPERRELEVANCE.
>> IS THERE ANY WAY TO TARGET
THESE MOSTLY YOUNG MEN BEFORE
THEY KILL?
>> HERE'S THE PATHWAY.
THE PATHWAY IS SOMEONE WHO
STARTS OUT BLAMING OTHERS,
RESENTFUL, AND WITHDRAWN.
AND OVER TIME, BECOME
INCREASINGLY WITHDRAWN.
AND THEN, INVESTED IN THE IDEA
OF BLAMING OTHERS.
SO, IT'S A PERSON WHO BECOMES
INVESTED IN THE IDEA THAT
EVERYBODY IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
THEIR SOCIAL AWKWARDNESS, FOR
HIS SEXUAL INCOMPETENCE, MAN'S
MAN.
OKAY?
AND IDENTIFIES WITH DESTRUCTION
AND THEMES OF DESTRUCTION.
IT'S MASCULINITY BECAUSE THAT
PERSON HAS FAILED.
AND OVER TIME, SEEING STORIES
ABOUT MASS KILLERS AND HEARING
THE DIALOGUE BEING, WE FAILED.
THE END POINT OF THAT IS, PEOPLE
DESERVED WHAT THEY GOT.
AND WHEN SOMEONE TAPS INTO THAT
AND HAS GONE DOWN THAT PATH, AND
IT'S A PATH.
ONCE THEY'VE GONE DOWN THAT PATH
AND THEIR LIFE IS GOING NOWHERE,
THEY START TO ENTERTAIN THE IDEA
OF ADOPTING THAT AS AN AMBITION.
AND WHEN THAT HAPPENS, IT'S A
TICKING PROCESS.
THEY NEVER STOP.
>> WE HAVE TO FIND A WAY TO
BLOCK THAT PATH.
>> THERE IS A WAY.
WE HAVE TO ELIMINATE IT.
AND THERE ARE THINGS THAT EACH
ONE OF US CAN DO.
EACH ONE OF US CAN DO.
FIRST OF ALL, WHAT CAN PARENTS
DO?
TEACH YOUR CHILDREN PERSONAL
RESPONSIBILITY.
TEACH OUR CHILDREN RESILIENCE
BECAUSE TEACH THEM TO UNDERSTAND
WHEN THEY FALL DOWN THEY CAN GET
BACK UP.
TEACHERS, TEACH IN CHILDREN THE
VALUES, THE VALUES OF
VOLUNTEERISM.
CONNECTING TO OTHER PEOPLE.
CREATING, INSTEAD OF DESTROYING.
NEIGHBORS, SET AN EXAMPLE OF
HELPING PEOPLE WHO ARE
SUFFERING.
>> WE ALL HAVE A RESPONSIBILITY.
I'M SORRY, THAT'S ALL WE HAVE
TIME FOR RIGHT NOW.
DR. WELNER, THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> LET'S GO TO SAM WITH THE
WEATHER.
>> HEY, GEORGE.
WE'RE GOING TO START WITH
PICTURES OUT OF COLORADO.
THE ROCKIES IN THE LAST FEW
STORMS HAVE PICKED UP POWDER.
AS SKIERS LIKE TO CALL IT,
FRESHYS.
AND LARA'S LIKE, NO?
I'M LIKE, YES.
ABSOLUTELY.
LOOK AT THE CURRENT ADVISE
REMEMBERS.
WINTER STORM WATCHES AND
WARNINGS FROM GREEN BAY.
CHICAGO, YOU'RE RIGHT ON THE END
OF IT.
IF THIS GOES SOUTH, YOU'RE THE
LONGEST SNOW DROUGHT PERIOD FROM
YEAR-TO-YEAR.
YOU COULD GET MORE OUT OF THIS.
THERE'S WHERE THE BLIZZARD
WARNINGS ARE, IN REDMOND.
AND ALL THE WAY TO THE WEST
COAST, AS WELL.
IT LAYS DOWN A LINE OF SNOW AND
SEVERE STORMS, AS WELL.
IF YOU'RE IN THOSE
>> MAYBE SKIERS IN THE '80s SAID
FRESHIES.
>> STILL NOT.
>> IT'S LIKE A WET WIPE,
FRESHIES.
>>> ANOTHER BECKHAM IN THE
SPOTLIGHT.
DAVID BECKHAM'S SON, ROMEO.
10 YEARS OLD AND ALREADY MAKING
A MARK IN THE MODELING WORLD.
WILL HE BECOME THE MOST FAMOUS
OF THAT VERY FAMOUS FAMILY?OF JN
FOR CENTURIES."
♪
THIS LEVIAN COLLECTION
IS AMAZING.
MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO START YOUR OWN.
[ Female Announcer ]
KAY JEWELERS PRESENTS
TODAY'S LEVIAN COLLECTION...
[ gasps ]
FEATURING EXCLUSIVE
LEVIAN CHOCOLATE DIAMONDS.
FROM THE LEVIAN FAMILY -
WHERE THE LATEST IN FASHION
MEETS FINE JEWELRY.
ONE MORE REASON KAY
IS THE NUMBER-ONE JEWELRY STORE
IN AMERICA.
IT'S...
A WORK OF ART?
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
WE TURN, NOW, TO ROMEO BECKHAM.
HE IS THE SON OF DAVID BECKHAM
AND FOLLOWING IN HIS FAMOUS
FATHER'S FOOTSTEPS.
LANDING HIS FIRST MAJOR FASHION
CAMPAIGN AT BURBERRY.
NICK WATT HAS THE STORY.
>> Reporter: BEHOLD THE MODELING
DEBUT OF 10-YEAR-OLD ROMEO
BECKHAM.
THE FASHION-FORWARD SPAWN OF
DAVID AND VICTORIA.
>> THIS IS SORT OF A NATURAL
EXTENSION OF THE BECKHAM BRAND.
>> Reporter: FASHION SENSE
PASSED FROM FATHER TO SON LIKE A
THRONE.
OR THE KEYS TO NORTH KOREA.
BEAUTY IS IN THE BLOOD.
CINDY CRAWFORD'S DAUGHTER
MODELS.
DANNIELYNN, ANNA NICOLE SMITH'S
LITTLE GIRL, JUST STARTED AT AGE
6.
FOLLOWING IN THE FOOTSTEPS OF
PATRICK SCHWARZENEGGER.
I SAID PATRICK SCHWARZENEGGER.
>> THERE'S A LOT OF CUTE KIDS IN
THE WORLD.
BUT NO KID BRINGS THE IMMEDIATE
VALUE THAT A CELEBRITY KID
BRINGS.
THERE'S AN INSTANT
RECOGNIZABILITY, EVEN IF THEY
DON'T KNOW THE KID.
THEY CERTAINLY KNOW THE PARENTS.
>> Reporter: BUT BEWARE
BECKHAMS' SENIOR.
SOMETIMES THE OFFSPRING CAN
ECLIPSE.
JON VOIGHT WAS BIG.
ANGELINA WAS HUGE.
AND SOME WILL NOT KNOW WHO BILLY
RAY CYRUS IS.
NICK WATT, ABC NEWS, LOS
ANGELES.
>> ACCORDING TO THE CREATIVE
DIRECTOR OF BURBERRY, ROMEO
STOLE THE SHOW.
SHE IS, INDEED.
>>> COMING UP, JOHN TRAVOLTA AND
OLIVIA NEWTON-JOHN TELL US ABOUT
THE CONVERSATION THAT BROUGHT
THEM BACK TOGETHER FOR THEIR NEW
COLLABORATION.
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY
IS THE SAME FREQUENT HEARTBURN
TREATMENT AS PRILOSEC OTC.
NOW WITH A FANCY COATING
THAT GIVES YOU A BURST
OF WILDBERRY FLAVOR.
NOW WHY MAKE A FLAVORED
HEARTBURN PILL?
BECAUSE THIS IS AMERICA.
AND WE DON'T JUST
MAKE THINGS YOU WANT,
WE MAKE THINGS YOU
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW YOU WANTED.
LIKE A SPOON FORK.
SPRAY CHEESE.
AND JEANS MADE
OUT OF SWEATPANTS.
SO GRAB YOURSELF SOME
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY.
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
SATISFACTION GUARANTEED
OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
LOOKS LIKE YOUR BAGS
DIDN'T MAKE IT.
WE'LL SEND THEM
TO YOUR HOTEL.
[ SAD MUSIC PLAYING ]
THIS IS FUN.
[ SAD MUSIC CONTINUES ]
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
YOUR BAGS, SIR.
THANKS.
Both: FINALLY!
ONE TASTE,
AND YOU'LL UNDERSTAND.
ENJOY DELICIOUS DUNKIN' DONUTS
COFFEE ANYTIME.
BEST VACATION EVER!
PICK SOME UP
WHERE YOU BUY GROCERIES.
AMERICA RUNS ON DUNKIN'.
>>> RIGHT THEN, HERE'S "THE PLAY
OF THE DAY."
>> IT IS ACTUALLY VIEWERS' PLAY
OF THE YEAR WEEK.
AND THIS WEEK, WE COULD REALLY
USE IT.
VOTED ON BY YOU.
LET'S GET TO NUMBER FIVE, SHALL
WE?
OUR FAVORITE EUROPEAN CANNONBALL
GUY.
A DRUMROLL, PLEASE.
YEAH.
>> OH.
>> YEAH.
WE HAVE REPLAY.
>> OH.
>> DID HE GET UP RIGHT AWAY?
>> YEAH.
HE'S FINE.
>> THREE TIMES?
>> I DON'T KNOW IF HE'S FINE.
>> I DON'T KNOW IF HE'S FINE?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
QUICKLY, NUMBER FOUR.
DO WE HAVE TIME FOR IT?
OH.
I DON'T THINK WE HAVE TIME.
WE LIKE THAT ONE TOO MUCH.
>> YEAH.
>> THIS IS THE OREGON ZOO.
THAT'S A HUNGRWE HAN.EVER WISH
TO PRACTICE MATH
MORE?
I LOVE MATH!
BUT TWO iPADS
MEANS TWO DATA PLANS?
THAT'S CRAZY.
MAYBE NOT.
WITH AT&T MOBILE SHARE,
ADDING AN iPAD
IS JUST $10 A MONTH.
BUT HONESTLY, MOM AND DAD'S LOVE
IS ALL I REALLY NEED.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE
FOR US.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE.
WHAT?!
[ Male Announcer ]
AT&T MOBILE SHARE.
ADD AN iPAD
FOR JUST $10 A MONTH.
ONE PLAN. UP TO 10 DEVICES.
AT&T. RETHINK POSSIBLE.
HELLO?
[ Sea ] HI!
THIS IS THE SEA CALLING.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU VISITED ME?
WHEN I WENT SURFING.
I LOVE TO SURF.
CAN YOU IMAGINE
SURFING IN THE MIDDLE OF ME?
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOU?
OH YES!
[ giggles ] NICE MOVES!
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
OUR BIGGEST DECEMBER
SALES EVENT EVER.
GOING ON NOW.
CALL 1-800-ROYAL-CARIBBEAN.
♪
I made the clear choice.
I'm getting Claritin Clear
with Claritin-D.
Nasal congestion keep me away ?
Not since I made
the clear choice.
Non-drowsy Claritin-D.
Decongestant products on
the shelf can take hours
to start working.
Claritin-D starts to work
in just 30 minutes.
I can't wait hours for
a nasal decongestant.
That's why I made the clear
choice and got Claritin-D.
It has the best
decongestant for colds.
This cold season, get Claritin-D
at the pharmacy counter.
Live Claritin Clear.
I NEED ALL THE HELP I CAN GET.
THAT'S WHY I LIKE NUTELLA.
MOM, WHAT'S THE CAPITAL
OF WEST VIRGINIA?
CHARLESTON.
NUTELLA IS A DELICIOUS HAZELNUT
SPREAD MY WHOLE FAMILY LOVES.
MOM, HAVE YOU SEEN MY --
BACKPACK?
NUTELLA GOES GREAT
ON WHOLE-WHEAT TOAST
OR WHOLE-GRAIN WAFFLES.
AND ITS GREAT TASTE
COMES FROM A UNIQUE COMBINATION
OF SIMPLE INGREDIENTS
LIKE HAZELNUTS,
SKIM MILK AND A HINT OF COCOA.
YEAH, BYE.
HAVE YOU SEEN MY --
YES.
AND...THANK YOU.
[ Male Announcer ] NUTELLA.
BREAKFAST NEVER TASTED
THIS GOOD.
>>> COMING UP, EASY TIPS TO KEEP
THE HOLIDAY POUNDS AWAY, SAM.
AND YOU CAN STILL EAT.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
POTENTIAL SINKHOLE CAUSING
CONCERN IN CONTRA COSTA
COUNTY.
MARSH CREEK ROAD BETWEEN DEER
VALLEY ROAD AND PINE LANE IN
CLAYTON IS CLOSED CREWS SAY
RECENT RAIN COMPROMISE THEED
ROAD AND SINKHOLE IS STARTING
TO FORM.
WEEP KEEP YOU POSTED.
-- WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
LIVE DOPPLER PICKING UP
SHOWERS OFF THE COAST WHERE I
THINK THEY ARE GOING TO STAY
TODAY 30s AND 40s NOW LOW 50s
THIS AFTERNOON, RAIN THURSDAY
THROUGH SUNDAY.
>>> SLIGHT BART DELAY, AN TO
10 MINUTES EASTBOUND OUT OF
SAN FRANCISCO DUE TO EQUIPMENT
PROBLEM, SOUTHBOUND 880
ALVARADO NILES EARLIER
ACCIDENT HAS THINGS SLOW.
>>> THE NEWS
♪ YOU ARE THE ONE I WANT
YOU ARE THE ONE I WANT ♪
♪ WOO, WOO, WOO
HONEY ♪
>>> THE BEST-SELLING DUET IN POP
MUSIC HISTORY.
HIGH ABOVE TIMES SQUARE.
A GREAT CROWD DOWN BELOW.
AND OLIVIA NEWTON-JOHN AND JOHN
TRAVOLTA, BACK TOGETHER AGAIN.
THEY ARE HERE ON "GMA," THIS
MORNING, AFTER 30 YEARS.
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR SOME OF THE
NEW SONGS, HEAR ABOUT THEIR NEW
CAUSES.
AND WHAT REALLY HAPPENED BEHIND
THE SCENES OF "GREASE."
A LOT COMING UP.
WE SAY GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
AND ELIZABETH.
SO MUCH OF OUR HEARTS AND MINDS
STILL ON NEWTOWN.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AND A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
WONDERING, AFTER ADAM LANZA
COMMITTED THIS HORRIFIC CRIME
WHAT WE CAN DO IN THIS COUNTRY
TO HELP OUR YOUNG PEOPLE.
THERE'S AN ESTIMATED ONE IN FIVE
CHILDREN THAT SUFFER FROM MENTAL
ILLNESS IN THIS COUNTRY.
AND MANY OF THEM DO NOT GET
HELP, MOSTLY BECAUSE PARENTS
CAN'T FIND THE HELP.
WE'RE GOING TO GET INTO THAT
SEGMENT THIS MORNING, ON WHAT
PARENTS SHOULD LOOK FOR.
AND HOW TO GET THE MUCH-NEEDED
RESOURCES.
>> ALL PART OF OUR SEARCH FOR
SOLUTIONS.
>>> AND THEN, WE'RE GOING TO
SWITCH GEARS AND TALK TO THE
FUNNY LESLIE MANN.
AND ALSO, WE'RE GOING TO TALK
ABOUT HOLIDAY PARTIES.
THEY DON'T HAVE TO MEAN EXTRA
POUNDS.
WE'LL TELL YOU HOW TO STRATEGIZE
AND STAY STRONG WHEN FACED WITH
ALL OF THOSE GOODIES.
>>> LESLIE MANN, "THIS IS 40,"
THE NEW FILM.
SOMETHING OF A FOLLOW-UP.
THE SEMIFOLLOW-UP TO "KNOCKED
UP."
WE'LL TALK TO HER TODAY.
WITH PAUL RUDD AND HER CHILDREN,
AGAIN, IN THE FILM.
>> DIRECTED BY HER HUSBAND.
IT'S GREAT.
>>> WHAT'S BEEN VIEWED 500
MILLION TIMES?
THE HOT VIDEO FROM KARMIN,
BLOCKBUSTER DUO.
THEY'RE HERE ON "GMA," TO SING A
HOLIDAY FAVORITE FOR US.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO GET TO THE
NEWS AND JOSH.
>> WE'RE GOING TO RETURN TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
FOUR MORE FUNERALS FOR THE
VICTIMS OF FRIDAY'S SCHOOL
SHOOTING ARE BEING HELD THERE
TODAY.
ALL SCHOOLS EXCEPT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WILL REOPEN
TODAY.
IT IS UNCLEAR WHEN STUDENTS FROM
SANDY HOOK WILL RETURN TO CLASS.
BUT A SCHOOL IN A NEIGHBORING
TOWN, MONROE, IS BEING PREPARED
FOR THEM.
>>> WE ARE GETTING A CLEARER
PICTURE OF THE GUNMAN TODAY.
A FAMILY FRIEND SAYS ADAM LANZA
HASN'T SEEN HE FATHER OR HIS
BROTHER SINCE 2010.
HIS DAD MOVED OUT OF THE FAMILY
HOME IN 2001.
SPENT MOST WEEKENDS WITH ADAM
UNTIL TWO YEARS AGO.
A FORMER BABYSITTER SAYS ADAM
LANZA HAD BEHAVIORAL PROBLEMS
AND WAS TOLD TO NEVER LEAVE HIM
ALONE.
>>> AND MORE POLITICIANS,
INCLUDING GUN ADVOCATES ARE
PUSHING FOR STRICTER GUN CONTROL
LAWS.
SOME RETAILERS ARE CUTTING BACK
IN THE GUNS THEY SELL.
AND WE LEARNED THIS MORNING THAT
A NEW YORK INVESTMENT COMPANY
WILL SELL ITS STAKE OF
BUSHMASTERS, WHICH IS ONE OF THE
GUNS USED IN THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
>>> FIVE MONTHS AFTER THE MOVIE
THEATER SHOOTINGS IN COLORADO,
THAT STATE'S GOVERNOR IS ASKING
FOR $18 MILLION TO EXPAND MENTAL
HEALTH SERVICES IN THE STATE.
LAWYERS FOR ACCUSED SHOOTER
JAMES HOLMES, SAY THEIR CLIENT
IS MENTALLY ILL.
THE GOVERNOR WANTS TO ESTABLISH
24-HOUR WALK-IN CENTERS FOR
MENTAL HEALTH CARE.
>>> AND A BREAKING STORY
OVERNIGHT.
NBC NEWS FOREIGN CORRESPONDENT,
RICHARD ENGEL, AND HIS CREW ARE
FREE, AFTER FIVE DAYS OF
CAPTIVITY IN SYRIA.
THEY ESCAPED THIS MORNING,
DURING A FIREFIGHT BETWEEN THEIR
CAPTORS AND A SYRIAN REBEL GROUP
WHILE THEY WERE BEING MOVED.
THEY'RE BACK IN TURKEY AND
UNHARMED.
>>> A STEP IN THE RIGHT
DIRECTION.
THAT'S HOW HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER'S DESCRIBING PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S LATEST OFFER TO AVOID
THE FISCAL CLIFF.
THE NEW OFFER CUTS BACK ON TAX
INCREASES FOR THE WEALTHY.
AND INCLUDES MORE SPENDING CUTS
ON ENTITLEMENT PROGRAMS, SUCH AS
MEDICARE.
>>> TOYOTA IS BEING ORDERED TO
PAY A RECORD FINE AFTER BEING
ACCUSED OF WAITING TOO LONG TO
REPORT A SAFETY DEFECT.
GOVERNMENT REGULATORS SAY THE
COMPANY WAITED FOR A MONTH
BEFORE REPORTING PROBLEMS WITH
FLOOR MATS IN CERTAIN LEXUS SUVs
THAT MADE THE GAS PEDAL STICK.
>>> AND FINALLY, A CHUCKLE FOR
ALL OF YOU THIS MORNING.
WE WANTED TO SHOW YOU THIS.
SOME GUYS IN NORWAY JUST WON AN
AWARD FOR A VIDEO THEY MADE.
SHOWING JUST HOW EASILY THEIR
CO-WORKER IS PRANKED.
TAKE A LOOK.
THEY DECIDED TO PULL SOME AROUND
THE OFFICE.
AND THEIR CO-WORKER'S REACTION
HAS GONE VIRAL.
WHETHER IT'S THE --
>> OH.
>> ANY SUDDEN MOVEMENT, HE
APPARENTLY HAS A PROBLEM WITH.
THAT ONE SCARED ME.
I'M SORRY.
THAT WOULD SCARE ME.
HAD WE KNOWN THAT IT WOULD WIN
AN AWARD, WE COULD HAVE
POTENTIALLY SUBMITTED ANY
EPISODE OF THIS PROGRAM AND
TAKEN IT.
>> WE COULD JUST DO THIS
MORNING, BETWEEN LARA'S COFFEE
SPILL, TWICE.
YOUR TENNIS SHOE LACE.
AND MY -- YOU'RE JUST GEORGE.
>> WE LOOK TO YOU, GEORGE.
>> OKAY.
>>> LET'S GET SOME "POP NEWS."
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU ALL.
AND TO YOU.
AND YOU KNOW, THERE'S NOTHING
LIKE A GOLDEN RETRIEVER TO WARM
YOUR HEART.
SO, 10 OF THEM TRAVELED 800
MILES, FROM CHICAGO TO NEWTOWN,
TO BRING A LITTLE COMFORT IN THE
COMMUNITY.
THE CANINE COMFORT INITIATIVE IS
ALL ABOUT UNCONDITIONAL LOVE.
THE DOGS ARE ACCEPTING.
THEY'RE SO KIND NATURED.
AND PEOPLE BELIEVE THAT HELPS TO
CREATE AN ATMOSPHERE WHERE IT'S
EASIER TO EXPRESS FEELINGS,
WHICH IS SO NEEDED AT THIS TIME.
EACH DOG HAS THEIR OWN FACEBOOK
PAGE AND E-MAIL ACCOUNT.
SO, THOSE WHO MEET THEM CAN STAY
IN TOUCH.
THE INITIATIVE HAS GROWN TO 60
DOGS IN 6 STATES.
TO LEARN MORE AND OTHER WAYS YOU
CAN HELP THE SANDY HOOK
COMMUNITY, PLEASE GO TO
GOODMORNINGAMERICA.COM ON YAHOO!
>> THEY ARE THE BEST.
GOLDENS -- YOU JUST WANT TO LOVE
THEM.
YOU CAN DO IT ALL DAY.
>> MAX AND SADIE AT HOME.
THEY'RE PERFECT.
>> ALL DOGS, REALLY.
>>> ALSO IN "POP NEWS" THIS
MORNING, TWO CELEBRITIES ARE
PLAYING A GAME OF ONEUPSMANSHIP.
BUT IN THE BEST WAY POSSIBLE.
CHARLIE SHEEN STARTED IT.
DONATING $75,000 TO HELP A
LITTLE GIRL'S FAMILY WITH CANCER
TREATMENT BILLS.
NOT TO BE OUTDONE,
STEVIE WONDER DONATED ANOTHER
$100,000.
SHEEN -- IT WASN'T SHEEN.
IT WAS STEVIE MADE THE
ANNOUNCEMENT AT A CONCERT IN
L.A. THIS WEEKEND, AFTER CALLING
10-YEAR-OLD JASMINE FALK ON TO
THE STAGE.
HE THEN DOUBLED DOWN ON HIS
GENEROUS GIFT AND
HE SERENADED HER WITH HIS
CLASSIC, "ISN'T SHE LOVELY."
>>> AND FINALLY, DO WE HAVE
PROPS?
DO WE HAVE THE -- DO WE NOT?
ANYBODY?
WELL.
THERE'S A PROP.
AND I WAS VERY EXCITED TO SHARE
IT.
>> HERE THEY COME.
>> THANK YOU, ALL, SO MUCH.
EVERYBODY.
PLEASE ENJOY -- GEORGE, WILL YOU
HELP ME, PLEASE.
PUT YOUR HAND IN THERE.
I SHOULD GO HERE.
WE'VE WARMED YOUR HEART
HOPEFULLY, A LITTLE BIT.
NOW, WE WANT TO WARM YOUR HANDS
WITH THE TWITTEN.
THIS IS THE WORLD'S FIRST
TWO-HANDED MITTEN, MAKING SURE
YOU NEVER HAVE TO STOP HOLDING
HANDS WITH THE ONE YOU LOVE.
WHETHER YOU'RE A COUPLE, BEST
FRIENDS, PARENTS AND CHILD, OR
CO-ANCHORS, THEY COST $45.
THEY'RE HANDMADE IN PERU.
AND ALL PROFITS GO TOWARDS
CHARITY.
GEORGE, LET GO.
>> COMING HOME.
>> WE FOUND THOSE ONLINE.
WE THOUGHT THOSE WERE SPECIAL
FOR THIS MORNING.
>> THEY'RE COOL.
>>> AND FINALLY, THE POP QUIZ.
WHICH CELEBS WILL KICK OFF 2013
ON "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE"?
WE HAVE A NEW TIME AND NEW
GUESTS.
THEY'RE BIG.
WE'LL HAVE THE ANSWER
EXCLUSIVELY FOR YOU IN A MOMENT.
>> LOOKING FORWARD TO THAT.
>>> LET'S GET THE WEATHER, NOW,
FROM SAM.
>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYBODY.
HELLO, EVERYBODY.
SIGNS, EVERYWHERE.
NOW, WHO IS THAT?
>> THAT'S MY GRANDDAUGHTER.
>> YOUR GRANDDAUGHTER.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, THANK YOU.
HANG ON.
FROM WHERE?
>> MISSISSIPPI.
>> ALL RIGHT.
FANTASTIC.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYBODY.
LET'S GET TO THE BOARDS.
HERE'S A LIVE SHOT OUT OF
BOSTON.
WE'VE ALREADY STARTED TO GET RID
OF THE RAIN HERE.
WE'RE GETTING RID OF THE FOG A
LITTLE LATER.
IN BOSTON, IT WILL TAKE LONGER
TO GET THE MIST AND DRIZZLE OUT
TODAY.
THE IDEA IS TO BRING IN DRIER,
MILDER AIR.
LOOK AT BOSTON AT 52 TODAY.
PHILLY AT 58.
D.C. AT 58, AS WELL.
THAT'S PRETTY NICE FOR THIS TIME
OF YEAR.
THEN, COLDER WEATHER AHEAD.
WATCH THIS STORM MOVE ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
AND ONE OF THE THINGS IT DOES IS
DROPS THOSE TEMPERATURES.
LOOK AT CHICAGO GOING TO 28, BY
THE TIME WE GET TO FRIDAY.
THAT STORM MAY BE HARDER ON
CHICAGO WHEN IT PASSES.
WHEN THE COLD AIR COMES IN
BEHIND IT, IT'S REALLY GOING TO
>> THANK YOU.
WE ARE LIVE IN TIMES SQUARE THIS
MORNING.
AND NO MIST IS GOING TO KEEP
THIS CROWD FROM BEING, WELL, ITS
NORMAL, ROWDY SELF.
LARA, BACK TO YOU.
>> THANK YOU, SAM.
>>> HERE'S A LOOK AT WHAT'S
COMING UP ON OUR "GMA MORNING
MENU."
WE HEAR FROM TWO ICONS.
JOHN TRAVOLTA AND OLIVIA
NEWTON-JOHN, REUNITED
FOR A NEW ALBUM.
A VERY SPECIAL INTERVIEW.
>>> AND THE LITTLE GIRL WHO
WANTED TO GIVE HER LITTLE
BROTHER THE PERFECT CHRISTMAS
GIFT.
AN EASY-BAKE OVEN THAT EVEN BOYS
WILL LOVE.
WE'LL EXPLAIN.
>>> PLUS, HOW TO KEEP OFF THE
HOLIDAY POUNDS WITHOUT STARVING
YOURSELF?
DR. JENNIFER ASHTON IS WEIGHING
IN.
AND THAT'S COMING UP LIVE ON
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA."
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
JILL AND HER MOUTH HAVE LIVED
A GREAT LIFE.
BUT SHE HAS SOME DENTAL ISSUES
SHE'S NOT HAPPY ABOUT.
SO JILL'S DENTIST
INTRODUCED HER
TO CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SELECTED FOR PEOPLE OVER 50.
PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE IS A
TOOTHPASTE THAT DEFENDS AGAINST
TENDER, INFLAMED GUMS,
SENSITIVITY AND WEAK ENAMEL.
CONDITIONS PEOPLE OVER 50
EXPERIENCE.
CREST PRO-HEALTH FOR LIFE.
SO JILL CAN KEEP LIVING
THE GOOD LIFE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
THAT'S WHY NEW
Dove Style + Care
Frizz Free Cream Serum
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS,
KEEPING HAIR SMOOTH SHINY
AND FREE FROM FLYAWAYS.
NEW Dove Style + Care
Frizz Free Cream Serum.
BETTER STYLE
THROUGH BETTER CARE.
THEY'RE WHOLE GRAIN GOOD...
AND YUMMY GOOD.
REAL FRUIT PIECES.
12 GRAMS OF WHOLE GRAINS
AND A CREAMY
YOGURT FLAVORED COATING.
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
TREAT YOURSELF GOOD.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
A deep, throbbing,
persistent ache.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can do more of
the things that I enjoy.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
[ Male Announcer ] 'TIS
THE SEASON FOR NONSTOP CHEER
AND NONSTOP GET-TOGETHERS.
THANKFULLY, Walgreens MAKES IT
EASY TO ENJOY THE HOLIDAYS,
WITH EVERYTHING FROM TASTY
Good & Delish BRAND TREATS
TO UNIQUE HOLIDAY décor.
SO RSVP "YES"
AND SPREAD SOME CHEER
OF YOUR OWN.
COME TO Walgreens FOR
Hershey's Kisses Chocolates
AND ALL THE TREATS
OF THE SEASON.
AND MOST STORES ARE EVEN OPEN
TILL MIDNIGHT, HERE.
AT THE Corner
of Happy and Healthy.
>>> NOW, THE ANSWER TO OUR POP
QUIZ OF THE DAY.
WHICH CELEBS WILL KICK OFF 2013
ON "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE" ON HIS
NEW TIME SLOT OF 11:35.
THE ANSWER IS, SOFIA VERGARA,
RYAN GOSLING, NICKI MINAJ.
AND THAT'S JUST TO NAME A FEW.
THANKS.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO TURN TO THE
AFTERMATH OF THE SHOOTINGS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THERE'S A LOT OF QUESTIONS IN
THIS COUNTRY ABOUT CHILDREN AND
MENTAL ILLNESS.
ONE THING THAT IS CLEAR ABOUT
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA, HE HAD
BEEN TROUBLED FOR A LONG TIME.
AND HIS MOTHER WAS UNABLE TO
HELP HIM.
AN ESTIMATED ONE IN FIVE
CHILDREN SUFFER FROM MENTAL
DISORDER OR ILLNESS IN THIS
COUNTRY.
AND THEIR PARENTS ARE OFTEN
DESPERATE FOR HELP AND FOR
ANSWERS.
FOR MILLIONS OF AMERICANS WHO
HAVE CHILDREN WITH MENTAL
ILLNESS OR DISORDERS, THE
STRUGGLE IS A DAILY ONE.
>> IT'S TERRIFYING.
IT'S DISTRESSING.
THE LEGACY OF PARENTS BEING
BLAMED FOR THEIR CHILDREN'S
MENTAL ILLNESS LINGERS.
>> Reporter: TRICIA KNOWS THIS
FIRSTHAND.
>> MY SON BATTLES MENTAL
ILLNESS.
WE'VE BEEN BATTLING IT SINCE THE
FALL OF 2008.
>> Reporter: IN NOVEMBER, SHE
PREVENTED A TRAGEDY BY CALLING
POLICE ON HER 20-YEAR-OLD SON,
BLAKE, WHO WAS PLOTTING A MOVIE
THEATER MASSACRE AT THE
SCREENING OF "TWILIGHT."
AUTHORITIES STOPPED HIM IN TIME.
>> I THINK ANY MOM WOULD BLAME
HERSELF.
>> Reporter: HOW TO HELP
TROUBLED, YOUNG PEOPLE?
IT'S A TOPIC WE'VE COVERED
OFTEN.
A FEW YEARS AGO, JODI
RICHARDSON, A TEACHER AND
MOTHER, TOLD US HER 14-YEAR-OLD
WAS BECOMING OUT OF CONTROL.
THREATENING HER PHYSICALLY.
>> YOU THINK, WHAT HAVE I DONE
TO BRING THIS ON?
WHAT AM I DOING WRONG?
>> Reporter: SINCE OUR INTERVIEW
WITH RICHARDSON, HER SON HAS
BEEN DIAGNOSED WITH TWO MENTAL
DISORDERS.
BUT EVEN WITH A DIAGNOSIS,
THEY'RE STILL FIGHTING AN UPHILL
BATTLE.
>> WHY WOULD I WANT TO RAISE A
BULLY?
I'M TRYING HARD.
>> THE RESOURCES FOR PARENTS
DEALING WITH THESE THINGS VARY
ENORMOUSLY FROM STATE-TO-STATE,
COUNTY-TO-COUNTY, FROM
DISTRICT-TO-DISTRICT.
>> Reporter: NO ONE KNOWS THAT
BETTER THAN THIS FAMILY.
WHEN WE MET THEM IN 2010 FOR A
"20/20" INTERVIEW, 13-YEAR-OLD
BRENNA WAS HAVING A PSYCHIATRIC
EPISODE.
>> I CANNOT STOP.
I CANNOT STOP.
>> Reporter: SHE WAS BEGGING TO
THE HOSPITALIZED.
>> I'D LIKE TO FIND OUT IF YOU
HAVE ANY BEDS AVAILABLE IN THE
ADOLESCENT --
I WANTED TO KNOW IF YOU HAVE A
BED.
I WANT TO KNOW IF YOU HAVE A
>> Reporter: AND AFTER TWO HOURS
OF PHONE CALLS.
>> THEY HAVE A BED, RIGHT THIS
SECOND.
BUT IT CHANGES MINUTE-TO-MINUTE.
>> Reporter: THREE WEEKS LATER,
THE HOSPITAL RELUCTANTLY
DISCHARGED BRENNA BECAUSE THE
FAMILY'S INSURANCE WOULDN'T PAY
ANYMORE.
LEAVING BRENNA'S PARENTS TO
AGAIN LOOK FOR THEIR OWN
SOLUTIONS.
BRENNA IS NOW IN A RESIDENTIAL
STEPDOWN TREATMENT PROGRAM.
HER MOTHER AND FATHER ARE JUST
TWO OF MANY PARENTS OUT THERE
WHO ARE STRUGGLING TO GET THE
HELP THEIR CHILDREN NEED.
AND FOR MORE ON THAT, WE'RE
JOINED BY DR. JAMIE HOWARD, A
CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST, WITH
CHILD MIND INSTITUTE.
IT'S A LEADING TREATMENT AND
ADVOCACY GROUP FOR CHILDREN'S
MENTAL HEALTH IN THIS COUNTRY.
GOOD MORNING.
GOOD TO HAVE YOU HERE.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THERE'S AN ESTIMATED 15
MILLION CHILDREN WITH MENTAL
ILLNESS IN THIS COUNTRY.
ONLY HALF OF THEM GET HELP?
WHY IS THAT?
>> THAT'S A BIG PROBLEM.
WE HAVE A STIGMA AROUND
CHILDHOOD PSYCHIATRIC DIAGNOSES.
WE WANT TO CHANGE THAT.
>> DO YOU THINK PARENTS DON'T
SEEK THE HELD?
>> I THINK PARENTS LACK THE
INFORMATION.
AND WE CREATE AN ATMOSPHERE
WHERE PARENTS CAN BE BLAMED.
YOU WATCH A PARENT WATCHING AN
OUT-OF-CONTROL CHILD.
AND YOU SEE THEM ROLL THEIR
EYES.
THAT CHILD MAY HAVE PROBLEMS
THAT WARRANT INTERVENTION.
AND ANY PARENT WOULD HAVE A HARD
TIME MANAGING.
>> NO PARENT WOULD TAKE THAT
LONG, TWO YEARS, TO TREAT A
PHYSICAL AILMENT.
I MEAN, THE MINUTE THEY GET
A COLD OR A STOMACH BUG, WE HAVE
THEM INTO THE DOCTOR.
>> RIGHT.
YOU HAVE A RASH, YOU GO TO THE
DOCTOR.
YOU DON'T WAIT TO SEE WHAT IT
TURNS INTO.
WE GO TO THE DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY.
WE NEED TO DO THAT WITH
PSYCHIATRIC DIAGNOSES, AS WELL.
>> WE WERE TALKING ABOUT HOW TO
RECOGNIZE A CHILD NEEDS TO GO TO
THE DOCTOR.
YOU AND I WERE TALKING ABOUT
THIS A MOMENT AGO.
I BELIEVE IN A MOTHER'S
INSTINCT, WE KNOW WHEN
SOMETHING'S OFF, NOT QUITE
RIGHT.
IT'S IMPORTANT WE PAY ATTENTION
TO THOSE INSTINCTS AND NOT BE
AFRAID.
AND THE FIRST STEP SHOULD BE TO
TAKE THE CHILD TO THE
PEDIATRICIAN.
>> PARENTS WAIT ABOUT TWO YEARS
ON AVERAGE AFTER THE ONSET OF
PSYCHIATRIC SYMPTOMS BEFORE
REACHING OUT.
SO, THEY HAVE THE GUT INSTINCTS.
BUT THEY DON'T ALWAYS FOLLOW-UP
ON IT.
SO, WE ADVOCATE FOR PARENTS TO
GO TO THE PEDIATRICIAN AND TALK
TO THE PEDIATRICIANS ABOUT
WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> WHAT ARE THE WARNING SIGNS
THAT SOMETHING MORE SERIOUS MAY
BE GOING ON WITH YOUR CHILD?
>> YOU WANT TO LOOK FOR CHRONIC
IRRITABILITY AND UNHAPPINESS.
YOU WANT TO LOOK FOR SOCIAL
LONER.
SOCIAL ISOLATION.
NOT HAVING MANY FRIENDS OR ANY
MEANINGFUL FRIENDSHIPS.
BEING ARGUMENTATIVE AND
OPPOSITIONAL.
NOT TAKING RESPONSIBILITY FOR
ANTI-SOCIAL ACTS, LIKE STEALING
OR BEING MEAN TO KIDS.
>> ALL THOSE SYMPTOMS YOU
DESCRIBED COULD BE FOUND IN ANY
CHILD, ANY NORMAL CHILD.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
THEY CAN.
SO, WHAT WE WANT TO LOOK FOR IS
SOMETHING WE CALL FUNCTIONAL
IMPAIRMENT.
WHERE KIDS' JOBS ARE BEING
COMPROMISED.
A KID'S JOB IS TO GO TO SCHOOL
AND LEARN AND TO CONCENTRATE.
AND A KID'S JOB IS TO MAKE AND
KEEP FRIENDS.
IF THEY'RE NOT ABLE TO DO THOSE
TWO IMPORTANT THINGS BECAUSE
SYMPTOMS ARE GETTING IN THE WAY,
WE WANT TO REACH OUT AND GET
HELP.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE FACT THERE'S A
LACK OF RESOURCES FOR SO MANY
FAMILIES?
I'VE DONE SO MUCH REPORTING OVER
THE YEARS.
WE JUST SAW IN THAT PIECE JUST
NOW WE HAD ON "20/20," SHOWING
FAMILIES DESPERATE FOR HELP.
BUT THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
INSURANCE DOESN'T COVER IT.
OR A HOSPITAL DOESN'T HAVE A BED
FOR A CHILD.
>> WE WANT TO MAKE IT EASIER FOR
PARENTS TO GET CONNECTED TO THE
RESOURCES THEY NEED.
PSYCHIATRIC DISORDERS ARE COMMON
AND TREATABLE.
WE HAVE A NUMBER OF RESOURCES
BEYOND YOUR PEDIATRICIAN.
THERE'S THE AMERICAN
PSYCHOLOGICAL ASSOCIATION, THE
AMERICAN ACADEMY OF CHILD AND
ADOLESCENT PSYCHIATRY.
AND OUR WEBSITE AT CHILD MIND,
WE HAVE CHILDMIND.ORG, WHICH IS
A SINGLE DESTINATION TO COMPILE
THIS INFORMATION FOR PARENTS.
>> I KNOW IN THE STATE OF
WYOMING, THEY'VE ONLY 6 CHILD
PSYCHOLOGISTS FOR A POPULATION
OF 500,000.
IT'S SOMETHING WE NEED TO PAY
MORE ATTENTION TO IN THIS
COUNTRY.
>> IT IS.
>> AND YOU SAID, ON THE CHILD
MIND INSTITUTE WEBSITE, THERE'S
A QUESTIONNAIRE THAT PARENTS CAN
FILL OUT TO SEE IF THERE'S A
PROBLEM WITH THEIR CHILD.
DR. JAMIE HOWARD,
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR BEING
HERE.
IT'S IMPORTANT INFORMATION FOR A
LOT OF FAMILIES.
FOR MORE MENTAL HEALTH RESOURCES
GO TO GOODMORNINGAMERICA.COM ON
YAHOO!
GEORGE?
>> A LOT MORE INFORMATION THERE.
>>> NOW, WE'RE GOING TO TURN TO
THE REUNION WE'VE BEEN WAITING
FOR.
AFTER 30 YEARS, JOHN TRAVOLTA
AND OLIVIA NEWTON-JOHN ARE
MAKING MUSIC TOGETHER AGAIN.
AND THEY SAT DOWN WITH AMY
ROBACH LAST WEEK BEFORE THE
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN, TO TALK
ABOUT TWO CAUSES CLOSE TO THEIR
HEARTS.
♪ YOU'RE THE ONE THAT I WANT
YOU ARE THE ONE THAT I WANT ♪
>> THREE DECADES AFTER THEIR
LAST DUET, JOHN TRAVOLTA AND
OLIVIA NEWTON-JOHN ARE BACK WITH
A BRAND-NEW HOLIDAY ALBUM, "THIS
CHRISTMAS" FOR A GOOD CAUSE.
THANK YOU FOR BEING WITH US.
>> THANK YOU.
>> HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
>> THIS IDEA CAME LAST CHRISTMAS
WHEN OLIVIA SENT YOU A TEXT.
>> WE CAN DRAMATIZE IT FOR YOU,
IF YOU LIKE.
>> WOULD YOU?
>> CONGRATULATIONS, JOHN.
"YOU'RE THE ONE THAT I WANT" HAS
JUST BEEN VOTED THE MOST POPULAR
DUET OF ALL-TIME.
>> GUESS WHAT, KIDS,
HONEY.
"YOU'RE THE ONE THAT I WANT" IS
THE BIGGEST DUET IN HISTORY.
I'M GOING TO CONGRATULATE HER
BACK.
WHY DON'T I DO A DUET WITH
OLIVIA?
>> WOW.
GREAT IDEA.
I WISH I HAD THOUGHT OF THAT.
THAT'S AWESOME.
JUMP TO THREE WEEKS LATER.
>> WHY DON'T WE DO A WHOLE
ALBUM?
>> THAT'S A FANTASTIC IDEA.
AND LET'S DO IT FOR OUR
CHARITIES.
>> LET'S DO IT.
>> I LOVE IT.
IT WAS LIKE TWITTER THEATER.
TELL ME ABOUT THE SONG.
THIS IS AN ORIGINAL CHRISTMAS
SONG.
PEOPLE DO CHRISTMAS ALBUMS ALL
THE TIME.
BUT THEY DON'T HAVE A BRAND-NEW
SONG.
>> WELL, JOHN FARRA, WHO WROTE
"YOU'RE THE ONE THAT I WANT"
WROTE IT FOR THE ALBUM.
♪ I THINK YOU MIGHT LIKE IT
>> HOW DOES IT GO?
♪ THINK YOU MIGHT LIKE IT
>> I LIKE IT.
>> WE MENTIONED THAT THIS WAS
ALL FOR A GOOD CAUSE.
AND, OLIVIA, I KNOW YOU'RE
GIVING YOUR PART OF THE PROCEEDS
TO YOUR CANCER RESEARCH CENTER.
AND, JOHN, THIS IS FOR YOUR SON,
JETT.
THIS HAS TO BE A TOUGH TIME OF
YEAR FOR YOU AND YOUR FAMILY.
>> EVERY DAY IS A TOUGH TIME
WHEN YOU LOSE A CHILD.
SO, THIS IS A WAY THAT YOU HELP
SOLVE SOME OF THAT ANGST, YOU
KNOW?
AND I THINK IT'S THE SAME FOR
OLIVIA.
WHEN YOU HAVE A BIGGER PURPOSE,
IT HELPS SOOTHE THAT, YOU KNOW?
BUT THERE'S NOT A MOMENT OF THE
DAY I DON'T THINK ABOUT MY SON.
>> OLIVIA, WE KNOW YOU'RE A
BREAST CANCER THRIVER.
>> YES.
>> AND ROBIN IS DEALING WITH HER
OWN STRUGGLES.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SAY SOMETHING
TO HER?
>> I'D LOVE TO.
I WANT TO SEND MY LOVE TO YOU,
ROBIN.
THINKING ABOUT YOU.
I KNOW YOU'RE GOING TO BE FINE.
SENDING LOTS OF LOVE AND LIGHT
TO YOU.
>> SHE'S GROWING STRONGER EVERY
DAY.
I'M SURE SHE'LL APPRECIATE THAT.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE ON THE SET
FILMING "GREASE"?
PEOPLE TALK ABOUT THE CHEMISTRY
YOU TWO HAD.
AND IT'S STILL THERE.
>> YES.
LOOK AT THAT CHEMISTRY.
OH, MY GOSH.
>> IT'S RARE TO SEE SOMETHING
LIKE THAT, THOUGH.
>> WE HAD AN AMAZING EXPERIENCE
MAKING THAT MOVIE.
IT WAS INCREDIBLE.
AND WE'RE BOTH SO GRATEFUL THAT
PEOPLE ARE LOVING THAT FILM AND
STILL DISCOVERING IT.
>> THEY ASK US IF WE'RE TOGETHER
ALL THE TIME.
>> WHAT HAPPENS TO SANDY AND
DANNY?
DO THEY LIVE HAPPILY EVER AFTER?
>> I THINK HE WAS A MECHANIC.
♪ CHROME METAL RODS, OH, YEAH
>> AND SANDY MIGHT HAVE BEEN A
BEAUTICIAN.
>> AND HAD LOTS OF KIDS?
>> A MANICURIST.
>> I WOULD HAVE HAD A GUT.
I WOULD STILL HAVE THE GREASER
HAIR.
>> YOU AGREED, I THINK, I
UNDERSTAND, TO PLAY A LITTLE
ROUND OF RAPID-FIRE HERE ON
"GMA."
>> SURE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> MY GUILTY PLEASURE IS, BLANK.
>> I DON'T HAVE ANY GUILT FOR MY
PLEASURES.
I LIKE CUPCAKES.
YOU KNOW?
ALL THE -- I DON'T HAVE ANY
GUILTY PLEASURES.
>> THAT'S TREMENDOUS.
CAN YOU TEACH ME HOW TO DO THAT?
>> YEAH.
CHOCOLATE, PROBABLY, YEAH.
>> GIRLS ALWAYS HAVE GUILTY
PLEASURES.
THERE'S NO WAY AROUND THAT.
PEOPLE MIGHT BE SURPRISED TO
LEARN I'M REALLY GOOD AT BLANK.
>> SCRABBLE.
I'M REALLY GOOD AT SCRABBLE.
WITHOUT THE HELP FROM --
>> YOU WANT TO PLAY?
>> YEAH.
I LOVE SCRABBLE.
>> YOU CAN DO IT ON THE WORD
GAMES.
>> I DO IT ALL THE TIME.
>> OH, GOSH.
>> I'LL KICK YOUR --
>> TENNIS.
>> VERY GOOD.
>> ME, TOO.
>> THE TOUGHEST PART ABOUT
GETTING OLDER IS BLANK?
>> NOT SLEEPING AS WELL.
>> GET UP AT 5:00 A.M.?
>> WELL, I GO TO BED AT 5:00
A.M.
BUT I DON'T STAY ASLEEP LONG
ENOUGH.
THAT'S PROBABLY THE TOUGHEST
PART.
>> OH, WOW.
I'M LIKING IT.
I'M LOVING IT.
I'M THE HAPPIEST I'VE BEEN.
>> AND YOU TWO HAVE ALWAYS JUST
BEEN FRIENDS, HUH?
>> YES.
>> WITH OVERTONES OF OTHER
THINGS.
>> WELL, IT IS A REMARKABLE
FRIENDSHIP TO WITNESS AND TO
SEE.
JOHN TRAVOLTA, OLIVIA
NEWTON-JOHN, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I LIKE IT.
>> OVERTONES.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
.
>>> GOOD MORNING I'M
KRISTEN SZE.
THE OPENING OF A GUN SHOP IN
LOS GATOS IS FACING CHALLENGES
BY SOME IN THE WAKE OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TRAGEDY
SOME RESIDENTS COMPLAIN THE
SHOP IS TOO CLOSE TO PARKS AND
SCHOOLS.
POLICE SAY THE STORE'S
SECURITY MEASURES GO BEYOND
FEDERAL LAW.
GUN SALES ACROSS THE NATION
ARE ON THE RISE.
BUYERS PURCHASE BEFORE
RESTRICTIONS ARE PASSED BY
CONGRESS.
>>> SUE CHECK ON THE MORNING
COMMUTE.
>>> A LITTLE DELAY FOR BART 5
TO 10 MINUTES EASTBOUND OUT OF
SAN FRANCISCO.
SOUTHBOUND 880 ALVARADO NILES
EARLIER ACCIDENT CLEARED.
VERY SLOW NORTHBOUND SOUTH OF
-- SOUGHT OUT OF HAYWARD
MOTORCYCLE DOWN PAST HESPERIAN
SLOW SOUTHBOUND 880.tm6F
SOUTHBOUND FREMONT TRUCK
SCALES, STALL.
>> MIKE WILL
>>> WELCOME BACK.
LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD, SHOWERS
OVER THE OCEAN WATERS WHERE
THEY WILL STAY FOR THE BETTER
PART OF THE DAY.
STILL IN THE 30s INLAND TO
REDWOOD CITY AND LOS GATOS
EVERYBODY ELSE LOW TO UPPER
40s ON OUR WAY TO LOW TO MID
50s.
EVEN WITH THE EXTRA SUNSHINE,
COOLER THAN QUESTIONED,
TONIGHT HARD FREEZE LIKELY
NORTH BAY, FROST FOR ALL OF
♪ JUST HEAR THOSE SLEIGH BELLS
RING ALING ♪
♪ IT'S LOVELY WEATHER
FOR A SLEIGH RIDE ♪
♪ TOGETHER WITH YOU
OUTSIDE THE SNOW IS FALLING ♪
♪ AND FRIENDS ARE CALLING
YOO-HOO ♪
♪ IT'S LOVELY WEATHER
FOR A SLEIGH RIDE TOGETHER WITH
YOU ♪
>>> HOW ABOUT THAT CHRISTMAS
MUSIC FROM KARMIN.
GREAT CROWD.
THE RAIN'S TRYING TO COME DOWN A
LITTLE BIT.
LITTLE SURPRISED.
>> I LIKE THAT.
>>> PLUS, COMING UP, WE HAVE
SOMETHING WE ALL NEED TO LISTEN
TO.
HOW TO PACK ON THE POUNDS, JOSH,
DURING CHRISTMAS.
>> HEY.
>> JUST KIDDING.
WHAT DO YOU DO TO TURN DOWN THE
TEMPTING OVERTURES?
>> OH, HELLO.
>> I THINK I --
>> OVERTURES.
>> GOOD MORNING.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HELP YOU KEEP
FROM PACKING ON THE POUNDS THIS
HOLIDAY SEASON.
SAM'S GOING TO BRING US THAT
STORY.
>> BECAUSE YOU NEVER LOOKED
BETTER.
>> IT'S TRUE.
>>> ALSO, COMING UP THIS
MORNING, IT'S OUR COUNTDOWN TO
CHRISTMAS.
12 DAYS OF COOKING.
WE HAVE CHEF DANIEL HUMM IN OUR
KITCHEN.
>> CAN'T BEAT IT.
>>> ALSO, FOR THE NEXT COUPLE OF
DAYS, WE'LL BE HAVING "GOOD
MORNING AMERICA'S" MEGAHOLIDAY
"DEALS AND STEALS."
MORE BARGAINS.
WE'LL HAVE SPECIAL DEALS.
SUP
SUPERSIZING SAVINGS.
WE'LL GET THEM ONLINE IN TIME
FOR CHRISTMAS.
>> THAT'S GOOD NEWS, BY THE WAY.
WE HAVE TO REMIND YOU THAT THESE
DEALS ARE ONLY AS SUPPLIES LAST.
IF YOU DON'T JUMP ON THE
WEBSITE, GOODMORNINGAMERICA.COM
ON YAHOO! YOU HAVE ONLY YOURSELF
TO BLAME.
THE CODES AND LINKS ARE RIGHT
THERE.
RIGHT, GEORGE?
>> NUMBER ONE.
>> TAKE BOTH OF YOU.
FIRST DEAL.
PERFUME MANIA.
I'M WAITING FOR THE SAM CHAMPION
FRAGRANCE.
>> I'M WORKING ON IT.
>> PERFUME MANIA HAS DOZENS OF
CELEBRITY FRAGRANCES TO CHOOSE
FROM.
THEY'RE REGULARLY $5 TO $70.
JOSHED BY 50%.
ALL UNDER $30.
AND $5 SHIPPING.
SARINA'S GOING TO LOVE THIS.
THIS IS FROM PVT.
THIS IS A LAPTOP DESK.
IT'S SOPHISTICATED FOR SARINA.
BUT ALSO AMAZING FOR THE COLLEGE
KIDS.
HUGE SELECTION FROM PB TEEN.
THEY'RE REGULARLY $60 TO $70.
SLASHED BY 50%.
$30 TO $35.
BUT FREE SHIPPING.
YOU HAVE TO DO IT TODAY.
>> GET ON, LOGON, GET IT DONE.
WE WANT TO THANK THE COMPANIES
IN ADVANCE FOR HELP SUPPORT ALL
OF YOU.
>> ANOTHER ONE TOMORROW.
>>> LET'S GET INSIDE TO
ELIZABETH.
>> NO, I'M RIGHT HERE.
>> NEXT DOOR TO ELIZABETH.
>> I'M JUST A FEW FEET AWAY,
SAM.
>> ELIZABETH?
>> NOW, TO A GIRL ON A MISSION.
SHE STARTED A CAMPAIGN TO
CONVINCE HASBRO, THE TOYMAKING
GIANT, TO RETHINK HOW IT MARKETS
ONE OF ITS MOST POPULAR TOYS.
ALL BECAUSE SHE WANTED TO GET
THE PERFECT CHRISTMAS PRESENT
FOR HER LITTLE BROTHER.
>> Reporter: McKENNA POPE DIDN'T
HAVE TO GO TO THE NORTH POLE.
SHE WENT TO YOUTUBE TO MAKE AN
APPEAL FOR HER 4-YEAR-OLD
BROTHER, GAVIN.
AND THE ONE THING HE WANTED FROM
SANTA.
>> I WANT AN EASY-BAKE OVEN.
>> Reporter: IT'S NOT THAT EASY.
THE CHER WAS HOPING FOR A COLOR
THAT WASN'T JUST FOR GIRLS.
BUT HASBRO MAKES THE EASY-BAKE
OVEN IN A PINK AND PURPLE FLORAL
PRINT.
THAT'S WHY HIS BIG SISTER WENT
TO BAT FOR HIM.
BY STIRRING THINGS UP WITH A
PETITION ON CHANGE.ORG, ASKING
HASBRO TO INCLUDE A MORE
GENDER-NEUTRAL COLOR AND INCLUDE
BOYS IN THE COMMERCIALS.
THE PETITION GOT 40,000
SIGNATURES.
SINCE THE '40s, THEY'VE COME IN
ALL SORTS OF COLORS.
AND ON MONDAY, WHEN HASBRO
WELCOMED McKENNA AND HER BROTHER
TO THE HEADQUARTERS, SHE GOT TO
SEE THEM ALL.
INCLUDING THE NEWEST MODEL, IN
BLACK AND SILVER.
>> YOU COULD SEE HIS EYES LIGHT
UP.
>> Reporter: HASBRO TOLD ABC
NEWS, THE COLOR CHANGE HAS BEEN
IN DEVELOPMENT OVER THE PAST 18
MONTHS.
AND WILL BECOME AVAILABLE IN THE
FALL OF 2013.
>> WHAT I HAD WANTED TO HAPPEN,
IT WAS ALL COMING TO FRUITION.
IT WAS JUST LIKE SO AMAZING.
>> SO, GAVIN WILL GET HIS
GENDER-NEUTRAL COLOR AFTER ALL.
>> I'M COOKING COOKIES.
>> Reporter: FOR "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA," LINSEY DAVIS, ABC
NEWS, NEW YORK.
>> FOR ALL OF THE BAKERS OUT
THERE, BOYS AND GIRLS.
HERE'S THE NEW ONE.
LET'S GO INSIDE.
YOU WANT ONE OF THESE?
>> I'M JUST LOOKING.
>>> LET'S GO IN TO LARA AND
LESLIE MANN.
>> INDEED.
LESLIE MANN IS BACK UP ON THE
BIG SCREEN, AS A WIFE AND MOM
FACING A BIG BIRTHDAY, IN THE
NEW COMEDY, "THIS IS 40."
IT IS A FAMILY AFFAIR, DIRECTED
BY HER HUSBAND, JUDD APATOW, AND
CO-STARRING THEIR REAL-LIFE
DAUGHTERS.
HERE TO TALK ABOUT HOW ART
IMITATES LIFE, IS THE LOVELY
LESLIE MANN.
>> HELLO.
>> WE FIRST MET YOUR CHARACTER
AND PAUL RUDD'S CHARACTERS IN
"KNOCKED UP."
HOW DID IT FEEL TO HAVE DEBBIE
BACK IN YOUR LIFE?
>> WELL, THAT WAS FIVE YEARS
AGO.
"KNOCKED UP."
AND IT'S BEEN FUN.
YOU KNOW?
WE HAD SUCH A GOOD TIME
TOGETHER.
IT WAS -- IT'S LIKE A BIG
FAMILY.
AND IT IS MY ACTUAL FAMILY.
BUT WORKING WITH PAUL, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE VERY CLOSE.
AND THE CREW.
YOU KNOW, WE USE A LOT OF THE
SAME CREW THAT WE USED FOR
YEARS.
AND SO, IT'S REALLY FUN.
AND WE HAVE A GREAT TIME WORKING
TOGETHER.
>> AND 40 MEANS A LOT OF
DIFFERENT THINGS TO EVERYBODY
WHO FACES IT.
WHAT DOES IT MEAN TO YOUR
CHARACTER AND TO THE MOVIE?
>> WELL, I THINK SHE'S IN THE
MIDDLE OF A LITTLE BIT OF A
NERVOUS BREAKDOWN.
AND SHE'S TRYING TO, YOU KNOW,
MAKE EVERYTHING BETTER.
BUT IN THE PROCESS OF TRYING TO
MAKE EVERYTHING BETTER,
EVERYTHING KIND OF FALLS APART.
AND THEN, IN THE END, IT GETS
BETTER AGAIN.
BUT IT'S AN INTERESTING TIME.
>> AND AT THE HANDS OF YOUR
HUSBAND, IT'S VERY, VERY FUNNY.
LET'S SHOW EVERYBODY A CLIP.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> YOU NEED TO GET OUTSIDE MORE.
DO SOME PLAYING OUTSIDE.
>> YEAH.
YOU CAN BUILD THINGS.
YOU CAN BUILD A FORT OUTSIDE.
>> WHAT?
>> YEAH, BUILD A FORT.
PLAY WITH YOUR FRIENDS.
>> MAKE A FORT OUTSIDE?
AND DO WHAT?
DO WHAT IN A FORT?
>> WHEN I WAS A KID, WE USED TO
BUILD TREE HOUSES AND PLAY WITH
STICKS.
>> NOBODY PLAYS WITH STICKS.
>> YOU CAN HAVE A LEMONADE
STAND.
>> PLAY KICK THE CAN.
>> LOOK FOR BED BODIES.
>> THAT'S FUN TO DO.
>> GET A TIRE AND RUN DOWN THE
STREET WITH IT.
>> IT'S 2012.
>> YOU DON'T NEED TECHNOLOGY.
>> NO TECHNOLOGY.
>> CHARLOTTE, PUT THAT DOWN.
>> SO FUNNY.
THOSE ARE YOUR REAL DAUGHTERS.
AND DAD WAS BOSS, JUDD APATOW.
DO THEY LISTEN TO HIM ON THE
SET?
>> THEY DON'T LISTEN TO HIM.
THEY DON'T.
HE THOUGHT THEY MIGHT BECAUSE
HE'S THE DIRECTOR.
BUT NO.
THEY COULD CARELE LESS WHAT HE S
TO SAY.
IF THEY GET TIRED, THEY JUST
TAKE NAPS.
THEY'RE AWFUL TO DEAL WITH.
BUT THEY'RE REALLY GOOD IN THE
MOVIE.
>> REALLY GOOD IN THE MOVIE.
IT IS SO VERY FUNNY.
LOOK FOR ONE OF THE FUNNIEST
SCENES FROM MELISSA McCARTHY ON
THE OUTTAKES.
>> SHE'S SO GREAT.
SHE'S HILARIOUS.
>> SO ARE YOU.
THE MOVIE IS "THIS IS 40."
IT'S IN THEATERS THIS FRIDAY.
SAM, WE NEED A DOUBLE-DATE TO GO
SEE IT AGAIN.
>>> LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT THE
WEATHER.
>> I'M IN.
MAYBE JOSH WILL GO.
HE TALKS THROUGH ALL THE MOVIES.
>> THAT'S -- TRUE.
IT'S GOING TO BE A GREAT MOVIE.
>> IT'S TIME TO UPDATE YOU WITH
A BRAND-NEW TALLY ON OUR WARM
COATS AND WARM HEARTS COAT
DRIVE.
DO WE HAVE THE MAGICAL DRUMROLL
THAT COMES FROM NOWHERE?
YES, WE DO.
AND THE TOTAL IS 69,684 COATS
FOR THOSE IN NEED.
WE CAN DO BETTER.
HELP US OUT.
>> WE WANT YOU TO SEND PICTURES
OF YOU DONATING, AS WELL.
THE #WARMCOATS.
>> LET'S GET TO THE BOARDS.
HERE ARE ONE OR TWO THINGS,
JOSH.
>> MAYBE THREE.
>> MAYBE THREE THINGS THAT YOU
MIGHT NEED TO KNOW.
HOLIDAY LIGHTS.
SEND US YOUR HOLIDAY LIGHTS.
WE CANNOT WAIT TO SEE THEM.
SEND THEM TO US.
BALTIMORE, A LITTLE SHOT OF SAN
ANTONIO, TEXAS.
A LOT OF THEM COMING IN TODAY.
AS THE MORNINGS GET CLOSE TO
CHRISTMAS, WE'LL PUT MORE ON
DURING THE MORNING.
TAKE A LOOK AT THE MILD AIR
THAT'S RUNNING ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
HELLO, OKLAHOMA CITY.
AND FOLLOWING BY THIS, SNOW.
THERE WILL BE BLIZZARD
CONDITIONS IN SOME PARTS OF THE
COUNTRY, AS THIS STORM REALLY
GETS ROLLING.
DENVER, YOU JUST GET KISSED ON
THE EDGE OF THIS.
>>> HOLIDAY SNACKS GOT YOU DOWN?
ARE YOU WORRIED YOU MIGHT PACK
ON A FEW POUNDS DURING THE FREE
FESTIVITIES AT THE TABLE OF
FOOD?
SO MANY OF US ARE WORRIED ABOUT
PACKING ON THE POUNDS.
BUT OUR "SECRETS TO LIVING
LONGER," OUR JENNIFER ASHTON HAS
THE SECRETS ON WHAT TO AVOID AND
WHAT TO GO FOR.
>> Reporter: IT'S TIME TO PARTY.
AND WHILE IT'S THE SEASON TO BE
JOLLY, IT DOESN'T MEAN YOU HAVE
TO GAIN WEIGHT, TOO.
I HAVE HOLIDAY TRADITIONS TO
KEEP FROM PACKING ON THE POUNDS.
FIRST, I WORKOUT FOR PEACE OF
MIND.
I DRINK LOTS OF WATER TO FILL UP
AND HYDRATE.
ONCE THE PARTY STARTS, I PLAN TO
ENJOY IT.
BUT IT TAKES MORE THAN THAT TO
MAKE GOOD CHOICES.
I INVITED NUTRITIONIST KERI
GLASSMAN TO GIVE MY GUESTS SOME
POINTERS TO BE HEALTHIER AT
THEIR HOLIDAY GATHERING.
>> I'M SO HAPPY THEY HAVE PIGS
IN A BLANKET AND CHEESE.
>> THERE'S OTHER HEALTHIER
OPTIONS.
WHAT IF YOU WENT FOR A COUPLE
SHRIMP?
>> Reporter: SHRIMP ARE LOWER IN
CALORIES, FAT AND SODIUM, MAKING
THEM A BETTER CHOICE OVER PIGS
IN A BLANKET.
>> I'M SO HAPPY THIS FRUITCAKE'S
HERE.
>> DR. ASHTON HAS A MUCH BETTER
OPTION OF FRUIT AND GINGERBREAD
COOKIES.
>> CAN I HAVE A TINY SLICE OF
IT?
>> GO FOR THE THREE BITES WITH
SOME FRUIT AND YOU'LL BE GREAT.
>> Reporter: YOU NEVER HAVE TO
COMPLETELY DEPRIVE YOURSELF,
ESPECIALLY IF YOU EAT WELL THE
OTHER 364 DAYS OF THE YEAR.
WHAT ABOUT THIS?
>> YOU CAN HAVE THAT.
TWO CUBES THERE AND VEGETABLES.
THAT WOULD BE GREAT.
>> I MEAN THE WHOLE THING.
>> Reporter: TWO CUBES OF CHEESE
AND A FEW RAW VEGGIES WILL TIDE
YOU OVER UNTIL DINNER.
GOOD FOOD, SMART CHOICES AND
CLOSE FRIENDS CAN GO A LONG WAY.
>> HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
>> GOOD LUCK.
>> PIGS IN A BLANKET.
I'M JUST SAYING.
SERVE THOSE.
LOTS OF THOSE.
>>> COMING UP, MASTER CHEF,
DANIEL HUMM IN THE KITCHEN.
COME BACK.
YOU DON'T WANT TO MISS THIS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> WE'RE COUNTING DOWN TO
CHRISTMAS.
12 DAYS OF COOKING.
DANIEL HUMM, CHEF AND OWNER OF
11 MADISON PARK.
EVERYBODY'S EATING.
>> I KNOW.
>> AUTHOR OF "11 MADISON PARK,"
THE COOKBOOK.
GREAT TO HAVE YOU BACK.
AND YOU'RE DOING SO WELL.
BRAND-NEW RESTAURANT.
IT IS FANTASTIC, AS WELL.
>> GOOD TO SEE YOU, GEORGE.
THANK YOU.
>> WHAT ARE WE DOING TODAY?
>> WE HAVE AN HERBED MUSHROOM
CRUST.
YOU CAN USE REGULAR BREAD.
>> YOU MADE THIS AROUND.
>> WE HAVE MUSHROOMS.
WE HAVE PARSLEY.
HERE, WE HAVE SOME SOFT BUTTER.
AND YOU KNOW, DURING THE
HOLIDAYS, IT'S REALLY CRAZY
TIME.
IT'S CRAZY AT HOME WITH KIDS AND
WIFE AND WORK AND JUGGLING
EVERYTHING.
I THINK IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT TO
BRING THE FAMILY TOGETHER.
>> THEY'RE ALREADY COMING
TOGETHER ON THE OTHER SIDE HERE.
>> THIS IS THE REALLY EASY
RECIPE.
WE HAVE THE CRUST.
WE HAVE SOME SHALLOTS.
AND BASICALLY, WE JUST PUT THIS
TOGETHER.
WE ROLL IT OUT.
BETWEEN TWO PARCHMENT PAPERS.
PUT THE PARCHMENT PAPER ON TOP.
WE HAVE A ROLLER HERE.
AND EVEN THE KIDS LOVE TO HELP
WITH THIS.
MAKE A MESS ALL OVER THE
KITCHEN.
>> I'LL BE THE KID FOR A SECOND.
YOU CAN MOVE ON.
THIS IS WHAT IT'S GOING TO LOOK
LIKE, RIGHT?
>> OVER HERE, WE HAVE A FINISHED
CRUST.
WE PUT IT ON TOP OF THE BEEF.
IT'S SIMPLE.
YOU CAN DO IT AHEAD OF TIME.
DO IT IN THE AFTERNOON.
PUT THIS IN THE OVEN.
IT TAKES LIKE 15 MINUTES TO
COOK.
IT'S VERY SIMPLE.
YOU KNOW, IT SEEMS LIKE MAYBE
EVERYTHING WE DO IS SO HARD.
BUT REALLY, COOKING IS VERY
SIMPLE.
A FEW INGREDIENTS.
HERE, WE HAVE A BEAUTIFUL
BUTTERNUT SQUASH CURRY.
>> ON SIDE?
OR ON TOP?
>> WE PUT IT ON THE PLATE.
>> IT TAKES 15 MINUTES TO COOK.
IT TAKES ABOUT THREE MINUTES TO
EAT.
>> THAT'S ALWAYS THE CASE.
>> OH, MY GOSH.
SO AMAZING.
>> WE HAVE A LITTLE CURRY.
AND YOU SEE HOW EASY THIS IS.
AND IT LOOKS -- THIS IS A BEEF
SAUCE.
JUST A BEEF SAUCE THAT WE MADE,
FROM THE RESTAURANT.
AT HOME, YOU CAN USE, YOU KNOW,
SOME BEEF TRIMMINGS, VEGETABLES,
RED WINE, REDUCE IT.
>> BEAUTIFUL.
>> FRESH HERBS.
>> I HOPE THERE'S TEN MORE.
>> AND TELL US ABOUT THE SALAD,
QUICKLY, BEFORE YOU GO.
>> WE HAVE A QUICK SALAD.
RADICCHIO SALAD.
SOME MANGO, BASIL, MOZZARELLA.
>> THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
THE CRUNCHY SALT AND THE PEPPER.
IT GIVES A LITTLE --
>> YOU HAD YOUR LUNCH EARLY.
>> YOU CAN EAT.
>> FIND ALL OF THE RECIPES AT
GOODMORNINGAMERICA.COM ON YAHOO!
>
>> IF YOU DON'T FEEL LIKE
COOKING, COME SEE US AT THE
RESTAURANT.
>> OR DO THAT.
>>> BACK, NOW, WITH KARMIN.
YOUTUBE SENSATIONS, AMY
HEIDEMANN, JAKE NOONAN.
TO DO "SLEIGH RIDE."
IT SOUNDED GREAT IN SOUND CHECK.
BUT THAT'S ALL PROLOGUE.
HERE WE GO.
"SLEIGH RIDE."
>> "GMA," HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
♪ JUST HEAR THOSE
SLEIGH BELLS JINGLING ♪
♪ RING-TING-TINGLING TOO
♪ COME ON, IT'S LOVELY
WEATHER FOR A SLEIGH RIDE ♪
♪ TOGETHER WITH YOU
♪ OUTSIDE, THE SNOW IS
FALLING AND FRIENDS ARE ♪
♪ CALLING "YOO-HOO"
♪ COME ON, IT'S LOVELY
WEATHER FOR A SLEIGH RIDE ♪
♪ TOGETHER WITH YOU
♪ GIDDY-YAP GIDDY-YAP
GIDDY-YAP LET'S GO ♪
♪ OUR CHEEKS ARE NICE AND ROSY
AND COMFY COZY ARE WE ♪
♪ WE'RE SNUGGLED UP TOGETHER
LIKE BIRDS ♪
♪ OF A FEATHER WOULD BE
♪ LET'S TAKE THE ROAD
BEFORE US AND SING ♪
♪ A CHORUS OR TWO
♪ COME ON, IT'S
LOVELY WEATHER FOR ♪
♪ A SLEIGH RIDE TOGETHER
WITH YOU ♪
♪ GIDDY-YAP GIDDY-YAP
GIDDY-YAP ♪
GIDDY-YAP LET'S GO ♪
♪ LET'S LOOK AT THE SNOW
WE'RE RIDING IN ♪
♪ A WONDERLAND OF SNOW
GIDDY-YAP GIDDY-YAP ♪
♪ GIDDY-YAP IT'S GRAND
JUST HOLDING YOUR HAND ♪
♪ WE'RE RIDING ALONG
WITH THE SONG ♪
♪ OF A WINTERY FAIRY LAND
♪ JUST HEAR THOSE
SLEIGH BELLS JINGLING ♪
♪ RING-TING-TINGLING TOO
♪ COME ON, IT'S LOVELY
WEATHER FOR A SLEIGH RIDE ♪
♪ TOGETHER WITH YOU
♪ OUTSIDE, THE SNOW IS
FALLING AND FRIENDS ARE ♪
♪ CALLING "YOO-HOO"
♪ COME ON, IT'S LOVELY
WEATHER FOR A SLEIGH RIDE ♪
♪ TOGETHER WITH YOU
♪ YEAH
♪ DING DONG
WE POP IT HARD ♪
♪ JUST LIKE BEFORE
POINSETTIA IN THE CAR ♪
♪ GINGERBREAD TOO
♪ AND WITH THE ICE SO COLD
YOU ARE GOING IN THE SNOW ♪
♪ I NEED THE FIREPLACE HOT
UNTIL I GET MY EGGNOG ♪
♪ CATCH ME CANDY CANE CRUNCHING
COME ON ♪
♪ OUR CHEEKS ARE NICE AND ROSY
AND COMFY COZY ARE WE ♪
♪ WE'RE SNUGGLED UP TOGETHER
LIKE BIRDS ♪
♪ OF A FEATHER WOULD BE
♪ LET'S TAKE THE ROAD
BEFORE US AND SING ♪
♪ A CHORUS OR TWO
♪ COME ON, IT'S
LOVELY WEATHER FOR ♪
♪ A SLEIGH RIDE TOGETHER
WITH YOU ♪
>>> THANK YOU TO KARMIN.
WHAT A GREAT GIFT.
SEE YOU GUYS TOMORROW.
>>> GOOD MORNING I'M
KRISTEN SZE.
METEOROLOGIST MIKE NICCO
CHECKS IN ON YOUR CHILLY
FORECAST.
>>> ON OUR WAY TO 50s THIS
AFTERNOON PARTLY CLOUDY,
SHOWERS ALONG THE COAST LIVE
DOPPLER THAT'S WHERE THEY STAY
AS THEY FLY OUT EAST MORE SUN
TODAY NOT AS WARM AS YESTERDAY
WATCH OUT TONIGHT HARD FREEZE
IN THE NORTH BAY VALLEYS FROST
FOR THE REST OF US EXCEPT
BEACHES AND THEN RAIN COMES
THURSDAY THROUGH THE WEEKEND.
>>> A GRIND 80 WESTBOUND WELL
BEFORE THE 580 MERGE TOWARDS
THE MacMARK AND
BUMPER-TO-BUMPER AT THE --
MacARTHUR MAZE AND
BUMPER-TO-BUMPER AT THE BAY
BRIDGE TOLL.
MOTORCYCLE DOWN HESPERIAN AND
FREMONT TRUCK SCALES SOUTH 880
EARLIER ACCIDENT CLEARING SLOW
FROM 92
ANNOUNCER: IT'S "LIVE! WITH
KELLY & MICHAEL."
TODAY, FROM THE NEW FILM, "THE
GUILTY TRIP," SETH ROGEN.
AND OUR COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS
WEEK CONTINUES WITH A
PERFORMANCE FROM THE BROADWAY
HIT MUSICAL, "ANNIE."
PLUS YOUR COMMENTS AND QUESTIONS
ON ANOTHER EPISODE OF KELLY AND
MICHAEL'S "INBOX."
ALL NEXT ON THE EMMY
AWARD-WINNING "LIVE."
NOW, HERE RIPA AND ARE KELLY RID