>> Terry: INDIVIDUAL I 0 THE
PHONE IS CONTINUING TO HEAR WHAT
YOU BELIEVE TO BE ....
>> ATTACK ON AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> MOST OF THE BULLETS AIMED AT
LITTLE CHILDREN.
>> WE HEARD THIS RACKET.
>> AND THEN CHAOS AND CONFUSION
AS YOUNG SURVIVORS WERE LED OUT
OF THE SCHOOL.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE THAT
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN,
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF FIVE AND TEN YEARS
OLD.
>> Dan: GOOD EVENING.
I'M DAN ASHLEY.
>> Ama: I'M AMA DAETZ.
A LOSS UNIMAGINABLE SCALE.
>> A MAN STARTED SHOOTING WITH
CHILLING AGO.
>> WAS THERE ARE 27 VICTIMS, 20
OF THEM CHILDREN AND 7 ADULTS.
WE HAVE TEAM COVERAGE BEGINNING
IN CONNECTICUT.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> Reporter: A QUAINT NEW
ENGLAND SUBURB.
>> I'M TERRIFIED.
>> BECAME A SCENE OF HORROR.
A GUNMAN IDENTIFIED AS ADAM
LANZA BARGED INTO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND BEGIN
SHOOTING.
>> COMPLETE CHAOS.
>> TEACHERS RUSHED TO SHEPPARD
THE YUCK CHILDREN TO SAFETY.
THEY WERE TOLD TO CLOSE THEIR
EYES ON THE WAY OUT.
>> WE ALL PUT OUR HANDS ON OTHER
PEOPLE'S SHOURDZ AND TEACHER LED
THE FIRST PERSON'S HAND AND LEAD
US OUT.
>> ONE SPOKE EXCLUSIVELY TO
DIANE SAWYER.
>> I NEED TO KNOW I LOVE YOU ALL
VERY MUCH.
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY BECAUSE
THAT WAS THE LAST THING I WOULD
HAVE HEAR.
>> ALL EINTS THE INDIVIDUAL I
HAVE ON THE PHONE CONTINUES TO
BELIEVE WHAT HE HEARS IS
GUNFIRE.
>> A SMALL ARM SWARMED THE
SCHOOL BUT NOT BEFORE THE GUNMAN
TOOK HIS TOLL.
>> ALL AFTERNOON DESPERATE
PARENTS CONVERGED.
SOME TOOK THEIR CHILDREN AWAY
AND OTHERS WENT AWAY WITH
UNIMAGINABLE GRIEF THE VICTIMS
WERE REMEMBERED AT A CANDLELIGHT
VIGIL IN NEWTOWN.
SIMILAR PRAYER SERVICES ARE
GOING ON ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
WITH PEOPLE PAYING THEIR
RESPECTS TO THE FALLEN WHAT IS A
TRUE NATIONAL TRAGEDY.
>> Dan: TONIGHT WE ARE LEARNING
MORE ABOUT HIM.
HE WAS AN HONOR STUDENT IN HIGH
SCHOOL.
HE DID NOT APPEAR IN HIS HIGH
SCHOOL YEAR BOOK.
HIS PARENTS DIVORCED.
HIS FATHER IS VICE PRESIDENT OF
GEY CAPITAL AND REMARRIED.
BOTH HAD LEGALLY WEAPONS.
>> LANZA TOLD OFFICERS HE HAD
NOT SEEN HIS BROTHER IN YEARS
AND NOT BEEN IN CLOSE CONTACT
WITH HIM.
POLICE STRESS THAT HE IS NOT A
SWHEENGD COOPERATING FULLY WITH
THE INVESTIGATION.
>> HUNDREDS PACKED THE CATHOLIC
CHURCH TO REMEMBER THE VICTIMS
OF THE SHOOTING.
THE CHURCH WAS FILLED TO
CAPACITY AND HUNDREDS MORE STOOD
OUTSIDE TO PRAY AND MOURN.
VIGILS HAVE POPPED UP ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY INCLUDING THIS ONE
IN MILL VALLEY WHERE 20 PEOPLE
TURNED OUT TO REMEMBER THE
VICTIMS.
SERGIO QUINTANA IS LIVE IN
WALNUT CREEK WHERE ANOTHER VIGIL
WAS HELD TONIGHT.
>> Reporter: ABOUT 24 PEOPLE
TURNED OUT FOR THIS VIGIL ON THE
FRONT STEPS OF WALNUT CREEK CITY
HALL.
THEY LEFT BEHIND A CARD AND
CANDLE, FLOWERS TO HONOR THOSE
WHO WERE KILLED IN CONNECTICUT
AND HIMSELF THEY CAME TOGETHER
TO SHARE IN SOME COMFORTABLE IN
THE FACE OF SUCH TRAGEDY.
>> THIS CANDLELIGHT VIGIL LIKE
SO MANY ACROSS THE COUNTRY CAME
TOGETHER WITHIN JUST A FEW
HOURS.
ORGANIZER ASHLEY MONTGOMERY WAS
COMPELLED TO DO SOMETHING AFTER
WATCHING NEWS REPORTS.
>> SOMETHING LIKE THIS, OUR
HEARTS ARE BROKEN BUT WE GATHER
HERE LIKE THIS IT SHOWS OUR
SPIRIT IS NOT BROKEN.
>> AMONG THOSE WERE ELEMENTARY
AGED STUDENTS.
>> DID YOU HEAR IT THROUGH
FRIENDS OR DID YOU HEAR IT ON
THE PHONE?
>> I HEARD IT FROM MY MOM.
>> HIS MOTHER TELLS ME SHE HAD A
CONVERSATION WITH HIM ABOUT THE
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT WHEN SHE
PICKED HIM UP FROM SCHOOL.
>> I THOUGHT IT WAS IMPORTANT TO
KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
USUALLY I TRY TO SHIELD THEM
FROM EVENTS BUT I THINK IT WAS
TOO CLOSE.
>> ANOTHER MOTHER ALSO TALKED
WITH HER KIDS AND HOPES TO
UNDERSTAND WHAT FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> I CAN ONLY IMAGINE BEING THE
PARENT GOING TO SCHOOL HOPING
THAT IT WASN'T MY CHILD IN THAT
CLASSROOM.
AT THE SAME TIME IF IT WASN'T,
THEN YOU ARE HORRIFIED BY THE
FACT THAT IT WAS MY DAUGHTER'S
BEST FRIEND.
>> THE HEAD MASTER OF AN
INDEPENDENT SCHOOL IN WALNUT
CREEK, THE DAY WAS DIFFICULT FOR
HIS STAFF AS NEW DETAILS WERE
LEARNED ABOUT THE SHOOTING.
>> I TALKED TO THEM TODAY AND
SAID, THESE WERE OUR CHILDREN.
THESE WERE OUR STUDENTS.
THESE WERE ALL MY TEACHERS AND
THESE ARE OUR COLLEAGUES.
>> AMONG THE PARENTS, CHILDREN
AND EDUCATORS WHO WERE PART OF
THIS GROUP, THERE WERE PEOPLE
WHO DID NOT HAVE ANY CHILDREN
BUT THEY STILL WANTED TO COME
OUT AND SHOW THEIR SUPPORT.
SERGIO QUINTANA, "ABC 7 NEWS."
>> VERY TOUCHING TO SEE SO MANY
PEOPLE COME OUT.
TODAY'S SHOOTING IS EMOTIONAL
PARTICULARLY FOR PARENTS.
MANY OF US WONDERING HOW TO TALK
WITH OUR CHILDREN ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
WHAT DO WE SAY WHAT WORDS DO WE
USE.
DEAN OF SCHOOL EDUCATION AT
SANTA CLARA UNIVERSITY GAVE US
SOME ADVICE.
FIRST CONFRONT YOUR OWN FEELINGS
WHETHER THOSE INCLUDE FEAR,
ANGER OR ANXIETY AND THEN SPEAK
TO YOUR CHILD CALMLY AND LISTEN
INTENTLY.
THE TIME TO DO THAT IS NOW
BEFORE THEY SEE IT SOMEWHERE
ELSE.
>> I WOULD TALK TO TODAY.
I DON'T THINK IT'S WORTH WAITING
UNTIL THE END OF THE WEEKEND.
THE MOMENT IS NOW.
THE EXPERIENCING THIS.
THEY HAVE TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
DOES THIS REALLY MEAN WHEN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS THIS KIND
OF TRAGEDY.
>> Dan: THE DOCTOR SAYS YOU
SHOULD REASSURE YOUR KIDS THAT
THEY ARE SAFE IN SCHOOL AND DO
SO BEFORE THEY GO BACK TO CLASS
ON MONDAY BECAUSE THEY WILL BE
ANXIOUS.
>> AS WORD OF THE SHOOTING
TRAGEDY SPREAD ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, SCHOOL DISTRICTS ACROSS
THE BAY AREA LOOKED AT THE
SAFETY OF THEIR OWN STUDENTS.
ALAN WANG JOINS US LIVE FROM THE
NEWSROOM WITH MORE.
>> SCHOOL OFFICIALS ACROSS THE
BAY AREA THEY WERE FIELDING
CALLS FROM PARENTS AND EVEN A
FEW WHO TOOK THEIR KIDS HOME.
ALMOST EVERY SCHOOL DISTRICT
SENT A LETTER HOME.
EACH ONE WRITTEN TO REASSURE
PARENTS THEIR CHILDREN ARE SAFE
AT SCHOOL.
>> AS NEWS OF THE TRAGEDY SPREAD
SO DID A SENSE OF INSECURITY IN
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE BAY AREA.
>> IT REMINDED ME TO APPRECIATE
WHAT I HAVE.
>> IN OAKLAND, CITY POLICE
OFFICERS WERE AVAILABLE FOR ANY
SCHOOL TO OFFER SAFETY ADVICE
AND SENSE OF REASSURANCE.
>> THEY ARE NOT EVEN ADULTS YET
AND THEY ARE KILLING LITTLE
KIDS.
>> IN UNION CITY THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT WILL HAVE THE FIRST
EVER ACTIVE SCHOOL DRILL NEXT
MARCH AND OFFICIALS ARE KEENLY
AWARE OF HOW THE TRAGEDY MIGHT
AFFECT YOUNGER STUDENTS.
>> WITH YOUNGER CHILDREN, IT'S
LIKE AN EARTHQUAKE DRILL
MANEUVER YOU ARE REASSURING THE
CHILDREN AND MOVING THE CHILDREN
AROUND.
>> DISTRICT PSYCHOLOGISTS WERE
COACHING FACULTY MEMBERS IN HOW
TO SEE DISTRESS IN KIDS.
>> LET THEM KNOW EVERY ONCE IN A
WHILE IT HAPPENS BUT RARELY
HAPPENS AND THERE ARE ADULTS
THEY CAN GO TO.
>> IN SAN FRANCISCO IT WAS GUT
CHECK TIME.
SCHOOL OFFICIALS WERE
REEXAMINING SAFETY PLANS SINCE
THE COLUMBINE MASSACRE.
SINCE THEN, THEIR TACTICS HAVE
CHANGED.
>> WE TAKE IMMEDIATE ACTION.
WE KNOW THAT LIES ARE AT STAKE
AND IF THERE IS AN IMMEDIATE
SHOOTING, OUR OFFICERS GATHER
AND ENGAGE.
>> OVERALL THERE WAS VERY LITTLE
PANIC AT LOCAL SCHOOLS BUT
DEFINITELY A SOLEMN NEWS THAT
MADE PARENTS WANT TO BE CLOSER
TO THEIR CHILDREN TODAY.
>>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> THERE IS A VIGIL OF ONE IN
SAN JOSE WE WANT TO SHARE WITH
YOU.
REMARKABLE PICTURE, THE MOTHER
SHARED THIS PHOTO.
THE LITTLE GIRL LIGHTING A
CANDLE.
SOME JUST HIS CHANGE.
SAN JOSE LOVES CONNECTICUT.
THAT IS SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> WE HAVE A LOT MORE AS THE
TRAGEDY UNFOLDS.
STAY WITH US FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE.
RECEIVE URGENT UPDATES BY
DOWNLOADING OUR FREE NEWS APP
AND OPTING FOR A PUSH
NOTIFICATION.
FIND THE LATEST AT ABC7NEWS.COM
AND UPDATING OUR FACEBOOK PAGE
AND ALSO ON TWITTER.
>> WE'RE GOING TO MOVE ON.
THERE ARE SOME CHANGES IN OUR
WEATHER AS WE HIT THE WEEKEND.
METEOROLOGIST SANDHYA PATEL IS
HERE WITH THE LATEST ON THE
FORECAST.
>> THE RAIN WE HAD TODAY IS LONG
GO GONE BUT MORE RAIN COMING IN.
LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD, SHOWS YOU
WHAT IT IS LOOK LIKE, SKIES ARE
CLEARING OUT OTHER THAN A FEW
CLOUDS.
TEMPERATURES ARE FALLING, SO
LOOKS AT THESE TEMPERATURES,
ALREADY DOWN TO FREEZING IN
FAIRFIELD.
35 IN NAPA.
SANTA ROSA AND LIVERMORE GOING
DOWN.
38 IN CONCORD.
IT IS GOING TO BE A COLD START
FOR YOUR WEEKEND.
I'LL BE BACK WITH THE LOWS AND
PARTIAL LOOK WHEN THE NEXT
SYSTEM WILL BRING US RAIN OVER
THE WEEKEND.
>> Dan: THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> UP NEXT, NEW CALLS FOR GUN
CONTROL AS PEOPLE STRUGGLE WITH
THE STRATEGY IN CONNECTICUT.
THEY ARE THINKING ABOUT HOW TO
KEEP IT FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
>> STAY WITH US, OUR COVERAGE OF
THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT IN A MOMENT.
>>> GUN CONTROL IS ONCE AGAIN
BEING DID HE BAITED AFTER THE
TRAGIC SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> PLEASE LAY OUT A PLAN OF
ACTION HOW WE MAY ADDRESS THIS
SEWAGE OF GUN VIOLENCE IN OUR
COMMUNITY.
>> THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN GAVE RISE TO
ANTI-GUN RALLY.
THEY ARE CALLING ON CONGRESS TO
FURTHER RESTRICT ACCESS TO
FIREARMS IN RESPONSE TO TODAY'S
TRAGEDY.
IN CALIFORNIA WE HAVE THE
STRONGEST GUN LAWS IN THE
COUNTRY AS RANKED BY THE BRADY
CAMPAIGN.
>> CALIFORNIA HAS THE LOWEST
MORTALITY RATE IN THE NATION
FROM FIREARMS.
>> THEY ARE CONSIDERING
REINTRODUCING A BILL.
MOST RECENT POLLS SHOW AMERICANS
IN GENERAL ARE IN FAVOR OF MORE
RESTRICTIONS, GUN STORE OWNER
SAYS THE CURRENT LAWS ARE JUST
FINE.
>> ISOLATED INCIDENTS, IT'S
TRAGIC BUT WE CAN'T KNEE-JERK
AND THINK THAT IS GOING TO SOLVE
THE PROBLEM BECAUSE IT'S NOT.
IF PEOPLE WANT TO DO SOMETHING
BAD THEY WILL FIGURE OUT A WAY
TO DO IT.
>> SOME OTHERS FEEL SOMETHING
NEEDS TO CHANGE.
>> WATCHING THE GUN VIOLENCE IN
OUR SOCIETY, I CAN'T STAND BY
AND WATCH THAT.
>> MARSHALL GREW UP WITH GUNS.
HE ATTENDED AT A VIGIL TO
REMEMBER THE LIVES LOST IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> YOU NEED TO LOOK IN THE
MIRROR AND TAKE A LOOK AT
OURSELVES, REALIZING CHANGE A
FEW THINGS HOW WE DEAL WITH GUNS
AND WAY WE ISSUE THEM AND HOW WE
ENCOURAGE VIOLENCE IN SOCIETY.
>> WE HAVEN'T HEARD FROM GUN
ADVOCACY GROUPS BUT THE
ORGANIZATION'S FACEBOOK PAGE HAS
BEEN UNAVAILABLE FOR MOST OF THE
DAY.
>> TOMORROW'S RED CARPET
PREMIERE OF TOM CRUISE ACTION
MOVIE HAS BEEN POSTPONED.
THEY SAY THE MOVE IS OUT OF
RESPECT FOR THE FAMILIES OF THE
CONNECTICUT VICTIMS.
A SPECIAL ONE HOUR EDITION OF
"NIGHTLINE" WITH CONTINUING
COVERAGE OF THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
THAT IS "NIGHTLINE" STARTING IN
A FEW MINUTES AT 11:35.
>> AN OFF-DUTY OFFICER WAS
KILLED IN A HEAD ON ACCIDENT ON
HIGHWAY 12.
AUTHORITIES SAY AN OFFICER ON
HIS PERSONAL MOTORCYCLE HIT A
PICKUP TURNING LEFT IN FRONT OF
HIM.
THE OFFICER WAS THROWN AND THEN
HIT BY A HONDA.
THE UNIDENTIFIED OFFICER WAS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE.
>>> MEANTIME, AN 82-YEAR-OLD
GRIEV DRIVER IS FAY GO FELONY
CHARGES AFTER A TERRIFYING AND
DEADLY CRASH IN SAN MATEO
COUNTY.
THREE PEOPLE WERE KILLED.
NICK SMITH EXPLAINS WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> SKY7HD WAS OVER THE SCENE
MINUTES AFTER A CRASH AT I-280
AT EDGEWOOD ROAD.
THE DRIVER OF THIS LEXUS HAD
PULLED IN NEXT TO THE MEDIAN TO
FIX A FLAT TIRE.
IT WAS THEN THE BLACK CAR
SWERVED AND CRASHED INTO THE
LEXUS.
>> THERE WERE FOUR PEOPLE TOTAL.
THREE OF THE PEOPLE WERE
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE.
>> KILLED AT THE SCENE
40-YEAR-OLD WOMAN AND
28-YEAR-OLD MAN AND ANOTHER
20-YEAR-OLD WOMAN.
>> IT LOOKS LIKE SPEED WAS A
FACTOR.
>> WE HAVE LEARNED THAT THE
DRIVER OF THE BLACK CAR IS AN
82-YEAR-OLD MAN FROM THE BAY
AREA.
HE WAS TAKEN TO STANFORD MEDICAL
CENTER FOR NON LIFE-THREATENING
INJURIES.
ONCE HE IS RELEASED HE WILL FACE
FELONY CHARGES OF VEHICULAR
MANSLAUGHTER.
LATE AFTERNOON CRASH CAUSED A
BACK-UP FOR MILES.
>> INVESTIGATORS SAY NEITHER
ALCOHOL OR DRUGS APPEAR TO BE
FACTOR TOR.
ALONG I-280 NICK SMITH.
>> SANDHYA PATEL IS HERE WITH A
LOOKAT THE FORECAST.
>> WINTER IS WEEK AWAY FROM
TODAY BUT WE ARE FEELING THE
CHILL OUTSIDE.
AS YOU LOOK OUT LIVE DOPPLER
RADAR, SKIES ARE CLEARING OUT.
COLD OVERNIGHT AND CHILLY WITH
LIGHT AFTERNOON RAIN AND CHANCE
OF SHOWERS IN THE NORTH BAY ON
SUNDAY.
SO NOT A COMPLETE WASHOUT JOUT
FOR THE WEEKEND.
I WOULDN'T CANCEL ANY OF YOUR
ARE PLANS.
HERE IS THE SYSTEM THAT BROUGHT
US RAIN TODAY.
SOME PICKED UP LIGHT RAIN AND
RAINFALL TOTALS LOCALLY A FEW
HUNDREDTHS OF AN INCH.
AT MOST THERE WAS A TENTH OF AN
INCH REPORTED IN PACIFICA.
THE SYSTEMS ARE COMING OUT OF
THE NORTH.
DON'T HOLD AS MUCH MOISTURE AS
THE ONES COME OUT OF THE SOUTH
OR SOUTHWEST.
SO TOMORROW MORNING, 8:00 IF YOU
HAVE PLANS, BUNDLE UP.
WE'LL SEE HIGH CLOUDS AHEAD OF
THE STORM AND BY NOONTIME, RAIN
ARRIVES.
IT WILL BE LIGHT TO MODERATE
SPREADING ACROSS THE ENTIRE BAY
AREA.
WE MAY SEE SNOW AS THE SNOW
LEVELS WILL BE COMING DOWN TO
4,000 FEET.
THIS IS LAKE COUNTY AREA.
THE RAIN WILL PRETTY MUCH TAPER
TO SHOWERS LATE AFTERNOON AND
THEN SUNDAY, IT'S MOSTLY A LIGHT
SHOWER CHANCE FOR THE NORTH BAY.
SUNDAY IS ACTUALLY LOOKING FINE
IN TERMS OF RAINFALL.
TEMPERATURES CHILLY AS I
MENTIONED.
I LOWERED THESE, 30 DEGREES IN
FAIRFIELD BY MORNING.
31 IN LIVERMORE.
CONCORD, VALLEJO MID 30s AND 31
IN SANTA ROSA.
GOING TO BE COLD IN SAN JOSE, 37
DEGREES.
MAKE SURE YOU HAVE A JACKED OR A
SWEATER OR COAT.
AFTER THIS WE ARE LOOKING AT
STILL CHILLY CONDITIONS FOR YOUR
SATURDAY AFTERNOON.
IT'S GOING TO BE IN THE UPPER
40s TO LOW 50s.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO GET A CHANCE
TO WARM UP YET.
SNOW IS POSSIBLE IN THE
MOUNTAINS AROUND CLEARLAKE AND
SIERRA.
MONTEREY BAY IS GOING TO BE
HIGHS, UPPER 40s TO LOW 50s.
MUCH LIKE TODAY THE CHILL IS IN
THE AIR FOR SATURDAY.
CHANCE OF A FEW SHOWERS SUNDAY
MORNING, MAINLY NORTH BAY.
RAIN AGAIN ON MONDAY GOING INTO
EARLY TUESDAY.
THAT IS MILDER STORM.
WE'LL BRING YOU A DRY DAY ON
WEDNESDAY AND NOW COMPUTER
MODELS WANT TO BRING A CHANCE OF
RAIN GOING INTO FRIDAY.
BUT THE OVERALL PATTERN FOR THE
WEEKEND NOT SO BAD.
A LITTLE BIT OF THIS AND A
LITTLE BIT OF THAT.
>> WARRIORS ON ROAD AND THEY
HAVE BEEN ON A ROLL.
>> PAST TENSE NOW.
WE ARE TRYING TO KEEP THEIR WIN
STREAK AND NEW SET IN THE RAIN
IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
HARD TO HANDLE.
>>> J.J. REDDICK TO END THE
THIRD QUARTER.
HE HAD 16.
MAGIC UP 17.
DAVID LEE PLAYING OUT OF HIS
MIND.
ALL-STAR CALIBER.
HAD 24 POINTS, 15 BOARDS BUT THE
WARRIORS NEVER GOT CLOSER TO 9.
NELSON, YOU GOT TO GUARD HIM!
THEY ARE CLOSING OUT A LONG
EXTENDED TRIP TOMORROW.
>> KOBE BRYANT BEHIND THE BACK
TO DWIGHT HOWARD.
HE HAD 12 POINTS IN THIS GAME.
WIZARD FANS HAVE HAD NOT MUCH TO
CHEER FOR IN ABOUT 20 YEARS.
MARCEL WEBSTER BUT KOBE FINISHED
WITH 30.
FUNDAMENTALLY SOUND.
YOU ARE GOING TO BOX KOBE, I
KNOW YOU ARE GOING TO MIX.
LAKERS STOP THE SKID 102-THE 6
BUT THEIR RECORD 10-14.
>> DE LaSALLE WILL FACE THEIR
OPPONENTS IN CARSON.
THIS COULD BE THE FINAL GAME AS
HEAD COACH FOR BOB LADASAUR WHO
IS CONSIDERING RETIREMENT.
>> I WANTED TO BE A HIGH SCHOOL
TEACHER.
I WANTED TO BE AT THIS SCHOOL.
THAT IS WHEN I WAS 24 YEARS OLD.
IT NEVER CHANGED.
IT'S BEEN VERY REWARDING AND
BEEN A VERY GOOD CAREER.
I HAVE NO REGRETS WHATSOEVER.
>> A HUGE UPSET IN THE DIVISION
ONE CHAMPIONSHIP TONIGHT.
SACRAMENTO, FACING LONG BEACH
AND POLY IS PICKED OFF BY HIM
TAKES IT INTO THE TOUCHDOWN.
IT'S TIED AT 14.
HE FIGHTS HIS WAY TO THE END
ZONE.
HE MISSED THE EXTRA POINT SO
THEY WERE UP ONLY BY 6.
THEY ANSWER WITH JOHN COOLY.
THEY MADE THE EXTRA POINT.
THAT WAS THE DIFFERENCE.
GRANITE RANKED 92nd THE NATION
DEFEATS TEAM THAT RATED 12th AND
WAS HEAVY FAVORITE, 21-20 WAS
THE FINAL.
THAT WAS A THRILLER.
ABC7 SPORTS BROUGHT TO YOU BY
RIVER ROCK CASINO.
GRANITE CAME IN 1-3 AND WENT ON
A MASSIVE WINNING STREAK.
>> WHEN WE
>>> HERE IS THE LATEST IN
TODAY'S SHOOTING.
SHOOTING IS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA A MAN FORMER CLASSMATES
DESCRIBE AS INTROVERTED.
27 PEOPLE WERE KILLED INCLUDING
THE GUNMAN'S MOTHER.
AUTHORITIES WILL LIKELY RELEASE
NAMES TOMORROW MORNING.
ONE PERSON WAS INJURED.
HE SHOT AND KILLED HIMSELF AT
THE SCHOOL AND WE ARE TOLD HE
HAD THREE WEAPONS, ALL LEGALLY
PURCHASED BY A FAMILY MEMBER.
>> OUR COVERAGE OF SCHOOL
TRAGEDY CONTINUES TOMORROW
MORNING AT 4:00 A.M. WITH A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA."
WE'LL HAVE BAY AREA REACTION
FOLLOWED BY ANOTHER HOUR OF
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA" AT 7:00
AND THEN THE MORNING NEWS AT
8:00.
>> WE'LL STAY ON TOP OF THIS.
>> IT'S GOING TO BE A CHILLY
START ESPECIALLY INLAND.
LOW 30s TO MID 40s.
PARTLY CLOUDY BY 8:00 A.M.
MID 30s TO 40s, RAIN COMING IN
BY THE AFTERNOON.
>> Dan: THANKS VERY MUCH.
THAT IS OUR REPORT.
"NIGHTLINE" IS NEXT.
>>> TONIGHT ON A SPECIAL EDITION
OF "NIGHTLINE," CLASSROOM
TRAGEDY.
AT LEAST 20 YOUNG CHILDREN AND
SIX ADULTS SHOT AND KILLED
INSIDE A CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
THE WORST SHOOTING OF ITS KIND
IN HISTORY.
WE'RE EEG ON THE GROUND WITH
PARENTS, STUDENTS AND TEACHERS,
AS A TOWN AND A NATION GRIEVES.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN,
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.