>> FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN,
LET US FIND THE STRENGTH TO
CARRY ON.
KATIE: IF YOU'RE LIKE MOST
AMERICANS, IT WAS NEARLY
IMPOSSIBLE TO STOP THINKING
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED FRIDAY
MORNING AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE FELT BOTH DEEP SADNESS AND
OUTRAGE.
IT WAS INCOMPREHINSIBLE AND SO
OVERWHELMING.
TODAY, WE'LL TALK ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED, THOUGH WE'LL NEVER
UNDERSTAND IT.
AND TRY TO FIND THE ANSWER TO
WHAT SO MANY OF US ASKED
OURSELVES OVER THE WEEKEND.
OH MY GOD, WHAT IS THE WORLD
COMING TO?
27 LIVES LITERALLY SNUFFED OUT.
BRAVE TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS AND A MOTHER
ANDED BY HER OWN FLESH
BLOOD.
BUT THE CHILDREN, 20 OF THEM,
SO YOUNG AND SMALL AND SO MUCH
AHEAD OF THEM, THEIR DEATHS
SEEM TOO MUCH TO BEAR.
I WENT TO NEWTOWN LAST NIGHT
AND SPOKE TO TWO FAMILIES.
ONE LOST THEIR FIRST BORN
DAUGHTER, ANOTHER THEIR BABY
BOY.
TO TRULY UNDERSTAND THIS
TRAGEDY WE NEED TO UNDERSTAND
DEPTH OF THE LOSS AND THE
EXCRUCIATING PAIN.
WE BEGIN WITH MARK AND JACKIE
BARDEN.
THEIR SON DANIEL WAS A FIRST
GRADER AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND LEAVES BEHIND HIS
TWO SIBLINGS, NATALIE AND JAMES.
JAMES IS 12 AND WANTED A CHANCE
LITTLE ABOUT HIS
BROTHER.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE SPENDING TIME
WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA?
WAS THAT HELPFUL FOR YOU ALL?
>> TO BE HONEST, IT WAS A LITTLE
LESS FRUITFUL THAN WE WERE
HOPING.
JAMES AND OUR DAUGHTER NATALIE
HAD A FEW THINGS THEY WERE
HOPING TO EXPRESS TO HIM OUT OF
CONCERN FOR THE WAY, THE FACT
ATT THIS SITUATION HAPPENED
ALL AND HOW WE CAN MAYBE,
HOPEFULLY STOP THIS FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
MY DAUGHTER NATALIE WAS
INTERESTED IN ASKING HIM IF HE
COULD PASS SOME LEGISLATION SO
THAT THE ONLY PEOPLE THAT HAD
GUNS WERE MILITARY PERSONNEL
AND LAW ENFORCEMENT.
AND IF PEOPLE NEEDED GUNS FOR
SPORT, THEY COULD GO TO A RANGE
AND THE GUNS WOULD HAVE TO STAY
THERE.
THAT WAS MY 10-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER.
THAT WAS ALL HER OWN ORIGINAL
THOUGHT.
>> SHE JUST DOESN'T UNDERSTAND
HOW ANYBODY COULD HAVE ACCESS,
WALK INTO A SCHOOL WITH THIS
STUFF.
KATIE: WHAT DID YOU WANT TO ASK
AM, JAMES, IF YOU HAD HAD
CHANCE TO TALK TO THE PRESIDENT
A LITTLE MORE?
>> I WANTED TO ASK HIM WHAT HE
WAS GOING TO DO TO MAKE SURE
THIS NEVER HAPPENS AGAIN.
BECAUSE IT SHOULD NEVER HAPPEN
AGAIN, NO ONE SHOULD EVER HAVE
TO GO THROUGH THIS.
KATIE: HOW WILL YOU ALL USE
THIS?
OR WILL YOU BE ABLE TO USE THIS
TO TRY TO INACT SOME KIND OF
CHANGE?
>> WE'RE STILL NOT EVEN REALLY
FULLY AWARE, OR REALLY HAVEN'T
PROCESSED OR ABSORBED OR
DIGESTED THE FACT THAT OUR
SWEET LITTLE DANIEL IS NOT HERE
WITH US ANY MORE.
THAT'S ALL WE'RE TRYING TO DEAL
WITH AT THIS MOMENT.
KATIE: TELL ME A LITTLE BIT
ABOUT DANIEL.
>> IN ONE WORD, DANIEL WAS A
LIGHT.
AND WHEN I TELL YOU, WHEN HE
WAS 4 YEARS OLD, HE WAS SELECTED
TO BE PART OF A PROGRAM WHERE
HE WAS PAIRED UP WITH SPECIAL
NEEDS CHILDREN IN A PRESCHOOL
ENVIRONMENT, AND HE WAS
SELECTED FOR THAT BECAUSE HIS
PERSONALITY WAS PERFECT FOR
THAT.
KATIE: TO HELP OUT THE OTHER
KIDS.
>> AND HE WAS ONLY SUPPOSED TO
BE IN THE ENVIRONMENT WITH THEM.
>> BUT TEACHERS USED TO ALWAYS
COMMENT --
>> IF HE NOTICED SOMEBODY
SITTING BY THEMSELVES, HE WOULD
NOTICE THAT AND ASK THE TEACHER
CAN I BE EXCUSED TO GO SIT WITH
THIS PERSON?
BECAUSE THEY'RE ALL ALONE AND
HE WOULD TRY TO COMFORT THEM.
AT 4.
AND FROM THEN ON, EVERY
PARENT/TEACHER CONFERENCE WE'VE
HAD, WE HEARD THE EXACT SAME
THING.
>> HOW UNUSUAL HE WAS.
>> HE WAS DIFFERENT IN THAT WAY.
>> OUR NEIGHBORS ALWAYS SAID
HE'S LIKE AN OLD SOUL.
THE DAY THAT HE WENT TO SCHOOL
THAT DAY, HE GOT UP EARLY.
AS HE ALWAYS DID, MARK SAID.
WE TALKED AND HE SAID I
FOOSE BALL WITH HIM BEFORE
SCHOOL.
WE HAVE A FOOSBALL TABLE, OF
COURSE HE BEAT ME 10-8.
>> I HAD HIM AT FIRST.
I THOUGHT I WAS GOING TO.
>> THEN MARK TAUGHT HIM HOW TO
PLAY "JINGLE BELLS" ON THE
PIANO.
>> YEAH, WE DID A LOT IN THAT
HALF-HOUR.
SO, WE HELD HANDS ON THE WAY TO
THE BUS.
THAT WAS OUR LAST MORNING
TOGETHER.
HE DID GET UP EARLY THAT
MORNING AND RAN DOWN THE
DRIVEWAY SO HE COULD KISS HIS
BROTHER GOOD-BYE IN HIS PAJAMAS.
IT WAS 22 DEGREES.
HE WAS EXCEPTIONAL.
KATIE: OH JAMES, SO SORRY.
YOUR CHILDREN ARE REALLY,
OBVIOUSLY UNDERSTANDABLY IN SO
MUCH PAIN, BREAKS MY HEART TO
SEE HIM LIKE THIS.
>> HE'S BEEN SPENDING A LOT OF
TIME CONSOLING HIS LITTLE
SISTER.
HE'S DONE A WONDERFUL JOB
HOLDING HER, TRYING TO EXPLAIN
TO HER WE'RE GOING TO GET
THROUGH THIS.
HE'S BEEN A ROCK FOR HIS LITTLE
SISTER.
KATIE: WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT THIS
YOUNG MAN WHO DID THIS --
>> I DON'T.
>> WE DON'T.
WE REALLY HAVEN'T EVEN GONE
THERE.
>> NOT INTERESTED.
>> IT DOESN'T MATTER.
>> WE'RE CONCERNED WITH THE
FAMILIES THAT ARE SUFFERED THIS
HORRIBLE LOSS.
IT'S ABOUT THEM.
KATIE: WHAT ELSE WOULD YOU LIKE
PEOPLE TO KNOW ABOUT YOUR SON?
>> OUR SON HAD SO MUCH LOVE TO
GIVE TO THIS WORLD.
AND HE WAS SUPPOSED TO HAVE A
WHOLE LIFETIME OF BRINGING THAT
LIGHT TO THE WORLD.
AND EVERYONE, ALL OF US HAVE
SUFFERED A LOSS BECAUSE THAT
WON'T BE REALIZED.
KATIE: WHAT ABOUT YO
IS THERE SOMETHING THAT YOU
THINK PEOPLE SHOULD KNOW ABOUT
YOUR LITTLE BROTHER?
>> HE WAS JUST SO SWEET AND
KIND, AND THOUGHTFUL.
HE WOULD ALWAYS -- HE WAS SO
GOOD AT MAKING SURE THAT HE
CLEANED UP AFTER HIMSELF,
TURNED OFF ALL HIS LIGHTS --
>> HIS LIGHTS.
>> CLOSE THE DOOR.
>> CLOSE EVERY DOOR.
ST WAS VERY THOUGHTFUL.
>> HE WOULD HOLD DOORS OPEN FOR
ADULTS ALL THE TIME.
I'D BE ALREADY HALFWAY ACROSS
THE PARKING LOT LOOKING BACK AND
HIM AND HE WAS HOLDING THE DOOR
FOR SOMEBODY COMING DOWN THE
AISLE.
KATIE: SOUNDS KIND OF LIKE HE
WAS PERFECT.
>> YEAH.
>> IT DOES, DOESN'T IT?
>> BECAUSE HE WAS.
KATIE: ONE QUESTION MARK BARDEN
ASKED ME FOLLOWING THAT
INTERVIEW IS HOW CAN A MERCYFUL
GOD LET SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPEN?
LATER WE'LL ASK JOEL OSTEEN
ABOUT THAT.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
♪
KATIE: ROBBY PARKER AND HIS WIFE
ALYSSA MOVED EIGHT MONTHS AGO TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT BECAUSE HE
GOT A JOB AS A PHYSICIANS
ASSISTANT AT THE HOSPITAL.
THAT'S WHERE HE WAS WHEN THE
SHOOTING HAPPENED.
THE HOSPITAL WENT INTO LOCKDOWN
AND HE WENT TO THE EMERGENCY
ROOM EXPECTING THAT SOME OF THE
CHILDREN MIGHT BE TAKEN THERE.
HE FINALLY MADE HIS WAY TO THE
FIRE HOUSE WHERE HIS WIFE ALYSSA
WAS WAITING DESPERATE FOR ANY
NEWS ABOUT THEIR 6-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER EMILIE.
>> SHE WAS A VERY SPECIAL GIRL.
E
WE FIND COMFORT IN THE FACT THAT
SHE WAS ABLE TO TOUCH OUR LIVES
AND THE LIVES OF SO MANY PEOPLE
IS REALLY A HEART-WARMING THING
TO US.
AND IT BRINGS A LOT OF HAPPINESS
AND WE KNOW THAT'S THE KIND OF
GIRL SHE WAS AND WE CAN BE PROUD
OF THAT.
KATIE: ALYSSA, HOW ARE YOU
DOING?
>> I'VE BEEN ASKED THAT QUITE A
BIT.
I HAVEN'T YET COME UP WITH A
WORD THAT IS APPROPRIATE.
IT'S JUST -- IT'S HARD AND I'M
TAKING IT, HONESTLY A MINUTE AT
A TIME.
BECAUSE THAT'S ABOUT ALL I CAN
DO.
KATIE: YOU ALL HAVE TWO LITTLE
GIRLS IN ADDITION TO EMILIE.
>> MADELINE'S 4 AND SARA IS 3.
KATIE: DO THEY UNDERSTAND AT ALL
WHAT'S HAPPENED?
>> THEY JUST KNOW THEIR BEST
FRIEND HASN'T BEEN AROUND, AND
AS FAR AS WHAT THAT'S GOING TO
MEAN TO THEM AS THE DAYS GO ON,
WE'LL HAVE TO WAIT AND SEE.
KATIE: HOW DID YOU LEARN WHAT
HAD HAPPENED?
>> WHEN I CAME IN TO THE FIRE
STATION, SOMEBODY HAD TOLD THE
FAMILIES IN THAT ROOM THAT THERE
WERE 20 CHILDREN THAT WERE DEAD
AND, SO THAT WAS THE FIRST NEWS
THAT I RECEIVED WHEN I WALKED
IN.
AND SO WE WERE ALL JUST HOPING,
BECAUSE WE DIDN'T KNOW HOW MANY
PEOPLE WERE IN THE SCHOOL, HOW
MANY HAD MADE IT TO THE
HOSPITAL.
SO EVERYBODY IN THAT ROOM WAS
HOLDING ONTO SOME KIND OF HOPE
THAT MAYBE, I'M SO SORRY FOR ALL
OF YOU, BUT AT LEAST OUR CHILD
ISN'T ONE OF THOSE.
>> MOST OF US KNEW THE NUMBER.
ROBBY DIDN'T SEE BECAUSE THEY
HAD WRITTEN A LIST SO WE HAD
COUNTED HOW MANY WERE ON THERE,
SO WE KNEW OUR ODDS WEREN'T VERY
GOOD AT THAT MOMENT.
>> AND THEN EVENTUALLY THE
GOVERNOR CAME IN AND BASICALLY
GOT AROUND TO SAYING THAT ALL
THE CHILDREN THAT ARE IN THE
SCHOOL AREN'T GOING TO MAKE IT
OUT.
AND SO, AT THAT P
OUNCE OF HOPE IN THAT ROOM LEFT.
KATIE: SO FROM HOPE TO ANGUISH.
>> IN A SECOND.
KATIE: YOU MET WITH THE
PRESIDENT TODAY.
AND HE SPENT SOME TIME WITH YOU
AND SOME OTHER MEMBERS OF YOUR
FAMILY.
CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT THAT
MEETING?
WHAT THAT WAS LIKE FOR YOU ALL?
>> I THINK THE ONE THING THAT
STUCK OUT TO ME IS THAT HE SAID
ABOUT, HE WAS THERE REPRESENTING
THE NATION AND THE COUNTRY.
AND HOW EVERYONE'S BEEN SO AWARE
OF OUR SITUATION AND ALL THE
FAMILIES IN OUR SITUATION.
BECAUSE THERE'S SO MANY --
THEY'RE ALL SUCH AMAZING KIDS.
JUST THAT EVERYONE HAS
CONCERNED FOR NOT ONLY US, BUT
ALL OF THOSE FAMILIES AND I FELT
LIKE YOU KNOW, THAT WAS A GOOD
REPRESENTATION OF THE SUPPORT
THAT WE'VE JUST BEEN FEELING
FROM EVERYONE.
KATIE: AND YOU WERE ABLE TO SEE
SOME OF THE OTHER FAMILIES
TONIGHT.
AND, WAS THAT HELPFUL IN A WAY?
>> WE FOUND IT VERY HELPFUL.
IT WAS VERY CLEAR THEY KNOW
EXACTLY WHAT WE'RE GOING
THROUGH.
SO THAT I THINK IS SOMETHING
THAT WILL UNITE US FOREVER AND
HELP US COPE ABOUT EVERYTHING
TOGETHER.
KATIE: YOU SAID THAT YOU HAVE NO
ANGER TOWARD THE YOUNG MAN WHO
DID THIS.
>> I REALLY DON'T.
FROM WHAT WE'VE LEARNED, HE WAS
SOMEONE WHO WAS STRUGGLING WITH
SOMETHING THAT WAS VERY, VERY
DARK AND SOMETHING THAT HE
STRUGGLED WITH MIGHTILY.
AND HE STRUGGLES WITH SOMETHING
DIFFERENT THAN THE STRUGGLES
THAT I HAVE IN MY LIFE.
SO I CAN'T HAVE ANY JUDGMENT
TOWARDS HIM FOR THOSE THINGS
THAT HE MIGHT HAVE BEEN
FIGHTING.
KATIE: HOW ABOUT YOU ALYSSA?
HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT THE YOUNG
MAN WHO DID THIS?
>> YOU KNOW, AS HARD AS IT IS TO
DEAL WITH, THE LOSS OF MY
DAUGHTER, I FEEL VERY BLESSED BY
MY HEAVENLY FATHER THAT THAT'S
NOT SOMETHING I'VE EVEN HAD TO
STRUGGLE WITH AT ALL.
BECAUSE I FEEL LIKE IT WOULD
OVERWHELM ME IF I WAS FEELING
HATRED FOR HIM, OR ANGER.
ALL I FELT WAS SADNESS, REALLY.
AND STILL TO THIS DAY, ALL I
FELT WAS JUST SAD.
I FELT BAD FOR HIM.
BECAUSE I CAN'T IMAGINE THE
STATE OF MIND THAT SOMEONE IS IN
TO DO SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
THAT'S SUCH A DARK AND EVIL AND
AWFUL PLACE TO BE, AND IF
ANYONE'S IN A POSITION LIKE
THAT, I JUST CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE
HOW HARD THAT WOULD BE.
AND I FEEL SO SAD THAT THAT'S
WHERE HE WAS.
I REALLY, TRULY FEEL THAT WAY.
KATIE: HOW DO YOU HEAL FROM
THIS, ALYSSA?
HOW DO YOU MOVE FORWARD WITH
YOUR LIFE?
>> I FEEL LIKE THE ONLY WAY TO
MOVE FORWARD IS TO THINK ABOUT
THESE BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND
THEIR LIVES AND BE SO THANKFUL
THAT WE ALL HAD THEM, BECAUSE
THOSE CHILDREN WERE SO
BEAUTIFUL.
NOT JUST OUR GIRL, BUT THOSE
FAMILIES HAD AMAZING CHILDREN.
AND I JUST WOULD LOVE TO FOCUS
ON THOSE AMAZING LIVES AND HOW
INSPIRING THEY ARE TO ALE OF US.
>> AND EMILIE WAS SUCH AN
AMAZING PERSON AND I WANTED TO
MAKE SURE THAT SHE HAD A VOICE.
AND WE WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
ALL THE CHILDREN THAT SUFFERED
IN THERE, THAT THEY HAVE A VOICE
AND THAT THROUGH THEIR -- THAT
THROUGH WHAT HAPPENED WITH THEM,
WE CAN JUST DO SOMETHING TO HELP
EACH OTHER OUT AND TO MOVE
PEOPLE AND TO MOVE COMMUNITIES
AND DO BETTER AND BE BETTER.
KATIE: EMILIE WILL BE BURIED
LATER THIS WEEK IN THE FAMILY'S
HOMETOWN OF OGDEN, UTAH.
♪
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
♪
KATIE: WHEN EVER THERE'S A
SCHOOL SHOOTING, WE'RE REMINDED
OF WHAT HAPPENED AT COLUMBINE
HIGH SCHOOL 13 YEARS AGO.
THERE HAVE BEEN 31 SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS SINCE THEN.
IN THE EARLYLY MORNING HOURS IN
THE MIDST OF A SPRING SNOWFALL,
I TALKED TO TWO PEOPLE WHOSE
LIVES WERE FOREVER CHANGED.
ON APRIL 19, 1999, ERIC HARRIS
AND DYLAN KREBOLD WENT ON A
KILLING SPREE, MURDERING 12
STUDENTS AND ONE TEACHER.
AND THE TOWN OF LITTLETON,
COLORADO BEGAN AN EXAMPLE OF YOU
HOW HEALING BEGINS AND WHAT A
LONG AND DIFFICULT ROAD IT CAN
BE.
MICHAEL SHOLLS LOST HIS SON
ISAIAH THAT DAY.
CRAIG WAS NEXT TO ISAIAH IN THE
SCHOOL LIBRARY BUT PLAYED DEAD
AND LATER ESCAPED, HOPING HIS
17-YEAR-OLD SISTER RACHEL WOULD
DO THE SAME.
AS HE TOLD ME THE MORNING AFTER
THE SHOOTINGS, SHE DID NOT.
THEN WHAT HAPPENED?
>> ALL THESE PEOPLE THAT I WAS
PRAYING FOR 30 MINUTES LATER
THEIR BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
THEIR BROTHERS AND SISTERS WERE
SHOWING UP --
KATIE: BUT NOT YOUR SISTER.
AND NOW, AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, LIVES
ENDED BEFORE THEY HAD REALLY
BEGUN.
AND MORE LIVES SHATTERED NOT
KNOWING HOW TO BEGIN AGAIN.
NO ONE KNOWS BETTER THE PAIN THE
FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
ARE GOING THROUGH RIGHT NOW THAN
CRAIG SCOTT AND HIS MOTHER BETH,
AS DOES JOE, WHOSE 18-YEAR-OLD
DAUGHTER WAS ONE OF THE 32
KILLED AT VIRGINIA TECH, MORE
THAN FIVE YEARS AGO.
THANK YOU ALL SO MUCH FOR BEING
HERE.
IT'S GOOD TO SEE ALL OF YOU.
I THOUGHT ABOUT YOU WHEN THIS
SHOOTING HAPPENED, WHEN WORD GOT
OUT.
WHAT WAS YOUR REACTION, CRAIG,
WHEN YOU HEARD THE NEWS?
>> JUST SAD AND BROKEN HEARTED
LIKE EVERYONE ELSE.
AND IT ALSO, IT GOT ME TO
QUESTION WHERE MY GENERATION IS
AT, JUST SPIRITUALLY AND
CULTURALLY, BECAUSE OF THE
SHOOTINGS THAT HAVE BEEN
HAPPENING OVER THE LAST FEW
YEARS OF PEOPLE, NEAR MY AGE,
AND TARGETING TOTALLY HELPLESS
PEOPLE AND TRYING TO INFLICT AS
MUCH KILLING AS POSSIBLE.
SO, IT'S GOT ME THINKING ABOUT
THAT.
KATIE: WHAT ABOUT YOU, BETH?
>> I WAS ACTUALLY VERY ANGRY
WHEN I FIRST HEARD ABOUT IT.
AND I JUST PACED UP AND DOWN IN
MY KITCHEN WHERE I WAS DOING
SOME CHRISTMAS BAKING.
I WAS ANGRY.
I WAS LIKE, WHO WOULD GO AFTER
BABIES?
WHO WOULD GO AND TARGET BABIES
IN ORDER TO TAKE THEIR ANGER AND
T ON PAIN OUT ON SOMEONE SO
INNOCENT?
IT'S LIKE KILLING MY
GRANDCHILDREN.
SO IT TOOK ME A WHILE TO SIMMER
DOWN A LITTLE BIT BECAUSE MY
HEART WAS RACING.
AND I JUST FELT, I FELT SO
ANGRY.
THAT THESE CHILDREN WERE THE
TARGETS.
KATIE: JOE?
>> I WAS DRIVING IN MY CAR,
RECEIVED A CALL FROM MY DAUGHTER
AND SHE TOLD ME ABOUT THE
SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN.
AND I JUST DIDN'T HAVE ENOUGH
INFORMATION, SO I TURN ON THE
RADIO AND IT'S UTTER SHOCK,
PAIN, NUMBNESS.
AND, I THINK TO MYSELF FIVE
YEARS AGO, I SAID WE DON'T WANT
OTHER PARENTS TO HAVE TO WALK IN
OUR SHOES.
AND MY SHOES WERE WORN OUT.
BUT I'LL CONTINUE TO DO WHATEVER
I CAN TO HELP THEM THROUGH THIS
BECAUSE WE'VE EXPERIENCED THAT
TRAGEDY.
AND IT IS A SUFFERING THAT
NOBODY WANTS TO GO THROUGH.
KATIE: AND THAT PROBABLY REALLY
NEVER ENDS.
FOR THESE PARENTS, BETH AND JOE,
FOR YOU SPECIFICALLY, YOU KNOW
WHAT IT'S LIKE TO LOSE A CHILD.
AND IT WAS SO HEARTBREAKING TO
TALK TO THESE FAMILIES.
>> OH, I'M SURE.
KATIE: WHAT WOULD YOU TELL THEM?
HOW CAN YOU HELP THEM IN ANY WAY
GET THROUGH THIS VERY, VERY DARK
JOURNEY?
>> WELL, I MEAN, AS FAR AS THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS AND
VIRGINIA TECH AND THE SURVIVORS
OF VIRGINIA TECH, WE'VE ACTUALLY
CREATED A FOUNDATION TO DO JUST
THAT.
AND PART OF OUR MISSION IS TO
RESPOND TO SUCH.
FIVE YEARS LATER WE'VE BEEN ABLE
TO EDUCATE OURSELVES AND TO BE
ABLE TO HELP, BECAUSE IT'S NOT
ABOUT US, IT IS ABOUT THEM.
>> WELL, I WOULD LIKE TO
ENCOURAGE THEM THAT RIGHT NOW
THEY CAN'T SEE ANY LIGHT AT THE
END OF THIS TUNNEL BECAUSE THE
TUNNEL IS SO DARK AND SO LONG.
BECAUSE THIS PROCESS IS VERY
LONG AND ONGOING.
BUT THERE IS A LIGHT, IT MAY
TAKE YEARS TO GET THERE, BUT
THERE DOES COME A DAY WHERE YOU
DON'T CRY ALL DAY LONG.
YOU CAN LAUGH, YOU HAVE JOY
AGAIN IN YOUR LIFE.
COLUMBINE WAS LIKE GETTING HIT
WITH A FREIGHT TRAIN AND NOT
EVEN KNOWING WHAT HIT YOU.
IT DEVASTATES YOU.
THE PAIN IS SO GREAT YOU CAN'T
BREATHE.
YOU WANT TO DIE, BUT YOU'RE
GOING TO WAKE UP THE NEXT
MORNING.
AND IT COMES IN SURGES, YOU
KNOW.
THERE'S TIMES WHEN YOU'RE SO
OVERWHELMED BY IT, I THINK THE
LORD CREATED US TO WHERE SOME OF
THOSE THINGS ARE BLOCKED OUT.
AND THERE'S A BARRIER OR A
CUSHION THERE FOR A WHILE UNTIL
WE CAN ACTUALLY UNDERSTAND IT.
I DON'T THINK THEY HAVE ANY
UNDERSTANDING AT THIS POINT,
THEY'RE JUST DEALING WITH THE
FACTS OF THIS.
BUT, I KNOW, I KNOW THAT THEY
WILL SURVIVE THIS.
I KNOW THROUGH THE COMMUNITY AND
THE LOVE AND THE SUPPORT THAT
COMES FROM THEIR FRIENDS AND
FAMILY IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD.
THEY'LL GET SO MUCH HELP AND
ENCOURAGEMENT WITH THAT.
AND IT MEANT THE WORLD TO US, WE
HAD THE WHOLE WORLD REACHING OUT
TO THEM AND I KNOW NEWTOWN HAS
THE SAME THING AVAILABLE TO
THEM.
EVERYBODY WANTS TO DO ANYTHING
THEY CAN TO HELP.
AND IT REALLY MAKES A
DIFFERENCE.
KATIE: CRAIG, I KNOW YOU HAVE
SAID LOOK AT THE LIGHT IN THE
DARK PLACES, BUT YOU HAVE
STRUGGLED VERY A LONG TIME AFTER
LOSING RACHEL.
WHAT HAVE YOU LEARNED THAT WILL
HELP SOME OF THESE FAMILY
MEMBERS THAT WILL HELP JAMES,
WHO WITH 12 YEARS OLD, THAT
INCONSOLEABLE AND BROKENHEARTED?
>> WELL, I WENT THROUGH A LOT OF
ANGER AND I HATED THE SHOOTERS
AT COLUMBINE FOR A LONG TIME AND
HELD ONTO THAT ANGER AND IT
STARTED TO AFFECT MY FAMILY.
AND I HAD TO THINK ABOUT WHO I
WANTED TO BE DOWN THE ROAD.
AND TO JAMES, I WOULD SAY YOU
KNOW, USE THE MEMORY OF YOUR
BROTHER NOW AND ALL THAT HE WAS
AND ALL THE GOODNESS THAT HE WAS
AND THE PERFECTION AND USE WHO
HE WAS AS A FORCE IN YOUR LIFE
NOW.
YOU EXPRESS THAT TO THE WORLD.
YOU LET THE WORLD GET TO SEE
YOUR LITTLE BROTHER THROUGH YOU.
AND FOR ME, I EVENTUALLY HAD TO
LET GO OF MY ANGER AND HATRED
TOWARDS THE SHOOTERS AND I DID
THAT FOR FORGIVING THEM FOR WHAT
THEY HAD DONE.
NOT TO SAY WHAT SOMEONE DOES IS
OK, BUT IT'S A LETTING GO OF.
IT REALLY DID HELP ME HEAL NOW
TO THE POINT WHERE I'M ABLE TO
GO AND DO WHAT IT IS THAT I DO
IN SHARING RACHEL'S STORY IN
SCHOOLS, AND INSPIRING OTHER
STUDENTS TO STEP OUT IN
COMPASSION FOR OTHERS, AND SHOW
KINDNESS, WHICH HAS BEEN A BIG
ANTI-DOTE TO THAT ANGER AND
HATRED THAT IS BREWING IN A LOT
OF YOUNG PEOPLE AND A LOT OF
TEENS TODAY.
KATIE: I AM SO HAPPY TO SEE ALL
OF YOU.
I'M SO SORRY UNDER THESE
CIRCUMSTANCES.
THANK YOU ALL SO MUCH.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
♪
KATIE: AND WE'RE BACK WITH CRAIG
SCOTT WHOSE SISTER RACHEL WAS
KILLED IN THE COLUMBINE
SHOOTINGS, AND HIS AND RACHEL'S
MOTHER BETH NIMMO.
AND ALSO JOINED BY DAVE CULLEN,
THE AUTHOR OF COLUMBINE, THE
DEFINITIVE BOOK ON THAT TRAGEDY
IN COLORADO.
I KNOW YOU WORKED ON THIS BOOK
FOR 10 YEARS AND YOU STUDIED
DYLAN KLEBOLD AND ERIC HARRIS.
IT SEEMS TO ME THE PERPETRATORS
IN THESE INCIDENTS, THEY'RE
EARLY SIMILAR IN TERMS OF THEIR
BACK GROUNDS.
TELL US WHAT YOU LEARNED.
>> OK.
SURE.
A COUPLE OF THINGS.
ONE IS THAT THERE'S A VARIETY OF
DIFFERENT TYPES OF KILLERS.
THE FIRST IS RARE, BUT ERIC
HARRIS AT COLUMBINE, A SADISTIC
PSYCHOPATH.
THEN WE ALSO HAVE FAIRLY
UNUSUAL, THE PEOPLE WHO ARE
DEEPLY MENTALLY ILL IN THE SENSE
OF REALLY OUT OF TOUCH OF
REALITY AND NOT UNDERSTANDING,
THAT WAS TRUE OF JOE AT VIRGINIA
TECH AND ANOTHER SHOOTER IN
TUCSON.
IT'S USUALLY NOT THE CASE AND WE
DEFINITELY DON'T WANT TO
STIGAMATIZE PEOPLE BECAUSE
THEY'RE USUALLY NOT VIOLENT.
THE THIRD ONE WHICH TENDS TO BE
THE MOST COMMON ARE THE DEEPLY
SUICIDALLY DEPRESSED.
THIS IS NOT WHAT WE THINK OF AS
A DEPRESSED, MOROSE PERSON.
BUT THESE PEOPLE REACH SUCH A
SENSE OF HELPLESSNESS AND
HOPELESSNESS, WHERE THEY'RE
READY TO LASH OUT AND DO
SOMETHING THAT DOESN'T REALLY
EVEN MAKE SENSE TO THEM
COMPLETELY, WHICH IS IRRATIONAL,
BUT THEY'RE GOING TO LASH OUT IN
SOME EXTREME WAY.
AND SOMETIMES THEY DON'T KNOW
EXACTLY HA THEY'RE GOING TO DO.
THEY'VE GOT THE GUNS, BUT
THEY'RE NOT SURE EXACTLY WHAT
THEY'RE GOING TO DO WITH THEM OR
HOW FAR THEY'LL TAKE IT.
KATIE: ARE THERE WARNING SIGNS?
ARE THERE THINGS PARENTS CAN
TICK UP ON SO THEY REALIZE THEIR
CHILD IS CAPABLE OF THIS KIND OF
VIOLENCE OR NOT?
>> WELL, YES AND NO.
THERE ARE WARNING SIGNS OF THE
DEEP DEPRESSION AND OF THE
REALLY DANGEROUS SITUATION.
THERE'S NOT REALLY A WARNING
SIGN THAT IT'S GOING TO BE
VIOLENT OR MASS MURDER, BECAUSE
ACTUALLY THERE'S ABOUT A FEW
MILLIONED A LESS SENTS THAT ARE
CLINLY DEPRESSED IN THE U.S.,
MOST UNDIAGNOSED.
BUT THEY TEND TO LOOK VERY
SIMILAR.
IF WE'VE GOT A FEW MILLION
PEOPLE WITH THAT, THE 10 OR 15
OR 20 WHO ARE GOING TO GO
VIOLENT TO DO SOMETHING LIKE
THIS, THEY'RE INDISTINGUISHABLE.
KATIE: I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT TO
POINT OUT THAT YOU ACTUALLY
REACHED OUT TO SUE KLEBOLD,
DYLAN KLEBOLD'S MOTHER AFTER THE
TRAGEDY.
WHY WAS THAT?
>> I HAD A HEART FOR THE PARENTS
OF THESE TWO SHOOTERS.
THE WORLD CAME TO OUR RESCUE.
THEY EMBRACED US, THEY CONSOLED
WITH US AND THE SHOOTERS PARENTS
IN THIS SITUATION WERE VILL
ANNIZED.
THEY WERE REJECTED.
PEOPLE WANTED ANOTHER POUND OF
FLESH, BECAUSE THE BOYS HAD
TAKEN THEIR LIFE.
SO, YOU WANT TO PUT BLAME
SOMEWHERE, YOU WANT SOMETHING TO
POINT YOUR ANGER TOWARDS.
AND I ACTUALLY FELT KIND OF BAD
ABOUT THAT, AND SO I DID NINE
MONTHS AFTER THE FACT MET WITH
SUE, AND AS I WAS GOING IN
THERE, I ASKED THE LORD, I SAID
I HAVE NO CRY DEE WHAT TO SAY TO
THIS LADY.
AND HE SAID JUST ASK HER WHO HER
SON WAS BEFORE APRIL 20 OF 1999.
AND I DID, AND TEARS JUST ROLLED
DOWN HER FACE AND SHE TALKED
ABOUT THIS LITTLE BOY GROWING
UP, AND YOU KNOW, A NORMAL
LITTLE CHILD AND THEN AS HE GOT
INTO HIS OLDER HIGH SCHOOL
YEARS, SHE SAW A CHANGE TAKE
PLACE IN HIM WHERE HE WAS
DISTANCING HIMSELF.
SHE TOLD ME THE ONLY THING THAT
GAVE AWAY THE FACT THAT DYLAN
WAS DOING SOMETHING THAT THEY
WEREN'T AWARE OF WAS HE WOULD
NOT MAKE EYE CONTACT WITH HER
ANY MORE.
AND OUTSIDE OF THAT HE PLAYED
THE GAME PERFECTLY.
THEY HAD GONE TO CHECK OUT
SCHOOLS FOR COLLEGE, I MEAN,
THERE WAS NO INDICATION AT ALL
THAT HE WAS PLANNING TO DIE IN
TWO DAYS, YOU KNOW?
AND COMMIT THIS AWFUL ACT.
SO, THESE PARENTS, SOMETIMES ARE
JUST BLINDSIDED BY WHAT'S GOING
ON.
AND I HAVE A COMPASSION FOR
THAT, BECAUSE THANKFULLY MY
CHILDREN HAVE NEVER COMMITTED
ANYTHING AS HEINOUS AS MASS
SHOOTING OR A SHOOTING OF ANY
ONE PERSON FOR THAT, BUT I CAN
IMAGINE THE GUILT, THE REGRET
AND THE REMORSE AS A PARENT THAT
YOU JUST BEAT YOURSELF UP ABOUT
OVER AND OVER AGAIN WISHING YOU
COULD MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
KATIE: I KNOW THAT FORGIVENESS
AS IT HELPED CRAIG, HELPED YOU
TO HEAL AS WELL.
WELL BETH, CRAIG AND DAVE, THANK
YOU ALL SO MUCH FOR COMING BY,
REALLY APPRECIATE IT.
ALWAYS WONDERFUL TO SEE BOTH OF
YOU.
SORRY IT'S SUCH SAD
CIRCUMSTANCES THAT WE SEEM TO
GET TOGETHER.
SO, MAYBE WE CAN SEE EACH OTHER
IN HAPPIER TIMES AT SOME POINT.
AND WE'LL BE BACK RIGHT AFTER
THIS.
♪
>> CAN I GO BACK AND DO THAT
AGAIN?
ANNOUNCER: WANT TICKETS TO
"KATIE"?
VISIT KATIE COURIC.COM TO
REQUEST A SPOT IN OUR LIVE
AUDIENCE.
♪
KATIE: THE SHOOTING IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT HAS BROUGHT TWO
MAJOR ISSUES FRONT AND CENTER.
GUN CONTROL AND MENTAL HEALTH.
DAN GROSS IS THE PRESIDENT OF
THE BRADY CAMPAIGN TO END GUN
VIOLENCE AND DR. HAROLD IS A
CHILD PSYCHOLOGIST.
DAN, LET ME START WITH YOU.
MANY PEOPLE ARE SAYING THIS IS A
WAKE UP CALL WHEN IT COMES TO
STRICTER GUN LAWS.
DO YOU REALLY THINK IT IS?
BECAUSE WE'VE HEARD THIS SONG
BEFORE.
>> I THINK IT'S A WAKE UP CALL
FOR ANYBODY IT NEEDS TO BE A
WAKE UP CALL FOR CONGRESS.
BECAUSE THE AMERICAN PUBLIC IS
ALREADY AWAKE.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE SENTIMENT
OUT THERE FOR CHANGE, THE
NATIONAL CONVERSATION THAT'S
ALREADY BEEN PERCOLATING IN THE
WAKE OF ALL THE TRAGEDIES THAT
HAVE BEEN HAPPENING THIS YEAR,
IN THE WAKE OF THE 32 MURDERS
THAT HAPPEN EVERY DAY IN OUR
COUNTRY.
THE ONLY PART THIS IS PART OF
DEBATE IS IN CONGRESS.
WE NEED TO MAKE THE VOICE OF THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC HEARD.
HOPEFULLY THIS WILL CONNECT THE
DOTS AND CAST A SPOTLIGHT ON OUR
ELECTED OFFICIALS.
THERE ARE EASY THINGS WE CAN DO
--
KATIE: BUT DAN, BEFORE WE GET TO
THAT, THE PUBLIC SENTIMENT DOES
NOT SEEM TO BE THERE EITHER.
AFTER THE SHOOTING OF GIFFORD,
THERE WAS A POLL CONDUCTED.
49% SAID IT'S MORE IMPORTANT TO
PROTECT RIGHTS OF AMERICANS TO
CONTROL GUN, 46% SAID IT'S
IMPORTANT TO CONTROL GUN
OWNERSHIP.
SO THERE SEEMS TO BE A
DISCONNECT HERE.
>> RIGHT.
THAT'S NOT A REFLECTION OF HOW
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC FEELS ABOUT
THE SENSIBLE MEASURES, THAT'S A
REFLECTION OF THE DEBATE BETWEEN
GUN OWNERS AND THE SECOND
AMENDMENT AND WANTING SENSIBLE
CHANGE.
THAT'S NOT THE WAY THE AMERICAN
PUBLIC IS THINKING ABOUT THIS.
WE'RE THINKING THAT WE'RE BETTER
THAN THIS AS A NATION.
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
74% OF N.R.A. MEMBERS SUPPORT
CRIMINAL BACKGROUND CHECKS THAT
WILL KEEP GUNS OUT OF THE HANDS
OF CONVICTED FELONS AND
DANGEROUSLY, MENTALLY ILL
PEOPLE.
THAT'S THE CONVERSATION THAT THE
AMERICAN PUBLIC WANTS TO HAVE.
THAT'S THE CONVERSATION THAT GUN
OWNERS ARE IN FAVOR OF AND THE
GUN LOBBY JUST WANTS TO PULL
THIS BACK AND SAY THIS IS
PARTISAN POLITICAL DEBATE.
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC, WE JUST
KNOW WE'RE BETTER THAN THIS.
KATIE: WHAT ABOUT ASSAULT
WEAPONS, THE BAN EXPIRED IN
2004, AFTER 10 YEARS.
DO YOU THINK IT WILL BE PUT IN
PLACE AGAIN?
>> I'M DEFINITELY HEARING A LOT
OF CONVERSATION.
OUR JOB IS TO REPRESENT THE
VOICE OF THE AMERICAN PEOPLE ON
THIS, AND I'M DEFINITELY HEARING
A LOT OF CONVERSATION ABOUT THAT
AS WE TALK TO VICTIMS TO
TRAGEDIES ABOUT THIS.
WE'LL BE BRINGING A NUMBER OF
THEM TO WASHINGTON, D.C.
TOMORROW AND REALLY MAKE THE
VOICE HEARD.
BUT ANOTHER BIG, IMPORTANT PART
OF THE CONVERSATION IS
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
40% ALL OF GUN SALES IN OUR
COUNTRY DON'T REQUIRE A CHECK.
THAT'S THE NEXUS OF THE MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUE AND THE GUN
VIOLENCE ISSUE, WHICH MEANS
SOMEBODY WHO HAS BEEN
ADJUDICTED, DANGEROUSLY MENTALLY
ILL, CAN BUY A GUN, NO QUESTIONS
ASKED.
IF WE CAN JUST FRAME THE
CONVERSATION AROUND THINGS LIKE
THAT THAT CAN MAKE ALL OF THAT
BETTER, LIKE THE PRESIDENT SAID
LAST NIGHT WE CAN SOLVE THAT
PROBLEM.
KATIE: LET'S TALK ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH.
ARE WE READY TO HAVE A REAL
CONVERSATION ABOUT HOW MENTAL
HEALTH IS VIEWED AND TREATED IN
THIS COUNTRY, HAROLD?
>> I THINK IT'S CERTAINLY TIME.
HOW MANY MORE SHOOTINGS DO YOU
HAVE TO HAVE?
THE AMAZING PARTS ARE SHOOTINGS
ARE RARE, THE REAL LOSSES ARE
EVERY DAY.
KIDS, 15 MILLION OF THEM IN THE
UNITED STATES WHO HAVE A
PSYCHIATRIC DISORDER ARE MORE AT
RISK FOR ACADEMIC FAILURE, MORE
AT RISK FOR SOCIAL ISOLATION,
SUBSTANCE ABUSE, SCHOOL DROP
OUT, UNEMPLOYMENT AND
INTERACTIONS WITH THE LAW.
YET IT'S EASIER FOR US TO TALK
ABOUT CANCER OR DIABETES THAN TO
TALK ABOUT THINGS THAT HAPPEN
FROM YOUR NECK UP.
KATIE: WE HAVE TO TALK ABOUT IT,
BUT ALSO HAVE THE RESOURCES TO
TREAT IT.
FUNDING HAS BEEN CUT SO
DRAMATICALLY IN THE LAST FEW
YEARS.
>> TREMENDOUSLY, ACROSS THE
NATION.
MENTAL HEALTH BUDGETS HAVE BEEN
SLASHED.
WITHOUT MONEY FOR RESEARCH,
WITHOUT MONEY FOR PROPER
FACILITIES, AND MOST IMPORTANTLY
WITHOUT MONEY FOR INNOVATIVE
CARE, BEING ABLE TO SEE, THERE'S
7,500 CHILD PSYCHOLOGIST, THE
MATH DOESN'T WORK.
YOU CAN'T SEE A DOCTOR TUESDAYS
AT 4:00.
FOR SOME OF THESE KIDS THEY NEED
A VERY INNOVATIVE PROGRAM,
YOU'RE INCLUDING PARENTS, AND
YOU'RE MORE FLEXIBLE.
YOU'RE ABLE TO SEE THEM SEVEN
DAYS A WEEK OR IN THE EVENINGS.
UNTIL WE HAVE A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION THAT MENTAL ILLNESS
IS EQUAL TO PHYSICAL ILLNESS,
THESE KINDS OF EPISODES, AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY THE KIND OF
EPISODES OF HIGH SCHOOL DROP
OUTS AND CAR CRASHES AND TEEN
PREGNANCIES, AND SUICIDE, WHICH
IS MUCH MORE LIKELY TO OCCUR
WITH PSYCHIATRIC ILL KIDS THAN
HOMICIDE.
KATIE: WE BARELY SCRATCHED THE
SURFACE, TWO SUCH CRITICALLY
IMPORTANT ISSUES AND I HOPE
YOU'LL COME BACK WHEN WE CAN
HAVE AN HOUR LONG CONVERSATION
ABOUT EACH OF THEM, BECAUSE
THEY'RE THAT IMPORTANT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, DAN AND
HAROLD.
APPRECIATE IT.
UP NEXT, JOEL OSTEEN ON HEALING
A COMMUNITY AND AN ENTIRE
NATION.
KATIE: I'D LIKE TO SHARE A PHOTO
WITH ALL OF YOU THAT WAS GIVEN
TO ME BY SOMEONE WHO WORKS AT
ST. ROSE CATHOLIC CHURCH IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
A PHOTO HE TOOK AT 9:30 A.M. ON
FRIDAY MORNING.
JOEL OSTEEN IS THE PASTOR OF THE
LARGEST CONGREGATION IN THIS
COUNTRY IN HOUSTON, TEXAS.
AND JOEL, A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE
REALLY STRUGGLING TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT HAPPENED ON FRIDAY MORNING
AT THAT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WITH
ALL THOSE PRECIOUS KIDS.
AND LAST NIGHT, ONE OF THE DAD'S
SAID TO ME, HOW CAN A MERCIFUL
GOD ALLOW SOMETHING LIKE THIS TO
HAPPEN.
AND I SAID I'M GOING TO BE
TALKING TO JOEL OSTEEN TOMORROW
AND I'M GOING TO ASK HIM THAT
QUESTION.
>> YOU KNOW, KATIE, WE DON'T
UNDERSTAND EVERYTHING ABOUT IT
ALL.
I THINK MY TAKE ON IT IS THAT
GOD HAS GIVEN US ALL OUR OWN
FREE WILL.
HE DIDN'T MAKE US ROBOTS, HE
GAVE US THE ABILITY TO CHOOSE
AND UNFORTUNATELY SOME PEOPLE
CHOOSE EVIL.
I STILL BELIEVE THAT GOD IS GOOD
AND THAT HE IS FOR US, BUT GOD
DOESN'T MAKE US DO WHAT'S RIGHT
AND THAT'S WHY WE'RE IN A FALLEN
WORLD, IT'S NOT PERFECT.
KATIE: IF YOU HAD AN OPPORTUNITY
TO COUNSEL SOME OF THE PARENTS,
I SPOKE TO SOME OF THEM LAST
NIGHT AND THEIR GRIEF IS JUST SO
ALL-CONSUMING, AS OF COURSE ALL
OF US CAN UNDERSTAND.
BUT WHAT WOULD YOU SAY TO THEM?
HOW WOULD YOU HELP THEM GET
THROUGH THIS EXCRUCIATINGLY
DIFFICULT TIME?
>> WELL, OUR HEARTS BREAK WITH
THEIR HEARTS.
SOMETIMES WORDS AREN'T GOOD
ENOUGH, YOU KNOW.
JESUS SAID YOU WEEP WITH THOSE
THAT WEEP AND MOURN WITH THOSE
THAT MOURN.
I WOULD TELL THEM, NOT BRINGING
ALL THE ANSWERS BUT GOD HAS THEM
IN THE PALM OF THEIR HAND.
LIKE THOSE STORIES WE WERE
WATCHING EARLIER TODAY ON YOUR
PROGRAM, IT'S AMAZING HOW WHEN
YOU TURN TO YOUR FAITH, GOD WILL
GIVE YOU A STRENGTH THAT ONLY HE
CAN GIVE YOU.
A COUPLE OF THEM TALKING ABOUT
HOW THEY WEREN'T ANGRY, THEY
WEREN'T MAD AT THE OTHER PERSON,
AND I BELIEVE IT COMES IN WAVES
OF GRIEF, BUT AT THE SAME TIME,
GOD WILL GIVE YOU WAVES OF HIS
GRACE TO MAKE IT THROUGH THAT
TIME.
SO I JUST SAY TO BE STRONG, TAKE
IT A DAY AT A TIME, LIKE THAT
ONE LADY SAID.
SHE WAS TAKING IT AT A MINUTE A
TIME.
YOU MAY LOOK UP AND SAY I CAN'T
DO THIS FOR SIX MONTHS, I CAN'T
LIVE WITHOUT MY CHILD.
GOD DOESN'T ASK YOU TO DO THAT.
CAN YOU DO IT FOR FIVE MORE
MINUTES.
JUST TAKE IT ONE MINUTE AT A
TIME.
KATIE: HOW DO WE ALL EXPLAIN
SOMETHING LIKE THIS TO OUR
CHILDREN?
THAT'S SOMETHING PEOPLE WERE
ASKING EACH OTHER ALL WEEKEND.
HOW DO YOU TALK TO KIDS ABOUT
THIS WITHOUT TERRIFYING THEM AND
FEELING SO UNSAFE IN THE WORLD?
>> IT'S DIFFICULT.
I DO THINK, OBVIOUSLY DEPENDING
ON WHAT AGE THEY ARE, YOU TALK
TO THEM IN THE APPROPRIATE WAY,
BUT I DON'T THINK YOU DO IT OUT
OF FEAR AND SAY OH, WE'RE IN
THIS TERRIBLE WORLD.
I THINK YOU STILL HAVE TO DO IT
FROM A PLACE OF GOD'S IN CONTROL
OF YOUR LIFE, AND THERE ARE EVIL
PEOPLE OUT THERE, BUT YOU KNOW
CHOOSE TO BELIEVE THAT GOD HAS
GOOD THINGS IN STORE FOR YOU,
AND NOT APPROACH IT FROM A
FEAR-BASED THING WHERE YOU GO
OUT AND JUST ALWAYS BE WATCHING
FOR SOMETHING.
I DON'T THINK THAT'S THE RIGHT
WAY.
KATIE: AND HOW DO WE CHANGE SORT
OF THE TENOR OF OUR COUNTRY?
IT SEEMS TO ME, THIS IS MY
PERSONAL OPINION, THAT OBVIOUSLY
THERE'S SO MUCH GOOD IN OUR
COUNTRY, AND YOU SEE IT EVERY
DAY, AND YET THERE SEEMS TO BE
SUCH A STRONG UNDERCURRENT OF
ANGER AND RAGE, AND
DEVICIVENESS.
IS THERE ANYTHING WE CAN DO TO
FOSTER A BETTER ATMOSPHERE WHERE
PEOPLE DO SUPPORT AND CARE FOR
EACH OTHER AND AREN'T SO ANGRY
AND LASHING OUT ALL THE TIME?
>> I KNOW.
WE SEE IT AS WELL.
I THINK IT STARTS, KATIE, WITH
EACH ONE OF US BEING AN EXAMPLE
AND HOW CAN WE BE GOOD, DO
SOMETHING GOOD FOR SOMEBODY
EVERY DAY.
YOU KNOW, IT'S JUST I THINK
THERE ARE AS WELL FORCES, I CALL
THEM FORCES OF DARKNESS, THERE
ARE FORCES THAT TRY TO PULL
PEOPLE DOWN INTO ANGER AND
DECEPTION AND THEY HEAR VOICES
AND THINGS LIKE THAT.
I THINK THAT'S WHAT YOU HAVE TO
FIGHT TO KEEP YOUR MIND ON THE
RIGHT THING, BE CAREFUL WHAT YOU
PUT IN YOURSELF SO THAT YOU KNOW
YOU DON'T GIVE OVER TO SOME OF
THESE TERRIBLE THINGS WE'VE
SEEN, WHICH ARE UNIMAGINABLE.
KATIE: DO YOU TALK TO YOUR CON
GREFATION WHEN THINGS LIKE THIS
HAPPEN AND HOW DO YOU EXPLAIN
THEM?
>> YEAH, THERE'S NO GOOD
EXPLANATION, EXCEPT TO BELIEVE
GOD'S IN CONTROL, EVEN WHEN IT
LOOKS LIKE GOD'S OUT OF CONTROL.
EVEN IN THAT PICTURE, THAT'S GOD
SAYING I'M HERE, IT'S GOING TO
BE CRAZY, I'VE GOT YOUR CHILDREN
AND I'M WATCHING OVER YOU.
WE DEAL WITH IT EVERY DAY IN THE
BIG CHURCH, NOT TRAGEDIES LIKE
THIS, BUT STILL LOSING FAMILY
MEMBERS AND THINGS.
YOU'VE GOT TO COME BACK TO THAT
PLACE OF PEACE AND SAY GOD, I
BELIEVE YOU'RE IN CONTROL OF MY
LIFE.
NOTHING CAN SNATCH YOU OUT OF MY
HAND.
YOU MAY NOT ALWAYS UNDERSTAND IT
BUT YOU COME BACK TO THAT PLACE
OF PEACE.
KATIE: JOEL OSTEEN, THANK YOU SO
MUCH FOR COMING BY AND TALKING
TO US TODAY.
>> THANK YOU, IT IS MY PLEASURE.
KATIE: AND WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
KATIE: FINALLY TODAY, ALONG WITH
THE 20 CHILDREN WHO WERE SHOT
AND KILLED INSIDE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WERE SIX
ADULTS WHO HAD SO BRAVELY TRIED
TO PROTECT THEM.
SCHOOL PRINCIPAL DAWN AND SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST RAN OUT INTO THE
HALL WAY AND TRIED TO LUNGE AT
THE GUNMAN TO STOP HIM.
TEACHER AIDES HAD DEVOTED THEIR
LIVES TO HELPING KIDS WITH
SPECIAL NEEDS.
RACHEL'S BOYFRIEND WAS GOING TO
PROPOSE ON CHRISTMAS EVE.
LAUREN AND VICTORIA HAD REALIZED
A LIFE LONG DREAM TO BE
TEACHERS.
IN LAUREN'S CLASSROOM, POLICE
FOUND 14 COATS STILL ON THEIR
HOOKS.
THOSE 14 CHILDREN WOULD NEVER GO
HOME AGAIN.
SIX CHILDREN DIED IN VICTORIA'S
CLASS EVEN AS SHE TRIED TO
SHIELD THEM.
AND AMANDA, THE FIRST GRADE
TEACHER WHO CALLED IN SICK ON
FRIDAY.
OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO HER.
IT'S TOO SOON TO USE THE WORD
ING.
RIGHT NOW IT'S ABOUT GRIEVING.
THE FAMILY I SPOKE TO WAS HOW
MUCH THE OUTPOURING OF SUPPORT
HAS THE MEANT TO THEM.
LET'S ALL REMEMBER THAT IN THE
DAYS, WEEKS, MONTHS, EVEN YEARS
TO COME.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
I'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME.
>>> GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERY
WURNGS I'M CAROLYN JOHNSON.
>> I'M LARRY BEIL.
IT'S A SOL YUM DOWN IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THE TOWN BEGINS TO BURY THE
VICTIMS OF FRIDAY'S SHOOTINGS.
>> WE HAVE THE LATEST ON THE
SERVICES AND INVESTIGATION
INTO THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
>> THE FIRST OF THE FUNERALS
VIS
GUNNED DOWN AT SANDY HOOK
NOAH WAS THE YOUNGEST VICTIM,
SELL BRAILTING HIS SIXTH
BIRTHDAY.
ALONG WITH HIS TWIN SISTER
ARIELL NEXT A DIFFERENT
CLASSROOM AND SURVIVED AT
TACK.
6-YEAR-OLD SCHOOL MATE JACK
PINTO WAS ALSO LAID TO REST.
THE OBITUARY SAYS HE DIED
QUOTE, DECEMBER 14th2002 IN
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN THE COMPANY OF HIS FRIENDS,
OFFICIALS SAY THE SCENE OF THE
MASSACRE IN THE GUNMAN'S HOME
ARE ACTIVE CRIME SCENES, TODAY,
VANS PULLED UP TO THE SCHOOL
TO TRANSPORT FURNITURE OWE A
TEMPORARY SCHOOL FOR KIDS,
SEVEN MILES AWAY.
HUNDREDS OF WORKERS ARE
PREPPING UNUSED BUILDING TO
OPEN SO SANDY HOOK CHILDREN
CAN RESUME CLASSES.
>> SCHOOLS ARE WORKING CLOSELY
WITH ALL OF THE FACULTY,
STUDENTS, AND PARENTS TO TRY
RESUME WHAT NORMALCY WE CAN
OUT THERE, AFTER A TRAGEDY
SUCH AS THIS.
>> INVESTIGATORS ARE SEARCHING
FOR CLUES BEHIND WHAT
MOTIVATED LANZA TO KILL HIS
MOTHER IN HER HOME BEFORE
GOING ON A MURDEROUS RAMPAGE.
POLICE REMOVED COMPUTERS AND
VIDEOS FROM THE HOME.
>> WE DID SEIZE SIGNIFICANT
EVIDENCE AT THE RESIDENTS.
WE ARE ANALYZING IT.
>> THE MASSACRE REIGNITED THE
DEBATE ABOUT GUN CONTROL AND
GUN RIGHTS, DURING A MEMORIAL
SERVICE, PRESIDENT OBAMA VOWED
TO HELP END THE RECENT STRING
OF MASS MURDERS.
>> THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST
CHANGE.
>> TODAY, STATE POLICE
REVEALED TWO ADULTS SURVIVED,
BOTH SHOT IN THE LOWER BODY.
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT ABC 7
NEWS.
>> ON CAPITOL HILL, THE SENATE
OBSERVED A MOMENT OF SILENCE
TODAY IN TRIBUTE TO THE
VICTIMS.
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR SAYS
STATE LAWMAKERS WILL OBSERVE A
MOMENT OF SILENCE 9:30 FRIDAY
MORNING A WEEK TO THE HOUR
AFTER THE RAMPAGE.
>> MEMORIALS TO REMEMBER THE