Alex:
ALISTAIR, YOU START.
ORDINAL NUMBER PHRASES
FOR $200, PLEASE, ALEX.
JUDY.
WHAT IS THE THIRD DEGREE?
YOU ARE RIGHT.
LITERARY RELATIONS
FOR $200.
JUDY.
WHO IS ELIZA DOOLITTLE?
CORRECT.
FOR $400, PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHO IS OPHELIA?
GOOD.
LITERARY RELATIONS
FOR $600, PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHO IS HER GRANDFATHER?
YOU GOT IT.
FOR $800.
JUDY.
WHAT IS
"LADY CHATTERLEY'S LOVER"?
NO.
ALISTAIR OR JOHN?
[ BEEP ]
"WHAT IS
'SONS AND LOVERS'?"
BACK TO YOU, THOUGH,
JUDY.
LITERARY RELATIONS
FOR $1,000.
ANSWER -- DAILY DOUBLE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
YOU'VE DISCOVERED IT
EARLY,
BUT YOU CAN STILL DO YOURSELF
A LOT OF GOOD.
YOU CAN RISK
UP TO $1,000.
$1,000.
ALL
HERE IS THE CLUE.
[ EXHALES DEEPLY ]
I DON'T KNOW.
[ BEEP ]
THE PLAY IS
"DEATH OF A SALESMAN,"
AND THE LAST NAME IS LOMAN.
LOMAN!
DAD -- WILLY LOMAN.
ALL RIGHT. YOU'RE AT -$400.
STILL EARLY.
GO AGAIN.
HODGEPODGE FOR $200,
PLEASE.
JOHN.
WHAT IS JetBlue?
THAT'S THE AIRLINE.
I'LL TAKE PORT FOR $200,
PLEASE.
JOHN.
WHAT IS ACAPULCO?
YES.
STAR BOARDS FOR $200,
PLEASE.
THIS ACTOR/DIRECTOR LOOKS AS IF
HE'S ABOUT TO SHANGHAI A LADY --
RITA HAYWORTH.
JOHN.
WHO IS BOB HOPE?
OH, NO.
JUDY.
WHO IS ORSON WELLES?
YES.
HODGEPODGE FOR $400,
PLEASE.
[ BEEP ]
AND THAT COUNTRY IS SYRIA.
BACK TO YOU, JUDY.
HODGEPODGE FOR $600,
PLEASE.
[ BEEP ]
AND THAT WOULD BE
BIG BEN.
ALISTAIR, I'M SURPRISED YOU
DIDN'T RING IN ON THAT ONE.
JUCK TO YOU.
HODGEPODGE FOR $800.
JOHN.
DY, BAAT IS A NYMPH?
GOOD.
PORT FOR $400, PLEASE.
JOHN.
WHWHAT IS SOUTHAMPTON?
RIGHT.
PORT FOR $600, PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHAT IS CUBA?
CUBA IS RIGHT.
AND THAT PUTS YOU BACK
ON THE PLUS SIDE AND PUTS
YOU IN SECOND PLACE.
AND YOU CAN SET
YOUR SIGNALING DEVICES DOWN
FOR A COUPLE OF MINUTES
BECAUSE WE ARE TAKING A BREAK
FOR THESE IMPORTANT MESSAGES.
[ APPLAUSE ]
JOHN McGEE
IS FROM DALLAS, TEXAS.
HE'S A TRAINING SPECIALIST.
DOES THAT MEAN MILITARY?
YES, IT DOES.
AND YOU SPENT
SOME TIME...
IN THE NAVY. YES, SIR.
IN THE NAVY.
BUT YOU WERE IN IRAQ?
I WAS.
IN OPERATION...
EARLY BEGINNING OF OPERATION
IRAQI FREEDOM IN 2003.
AND WHAT
WERE YOU DOING?
ON MY 28th BIRTHDAY,
I WAS ACTUALLY SPENDING
A LOT OF THAT TIME IN A ,
WEARING CHEMICAL GEAR
AFTER FLYING ALL NIGHT.
SO, IT WAS
A REAL NICE 28th BIRTHDAY.
UH-HUH.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY TO YOU.
THANK YOU.
OKAY.
JUDY STRONG IS A SOCIAL WORKER
FROM WASHINGTON --
BELLEVUE, WASHINGTON,
THE STATE OF WASHINGTON --
WHO USED TO DRIVE CARRIAGES
IN CENTRAL PARK.
YES, I DID.
AND ONE TIME, MY HORSE
AND CARRIAGE RAN AWAY FROM ME
DOWN CENTRAL PARK SOUTH,
AND I SAW I COULDN'T CATCH UP.
AND THERE WAS
AN EMPTY CAB ON THE CORNER,
SO I JUMPED INTO THE CAB
AND I SAID, "FOLLOW THAT HORSE!"
[ LAUGHTER ]
GOOD FOR YOU.
ALISTAIR BELL.
HE WAS BORN IN ENGLAND.
HE'S NOW FROM BERLIN,
MASSACHUSETTS.
AND IT SAYS HERE
THAT YOU DIDN'T MIND THE GAP.
NOW, TELL THE FOLKS
WHAT THE GAP IS.
WELL, AT LONDON TUBE STATIONS,
THERE IS OFTEN A FAIRLY BIG
BETWEEN THE TRAIN
AND THE PLATFORM,
AND YOU HAVE TO BE CAREFUL
WHEN YOU GET ON.
I DIDN'T.
WERE YOU
ON YOUR CELLPHONE?
I WAS TOO BUGAP
LKING ON
WERE YOU
MY CELLPHONE, AND I FELL DOWN.
THANKFULLY, I MANAGED TO GET UP
BEFORE THE TRAIN LEFT.
GOOD FOR YOU,
'CAUSE IF YOU HAD FALLEN DOWN
BEFORE OR AFTER THE TRAIN LEFT,
YOU'D BE SITTING DOWN THERE,
NOT DOING TOO WELL.
NO. ALL RIGHT. JUDY,
YOU ARE IN COMMAND OF THE BOARD.
YOU MAKE THE NEXT SELECTION,
PLEASE.
STAR BOARDS FOR $400,
JOHN BONHAM,
DRUMMER OF THIS ROCK GROUP,
IS ON THE STAIRWAY TO
"STARSHIP," THEIR TOUR PLANE.
JOHN.
WHAT IS LED ZEPPELIN?
YEAH.
PORT FOR $800, PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHAT IS FIJI?
OH, NO.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS TAHITI?
TAHITI. YES.
I'LL GO FOR ORDINAL NUMBERS
FOR $400, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS FIRST LIEUTENANT?
CORRECT.
ORDINALS FOR $600, PLEASE.
JOHN.
WHAT IS A FIFTH WHEEL?
GOOD.
PORT FOR $1,000, PLEASE.
JOHN.
WHAT IS YOKOHAMA?
THAT'S RIGHT.
STAR BOARDS FOR $600,
PLEASE.
IT'S PEPSI C.E.O. ALFRED STEELE
AND THIS ACTRESS.
THE PLANE WILL SURELY NOT BE
HOUSED IN A WIRE "HANGAR."
JUDY.
WHO IS -- OHH.
I'M BLANKING.
OH, THAT'S TOO BAD.
JOHN.
WHO ISCRAWFORD?
CORRECT.
STAR BOARDS FOR $800,
PLEASE.
HERE'S VIVIEN LEIGH
ALONGSIDE THIS HUSBAND,
A BRITISH
STAGE AND SCREEN STAR.
JOAN
HERE'S VIVIEN LEIGH
ALONGSIDJUDY.S HUSBAND,
WHO IS LAURENCE OLIVIER?
YOU ARE RIGHT.
STAR BOARDS FOR $1,000.
NO WAY, JOSé.
THAT'S THIS CUBAN-AMERICAN ACTOR
WITH HIS WIFE, MS. HEPBURN.
[ BEEP ]
AND HER HUSBAND'S NAME
WAS MEL FERRER.
JUDY, PICK AGAIN.
HODGEPODGE FOR $1,000.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS EASTER ISLAND?
YES. RAPA NUI.
ORDINAL NUMBERS FOR $800,
PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS SECOND FIDDLE?
YES.
ORDINALS FOR $1,000, PLEASE.
JOHN.
WHAT IS THE SIXTH MAN AWARD?
GOOD.
$200, PLEASE.
JIMMY?
IN CHARADES, I'M TELLING
THE OTHER PLAYERS
THE ANSWER WILL BE
ONE OF THESE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS A TV SHOW?
RIGHT.
$400, PLEASE.
JOHN.
WHAT IS FREEZE TAG?
FREEZE TAG. GOOD.
GAME FOR $600, PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHAT IS FLAG FOOTBALL?
YES.
I'M GAME FOR $800.
JOHN.
WHAT IS MAD LIBS?
RIGHT.
AND NOW THE LAST CLUE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS CLUEDO?
CLUEDO, YES.
WE'VE HAD
A FEW ENGLISH CLUES
THAT SEEM TO BE
COINCIDENTALLY HELPING YOU OUT.
YOU'RE IN SECOND PLACE.
YOU TRAIL JOHN BY $2,000.
AND JUDY, OF COURSE,
IN THIRD PLACE,
GOES FIRST
WHEN WE COME BACK.
[ APPLAUSE ]
IN THAT FIRST ROUND
IN THE RED.
SHE WANTS TO
TURN IT AROUND I --
THIS DOUBLE JEOPARDY! ROUND.
SO, SHE'LL DEAL WITH...
EACH CORRECT RESPONSE
WILL BEGIN WITH
THAT LETTER OF THE ALPHABET.
ANONOR OF A RE-LAUNCH
OF SOME OF MARVEL'S
MOST POPULAR CHARACTERS...
JUDY.
COMPOSERS FOR $400, ALEX.
JOHN.
WHO IS GERSHWIN?
CORRECT.
GERMAN "E" FOR $400, PLEASE.
JOHN.
O IS EINSTEIN?YES.
GEOGRAPHIC PHRASES FOR $400,
PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS THE DEEP BLUE SEA?
CORRECT.
COMPOSERS FOR $800, PLEASE.
JOHN.
WHO IS STRAUSS?
NO.
JUDY OR ALISTAIR?
[ BEEP ]
FAMOUS
POLISH PIANIST CHOPIN.
BACK TO YOU, AR.
COMPOSERS FOR $1,200,
PLEASE.
[ BEEP ]
THAT COMPOSER IS HANDEL.
GEORGE FRIDERIC HANDEL.
ALISTAIR.
[ SIGHS ]
I THINK
WE NEED TO GO SOMEWHERE ELSE.
GEOGRAPHIC PHRASES FOR $800,
PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHAT IS A CROSSROADS?
GOOD.
GEOGRAPHIC PHRASES
FOR $1,200.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS NO-MAN'S-LAND?
RIGHT.
$1,600 FOR GEOGRAPHIC,
PLEASE.
[ BEEP ]
AND OULD BE
THE GREAT DIVIDE.
ALISTAIR.
GEOGRAPHIC FOR $2,000,
PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHAT IS A HILL?
CORRECT.
GERMAN "E" FOR $800.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS ELF?
ELF. YES.
GERMAN "E" FOR $1,200,
ALISTAIPLEASE.
JOHN.
WHAT IS EDELWEISS?
CORRECT.
GERMAN "E" FOR $1,600,
PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHAT IS ESSEN?
ESSEN. CORRECT.
GERMAN "E" FOR $2,000.
JOHN.
WHAT IS ERSATZ?
CORRECT.
COMPOSERS FOR $1,600,
PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHO IS BRAHMS?
RIGHT.
COMPOSERS ,000.
ALISTAIR.
WHO IS SMETANA?
GOOD.
WE'LL GO FOR 18th CENTURY
TECHNOLOGY FOR $400, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS A SPINNING JENNY?
YEAH, THAT'S RIGHT.
TECHNOLOGY FOR $800,
PLEASE.
JOHN.
WHO IS BEN FRANKLIN?
RIGHT.
TECHNOLOGY FOR $1,200,
PLEASE.
WHO IS BEN FRANKLIN?
RIGHT.
ALISTAIR.
WHO IS JAMES WATT?
CORRECT.
$1,600, PLEASE.
ANSWER -- DAILY DOUBLE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
YOU ARE NOW TIED WITH JOHN
FOR THE LEAD AT $10,200.
I THINK I SHALL RISK $2,000,
PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT.
HERE'S THE CLUE FOR YOU.
WHAT IS A TUNING FORK?
TUNING FORK. YES.
[ APPLAUSE ]
[ SIGHS ] TECHNOLOGY
FOR $2,000, PL
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS A SEXTANT?
YES.
MEMOIRS FOR $400, PLEASE.
JUDY.
WHO IS REAGAN?
YES.
POLITICAL MEMOIRS FOR $800.
ALISTAIR.
WHO ARE JAMES CARVILLE
AND MARY MATALIN?
CORRECT.
MEMOIRS FOR $1,200, PLEASE.
ANSWER THERE --
THE OTHER DAILY DOUBLE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
WELL,
YOU HAVE A $4,800 LEAD.
I SHALL WAGER $2,000 AGAIN.
ALL RIGHT.
HERE IS THE CLUE.
WHO IS
GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS?
YES.
AND NOW WE HAVE MORE DAILY DOUB.
$1,600, PLEASE.
HERE'S THE NEXT CLUE.
JOHN.
WHO IS SHULTZ?
NO. ALISTAIR.
WHO IS JAMES B
YES.
MEMOIRS FOR $2,000, PLEASE.
WORKING WITH PRESIDENTS
FROM NIXON TO CLINTON,
THIS COMMENTATOR WROTE
"EYEWITNESS TO POWER."
JUDY.
WHO IS BRODER?
NO.
JOHN.
WHO IS GERGEN?
DAVID GERGEN. YES.
FOR $2,000.
WE'LL GO $
HE WAS
ONCE THE INCREDIBLE,
BUT NOW HE'S
THE INDESTRUCTIBLE THIS.
JOHN.
WHAT IS THE HULK?
YEAH.
MARVEL FOR $2,000, PLEASE.
MARVEL PROMISES
ALL-NEW CHIMICHANGAS
FOR THIS MERCENARY,
ALSO KNOWN AS WADE WILSON.
[ BEEP ]
CHARACTER IS DEADPOOL.
JOHN, BACK TO YOU.
MARVEL FOR $1,600, PLEASE.
TRAILING A GOD KILLER,
THOR VISITS
NOT ONLY VIKING TIMES,
BUT THIS REALM
OF THE NORSE GODS.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS VALHALLA?
NO, SORRY.
JUDY OR JOHN?
[ BEEP ]
VISITING ASGARD.
VALHALLA IS THE ROOM
WHERE THEY WERE GREETED.
JOHN, BACK TO YOU.
$1,200, PLEASE.
AN IS
THIS BILLIONAIRE CRIME FIGHTER
WHO SPORTS
A NEW SUIT OF ARMOR
IN EACH OF
THE FIRST FIVE NEW ISSUES.
ALISTAIR.
WHO IS TONY STIRON M
YES. AND NOW
THE LAST CLUE.
SUE AND REED'S KIDS
ARE PART OF THE FUN
WHEN THIS ALLITERATIVE GROUP
EMBARKS ON ITS EPIC JOURNEY.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS THE FANTASTIC FOUR?
CORRECT.
AND THAT TAKES YOU
UP TO $19,000.
CLOSE TO A RUNAWAY,
BUT NOT QUITE.
SO IT'S COMING DOWN
TO FINAL JEOPARDY!
AND HERE IS THE CATEGORY --
OLYMPIC GOLD MEDALISTS.
CLUE IN A MOMENT.
YOU NOTICE SOMETHING DIFFERENT
ABOUT THESE TOYS?
THE PRICES ARE SO LOW.
ARE WE DREAMING?
I GOT AN IDEA.
KICK ME IN THE SHIN.
IF I FEEL IT,
WE KNOW THE PRICES ARE REAL.
YEP, THEY'RE REAL.
WE'VE GOT MORE ROLLBACKS ON TOYS
ALL DECEMBER.
WAIT, WAS THAT REAL?
nnouncer ]
THIS CHRISTMAS, GET
THE HOTTEST BRANDS
AND ROLLBACKS
ON THE SEASON'S HOTTEST TOYS,
LIKE THE BEYBLADE
DESTROYER DOME,
ONLY $34.96,
THE NERF ELITE
HAILFIRE, ONLY $29.88
OR SELECT PLAYDOH SETS.
ALL BACKED
BY OUR LOW PRICE GUARANTEE.
AMERICA'S GIFT HEADQUARTERS.
Walmart.
ALL BACKED
BY OUR LOW PRICE GUARANTEE.
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the pol spin.
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
Let's keep Mliticae...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
$19,000 FOR HIM, AS HE LEADS
GOING INTO FINAL JEOPARDY!
DEALING WITH
OLYMPIC GOLD MEDALISTS.
HERE IS THE CLUE.
30 SECONDS.
GOOD LUCK, PLAYERS.
IN FACT, HE WAS
THE FIRST ATHLETE EVER TO WIN
FIVE OLYMPIC GOLD MEDALS.
WE COME TO YOU, JUDY.
DID YOU COME UP
WITH THE RIGHT NAME?
YOU WROTE DOWN,
"WHO IS ERIC HANSEN?"
OH, BOO HISS.
NOT RIGHT. GONNA COST YOU.
$2,800.
DROPPING YOU TO $2,000.
WE GO TO JOHN McGEE,
NEXT TO YOU.
WHAT DID HE WRITE DOWN?
"WHO WAS SMITH?"
MUCH? $9,001.
YOU'RE DROPPING
ALL THE WAY DOWN TO $1,999.
AND WE COME
TO ALISTAIR BELL.
AND HIS HOW SE
TO OUR CLUE WAS...
NOBODY.
WHO IS --
JUDY WAS CLOSEST.
SHE WAS
ON THE RIGHT TRACK.
IT'S ERIC HEIDEN.
ERIC HEIDEN, THE SPEED SKATER.
I'M SURE YOU WERE
THINKING OF HIM.
YOU DIDN'T COME UP WITH
THE RIGHT NAME.
ALISTAIR,
WHAT DID YOU LOSE?
$3,001.
RE STILL THE CHAMP.
YOU PICK UP $15,999 TODAY.
AND YOU HAVE
A 2-DAY TOTAL OF $29,199,
AND YOU GET TO WRAP UP THE WEEK
WITH US TOMORROW RIGHT HERE.
HOPE YOU WILL, TOO.
[ APPLAUSE ]
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
-- Captions by VITAC --
www.vitac.com
T.
THERE ARE FIVE T's.
PICK UP THAT WILD CARD!
OH, YEAH, BABY!
WHOO-HOO! WILD CARD!
WHEEL...
OF...
FORTUNE!
LADIES AND GEN,
PAT SAJAK AND VANNA WHITE.
HI, EVERYBODY.
HOW YOU DOING?
THANK YOU, JIM.
OUR WALK IS OVER.
OKAY.
WE'RE
PERFECTLY LINED UP.
OH, GO.
GOT TO RUN.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
HI. HOW YOU DOING?
GOOD TO SEE
YOUR SMILING FACES.
GET READY. WE'LL GIVE AWAY
SOME MONEY HERE.
$1,000
IN OUR FIRST "TOSS UP."
THE CATEGORY IS
"PROPER NAME."
$1,000
IN OUR FIRST "TOSS UP."
[ BELL CHIMES ]
AND IT'S SARA.
PONY EXPRESS.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.