ARE KELLY
RIPA AND MICHAEL STRAHAN!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
♪
KELLY: THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
HI!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: FRIDAY, DECEMBER 14,
2012.
WHAT A CROWD!
MICHAEL: YEAH!
KELLY: OH MY GOSH.
MICHAEL: YOU CAN TELL IT'S
FRIDAY.
KELLY: IT IS SO FRIDAY
BACKSTAGE.
LET ME TELL YOU HOW FRIDAY IT
IS.
IT IS SO FRIDAY THAT 10 SECONDS
BEFORE THE SHOW, NEITHER ONE OF
US HAD OUR CLOTHES ON.
[LAUGHTER]
I MEAN, SEPARATELY IN OUR OWN
DRESSING ROOMS, BUT THEY'RE LIKE
PLEASE, WE HAVE A SHOW TO DO.
AND I'M JUST SORT OF BUTTONING
MY TOP KIND OF, SORT OF KIND OF
PUTTING MY SHOES ON.
AND THEN I WAS LIKE, WELL, I
KNOW MICHAEL'S GOING TO BE
WAITING FOR ME.
HE WAS IN LOCKDOWN TOO.
HE WAS LIKE, JUST GOT TO PUT
DOWN THE PANTS.
MICHAEL: I WAS LATE, I WAS LATE.
ACTUALLY I WAS TALKING TO KERRY
WASHINGTON'S PARENTS.
KELLY: YEAH, I SAW THEM
BACKSTAGE.
MICHAEL: VERY NICE PEOPLE.
DAD'S A BIG GIANTS FAN, SO YOU
KNOW I LOVE HIM.
KELLY: HOW NICE.
MICHAEL: WE WERE HAVING A LITTLE
CONVERSATION, JUST BACK THERE
TALKING TO THE FOLKS, YOU KNOW.
I HAD A GREAT NIGHT LAST NIGHT.
KELLY: TELL ME WHAT DID YOU DO?
MICHAEL: REMEMBER CHRIS TUCKER
WAS HERE FOR "SILVER LININGS
PLAYBOOK."
AND HE SAID I'M GOING TO PLAY AT
THE
>>> GOOD AFTERNOON TO ALL OF
YOU.
I'M DIANE SAWYER HERE IN NEW
YORK.
WE DO HAVE THE BREAKING NEWS OF
A SHOOTING AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
YOU HEARD THAT RIGHT.
IT'S UNTHINKABLE.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
45 MILES SOUTHWEST OF HARTFORD.
WE KNOW AT LEAST THREE VICTIMS
ARE IN THE HOSPITAL AT THIS HOUR
IN VERY SERIOUS CONDITION.
WE KNOW THERE WAS AT LEAST ONE
GUNMAN, NOW CONFIRMED DEAD.
THE SCHOOL IS STILL ON LOCKDOWN.
S.W.A.T. TEAMS HAVE BEEN ON THE
SCENE.
WE HAVE SEEN THE IMAGES OF THE
CHILDREN BEING WHISKED OUT OF
THE SCHOOL BY THEIR TEEMPS AND
TAKEN TO A FIRE STATION NEARBY.
I SPOKE TO THE MOTHER OF A BOY
IN THE FIRE STATION.
TWO PARENTS RECEIVED THE JOYFUL
NEWS OF RELIEF AND THOSE WHO ARE
STILL IN DOUBT ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN.
SHE GOT THE GOOD NEWS THAT HER
7-YEAR-OLD SON WAS ALL RIGHT.
HERE'S WHAT SHE HAD TO SAY.
DID THEY GIVE YOU ANY SENSE WHEN
YOU GOT THERE, YOU GO TO THE
FIRE DEPARTMENT AREA WHAT HAD
HAPPENED?
WHAT DID THEY TELL YOU?
>> NO, NOBODY IS GIVING -- NO
OFFICIALS ARE GIVING US ANY
INFORMATION.
THERE'S A PARENT I KNOW WHO
HAPPENED TO BE IN THE BUILDING
AT THE TIME.
SHE'S PRETTY BROKEN UP.
SHE WAS IN A MEETING WITH THE
PRINCIPAL AND SOME OTHER PEOPLE.
THEY HEARD SHOOTING.
THEY GOT UP, WENT OUT.
SHE HAD STAYED IN THE CONFERENCE
ROOM AND MY UNDERSTANDING FROM
HER IS THE PRINCIPAL AND OTHER
PEOPLE GOT SHOT.
WHEN THEY WENT OUT INTO THE
HALLWAY.
SHE WAS THE ONE WHO CALLED 911.
>> YOU TALKED TO THE PERSON WHO
CALLED 911?
>> YES.
SHE SAID THERE WAS HUNDREDS OF
SHOTS, IT SOUNDED LIKE.
>> HUNDREDS OF SHOTS?
>> THAT'S WHAT SHE SAID.
>> AND WHERE THERE FAMILIES
THERE WHO DON'T KNOW WHERE THEIR
CHILDREN ARE?
>> YES, YES, THERE ARE STILL
FAMILIES HERE WHO DO NOT KNOW
WHERE THEIR CHILDREN ARE.
>> AND WHERE THEY GIVING THEM
ANY INFORMATION AT ALL?
ARE THERE STILL CHILDREN --
>> THERE'S NO INFORMATION FOR
THOSE PARENTS.
THE KIDS WHO WERE EVACUATED WERE
IN THE FIRE DEPARTMENT HOUSE.
THEY -- AS THEY HAVE BEEN TAKING
ATTENDANCE, THEY'VE BEEN
CHECKING KIDS OUT TO THEIR
PARENTS.
THERE ARE STILL PARENTS HERE WHO
DO NOT HAVE THEIR CHILDREN AND
HAVE NO IDEA AND THEY'RE NOT
BEING TOLD ANYTHING.
>> WHAT WAS YOUR THOUGHT WHEN
YOU GOT THIS CALL?
IT IS UNIMAGINABLE.
WHAT WAS YOUR THOUGHT?
>> I JUST -- I COULDN'T BELIEVE
IT.
THIS IS SUCH A -- WE JUST MOVED
HERE A YEAR AND A HALF AGO FROM
PROVIDENCE, LIVING IN AN URBAN
AREA.
WE THOUGHT WE WERE COMING TO A
MUCH SAFER, SECURE PLACE.
NEVER WOULD THINK SOMETHING LIKE
THIS WOULD HAPPEN HERE.
IT'S A LARGE TOWN WITH A
SMALLTOWN FAMILY FEEL.
THIS IS JUST UNIMAGINABLE.
AND JUST -- VERY SCARED, WORRIED
ABOUT MY SON, THE OTHER KIDS I
KNOW HERE.
UM -- AND STILL JUST REALLY --
IN SHOCK.
>> WHAT IS IT YOU'RE GOING TO
SAY TO YOUR SON ABOUT THIS?
HAVE YOU THOUGHT ABOUT THAT YET?
>> I HAVE NOT.
I HAVE NOT THOUGHT ABOUT THAT
YET.
AND I -- I MEAN, MY DAUGHTER IS
IN PRESCHOOL DOWN THE STREET.
I KNOW THE PRESCHOOL IS IN
LOCKDOWN.
I HAVE AN ORLANDO SLDE EER SON
INTERMEDIATE SCHOOL IN LOCKDOWN.
>> THANK YOU FOR CALLING IN.
THANKS HEAVEN YOUR CHILDREN ARE
ALL RIGHT.
WE SEND YOU LOVE AND ALL OF OUR
THOUGHTS FOR THE DAYS AHEAD.
THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
>> AND AGAIN, WE WANT TO STRESS,
THERE'S SO MUCH STILL
UNCONFIRMED.
THIS IS STILL A MOVING
SITUATION.
LET'S CHECK IN WITH OUR JUSTICE
DEPARTMENT CORRESPONDENT, PIERRE
THOMAS.
HE'S BEEN TALKING TO HIS SOURCE
THERE IS.
WHAT ARE THEY SAYING?
>> THE FBI AND THE BUREAU OF
ALCOHOL, TOBACCO, AND FIRE ARMS,
HAVE SENT PEOPLE TO THE SCENE.
IT'S AN ACTIVE SCENE.
ONE OFFICIAL SAID THE SHOOTER IS
DEAD.
THAT TWO FIRE ARMS HAVE BEEN
RECOVERED.
AGAIN, A LARGE NUMBER OF FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES ARE COMING TO THE
SCENE.
THAT SUGGESTS THERE IS A LOT TO
INVESTIGATE.
THEY'RE BEING VERY CAREFUL
TALKING ABOUT VICTIMS.
ONE OFFICIAL SAID HE HAD BEEN
TOLD OF TWO CHILDREN INJURED IN
SOME FASHION.
THEY'RE TRYING TO GET ADDITIONAL
INFORMATION FROM THE LOCAL
AUTHORITIES BEFORE THEY GIVE OUT
INFORMATION.
THEY'RE TRYING TO MAKE SLURE TH
SCHOOL IS CLEAR.
THERE'S A LOT OF EVIDENCE TO GO
THROUGH.
THE MAIN THING IS TO MAKE SURE
PEOPLE GET SAFE.
>> YES, ESPECIALLY THOSE
CHILDREN WITH ALL THE PARENTS
WAITING FOR THEM.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, PIERRE.
YOU'LL BE CHECKING ON ADULTS AND
THEIR CONDITIONS AND WHAT WE
HAVE BEEN HEARING AS WELL AS ANY
INJURED CHILDREN.
AND -- IT'S WORTH SAYING ONCE
AGAIN THAT WE KNOW WE ARE IN
THESE TIMES, 2 SN1/2 DAYS AFTER
THE SHOOTING AT THE MALL IN
PORTLAND, OREGON.
BY OUR CALCULATION, AT LEAST 31
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS SINCE COLUMBINE
IN 1999.
IT IS A TRULY TRAGIC REPORT
COMING OUT OF CONNECTICUT TODAY.
AND WE'RE GOING TO BE TRACKING
ALL OF THESE BREAKING DETAILS.
ON THE SHOOTING THROUGHOUT THE
DAY AT ABCNEWS.COM.
CHECK IN WITH US.
WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED ON THE
LAITS AS WE RECEIVE AND CONFIRM
THE NEWS.
WE'LL HAVE A FULL KNOW HOW
EVERYBODY HAS THEIR PRESENTS
UNDER THE TREE?
WELL, WE HAD OUR PRESENTS SORT
OF LIKE STACKED UP AGAINST THE
WALL, BECA
WALL, BECAUSE OUR TREE WAS ON
LIKE THIS, WE JUST USED THE TREE
SKIRT TO COVER THE GIANT BIN
THAT THE TREE WAS IN.
THEN MY FATHER REPLANTS IT IN
THE FRONT YARD, BECAUSE ISN'T IT
LOVELY WE DIDN'T KILL A TREE, WE
SAVED A TREE?
WELL, LOW AND BEHOLD, MY FATHER
HAD TO EVENTUALLY MOVE THE TREE
THREE TIMES AND THEN CUT IT DOWN
BECAUSE IT WAS KILLING THE
PLUMBING IN OUR HOUSE.
[LAUGHTER]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: THE TREE DEVOURED OUR
HOUSE!
MICHAEL: BUT EVERY YEAR HE WOULD
DIG UP THAT SAME TREE EVERY
YEAR?
OR GO BUY NEW TREES?
HOW MANY TREES IN YOUR FRONT
YARD?
KELLY: NO, NO THAT WAS THE ONLY
TIME HE DID THA BOUGHT AN ATHEN
BECAUSE THIS IS BACK BREAKING
WORK, I CAN'T DO THAT.
BUT THE TREE HE PLANTED KEPT
GROWING AND GROWING.
AND HE KEPT HAVING TO MOVE IT
AND MOVE IT.
AND EVENTUALLY, IT WAS LIKE THE
TREE THAT ATE OUR LIVES.
AND THEN, HE INVESTED IN THE
AXE.
MICHAEL: OH.
KELLY: IT WAS LIKE A SCENE FROM
"MOMMY DEAREST."
KELLY!
BRING ME THE AXE!
MICHAEL: WE HAD A FAKE TREE LONG
BEFORE THEY WERE INVOGUE.
WE HAD REAL TREES.
MY PARENTS WERE LIKE I'M TIRED
OF CLEANING IT UP.
SO WE ENDED UP GETTING A FAKE
TREE.
THE PAINFUL THING ABOUT THE FAKE
TREES, OR ANY TREE, TRYING TO
CONNECT ALL THOSE LIGHTS, THEN
YOU GET THE ONES THAT DON'T
LIGHT UP AND YOU'RE FOLLOWING
THROUGH THE TREE.
THIS IS A PAIN.
KELLY: I REMEMBER MY AUNT AND
UNCLE, THEY HAD, THEY WERE
REALLY, I FELT, THEY WERE VERY
HIGH FALLUTTING, A REAL TREE IN
THE UPSTAIRS FORM ROOM, AND THEN
IN THE DEN, IN THE KID'S WRECK
ROOM, THEY HAD ONE OF THOSE
TREES THAT WERE BIG IN THE
1970'S, LIKE, NOT -- ALUMINUM,
THANK YOU.
AN ALUMINUM TREE.
IT WAS BLUE ALUMINUM.
I WAS LIKE THIS IS WHAT HEAVEN
MUST BE LIKE!
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: A BLUE ALUMINUM TREE.
KELLY: AND THEY HAD A POOL
TABLE.
I WAS LIKE, I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
LE DID BUT I WAS SURE HE
WAS A ROCKEFELLER.
MICHAEL: MY COUSIN HAD A WATER
BED, I WAS LIKE YOU ARE LIVING
THE DREAM!
YOU ARE LIVING THE DREAM!
[LAUGHTER]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: YES, RIGHT?
MICHAEL: OH YEAH, ALWAYS THE
LITTLE THINGS.
KELLY: MY COUSIN HAD, MY UNCLE
MADE HIM A "STAR WARS" BED.
A "STAR WARS" BED.
I WAS LIKE CONVINCED THEY WERE
ROYALTY AND I WASN'T SURE HOW WE
WERE RELATED TO THEM!
MICHAEL: THEN I ALSO REMEMBER,
SINCE WE'RE BACK IN THAT ERA, I
FEEL LIKE I'M IN THE WINTER
PAGEANT TALKING ABOUT THE
DIFFERENT ERAS.
BUT I REMEMBER, YOU PUSH THE
INTERCOM BUTTON AND YOU CAN
TALK, BUT YOU COULDN'T
UNDERSTAND WHAT IT WAS SAYING.
BUT THE FACT THEY HAD ONE.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE, WHAT -- BUT IT
JUST LOOKS SO COOL.
PICKING IT UP.
KELLY: NO, YOU'RE RIGHT GELMAN,
WE DO HAVE ALUMINUM TREES HERE
RED AND SILVER.
AND I REALIZE THEY'RE NOT QUITE
AS HIGH FALLUTTING.
GELMAN: THEY HAVE FESTIVE.
KELLY: YES.
TREE IN THE DEN , TO HAVE
NEXT TO YOUR POOL TABLE MEANT
THAT YOU WERE WELL OFF.
THAT'S ALL I'M GOING TO SAY.
THANK YOU LADIES.
MICHAEL: THANK YOU.
SHE'S ONE OF THE WELL OFF FROM
THE 1970'S.
KELLY: SHE'S LIKE IT IS TRUE, WE
DID HAVE THAT.
WE HAD THIS ARTICLE THAT I
WANTED TO TELL YOU ABOUT,
BECAUSE, ARE THERE ANY LA TINA
WOMEN HERE IN THE AUDIENCE
TODAY?
OH, LISTEN TO THIS.
THERE'S A MAN, ALL HE WANTS FOR
CHRISTMAS IS ALA TINO
GIRLFRIEND.
HE LIVES IN SAN DIEGO, HE'S A
MULTIMILLIONAIRE, AND HE'S TAKEN
OUT AN AD, A BILLBOARD.
HE'S A REAL ESTATE INVESTOR,
WORTH $200 MILLION.
MICHAEL: HEY, I'LL GO OUT WITH
YOU!
[LAUGHTER]
ELLY: NOW LISTEN LADIES, I I WO
REALIZE HE'S RECEIVED OVER
15,000 EMAILS OFFERING HIM
COMPANIONSHIP.
BUT THE BILLBOARD HAS BEEN
PULLED DOWN BY VANDALS SINCE IT
WAS ERECTED A WEEK AGO.
AGREE THIS IST SAID.LL
ADORABLE.
MICHAEL: FOR ALL YOU LATINA
WOMEN OUT THERE.
IF HE HAS $200 MILLION AND CAN'T
GET A WOMAN, THERE'S ANOTHER
PROBLEM.
THAT'S ALL I'M SAYING.
[LAUGHTER]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: THAT'S ALL I'M SAYING.
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T SAY, OH,
THEY'RE ALL GOLD DIGGERS, YOU'RE
TELLING THEM HOW MUCH MONEY
YOU'VE GOT.
SOMETHING WRONG.
KELLY: CAN I SAY ONE THING?
HE'S GOT AN EMAIL, CAN I GIVE
OUT HIS EMAIL ADDRESS FOR THE
WOMEN?
IT'S ON THE BILLBOARD, IT'S
PUBLIC.
MICHAEL: WHY NOT, LET IT GO.
KELLY: I THINK THAT THE EMAIL IS
REALLY AMAZING.
A CHRISTMAS LATINA AT AOL.COM.
AND THE C AND THE L ARE
CAPITOLS.
JUST IN CASE, IT DOESN'T MATTER,
OH, IT DOESN'T MATTER?
OH.
SO YOU CAN EMAIL HIM.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THEY'RE WRITING IT DOWN.
MICHAEL: WOULD YOU REALLY WRITE
IN?
I'M JUST CURIOUS.
KELLY: SHE'S WAITING FOR YOU.
MICHAEL: SHE'S WAITING FOR ME.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: YOU HAD $200 MILLION TOO.
MICHAEL: I TELL YOU RIGHT NOW IF
I HAD $200 MILLION, I WOULDN'T
BE ON THE BILLBOARD, I TELL YOU
THAT
KELLY: HE WOULD BE ERECTING THE
BILLBOARD ON HIS OWN PRIVATE
ISLAND.
MICHAEL: EXACTLY.
KELLY: I HAVE $200 MILLION AND
THERE'S A MIRROR.
MICHAEL: AND I DON'T WANT
NOBODY!
KELLY: HEY, ON THE SHOW TODAY,
EWAN MCGREGOR FROM THE NEW FILM
"THE IMPOSSIBLE."
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: THE VERY TALENTED STAR
OF "SCANDAL," KERRY WASHINGTON
IS HERE.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
SHE'S ALSO IN THE NEW FILM
"DJANGO UNCHAINED."
KELLY: SO GORGEOUS.
MICHAEL: BEAUTIFUL.
KELLY: GORGEOUS.
AND OUR HOLIDAY HITS WEEK
CONCLUDES WITH A PERFORMANCE
FROM JACKIE EVANCHO, SHE WAS
WARMING UP TODAY HERE IN THE
STUDIO, AND I HAD MY BREATH
SUCKED OUT OF ME.
SHE IS THAT TALENTED.
SHE'S 12 YEARS OLD.
12, OK?
CRAZY.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
MICHAEL: LIKE 8:00 OR SOMETHING?
KELLY: YEAH.
MICHAEL: THAT WASN'T HER, THAT
WAS ME.
KELLY: THAT'S FUNNY, I THOUGHT
THAT WAS JACKIE.
YEAH, I DIDN'T REALIZE YOU COULD
GET IN THAT --
MICHAEL: I WAS IN THE RIGHT YOGA
POSE TO BRING IT OUT OF ME.
RIGHT NOW TIME FOR OUR HOLIDAY
TRAVEL TRIVIA.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
♪
KELLY: TODAY'S TRIVIA DANCER IS
COREY FROM BROOKLYN, NEW YORK.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: BROOKLYN!
LOVE THE HAT, I LOVE THE HAT.
YOU GOT TO SAY BROOKLYN!
LET IT OUT.
KELLY: WHERE BROOKLYN AT?
WHERE, WHERE, WHERE BROOKLYN AT?
WHAT?
SOMETIMES IT JUST COMES OUT OF
ME.
JANET IS ON THE PHONE FROM
CHICAGO, ILLINOIS.
HEY JANET.
KATIE: HI, HOW ARE YOU?
MICHAEL: HEY JANET, WHAT ARE YOU
UP TO THIS WEEKEND?
KATIE: WELL, RIGHT ACROSS FROM
SOLDIER FIELD AGAINST THE YUCKY
PACKERS.
MICHAEL: ARE YOU GOING TO THE
CAME?
>> NO, I WATCHED IN MY LIVING
ROOM AND I CAN SEE THE FANS
BEFORE THE GAME ON TV.
KELLY: YOU LIVE THAT CLOSE?
CALLER: YES.
KELLY: DO YOU SELL YOUR DRIVE
WAY FOR A PARKING SPACE?
CALLER: NO.
MICHAEL: NEXT YEAR.
KELLY: SOMETHING TO THINK ABOUT.
I'LL SPEND THE WHEEL AND SEE
WHAT YOU'RE PLAYING FOR, OK?
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: OH, YOU'RE PLAYING FOR A
GREAT PRIZE.
THE GUEST RANCH IN TUCSON,
ARIZONA.
WHICH REMINDS ME ABOUT A TV SHOW
I SAW LAST NIGHT.
SEVEN DAYS, SIX NIGHTS.
ANYBODY SEE "RATTLE SNAKE
REPUBLIC"?
NO?
ALL RIGHT.
DON'T ANYWAY.
IT'S YOUR WORST NIGHTMARE.
TUCSON, ARIZONA, SEVEN DAYS, SIX
NIGHTS, IT'S VALUED AT $8600.
YOU HAVE 20 SECONDS AND ONLY ONE
GUESS.
GOOD LUCK.
CALLER: THANK YOU.
MICHAEL: ON YESTERDAY'S SHOW, WE
TALKED WITH ACTOR DON JOHNSON.
WHAT CONCERT DID DON SAY HE
WOULD BE ATTENDING FOR HIS
BIRTHDAY ON SATURDAY?
CALLER: THE ROLLING STONES!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: CONGRATULATIONS, YOU
AND A GUEST WILL ENJOY SIX DAYS,
SEVEN NIGHTS.
EXPERIENCE AUTHENTIC DINING,
UNPARALLELED AMENITIES AND AN
ABUNDANCE OF ACTIVITIES.
IT'S A ONCE IN A LIFETIME
EXPERIENCE THAT CAN BE ENJOYED
BY ALL.
YOUR PRIZE IS VALUED AT $8600.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: HEY JANET,
CONGRATULATIONS.
GOOD FOR YOU.
CALLER: THANK YOU SO MUCH!
KELLY: NOW YOU GET TO HELP MAKE
THE DAY OF A LUCKY MEMBER OF OUR
STUDIO AUDIENCE WHO WILL RECEIVE
EIGHT PLACE SETTINGS FROM LENNOX
VALUED AT MORE THAN $500.
SO PLEASE PICK A NUMBER BETWEEN
1-235.
CALLER: I WILL PICK 16.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: CONGRATULATIONS JANET,
CONGRATULATIONS MA'AM!
EVERYBODY STAY RIGHT THERE,
NEXT, EWAN MCGREGOR.
ANNOUNCER: STILL AHEAD ON
"LIVE," "SCANDAL" STAR KERRY
WASHINGTON.
OUR HOLIDAY HITS LIST CONCLUDES
WITH A PERFORMANCE BY JACKIE
EVANCHO.
AND COMING UP NEXT, EWAN
MCGREGOR.
IN  JUST MADE IT BACK IN
TIME.
I KNOW, THANK YOU.
YOU LIKE THAT?
OH, THANK YOU.
LADY LIKES MY SHOES.
HEY, ON MONDAY'S SHOW, PAUL RUDD
WILL BE HERE FROM THE NEW FILM
"THIS IS 40."
MICHAEL: SAW IT LAST WEEK.
KELLY: HE'S REALLY GREAT.
MICHAEL: YEAH, MY OLD NEIGHBOR
ALSO.
ALSO, CHRISTOPH WALTZ IS HERE
FROM THE NEW FILM "DJANGO
UNCHAINED."
KELLY: AND WE BEGIN OUR
COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS, THIS I
LOVE, IT'S HOLIDAY ETIQUETTE
WITH LIZZY POPE.
SHE'S GOING TO TEACH US HOW TO
BEHAVE DURING THE HOLIDAYS SO WE
ARE NOT MONSTERS AND BEASTS.
HE'S ONE OF HOLLYWOOD'S MOST
TALENTED AND SOUGHT AFTER
ACTORS.
PLEASE WELCOME BACK TO THE SHOW
EWAN MCGREGOR.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: EWAN, I LOVE YOUR
TROUSERS.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
KELLY: FANTASTIC.
>> THAT'S KIND, THANK YOU.
KELLY: SO OF COURSE WE'VE GONE
OVER THIS BEFORE, YOU'RE
ORIGINALLY FROM SCOTLAND.
HOW DO YOU CELEBRATE THE
HOLIDAYS IN SCOTLAND?
IS THERE A BIG TRADITIONS THAT
YOU DO?
IS THERE A FATHER CHRISTMAS
THING?
WHAT DO YOU DO?
>> THE BIGGEST CELEBRATION IN
SCOTLAND IN THE CHRISTMAS PERIOD
IS NEW YEAR'S.
WE CALL IT HOGMANMY.
THERE'S LOTS OF OLD FASHIONED
TRADITIONS ABOUT IT.
ONE OF WHICH IS THE FIRST PERSON
INTO YOUR HOUSE AFTER MIDNIGHT
HAS TO, SUPPOSED TO BE A TALL,
DARK STRANGER.
MICHAEL: HEY!
[LAUGHTER]
>> MAYBE, MAYBE YOU COULD BE THE
GUY.
KELLY: MICHAEL WOULD LIKE TO
VOLUNTEER FOR THE JOB.
MICHAEL: I COULD PROBABLY CLEAN
UP IN THE RENTAL BUSINESS.
JUST RENT ME.
>> YOU WOULD BE FINE.
AND SORT OF OPEN HOUSE, OR IT
USED TO ALWAYS BE.
AND THE TALL, DARK STRANGER IS
MEANT TO COME WITH A LUMP OF
COAL, WHICH I DON'T REMEMBER THE
REASON FOR AND A BOTTLE OF
WHISKY.
AND YOU LITERALLY AT
GO FROM HOUSE TO HOUSE, GIVE
PEOPLE A DRINK FROM YOUR BOTTLE.
ONE YEAR MY GRANDFATHER WENT OUT
TO GET COAL FOR THE FIRE BECAUSE
IT WAS RUNNING OUT, MAYBE FIVE
TO MIDNIGHT AND THEN THE BELLS
WENT, IT WAS MIDNIGHT AND HIS
WIFE, MY GRANDMOTHER WOULDN'T
LET HIM BACK IN BECAUSE IT HAS
TO BE A STRANGER, OR AT LEAST
SOMEBODY YOU DON'T KNOW.
[LAUGHTER]
SO HE WAS OUT IN THE COLD SHED,
GOING COME ON!
MICHAEL: STRANGER, PLEASE, ENTER
MY HOUSE.
KELLY: THAT IS INCREDIBLE.
I KIND OF LIKE THAT TRADITION.
IT'S SPOOKY AND UNPREDICTABLE!
>> IT WAS REALLY LOVELY.
I REMEMBER THAT AS A CHILD.
ONLY NIGHT OF THE YEAR WE WERE
ALLOWED TO STAY UP REALLY LATE.
WE WOULD JUST GO FROM HOUSE TO
HOUSE, WE WOULD GO TO DIFFERENT
FRIENDS HOUSES.
KELLY: I'M TRYING TO PICTURE
THAT HAPPENING IN NEW YORK.
PEOPLE GOING FROM HOUSE TO HOUSE
OF PEOPLE YOU DON'T KNOW.
>> COME IN!
KELLY: COME ON IN, EVERYBODY!
MICHAEL: THE NEXT DAY YOU'RE
LIKE MY WATCH IS MISSING.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: ALL OF MY ENTIRE
POSSESSIONS ARE MISSING!
MICHAEL: YOU'RE A BIG
MOTORCYCLE, YOU LOVE
MOTORCYCLES.
>> I DO, YEAH.
MICHAEL: VINTAGE MOTORCYCLES.
RECENTLY DEVELOPED A NEW HOBBY.
>> WELL, I'VE STARTED BUILDING
BIKELES AS SORT OF A PASTTIME
BECAUSE I MADE A FILM CALLED
"PERFECT SENSE" WHICH IS A
LOVELY FILM.
IN IT I'D
BICYCLE , WITH NO FREE WHEEL.
AND I THINK IN NEW YORK, IT
STARTED THE COURIER STARTED
WRITING THESE FIXED GEAR BIKES
WITH NO BRAKES AND IT BECAME
VERY COOL.
NOW THERE'S A WHOLE SUB CULTURE.
SO I GOT REALLY INTO THEM.
THEY'RE SO SIMPLE THAT I STARTED
BUILDING THEM, BECAUSE I LIKE TO
TINKER AWAY AT THINGS.
I'M NOT GOOD ENOUGH TO BUILD
MOTORCYCLES BECAUSE I DON'T HAVE
THE SKILLS, BUT BIKELES ARE SO
MUCH EASIER.
MICHAEL: BUT YOU'RE BUILDING A
BIKE WITH NO BRAKES?
>> WHEN YOU STOP BACKPEDALING,
THE BACK WHEEL STOPS TURNING.
KELLY: OH, THAT SOUNDS LIKE FUN?
DOESN'T THAT SOUND LIKE IT'S
FUN.
MICHAEL: GET YOUR HEART RATE UP.
KELLY: I HOPE THAT'S UNDER THE
TREE THIS YEAR.
[LAUGHTER]
>> IT IS GOOD FUN.
YOU HAVE TO DEVELOP, YOU KNOW,
IT'S LIKE RIDING A SKATEBOARD.
KELLY: YOU SHOULD NOT BE SAYING
THIS ON THE TALK SHOW BECAUSE
THESE FILM COMPANIES ARE NOT
GOING TO WANT TO INSURE YOU.
SO EVERYTHING HE'S SAYING IS
JUST JOKES.
MICHAEL: HE'S ONLY RIDING IN
SECURE AREAS.
>> I DON'T RIDE IT, I JUST BUILD
IT.
KELLY: WE WOULD BE REMISS IF WE
DID NOT CONGRATULATE YOU ON YOUR
GOLDEN GLOBE NOMINATION.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
>> THANK YOU.
KELLY: FOR "SALMON FISHING IN
THE
>> THANK YOU.
KELLY: WE LOVE YOU AROUND HERE,
WE WOULD LOVE TO PLAY A GAME
WITH YOU.
>> LOVE TO.
KELLY: WE CREATED A GAME JUST
FOR YOU CALLED EW-IN OR EW-OUT.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
HERE'S WHAT HAPPENS.
WE'RE GOING TO ASK YOU A SERIES
OF QUESTIONS.
IF IT'S INCORRECT, YOU HAVE TO
GIVE US ALL OF YOUR MONEY.
>> RIGHT.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: EATING BRUSSEL SPROUTS,
IN OR OUT?
>> I'M IN.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: ALL RIGHT, KARAOKE?
>> I'M OUT.
KELLY: OH.
I'M SORRY, YOU WILL HAVE TO
FORFEIT YOUR WATCH.
PEEING IN THE POOL, IN OR OUT?
>> PEEING IN THE --
KELLY: PEEING IN THE POOL.
>> NO, I'M OUT.
COME ON.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: WHERE IS THAT LIE
DETECTOR WE USED FOR YESTERDAY'S
GUEST.
MICHAEL: REGIFTING, IN OR OUT?
>> I'M IN.
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: YEAH.
KELLY: MAN SCAPING?
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT IS.
MICHAEL: TAKE A RAZOR TO YOUR
HAIRY PARTS OF YOU'RE AREA.
>> I'M IN THERE.
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: ALL RIGHT, SKINNY
DIPPING?
>> IN, DEFINITELY.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: ALL THE WAY IN.
DANCING AT WEDDINGS?
>> IN.
KELLY: IN.
MICHAEL: OK, HONEY BOO BOO, YOU
IN, YOU OUT.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS.
MICHAEL: YOU OUT.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: I DON'T KNOW WHAT THAT
MEANS, THAT'S GOOD.
PLASTIC SURGERY?
I'M OUT.
MICHAEL: ROLLER COASTER RIDES?
>> USED TO BE IN, NOW I'M OUT.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: SMALL DOGS?
>> IN.
KELLY: IN?
MICHAEL: KISSING YOUR DOG ON THE
MOUTH?
[LAUGHTER]
YOU IN!
JUST QUICKLY, DON'T LINGER.
KELLY: ARE YOU TELLING ME YOU
WON'T MANSCAPE BUT YOU'LL KISS
THE DOG?
OH, HE DOES MANSCAPE.
>> FROM TIME TO TIME I MANSCAPE.
KELLY: BUT YOU WON'T PEE IN THE
POOL.
>> NO, DEFINITELY NOT.
KELLY: TAKING A BATH, IN OR OUT?
>> IN.
MICHAEL: SPEEDO BATHING SUIT.
>> USED TO BE IN.
[LAUGHTER]
ALWAYS A LITTLE PART OF ME
THAT'S STILL IN.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: WE GOT TO BREAK,
WE GOT TO TAKE A BREAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK WE'RE GOING TO
FIND OUT WHICH A-LIST STAR HAD A
PRIVATE SCREENING OF EWAN'S
MOVIE WHEN WE COME BACK.
ANNOUNCER: STILL AHEAD ON
"LIVE," A PERFORMANCE BY JACKIE
EVANCHO.
ALSO, "SCANDAL" STAR KERRY
WASHINGTON.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: WE'RE BACK WITH THE GREAT
EWAN MCGREGOR.
STAR OF THE VERY TOUGH FILM,
"THE IMPOSSIBLE,COURSE AF
COURSE A TRUE STORY ABOUT THIS
FAMILY THAT WAS CAUGHT IN THE
TSUNAMI IN THAILAND.
>> YES, IN 2004.
IT'S BASED ON A SPANISH FAMILY,
THE PRODUCER AND THE DIRECTOR
HAD THE MOTHER OF THE FAMILY
MARIA TELLING THE STORY ON THE
RADIO AND WERE VERY MOVED BY HER
STORY AND THEN MET HER AND ASKED
HER IF THEY COULD MAKE A MOVIE
OF HER STORY.
SHE WAS VERY RETICENT AT FIRST,
BECAUSE SHE FELT WHY WOULD THEY
HOW MUCH CAN WE SAY TO PEOPLE
THAT WE KNOW THAT IT IS REACHED
THIS SHATTERING LEVEL?
>> THE SITUATION IS VERY FLUID.
BUT WE HAVE BEEN VERY CAREFUL TO
TRY TO TALK TO MANY DIFFERENT
SOURCES AS WE CAN FROM MULTIPLE
AGENCIES, AGAIN, FROM STATE AND
FEDERAL SOURCES WE'RE BEING TOLD
MORE THAN A DOZEN SHOT AND
KILLED AT THE SCHOOL.
OBVIOUSLY, THE PARENTS AND THE
ZOOM COMMUNITY WILL BE NOTIFIED
AS E ADDITIONAL INFORMATION
COMES IN.
BUT MY SOURCES ARE JUST
DEVASTATED.
THEY'RE CALLING IT A TRAGEDY OF
EPIC POR PORTIONS.
>> OF COURSE, THERE ARE ALSO
PEOPLE IN THE HOSPITAL THAT
RIGHT NOW THEY HAVE BEEN TAKEN
INTO EMERGENCY ROOMS WHERE
TALKING ARE WORKING SURE TO MAKE
SURE NO MORE LIVES ARE LOST.
BUT SOME OF THEM ARE SERIOUSLY
INJURED.
THE GUNMAN CONFIRMED DEAD AS WE
SAID EARLIER.
WE'LL KEEP YOU POSTED THROUGHOUT
THE DAY ON THIS CRUSHING EVENT
AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT.
AND ONE OF THE PARENTS RECENTLY
TOLD ME THAT AS THE CHILDREN
WALKED OUT OF THE SCHOOL BY
THEIR TEACHERS, SOME OF THEM
WERE TOLD TO COVER THEIR EYES AS
THEY WALKED AND JUST HOLD ON TO
EACH OTHER.
WE'LL HAVE FULL REPORTS
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
WE'RE ALWAYS THERE OF COURSE AT
ABCNEWS.COM AND I'LL SEE YOU S
SUCH A GORGEOUS FILM AND YOU ARE
PHENOMENAL IN IT.
IT'S "THE IMPOSSIBLE," OPENS IN
SELECT THEATERS ON DECEMBER 21.
EWAN MCGREGOR EVERYBODY!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: NEXT, KERRY WASHINGTON.
ANNOUNCER: MONDAY
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: OUR NEXT GUEST IS THE
BEAUTIFUL AND TALENTED STAR OF
THE SERIES "SCANDAL" AND CAN
ALSO BE SEEN IN THE NEW
TARANTINO FILM "DJANGO
UNCHAINED."
PLEASE WELCOME THE GORGEOUS
KERRY WASHINGTON.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
♪
KELLY: YOU FEEL SO SOFT AND
SMOOTH.
>> I LOVE YOU SO MUCH!
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: SO YOU KNOW, OF COURSE
KERRY IS A BRONX GIRL.
GREW UP RIGHT HERE.
>> IN THE BIG APPLE.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: I LOVE THAT.
>> I LOVE BEING FROM NEW YORK.
AND WE SHOOT "SCANDAL" IN L.A.
SO EVERY TIME I GET TO COME EAST
AND HANG OUT WITH YOU GUYS AND
SEE MY PARENTS, WHO ARE HERE IN
THE FRONT ROW.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: HI, HI.
>> I'M ALWAYS SO HAPPY WHEN I
GET TO COME HERE.
MICHAEL: AND THEY'RE STILL HERE?
>> YEAH, ABSOLUTELY.
KELLY: THAT'S GREAT.
DO YOU STAY WITH THEM?
>> NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
MICHAEL: THAT WOULDN'T WORK?
>> NO, BECAUSE WE HAVE TO
MAINTAIN THE LOVING
RELATIONSHIP.
[LAUGHTER]
SO I STAY IN HOTELS.
KELLY: I TOTALLY GET IT.
IT'S NICE TO BE BACK DURING THIS
TIME OF YEAR WHEN THE CITY'S SO
PRETTY.
>> IT'S SO GORGEOUS, YEAH.
MICHAEL: AND THE SECOND SEASON
OF "SCANDAL," IN ITS CRAZIER
THAN EVER.
>> YEAH!
KELLY: CAN YOU BELIEVE THE
FOLLOWING THIS SHOW HAS?
>> IT'S SO EXCITING.
OUR FANS CALL THEMSELVES
GLADIATORS.
WE LOVE THAT.
EVERY TIME PEOPLE SAY THE SHOW
GETS BETTER AND BETTER, THE
EPISODES ARE MORE AND MORE
EXCITING, THAT'S HOW WE TALK TO
THE WRITERS BECAUSE WE HAVE NO
IDEA WHAT'S HAPPENING WEEK TO
WEEK UNTIL WE GET THAT SCRIPT
AND WE ARE BLOWN AWAY BY OUR
WRITERS.
MICHAEL: THAT'S WHAT YOU SAY
WHEN YOU DON'T WANT PEOPLE TO
COME UP AND ASK YOU WHAT'S GOING
TO HAPPEN.
KELLY: TONY GOLDWYNN IS HERE AND
HE LOVES WORKING WITH YOU.
>> I LOVE TONE YOU, BUT TONY HAS
BEEN MAKING ME LOOK BAD LATELY.
MICHAEL: WHY?
>> BECAUSE IN INTERVIEWS TALK
ABOUT HOW AWKWARD IT IS TO DO
LOVE SCENES.
YOU'RE MAKING OUT IN FRONT OF
STRANGERS, THERE'S LIGHTS
SHINING ON YOU.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE AN ACTRESS.
KELLY: YES, YES, BUT HIS
FAVORITE THING.
[LAUGHTER]
>> HE DOES SAY IT'S AWKWARD, BUT
I GET ON TROUBLE.
KELLY: ON OUR SHOW, HE WAS LIKE
IT IS WHAT I LIVE FOR!
[LAUGHTER]
>> HE IS FANTASTIC.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
COMMERCIAL BTO TAKE A
COMMERCIAL BREAK.
WE WANT TO TALK ABOUT "DJANGO
UNCHAINED" WHEN WE RETURN, OK?
MORE WITH KERRY WASHINGTON.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: THURSDAY ON "LIVE,"
ALSO FROM "DJANGO UNCHAINED,"
ACTOR SAMUEL L. JACKSON.
ANNOUNCER: "LIVE" STARTS THE
OFFICIAL COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS.
KELLY: CAN I
EARLY?
MICHAEL: SURE.
IF YOU CAN GET IT.
ANNOUNCER: NEXT LIVE, PAUL RUDD,
CHRISTOPH WALTZ AND THE INBOX.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: WE ARE BACK WITH KERRY
WASHINGTON, STAR OF "SCANDAL,"
ALSO "DJANGO UNCHAINED."
KELLY: I JUST WISH EVERYBODY AT
HOME COULD SEE WHAT GOES ON HERE
DURING THE COMMERCIAL BREAK.
>> YEAH, BECAUSE YOU GUYS ARE
AMAZING.
THEY'RE SUCH WONDERFUL, GENEROUS
PEOPLE THEY JUST GOT THEMSELVES
INVITED TO THE HOUSE FOR
CHRISTMAS DINNER.
KELLY: OH MY GOD!
HE GOT INVITED AS A GUEST, I GOT
INVITED TO HELP AS A KITCHEN.
>> IT'S FUN, I PROMISE IT'S FUN.
MICHAEL: YOU CAN SPEAK INTO THE
PARTY.
KELLY: I'LL BLEND.
MICHAEL: I'LL BLEND.
"DJANGO UNCHAINED," GREAT
PICTURE, GREAT NEW SHE.
AT THE PREMIERE, QUINN TEEN
TARANTINO SEEMS VERY ENERGETIC.
>> HE'S VERY INSPIRED AND SUCH A
VISIONARY.
SUCH AN HONOR TO WORK WITH
SOMEONE WHO HAS SUCH A UNIQUE
VOICE.
HE CHALLENGED ALL OF US,
DEFINITELY.
THE ACTORS IN THIS FILM, YOU'VE
NEVER SEEN ANY OF US DO WORK
LIKE THIS BEFORE.
LEONARDO, JAMIE FOXX, CHRISTOPH
WALTZ, SAM JACKSON, SOMEHOW I
GOT IN THE MOVIE.
AS A GROUP, EVERYONE'S DOING
PROFOUND.
KELLY: AND IT'S A LOVE STORY,
SET AGAINST THE BACK DROP OF THE
HORRORS OF SLAVERY.
IT'S SUCH AN UNEXPECTED FILM.
>> YEAH, YEAH.
IT KIND OF SOUNDS LIKE IT
WOULDN'T WORK, BECAUSE IT WAL T
IME, BUT THAT'S
ACTUALLY WHAT WORKS ABOUT IT, IS
THAT IT'S TWO TEAM WHO LOVE EACH
OTHER SO MUCH THAT THEY'RE
WILLING TO FACE THE WORST OF THE
WORST IN ORDER TO BE TOGETHER.
KELLY: IT'S A VERY EMOTIONAL
ROLE.
I OFTEN THINK PEOPLE DON'T
REALIZE HOW EXHAUSTING THAT MUST
BE TO GO DAY AFTER DAY, HOUR
AFTER HOUR AND CON JUROR UP
THES
>> YEAH, IT WAS FOR ME THE
HARDEST ROLE I'VE EVER HAD TO
DO, PSYCHOLOGICALLY AND
EMOTIONALLY, FOR SURE.
MICHAEL: WELL, WE HAVE A CLIP,
AND YOUR CHARACTER, BROOM BROOM
HILDA.
>> YES.
MICHAEL: I LOVE THAT, YOUR
CHARACTER'S NAME IS BROOM HILDA.
YOU KNOW ALL OF THE SLAVES GOT
THEIR NAMES FROM THEIR OWNERS.
AND MY CHARACTER WAS OWNED BY A
GERMAN FAMILY BEFORE SHE WAS
SOLD TO THE PLANTATION WHERE SHE
MEETS JAMIE'S CHARACTER.
MICHAEL: YOUR CHARACTER
BRUNHILDA HAS DISCOVERED
SOMETHING IMPORTANT AND IS BEING
QUESTIONED BY SAMUEL L.
JACKSON'S CHARACTER.
>> BABY, YOU NEED TO BE ON HIS
BLIND SIDE.
>> YOU SAY YOU AIN'T --
>> HUH?
>> I SAID, YOU SAID YOU AIN'T
KNOW HIM.
>> I DON'T.
>> YES YOU DO.
>> WHY IS YOU LYING TO ME?
>> I AIN'T.
>> THEN WHY IS YOU CRYING?
>> YOU SCARING ME.
>> WHY IS I SCARING YOU?
>> BECAUSE YOU SCARY.
MICHAEL: BECAUSE YOU SCARY.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: I MEAN, I'M TERRIFIED.
I FOR ONE AM SCARED TO DEATH, I
HAVE GOOSE BUMPS AND I'M
TERRIFIED!
>> THAT SAM JACKSON.
KELLY: YOU ARE INCREDIBLE.
AND WE LOVE HAVING YOU HERE.
>> THANK YOU.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: EVERYBODY, GO OUT AND
CHECK OUT "DJANGO UNCHAINED,"
OPENS NATIONWIDE ON DECEMBER 21
ON CHRISTMAS DAY.
KERRY WASHINGTON, EVERYBODY!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: UP NEXT, JACKIE EVANCHO
WILL PERFORM FOR US.
STICK AROUND.
ANNOUNCER: MONDAY ON "LIVE,"
ALSO FROM "DJANGO UNCHAINED,"
ACTOR CHRISTOPH WALTZ.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: WHAT A WAY TO CONCLUDE
HOLIDAY'S LIVE HIT WEEK WITH A
PERFORMANCE BY SINGING PRODIGY
JACKIE EVANCHO.
SHE HAS TWO C.D.'S OUT NOW.
SONGS FROM THE SILVER SCREEN AND
HER HOLIDAY C.D.
HERE'S JACKIE EVANCHO WITH "THE
FIRST NOEL QULTS.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
♪
>> ♪ THE FIRST NOEL
THE ANGELS DID SING FIRST FIRST
THEY LOOKED UP AND SAW SAW A
STAR
NOEL
BORN IS THE KING OF ISRAEL
THEY LOOKED UP AND SAW A STAR
SHINING IN THE EAST BEYOND THEM
FAR
AND TO THE EARTH IT GAVE GREAT
LIGHT
AND SO IT CONTINUED BOTH DAY AND
NIGHT
NOEL NOEL
BORN IS THE KING
BORN IS THE KING OF ISRAEL
♪
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KELLY: YOU ARE UNBELIEVEABLE!
MICHAEL: UNBELIEVABLE!
KELLY: ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
THAT WAS GORGEOUS.
MICHAEL: UNBELIEVABLE.
I'M BLOWN AWAY.
KELLY: WE ARE SPELLBIND.
WE HAVE CHILLS, THE WOLE THING.
AND WHAT AMAZED US IS HOW FAR
AWAY YOU HOLD YOUR MICROPHONE,
YOUR VOICE IS SO POWERFUL AND
GORGEOUS.
>> THANK YOU.
MICHAEL: ALL I CAN THINK OF
YOU'RE 12 YEARS OLD, YOU HAVE
YOUNGER BROTHERS, OLDER
BROTHERS, WHEN YOU CRY AT HOME
IT PROBABLY SOUNDS --
[LAUGHTER]
>> I THINK IT'S ACTUALLY PRETTY
ANNOYING.
KELLY: YOU THINK IT'S PRETTY
ANNOYING?
FOR THOSE THAT DON'T REMEMBER
IT, YOU FINISHED SECOND PLACE ON
"AMERICA'S GOT TALENT" A COUPLE
OF YEARS BACK.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
I CAN'T IMAGINE YOU EVER WINNING
SECOND PLACE FOR ANYTHING
BECAUSE YOU'RE SO INCREDIBLY
TALENTED.
YOU ARE ALSO MAKING YOUR FEATURE
FILM DEBUT.
>> YES, I AM.
KELLY: IN WHAT MOVIE?
>> I'M GOING TO BE IN A MOVIE
WITH ROBERT REDFORD AND A BUNCH
OF OTHER BIG NAMES.
KELLY: WE'RE EXCITED FOR YOU.
YOU CAN GO TO OUR WEBSITE FOR
JACKIE'S CONCERT DATES.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO
WRITE INTO OUR INBOX, GO TO
LIVEKELLYANDMICHAEL.COM.
THEY'RE WHOLE GRAIN GOOD...
AND YUMMY GOOD.
REAL FRUIT PIECES.
12 GRAMS OF WHOLE GRAINS
AND A CREAMY
YOGURT FLAVORED COATING.
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
TREAT YOURSELF GOOD.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: OH!
OH!
WE'RE BACK WITH THE INBOX.
BUT BEFORE WE DO THAT, DON'T
FORGET LIVE VIEWERS CHOICE 2012
SHOW IS COMING UP ON DECEMBER 31
KELLY: DON'T FORGET TO GO TO OUR
WEBSITE AND VOTE FOR YOUR
FAVORITE MOMENTS.
YOU CAN VOTE ONCE A DAY, EVERY
DAY.
MICHAEL: THE TOP 10 VIDEOS WILL
BE ON THE SHOW, ALONG WITH A
WHOLE LOT MORE.
KELLY: JOIN US AFTER THE SHOW
FOR OUR FIRST EVER GOOGLE PLUS
HANG OUT TO DISCUSS OUR FAVORITE
MOMENTS FROM 2012MENT
MICHAEL: JUST GOING TO BE
SITTING HERE HANGING OUT AND
CHILLING.
KELLY: THAT'S RIGHT.
MICHAEL: WE'LL BE STREAMING IT
ON OUR WEBSITE,
LIVEKELLYANDMICHAEL.COM.
WE'LL BE THERE STARTING IN ABOUT
10:10 RIGHT AFTER TH
>>> IT'S FRIDAY, DECEMBER 14th.
COMING UP ON AN ALL-NEW
"VIEW" --
>>> "DANCING WITH THE STARS'"
DEREK HOUGH IS OUR "GUY DAY
FRIDAY" GUEST COHOST AND TAKING
ON RUMORS HE'S GETTING OFF THE
DANCE FLOOR TO SIT AT THE
JUDGES' TABLE.
>>> THEN, "SILVER LININGS
PLAYBOOK" STAR CHRIS TUCKER IS
REVEALING WHY HE WALKED AWAY
FROM HOLLYWOOD WHEN HE WAS ONE
OF THE BIGGEST AND HIGHEST PAID
STARS IN THE WORLD.
>>> PLUS, ELISABETH AND SHERRI
WENT ON A ONE-STOP SHOPPING
SPREE TO FIND THE PERFECT
PRESENTS FOR ALL THE COHOSTS AND
THE VIEWMASTER, AND WAIT TILL
YOU SEE THE HOLIDAY HAUL THEY
BROUGHT BACK.