MORE COMING UP ON "THE VIEW."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ THEME FROM "DANCING WITH THE
STARS" PLAYING ]
♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> OH, GOOD MORNING, GOOD
MORNING.
HOW ARE YOU?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
YOU DANCING FOOLS, YOU.
HELLO AND WELCOME TO THE VF.
WHOOPI HAS THE DAY OFF.
AND THEY WALKED OUT TO -- WE ALL
WALKED OUT TO THE
"DANCING WITH THE STARS" THEME
IN HONOR OF OUR GUEST COHOST FOR
"GUY DAY FRIDAY," DEREK HOUGH.
>> YEA!
>> HI, THERE.
OH.
I HAVE TO SAY, THIS FEELS VERY
AT HOME FOR ME.
I AM THE ONLY BOY OF FOUR
SISTERS SO -- IT'S GREAT.
>> OH, BROTHER.
>> DID THEY ALL DANCE?
>> UM, YEAH.
YEAH.
PAJAMA DANCING, AT NIGHT.
>> YOU AND JULIANNE.
YOU GUY, AWESOME.
>> A LOT OF THIS IS
GENERATIONAL.
I'M VERY EASY DANCING WITH
PARTNER.
I'M VERY UNCOMFORTABLE DANCING
ALONE.
YOU, ON THE OTHER HAND --
>> I AM LIKE, WELL, THINK OUR
GENERATION HAS A PROBLEM WITH
DANCING.
GO TO A WEDDING, YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO.
TIM DOESN'T WANT TO DANCE WITH
ME, WE DON'T KNOW BALLROOM
DANCING.
WHAT IS ONE THING A COUPLE CAN
DO AT A WEDDING THAT DOESN'T
LOOK RIDICULOUS?
>> I'VE SAID THIS BEFORE.
THE GENERATIONS.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
WE GO EVENTS, PARTIES.
THE ORLANDO -- OLDER GENERATIONS
GET UP THERE AND ARE CUTTING A
RUG.
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T KNOW
HOW TO DANCE WITH PARTNER
ANYMORE.
>> YOU HAVE TO HAVE CONFIDENCE
TO GRAB HER AND DANCE WITH HER.
LET'S GO, SHERRI.
>> A LITTLE LIKE --
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
.
>> YOU'RE AT A PARTY.
>> YOU HAVE TO GRAB HER, TAKE
HER.
FEEL THE CONFIDENCE.
YOU HAVE TO BRING HER IN LIKE
THIS AND YOU JUST SWAY BACK AND
FORTH.
THAT'S IT.
>> SWAY, SWAY.
>> YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
THEN, OF COURSE, THE BEST ONE,
THIS IS HOW THEY DO IT.
YOU HAVE TO DO A LITTLE DIP,
JUST A LITTLE DIP, A LITTLE DIP
SO YOU KNOW THAT YOU CARE.
IF YOU CAN SWAY BACK AND FORTH,
THEN YOU'RE IN TROUBLE.
>> JUST SWAY A LITTLE BIT.
>> GIVE HER A ROUND OF APPLAUSE,
YOU GUYS.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> I WANT YOU TO SHOW ME HOW TO
GET UP THERE AND DANCE BY
MYSELF.
NOT NOW.
I WANT A PRIVATE LESSON.
>> I WILL.
>> IS IT TRUE YOU MAY BE LEAVING
"DANCING" TO BECOME A JUDGE?
>> WHAT?
>> NO.
I WAS AWAY.
I CAME BACK, THEY SAID, WE HEAR
YOU ARE JUDGING THE SHOW.
>> LIKE WE REALLY WANT TO SEE
YOU BEHIND A TABLE.
WHY DO PEOPLE COMPETE, THEY KEEP
COMING BACK.
YOU GET THIS MIRRORBALL TROPHY.
>> YOU KNOW WHY.
>> I KNOW WHY, BUT --
>> THE DANCING IS SO FUN TO
WATCH, SO ENTERTAINING.
IT'S A REFLECTION OF LIFE,
PEOPLE OUT OF THEIR COMFORT
ZONES.
THEY'RE PUTTING TRUST IN
SOMEBODY.
WE'RE SEEING THEM CONQUER
SOMETHING AND ACHIEVE SOMETHING
BEFORE YOUR EYES.
YOU GO, MAN, IF THEY CAN DO
THAT, MAYBE I'LL GO FOR AN
INTERVIEW FOR THAT JOB AND TAKE
A RISK.
>> REALLY?
>> I THINK IT'S ABOUT WEIGHT
LOSS.
A LOT OF PEOPLE GO ON THERE TO
LOSE WEIGHT.
>> THINK IT'S ABOUT WATCHING THE
DANCING.
I MEAN WHEN YOU SEE WHAT THE
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT PROFESSIONAL,
WHAT YOU'RE ABLE TO CHOREOGRAPH,
I JUST THINK IT'S GREAT.
WHILE WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
COUPLES, MY SEGUE.
WE HAVE A VERY INTERESTING
COUPLE ON "20/20" TONIGHT, THE
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES
AND THE FIRST LADY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THIS IS THEIR FIRST JOINT
INTERVIEW SINCE RE-ELECTION.
WE TALKED TO HIM ALONE FIRST,
THE PRESIDENT.
AND WE SHOWED A LITTLE BIT OF
THAT EARLIER WHEN HE TALKED
ABOUT BACKING THE SYRIAN REBELS
AND THE FISCAL CLIFF.
CAN YOU STOP THEM FROM FALLING
OFF THAT CLIFF?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> BUT YOU HAVE NEVER SEEN THEM,
THIN
I THINK, MORE RELAXED AND FUNNY
AND EASY THAN THEY ARE TOGETHER.
THEY RARELY DO INTERVIEWS
TOGETHER.
THIS IS JUST A LITTLE BIT OF IT.
THE FIRST LADY SAID, YOU KNOW, A
LOT OF PEOPLE THINK SHE SHOULD
RUN FOR SENATE.
SHE SAID SHE'S NOT INTERESTED IN
POLITICS.
TAKE A LOOK.
YOU SAID YOU DON'T HAVE THE
PATIENCE FOR POLITICAL LIFE.
THE PATIENCE FOR WHAT?
>> YOU KNOW, I HAVE BECOME
SNOILD THE ROLE OF FIRST LADY.
BECAUSE I GET TO CHOOSE THE
ISSUES THAT SPEAK TO ME.
I HAVE LEARNED FROM MY HUSBAND
WATCHING HIM THAT IT DOES
REQUIRE GREAT DEAL OF PATIENCE
TO FEEL THE FULL IMPACT OF THE
WORK THAT YOU DO ON THE GROUND.
IT DOESN'T HAPPEN RIGHT AWAY.
>> AND SHE HAS A BIGGER
DIFFICULTY BITING HER TONGUE.
>> OH?
>> THII THINK I HAVE DONE PRETT
WELL.
>> NOT BAD.
>> WAS THERE A TIME YOU WENT,
SHH?
>> NO, I NEVER SAID THAT.
ARE YOU KIDDING?
WE'VE BEEN MARRIED 20 YEARS, YOU
THINK I HAVE EVER SAID THAT TO
MY WIFE?
>> I DON'T THINK I HAVE HEARD
THAT.
>> DOES SHE SAY THINGS --
>> IMPOLITIC.
THINK AS FIRST LADY SHE'S A
MODEL OF GRACE.
>> GIVE ME AN EXAMPLE.
>> I CAN'T GIVE YOU AN EXAMPLE.
THE POINT IS, PRIVATELY, YOU
KNOW, THERE -- THERE MAY BE --
>> I HAVE OPINIONS.
>> SHE HAS OPINIONS.
>> JUST LIKE A LOT OF SMART,
CAPABLE PEOPLE HAVE.
>> EXACTLY.
SHE'S GOT A FEW VIEWS.
>> YOU KNOW A LITTLE SOMETHING
ABOUT VIEWS.
>> YES, YES, SOMETHING ABOUT
VIEWS.
YES, I DO.
>> WOW.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> YOU KNOW -- IT'S SO LOVELY TO
SEE WHEN YOU'RE INTERVIEWING THE
PRESIDENT AND HIS WIFE, THEY
HONOR EACH OTHER.
GIVE EACH OTHER GREAT DEAL OF
RESPECT.
MICK SHELL OWE WHAT IS A LAWYER.
SHE'S GREAT -- EVEN WHEN SHE
STEPS BACK.
>> YOU GET THE FEELING  INING -
HEARD HE'S COLD AND ELUSIVE WHEN
HE WAS RUNNING.
SO RIDICULOUS.
>> THIS WILL BE TONIGHT AT 10:00
ON "20/20," BUT WHEN YOU SEE
THEM SPARRING, AND YOU JUST SAW
A LITTLE BIT OF IT, AT THE
BEGINNING, THAT FAMOUS PICTURE
OF THEM EMBRACING.
I SAID, WHY DID YOU TO THAT
PICTURE?
HE SAID, BECAUSE I LOVE MY WIFE.
>> THERE WAS A PICTURE OF OBAMA
EMBRACING GOVERNOR CHRISTIE
RECENTLY ALSO.
>> AND SHE SAYS, I ASKED, WHAT
DO YOU DO WHEN ROW HAVE TO SHAKE
THOUSANDS OF HANDS OF ALL THESE
PEOPLE.
SHE SAID, I'M A HUGGER, WHAT I
DO, I HUG.
>>> WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH
MORE "HOT TOPICS."
>> Announcer: STILL AHEAD --
"SILVER LININGS PLAYBOOK" STAR
CHRIS TUCKER IS REVEALING WHY HE
WALKED AWAY FROM SHOW BUSINESS
WHEN HE WAS PULLING IN $25
MILLION A PICTURE.
the day I learned I had
to start insulin
for my type 2 diabetes.
ME...
thinking my only option was the
vial and syringe dad used.
And ME...
discovering once-daily
Levemir® FlexPen.
FlexPen® is prefilled.
Doesn't need
refrigeration
for up to
42 days.
No drawing from a vial.
Dial the exact dose.
Inject by pushing a button.
FlexPen® is insulin delivery...
MY way.
Levemir® (insulin detemir
[rDNA origin] injection)
is a long-acting insulin
used to control high blood sugar
in adults and children
with diabetes and is not
recommended to treat
diabetic ketoacidosis.
Do not use Levemir® if
you are allergic
to any of its ingredients.
The most common side effect
is low blood sugar,
which may cause
symptoms such as sweating,
shakiness, confusion,
and headache.
Severe low blood sugar can be
serious and life threatening.
Ask your healthcare provider
about alcohol use,
operating machinery, or driving.
Other possible side
effects include
injection site reactions.
Tell your healthcare provider
about all medicines you take
and all of your
medical conditions.
Get medical help right away
if you experience
serious allergic
reactions, such as body rash,
trouble with breathing, fast
heartbeat, or sweating.
With FlexPen®... say good night
to vial and syringe.
Ask your doctor about
Levemir® FlexPen.
Covered by
90% of insurance plans,
including Medicare.
Find your co-pay at
MyFlexPen.com.
♪ One for You.
♪ And one for me.
♪ You, you, you, you, you...
♪ TV for Jack.
♪ Sweaters for Nancy.
♪ I'm blown away...
I'm freaking out... ♪
♪ Deals, deals, deals!
♪ It's On, it's on, it's on,
♪ The Finish Your List Sale.
♪STIR IT, STIR IT,IR IT,
STIR IT UP, STIR IT UP. ♪♪
STIR UP A SMILE,
WITH HERSHEY'S SYRUP.
Last Christmas, I got my
husband this treadmill.
Now that I gave my son
these Reebok ZigKicks...
...someone's actually using it.
(INNER VOICE):
How you like me now?
The new Reebok Zigkick.
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
IS THE SAME FREQUENT HEARTBURN
TREATMENT AS PRILOSEC OTC.
NOW WITH A FANCY COATING
THAT GIVES YOU A BURST
OF WILDBERRY FLAVOR.
NOW WHY MAKE A FLAVORED
HEARTBURN PILL?
BECAUSE THIS IS AMERICA.
AND WE DON'T JUST
MAKE THINGS YOU WANT,
WE MAKE THINGS YOU
DIDN'T EVEN KNOW YOU WANTED.
LIKE A SPOON FORK.
SPRAY CHEESE.
AND JEANS MADE
OUT OF SWEATPANTS.
SO GRAB YOURSELF SOME
NEW PRILOSEC OTC WILDBERRY.
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
SATISFACTION GUARANTEED
OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
THEY'RE WHOLE GRAIN GOOD...
AND YUMMY GOOD.
REAL FRUIT PIECES.
12 GRAMS OF WHOLE GRAINS
AND A CREAMY
YOGURT FLAVORED COATING.
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
TREAT YOURSELF GOOD.
♪ Target REDcard...
♪ Save 5% and get...
♪ free shipping!
♪ It's On. Hit the sale.
♪ Hallelujah.
Grab Your REDcard. ♪
♪ Hallelujah!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> WE ARE BACK WITH OUR "GUY
DAY FRIDAY" GUEST COHOST, DEREK
HOUGH.
I DO WANT TO MENTION, YEAH, YOU
ASKED ME.
>> WE WERE TALKING ABOUT THE
PRESIDENT AND THE INTERVIEW YOU
DID WITH THEM TONIGHT.
IT'S ON AT 10:00.
I'M GOING TAPE IT AND WATCH
>>> THIS IS AN ABC NEWS SPECIAL
REPORT.
>>> GOOD AFTERNOON.
I'M DAVID MUIR HERE AT ABC NEWS
HEADQUARTERS IN NEW YORK.
WHERE WE CONTINUE TO COVER THIS
HORRIFIC STORY PLAYING OUT ON A
FRIDAY.
IF YOU HAVE CHILDREN IN THE ROOM
YOU MIGHT WANT TO TAKE THEM TO
ANOTHER PART OF THE HOUSE IT'S
SIMPLY NOT A STORY THAT YOU
WOULD WANT THEM TO HEAR.
HERE'S WHAT WE LEARNED AT THIS
HOUR, YOU'RE LOOKING AT THE
AERIAL VIEW OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
AT LEAST 27 PEOPLE KILLED IN A
SHOOTING AT THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
IT'S BELIEVED MANY OF THE
VICTIMS ARE IN FACT CHILDREN,
STUDENTS AT THAT SCHOOL, THE
INITIAL CALLS COMING IN AT 9:30
THIS MORNING, AUTHORITIES THEN
RACING TO THE SCENE, TO FIND OUT
WHAT WE'RE SIMPLY EXCRUCIATING
IMAGES TO WATCH, PARENTS,
TEACHERS BRINGING THE CHILDREN
OUT OF THE SCHOOL AS QUICKLY AS
THEY COULD, IN LINES EXITING THE
SCHOOL.
THEY WERE BROUGHT TO A FIRE
HOUSE NEARBY WE'RE TOLD WHERE
PARENTS WERE ALERTED.
ONE OF THE LINES RIGHT HERE.
AS YOU COULD IMAGINE IN THE
HOURS THAT ARE GOING TO FOLLOW
HERE THE TEACHERS IN THIS WILL
EMERGE AS THE HEROES WHO
CAREFULLY BROUGHT THOSE CHILDREN
OUT UNDER SOME VERY DIRE
CIRCUMSTANCES.
FOM LOSE THIS IS OUR SENIOR
JUSTICE CORRESPONDENT PIERRE
THOMAS.
HE JOINS US NOW.
PIERRE, WHAT DO WE KNOW RIGHT
NOW ABOUT THE GUNMAN, WE KNOW
THAT THERE WAS AT LEAST ONE
GUNMAN, WE DON'T KNOW IF THERE
WAS ANYONE ELSE INVOLVED?
>> WE'RE BEING TOLD AT LEAST ONE
GUNMAN WAS SHOT AND KILLED.
THEY RECOVERED AT LEAST TWO
WEAPONS IN CONNECTION WITH THIS
TRAGIC SHOOTING.
DAVID, I CAN TELL YOU, I TALK TO
FEDERAL SOURCES ALL THE TIME.
THEY'RE DEVASTATED BY THIS
INFORMATION.
THEY CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
THE NOTION OF 27 PEOPLE BEING
KILLED IN AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IS SHOCKING.
MOST OF THEM CHILDREN AND ALSO,
WE TALKED TO A SECURITY
CONSULTANT AS WELL, THAT MANY
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS AS YOU MIGHT
IMAGINE DON'T HAVE MUCH IN THE
WAY OF SECURITY AND TYPICALLY
DON'T HAVE ARMED PERSONNEL ON
THE SCHOOL ARE YOU GROUNDS.
>> THE LAST PLACE THAT YOU WOULD
EXPECT SOMETHING LIKE THIS
UNFOLD.
IT'S HARD TO SECURE ALL OF OUR
SCHOOLS IN OUR COUNTRY.
WE OFTEN ASK THESE QUESTIONS.
WE HAVE BEEN REPORTING ON
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS ONE FOR SOME
TIME.
I CAN'T REMEMBER THE NUMBERS
THAT WE'RE SEEING TODAY, THE
SCOPE AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
THIS COUNTRY BEFORE.
>> YEAH, WE'RE DOUBLE-CHECKING,
THIS LOOKS TO BE THE WORST
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN TERMS OF
NUMBER OF DEAD IN U.S. HISTORY.
AGAIN, SOURCES SAY THAT THE FBI,
ATF AND OTHER FEDERAL SOURCES
ARE ON THE SCENE TO ASSISTS THE
LOCAL POLICE WHO ARE THE LEAD ON
THIS CASE AND AGAIN, THEY ARE
TRYING TO ASSESS THE SITUATION
AND WE STILL HAVE AN ACTIVE
SITUATION WHERE THERE ARE
CHECKING TO SEE IF THERE MIGHT
BE A SECOND SHOOTER.
>> PIERRE, STAND BY.
WE'LL COME BACK TO YOU SHORTLY.
DIANE SAWYER ON THE WAY FOR
"WORLD NEWS" THIS EVENING.
ERIN, I WAS TAKING NOTE OF ONE
OF THE E-MAILS YOU SENT EARLY.
AN HOUR AGO, THEY WERE STILL
SEARCHING CAR TO CAR
>> IT WAS REALLY INTERESTING TO
SEE POLICE OFFICERS IN TACTICAL
GEAR WITH ASSAULT RIVALS DRAWN
GOING BUSINESS TO BUSINESS,
HOUSE TO HOUSE, CAR TO CAR,
LOOKING FOR ANY EVIDENCE OF
ANOTHER SHOOTER.
ONE OF THE SUSPECTED GUNMAN IS
DEAD.
REPORTS OF ANOTHER.
POLICE OFFICERS WERE CONDUCTING
THESE SEARCHES.
IN MANY CASES, DAVID, WITH
CHILDREN EVACUATED FROM THE
SCHOOL JUST 20, 30 YARDS AWAY AS
PARENTS HAVE COME TO LOCAL FIRE
HOUSE TO COLLECT THEIR CHILDREN
AS THEY PASS BY TO LEAVE THE
SCENE, THEY SAW THESE
TACTICALICALLY CLAD OFFICERS
WERE THEIR GUNS DRAWN AND ONE
FATHER PUT HIS ARMS AROUND HIS
SON'S EYES TO SHIELD HIS SIGHT.
>> HAVE YOU BEEN ABLE TO TALK
WITH ANY OF THE PARENTS AND HOW
ARE THE CHILDREN DOING?
WE HAVE SEEN IMAGES OF THE
TEACHERS WHO HAVE BEEN SIMPLY
HEROIC TODAY TAKING THESE
CHILDREN OUT OF THE SCHOOL?
>> AT FIRST WORD OF THE SHOOTING
AT 10 CAN:00 A.M., THE SCHOOL
DAY WAS FULLY UNDER WAY.
THE KIDS WERE TOLD TO GRAB A
BUDDY AND AND WALK QUICKLY.
WALK TO THE NEARBY FIRE HOUSE
AND THEY DID IT WITHOUT GRABBING
ANY OF THEIR BELONGINGS.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE TIME TO GRAB
THEIR OWN JACKET.
WEB WE TALKED TO MANY OF THE
PARENTS, AS YOU COULD IMAGINE,
THEY SAID THE WORST WENT THROUGH
THEIR HEAD.
AS REVERSE 911 ALERT SYSTEM,
INFORMED PARENTS TO COME TO THE
FIRE HOUSE TO COLLECT THEIR
CHILDREN.
ONE WOMAN SAID SHE HAD NO IDEA
WHAT TO THINK.
ONE FATHER SAID THAT HE HAD
NEVER BEEN MORE PANICKED ON THIS
DRIVE FROM WORK TO GET HIS SON.
>> WHEN PARENTS GET CALLS LIKE
THIS, THAT FLASHES UP, PEOPLE
FEAR THE WORST AND IT WOULD
APPEAR AS THESE NUMBERS UNFOLD
TODAY IF YOU'RE JUST TUNING IN.
THIS IS ABC NEWS LIVE COVERAGE
OF A HORRIFIC SHOOTING TODAY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
ABOUT 60 MILES NORTHEAST OF NEW
YORK CITY WHERE TODAY, A GUNMAN,
AT LEAST ONE GUNMAN SHOT AND
KILLED HIMSELF BUT NOT UNTIL HE
HAD EXACTED HORRIFIC TERROR
INSIDE THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
TODAY.
KILLING AT LEAST 27 PEOPLE, AT
LEAST 27, THE NUMBER CONTINUES
TO GROW THROUGHOUT THE MORNING
AND MANY OF THE VICTIMS ARE
BELIEVED TO IN FACT BE CHILDREN
AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AS YOU HEARD AARON REPORT JUST
MOMENTS, CHILDREN WERE BROUGHT
OUT, TOLD TO GRAB A FRIEND,
LEAVE THEIR BELONGINGS ASIDE,
IT'S A COLD DAY, TEMPERATURES IN
THE 40s, YOU CAN SEE, THEY DON'T
HAVE THEIR COATS ON, PARENTS
WERE ALERTED TO GO TO A NEARBY
FIRE HOUSE, THE SANDY HOOK FIRE
HOUSE.
THAT'S WHERE DAN HARRIS HAS BEEN
STANDING BE I THINK MORNING.
DAN, THESE REUNIONS WITH PARENTS
HAVE TO SOMETHING TO BE WITNESS.
>> Reporter: THEY ARE.
WE HAVE BEEN WATCHING A STEADY
STREAM OF FAMILIES EMERGING FROM
THIS FIRE HOUSE AND EVERYBODY IS
TRULY DISTRAUGHT AND SHAKEN.
I HAD A CONVERSATION WITH ONE
MOTHER WHO HAD AN 8-YEAR-OLD IN
THE SCHOOL.
I TALKED TO THE MOTHER AND HER
8-YEAR-OLD.
SHE SAID YOU DON'T EXPECT IT TO
HAPPEN IN A PLACE LIKE THIS.
YOU HEAR THAT ALL THE TIME.
HAVING COVERED EVENTS LIKE THIS,
THIS IS A TRULY UNIQUE
SITUATION, THAT THIS IS A VERY
SMALL TOWN IN A RURAL AREA, A
BEAUTIFUL SOUTHERN NEW ENGLAND
TOWN, NOT AT ALL WHAT YOU WOULD
EXPECT TO SEE ALL OF THESE
POLICE OFFICERS HERE AND HAVE
ALL OF THIS MAYHEM CARRIED OUT
IN THIS ENVIRONMENT.
I TALKED TO THIS 8-YEAR-OLD GIRL
EVACUATED FROM THIS SCHOOL, SHE
SAID THEY WERE VERY CALM BUT THE
STUDENTS WERE DISTRAUGHT AND
FEAR.
SHE SAID THERE WAS A LOT OF
CRYING AND SCREAMING.
SHE DIDN'T HEAR THE GUN SHOTS
BUT SHE HEARD THE AMBULANCES AND
SHE WAS VERY SCARED BUT THE
OTHER STUDENTS WERE EVEN MORE
SCARED.
LET ME TELL YOU ABOUT ONE OTHER
CONVERSATION, DAVID, A MOLT AGO
WITH A PARENT WHO ARRIVED HERE
AT THE FIRE HOUSE, SHE DID NOT
HAVE STUDENTS IN THIS SCHOOL,
SHE HAD STUDENTS IN ANOTHER
SCHOOL NEARBY, SHE SAID THAT SHE
WAS WAITING TO GO PICK UP HER
CHILDREN FOR TWO HOURS BECAUSE
SHE SAID, THESE ARE THE LAST TWO
REMAINING HOURS OF THEIR
CHILDHOOD, BECAUSE ONCE THEY
LEARN WHAT HAPPENED HERE, THEIR
INNOCENCE WILL MOST CERTAINLY BE
LOST.
>> WE CAN'T UNDERSCORE THAT
BEING THE CASE, THE KIND OF
CONVERSATIONS THAT WILL PLAY OUT
NOT ONLY IN THE HOUSEHOLDS BUT
FOR THE COMMUNITY THAT THIS THIS
IS TAKING PLACE AS THIS HEADLINE
CONTINUES TO WORSEN.
AS MORNING TURNS TO AFTERNOON.
AT LEAST 27 SHOT.
THAT'S DAN HARRIS REPORTING FROM
THE SANDY HOOK FIRE HOUSE.
DAN, THESE CHILDREN WERE AT
THEIR SCHOOL DESKS, THE SCHOOL
DAY WAS WELL UNDER WAY, THEY
WERE IN THEIR CLASS ROOMS WITH
THEIR TEACHERS, THEY WERE ASKED
TO SIMPLY GET UP AND WALK OUT.
AND AS YOU DESCRIBE THE TEARS,
NOT THE SCREAMING BUT THE TEARS,
IT WOULD SEEM THAT THESE
CHILDREN, ALTHOUGH IT'S
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, CERTAINLY
KNEW THE HEAVINESS OF THE
SITUATION THEY WERE ENDURING.
>> THEY KNEW THAT SOMETHING BAD
HAD HAPPENED.
THEY ABSOLUTELY KNEW THAT.
I DON'T KNOW IF THEY KNOW NOW AT
THIS LATE DAY, RELATIVELY
SPEAKING, I DON'T KNOW IF THEY
KNOW YET THE GRAVITY OF THIS
SITUATION.
IT'S JUST TRICKLING OUT THE
SERIOUSNESS OF THE CRIME
COMMITTED INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
IT REMAINS TO BE SEEN HOW THAT
INFORMATION WILL BE RELAID TO
THEM.
YOU SAID IT.
THESE CONVERSATIONS.
DIVOT CONVERSATIONS PARENTS WILL
NOW HAVE TO SAY WITH CHILDREN
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE THIS
SCHOOL.
UNIMAGINABLY HARD CONVERSATION.
THERE ARE THE PARENTS WHO AREN'T
ABLE TO PICK UP THEIR CHILDREN
NOW.
THE PARENTS WHO AREN'T GOING TO
BE WORST POSSIBLE AT ALL, THEIR
CHILDREN WERE IN FACT LOST
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL.
THAT DRAMA IS UNFOLDING AS WE
SPEAK.
IN A BUCOLIC LITTLE TOWN.
>> THE PARENTS ARE WAITING AND
HOPING THEY'RE NOT ONE OF THE
PARENTS WHO ARE INFORMED AND OF
COURSE, THERE WILL BE HUGS
ACROSS THIS COUNTRY AS KIDS COME
HOME FROM SCHOOL ELSEWHERE.
DAN, STICK WITH US.
THE FIRE HOUSE WEHERE THE
CHILDREN WERE BROUGHT.
DAN AS YOU MENTIONED, PARENTS
DESCRIBING THE SCENE,
APPRECIATING WHAT THE TEACHERS
PULLED OFF.
DIANE SAWYER TALKED WITH SOME
PARENTS A SHORT TIME AGO AS WE
WERE ON THE AIR COVERING THIS
BREAKING STORY.
VIEWERS JUST TUNING IN, A LITTLE
BIT OF THE COLOR THE PARENTS
DESCRIBING THIS SCENE AS IT
UNFOLDED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> WE GOT A PHONE CALL THAT
THERE HAD BEEN A REPORT OF A
SHOOTING AND THAT ALL SCHOOLS
WERE IN LOCKDOWN AND IT DIDN'T
SAY WHAT SCHOOL.
THEN A NEIGHBOR THEY SAID IT
HEARD IT WAS SANDY HOOK WHERE
OUR CHILDREN GOES.
AS A PARENT I KNOW WHO HAPPENED
TO BE IN THE BUILDING AT THE
TIME.
SHE WAS PRETTY BROKEN UP.
SHE WAS AT A MEETING WITH THE
PRINCIPAL.
SHE HAD STAYED IN THE CONFERENCE
ROOM AND MY UNDERSTANDING FROM
HER IS THAT THE PRINCIPAL AND
OTHER PEOPLE GOT SHOT.
WHEN THEY WENT OUT INTO THE
HALLWAY WAND AND SHE WAS THE ONE
WHO CALLED 911.
>> I SAW THE FIRST COP CARS
ROLLING DOWN THERE.
I JUST LITERALLY RAN DOWN THERE.
I GOT PRETTY MUCH UP TO THE
SCHOOL WITH OTHER PARENTS WHO
WERE RIGHT ON THE SCENE.
THEY WERE LEADING THE KIDS OUT
SINGLE FILE.
I SAW HIM RIGHT AWAY AND JUST
WENT WITH HIM AT THAT POINT.
>> HOW SHAKEN WAS EDWIN, WHAT
DID HE WANT TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT?
>> HE DOES NOT REALLY WANT TO
TALK ABOUT IT.
HE'S JUST SCARED AND SHAKEN.
HE SAID THAT HE DIDN'T SEE HE
HEARD.
HIS FRIENDS AND TEACHER ARE ALL
OKAY AND SO, RIGHT NOW, WE'RE
JUST FOCUSED ON COMFORTING HIM.
>> I HEARD THAT CHILDREN WERE
TAKEN OUT BLOODY.
SEVERAL TEACHERS AND MOTHER WHO
WAS ACTUALLY IN THE SCHOOL SAID
THAT A MASKED MAN CAME IN AND
STARTED FIRING.
>> MY WIFE AND I DROVE RIGHT
OVER THERE AND WHEN WE ARRIVED,
I WOULD SAY PROBABLY ABOUT 40
PEOPLE WERE THERE.
IT BECAME A VERY CHAOTIC
SITUATION, OBVIOUSLY, BECAUSE
EVERYBODY WAS TRYING TO GET
THEIR CHILDREN OUT.
BETWEEN THE POLICE AND THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT PERSONNEL AND
ESPECIALLY THE SCHOOL TOO
MUCHERS, I MEAN, I'M JUST SO
PROUD THE WAY OUR SCHOOL HAS
RESPONDED TO THIS.
>> THAT FATHER RIGHT THERE,
ECHOED WHAT OTHER PARENTS SAID,
THEY WILL BE HUGGING THEIR
CHILDREN.
THE CHILDREN WHO DID GET OUT
ALIVE.
ONE MOTHER DESCRIBING WHAT SHE
HAD HEARD.
REPORTS OF A MASKED MAN WHO
ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND STARTED
FIRING.
THERE WERE REPORTS FROM ONE
PARENT THERE, THAT SOME OF THE
CHILDREN WERE BROUGHT OUT FROM
THE SCHOOL, BLOODY AND THIS AS
WE LOOK AT THE NUMBER ON YOUR
SCREEN AND IT'S A HARROWING ONE,
AT LEAST 27 SHOT AT THIS SCHOOL
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IT'S THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
A SMALL, CLOSE-KNIT COMMUNITY.
A NUMBER OF THOSE VICTIMS,
PERHAPS A MAJORITY OF THEM COULD
BE CHILDREN AND OF COURSE, WE'LL
LEARN MORE AS THIS HORRIFIC
STORY YOU UNFOLD.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT PICTURES RIGHT
NOW OF PARENTS HOLDING ON TO
THEIR CHILDREN'S HANDS.
AUTHORITIES RESPONDING TO THE
SCENE IMMEDIATELY AFTER THOSE
INITIAL CALLS CAME IN AND AS IS
THE WITH ANY EMERGENCIES, YOU
START TO HEAR A TRICKLE OF
INFORMATION AND YOU FEAR THAT IT
COULD BE REALLY BAD BUT YOU'RE
HOPING THAT IT'S NOT, THAT'S
WHAT YOU CONTINUE TO HEAR FROM
PARENTS HERE, WHAT'S UNFOLDED IS
IN FACT, A HORRIBLE PICTURE, A
TRAGEDY IN THE SMALL TOWN AND
THE NUMBERS CONTINUE TO GROW.
WE'RE WAITING ON A NEWS
CONFERENCE A SHORT TIME FROM
NOW.
IT WILL BE O FIRST TIME
HEARING FROM AUTHORITIES IN THAT
COMMUNITY.
THE FBI IS ON THE SCENE.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE ARE
ALSO ON THE SCENE.
AS WE LOOK AT HELICOPTER SHOTS
FROM OUR AFFILIATE, SECURITY AT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS NATIONWIDE IS
EXTRAORDINARILY BASIC.
ARMED GUARDS VERY RARE AT
SCHOOLS.
ONE SECURITY CONSULTANT TELLING
US THAT THIS SCHOOL SHOOTING IS
UNPRECEDENTED AT AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
IT'S HISTORYMAKING FOR ALL OF
THE WRONG REASONS.
WE HAVE NEVER REPORTED ON A MASS
SHOOTING OF THIS SCOPE AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
AMERICA.
I KNOW FROM PICKING UP MY LITTLE
NIECE AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
YOU SIGN IN A CLIPBOARD WHEN YOU
GO INTO THE FRONT OF THE SCHOOL
AND THEN YOU PICK UP THE CHILD
AND THAT'S OFTEN THE CASE AT
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
THAT'S AN ALMOST IMPOSSIBLE FEAT
THAT THESE SCHOOLS COULD BE ANY
MORE SECURED.
WE KNOW THAT THESE EVENTS CAN
HAPPEN AND THAT'S WHY TEACHERS
AND ADMINISTRATORS ARE DRILLED
ON THIS.
TEACHERS CALMLY TOOK THOSE
CHILDREN FROM THE SCHOOL.
ONE FATHER SAID THAT HE WAS
PROUD OF THE WAY THE SCHOOL AND
HIS COMMUNITY WAS REACTING TO
THIS MORNING.
OUR SENIOR JUSTICE CORRESPONDENT
PIERRE THOMAS WORKING HIS
SOURCES IN WASHINGTON.
PIERRE?
>> AGAIN, THE FBI AND ATF AND
FEDERAL SOURCES ARE TRYING TO
GIVE ALL OF THE SUPPORT THEY CAN
TO THE LOCAL POLICE, AGAIN,
RIGHT NOW, THE CONCERN IS ABOUT
THE CHILDREN, AS YOU SAID, AT
LEAST 27 PEOPLE KILLED IN THIS
HORRIFIC INCIDENT.
MOSTLY CHILDREN, WE'RE TOLD.
THE FBI, WERE ALSO BEING TOLD,
HAS BEEN IN COMMUNICATION WITH
THE GOVERNOR AND STATE
OFFICIALS, ALSO WE'RE BEING TOLD
THAT THE PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES HAS BEEN BRIEFED ABOUT
THIS VERY TRAGIC AFFAIR.
>> OUR JAKE TAPPER AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
THE PRESIDENT WAS BRIEFED SOME
TIME AGO BY THE FBI DIRECTOR
ROBERT MUELLER.
HE'S TALKED TO THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTIC
CONNECTICUT, DANNEL MALLOY.
FOR THOSE OF YOU JUST TUNING IN
NOW, WE CONTINUE TO FOLLOW A
SCHOOL SHOOTING HERE.
1:29 IN THE AFTERNOON.
THE NUMBERS HAVE SIMPLY BEEN
BREATHTAKING.
AT LEAST 27 SHOT AND KILLED.
MANY OF THEM CHILDREN.
AUTHORITIES ON THE SCENE WERE
AWAITING THE FIRST PRESS
CONFERENCE TO GET A CLEARER
PICTURE.
THERE WAS AT LEAST ONE GUNMAN
INVOLVED.
IT'S BELIEVED THAT THIS GUNMAN
THEN TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
A MOTHER JOINED US EARLIERS TOLD
US THAT THE CHILDREN WERE
BROUGHT OUT, MANY OF THEM
INJURED, BLOODY.
A MASKED MAN ENTERED THE SCHOOL.
PARENTS THAT FOUND THEIR
CHILDREN AT THE NEARBY FIRE
HOUSE, HOLDING THEM, HUGGING
THEIR CHILDREN.
YOU CAN SIMPLY IMAGINE TRYING TO
FIND OUT IF THEIR CHILDREN IN
FACT ON THE OUTSIDE OR IF THEY
WERE PERHAPS IN ONE OF THE ROOMS
WHERE THIS DRAMATIC AND VERY SAD
TRAGEDY UNFOLDED HERE THIS
MORNING.
NO WORD ON WHO THIS GUNMAN IS,
WHAT THE MOTIVE COULD HAVE BEEN
FOR SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
NEVER ANY EXPLANATION FOR
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
BUT WE DO USUALLY GET A WINDOW
INTO THE PERSON WHO COULD COMMIT
SUCH A HEINOUS ACT.
WHAT WILL FOLLOW NOT ONLY THE
CONVERSATIONS THAT WILL PLAY OUT
IN THIS COMMUNITY BUT DOESN'T
ACROSS THE COUNTRY AS PAEMPBTS
GET A FLASH OF THIS.
CHILDREN IN THE HOUSE, THIS IS
OUR SPECIAL REPORT COVERAGE OF A
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
FOR OBVIOUS REASONS YOU MIGHT
WANT TO ASK THEM TO LEAVE THE
ROOM OR GIVE THEM SOMETHING ELSE
TO DO AS WE CONTINUE TO FOLLOW
THESE UNFOLDING DEVELOPMENTS.
DAN HARRIS ARRIVED AT THE FIRE
HOUSE A SHORM TIME AGO.
THAT WAS THE SPOT WHERE PARENTS
WERE ALERTED, TOLD TO GO.
I CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE DRIVE TO
GET TO THAT FIRE HOUSE TO FIND
OUT IF ONE OF THEIR CHILDREN WAS
AT THE FIRE HOUSE, WAITING FOR A
HUG, WAITING TO BE TAKEN HOME.
>> OH, YEAH, JUST FRANTIC.
DAVID, WATCHING THIS STEADY
STREAM OF FAMILIES FILING OUT OF
THIS FIRE HOUSE, WITH THE LOOKS
ON THEIR FACES, ON THEIR FACES,
JUST TELL THE WHOLE STORY,
PEOPLE ARE TEARFUL, THEIR FACES
ARE DRAWN AND PALE, SPEAKING TO
A PARENT EARLIER, SHE SAID I
NEED TO SORT OF PINCH MYSELF TO
WAKE UP AND REALIZE THAT THIS IS
HAPPENING HERE, IT DOESN'T FEEL
REAL, IT FEELS LIKE A DREAM AND
A VERY BAD ONE, A NIGHTMARE IN
FACT, THE TERM SHE USED.
PEOPLE ARE ABSOLUTELY IN SHOCK
AT THE DEPTH AND BREDth OF THE
HORROR HERE.
DAVID, I'M SO STRUCK BY WATCHING
THESE FAMILIES WALKING OUT OF
THIS FIRE HOUSE.
LOT OF HUGGING GOING ON EVEN
AMONG FIRST RESPONDERS.
YOU'RE SEEING PEOPLE HERE TRULY
SHOCKED, EVEN PEOPLE WHO ARE
USED TO SEEING VERY DIFFICULT
SCENES.
>> DAN HARRIS REPORTING FROM THE
VOLUNTEER FIRE HOUSE, RIGHT
AROUND THE CORNER FROM THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ABOUT 500 STUDENTS GO TO SCHOOL
THERE.
YOU CAN IMAGINE THE TASK UNDER
WAY AFTER THE FIRST REPORT OF
THIS.
THE TEACHERS IN THAT SCHOOL,
CHILDREN WERE IN CLASS ROOMS,
SITTING AT THEIR DESKS WHEN THEY
GOT THE WORD FROM THEIR TEACHER,
GRAB A PAL, A BUDDY FOR THE
CLASS ROOM AND LEAVE.
WE SAW SOME OF IMAGES OF THEM
LEAVING.
AS DAN HARRIS REPORTED EARLIER,
THE TEARS, YOU COULD HEAR THE
CRYING OF THE STUDENTS LEAVING
THE SCHOOL.
NO SCREAMING.
HOW CAREFULLY THESE TEACHERS
CARRIED THIS OUT THIS AFTERNOON
AND REALLY, WHAT A FINE JOB THEY
DID UNDER SUCH EXTRAORDINARY
CIRCUMSTANCES.
I CAN TELL YOU THAT WE'RE
GETTING BREAKING DEVELOPMENTS ON
THE INVESTIGATIVE SIDE OF IT,
CHRIS CUOMO.
ONE OF THE SHOOTERS WAS 24 YEARS
OLD.
THIS IS A NEW DEVELOPMENT.
WE KNEW AT LEAST ONE SHOOTER.
ONE SHOOTER TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
IT'S BELIEVED RIGHT NOW THAT
STATE POLICE ARE CONFIRMING TO
ABC NEWS THAT TWO SHOOTERS, TWO
SHOOTERS WERE INITIALLY INVOLVED
IN THIS MAZ SHOOTING.
ONE OF THOSE SHOOTERS TAKING
THEIR OWN LIFE AFTER THIS
HORRIFIC SCENE.
IT WOULD ALSO HELP TO EXPLAIN AS
AARON REPORTED EARLIER WHY
POLICE AS RECENTLY AN HOUR AGO,
ARMED IN TACTICAL GEAR WERE
CONTINUING TO GO CAR TO CAR
SURROUNDING THAT SCHOOL.
YOU CAN SEE THE AERIAL SHOTS
SHOWING THE CHAOS.
THE PARKING LOTS SURROUNDING
THOSE SCHOOLS.
THEY WENT CAR TO CAR LOOKING FOR
EVERYDAY.
IT'S BELIEVED THAT THEY WERE
ALSO BELIEVED LOOKING FOR A
SECOND POSSIBLE GUNMAN.
POLICE CONFIRMING THAT BELIEVE
TWO SHOOTERS WERE INITIALLY TO
BE BELIEVED IN THIS MASS
SHOOTING.
THEY'RE LOOKING FOR AN
ADDITIONAL SHOOTER ACCORDING TO
SOURCES AS THEY REPORT THIS TO
ABC NEWS.
PIERRE, WE HAVE UNFORTUNATELY
REPORTED ON SCENES LIKE THIS
BEFORE WHERE THERE WAS MORE THAN
ONE GUNMEN ENTERED THIS SCHOOL.
COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL 1999, TWO
SHOOTERS, 13 KILLED.
TO PUT THIS INTO CONTEXT, 13
KILLED IN COLUMBINE.
IT WAS HORRIFIC THEN AND IT'S
HORRIFIC TODAY.
AS IT STANDS TODAY, 27 SHOT AND
KILLED.
MANY OF THOSE VICTIMS ARE
CHILDREN.
>> DAVID, AGAIN, YOU TALKED TO
FEDERAL SOURCES THEY HAVE BEEN
INVOLVED IN ALL KINDS OF CASES.
AND THIS IS AS DEPRESSED THEY
HAVE SOUND SINCE 9/11 TO BE
HONEST.
THEY'RE COMMITTED TO TRYING TO
GIVE WHATEVER SUPPORT THEY CAN
TO STATE AND LOCAL OFFICIALS.
AGAIN, JUST DEVASTATING.
>> DEVASTATING TO LEARN THE
DEVELOPMENTS HERE, TOO, THAT
THERE WERE POSSIBLY TWO GUNMEN
THAT ONE TAKING THEIR OWN LIFE
AFTERWARDS AND IT'S BELIEVED
THAT A 24-YEAR-OLD GUNMAN, AS
THIS SUSPECT IS DESCRIBED WAS
ARMED WITH FOUR WEAPONS, WAS
WEARING A BULLET PROOF VEST, WE
KNOW THAT'S THE DESCRIPTION
COMING FROM SOURCES.
ONE OF THE SHOOTERS, 24 YEARS
OLD.
CARI
CARRYING FOUR WEAPONS.
AND BEGAN FIRING.
PARENTS GOT WORD QUICKLY.
AS DAN WAS SAYING, THIS IS A
VERY SMALL TOWN A VERY
TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY.
YOU CAN IMAGINE HOW QUICKLY WORD
SPREAD AS THESE PARENTS
DESCRIBED GOING TO THE SCENE,
HOPING THAT THEY WOULD FIND
THEIR LOVED ONES.
NOW, AS THIS AFTERNOON UNFOLDS,
THE QUESTION WILL BE, HOW MUCH
HIGHER CAN THIS NUMBER GO?
AND HOW THEY WILL BEGIN TO
NOTIFY THE PARENTS OF THE
CHILDREN WHO DID NOT MAKE IT
OUT?
IT'S BELIEVED TO BE THE WORST
SHOOTING AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN AMERICA, IN HISTORY, THAT'S
OUR BELIEF AT THIS POINT, WE
CONTINUE TO LOOK BACK AND ACROSS
OUR REPORTING OF INCIDENTS LIKE
THIS ONE, THEY ARE ALL HORRIFIC
AND OFTEN WHAT EMERGES ARE
SCENES OF GREAT HEROISM AND IN
THIS CASE JUST THE IMAGES OF THE
TEACHERS, THEY'LL BE APPLAUDED
FOR THEIR EFFORTS.
WABC SPEAKING TO A YOUNG BOY
ABOUT WHAT HE SAW AND IT'S
BELIEVED THAT WE HAVE SOME OF
THAT AUDIO NOW.
LET'S TAKE A LISTEN.
>> THERE'S A MAN PINNED DOWN TO
THE GROUND WITH HANDCUFFS ON AND
WE THOUGHT THAT WAS THE VICTIM.
WE REALLY DIDN'T GET A GOOD
GLANCE AT HIM BECAUSE, THERE WAS
LIKE A CAR BLOCKING IT.
PLUS, WE WERE RUNNING REALLY
QUICK.
SO, THEN, WE GOT TO THE FIRE
HOUSE AND WE SAT IN OUR CLASSES
AND WE JUST REALLY HAPPY THAT WE
WERE ALL ALIVE.
>> HAPPY THAT WE'RE ALL ALIVE,
POWERFUL WORDS FROM A LITTLE BOY
WITH A TRADEMARK BUZZ CUT
GETTING OUT OF ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
OKAY.
HE TALKED ABOUT THAT FIRE HOUSE,
THE SANDY HOOK VOLUNTEER FIRE
HOUSE.
STUDENTS WERE TOLD TO GRAB A
FRIEND AND GET TO THE FIRE
HOUSE.
THEY WALKED OUT OF SCHOOL ON A
SUNNY DAY, LOW 40s.
THEY DIDN'T HAVE A COAT ON.
THEY WERE HUDDLED WITH THEIR
PARENTS.
AFTER THEIR PARENTS ARRIVED.
THERE WAS ONE MOTHER WITH A CELL
PHONE, YOU CAN ONLY IMAGINE
PROBABLY CALLING DAD THAT THEIR
CHILD IS OKAY.
THAT LIMIT BOY SAYING THAT HE
GOT A QUICK VIEW OF SOMEONE BUT
THEY DIDN'T KNOW AT THE TIME
SOMEONE WAS CAUSING SUCH HOUR
>> Reporter:.
IT'S BELIEVED AT THIS HOUR AND
CONFIRMED THAT TWO SHOOTERS WERE
INITIALLY INVOLVED IN THE MASS
SHOOTING.
ONE OF THOSE SHOOTERS NOW DEAD.
WHETHER SOMETHING ENSUED AS
AUTHORITIES BEGAN ARRIVING AT
THE SCENE.
NOW THE BIG QUESTION WILL BE, IS
THERE IN FACT THAT SECOND
SHOOTER AND WHERE IS THAT SECOND
SHOOTER?
SEARCHES HAVE UNFOLDED
THROUGHOUT THE AFTERNOON.
CAR TO CAR.
WITH AUTHORITIES THERE ARMED AS
YOU CAN SEE.
THEY'RE HEAVILY ARMED.
MANY OF THEM CARRYING THEIR
AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
TO TRY TO FIND OUT REALLY WHAT
UNFOLDED HERE TODAY.
CAN YOU IMAGINE BEING A PARENT
OF A LITTLE CHILD WHO SAW THIS
SCENE THAT YOU'RE LOOKING AT
RIGHT NOW?
JUST TEAMS OF AUTHORITIES COMING
IN AND HOLDING GUNS?
THE KIND OF THING THAT YOU
TYPICALLY SEE IN A TELEVISION
DRAMA AND NOW, THESE CHILDREN
WILL BE ASKING THEIR PARENTS
ABOUT THE REALITY OF WHAT
UNFOLDED THERE AT THEIR
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TODAY.
PIERRE, REPORTS COMING IN ABOUT
A POSSIBLE SECOND SHOOTER, THAT
WOULD EXPLAIN WHY WE SAW
AUTHORITIES CONTINUING THEIR
SEARCH UP UNTIL MOMENTS AGO?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
IN SITUATIONS LIKE THIS, YOU
HAVE CONFLICTING INFORMATION
FROM EYEWITNESSES.
UNTIL YOU KNOW FOR SERB CERTAIN,
YOU'RE GOING TO CHECK EVERYTHING
AROUND THAT SCHOOL UNTIL YOU
KNOW WHAT FOR CERTAIN.
>>> THANK YOU.
LET'S GO TO PRESS CONFERENCE.
>>> GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE.
I WORK FOR GOVERNOR MALLOY.
AS YOU CAN IMAGINE, THE GOVERNOR
IS HORRIFIED BY WHAT'S HAPPENED.
HE'S MEETING WITH THE FAMILIES
RIGHT NOW.
HIS CHIEF CONCERN IS TO GET THE
FAMILIES THE INFORMATION THEY
NEED AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
THAT'S WHY HE'S NOT HERE.
I'M GOING TO INTRODUCE
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE FROM THE
STATE POLICE.
WHO WILL TALK A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
WHAT'S KNOWN SO FAR.
WE UNDERSTAND THAT YOU ARE ALL
INTERESTED IN INFORMATION.
WE WOULD LIKE TO GET YOU THAT
INFORMATION AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE.
BUT THE GOVERNOR'S CHIEF CONCERN
IS MAKING SURE THAT THE FAMILIES
HAVE INFORMATION AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE.
THAT IS WHERE HE IS NOW.
THIS IS LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE
WITH THE STATE POLICE.
>> HI, GOOD AFTERNOON.
I'LL GIVE YOU SOME VERY BASIC
AND BRIEF INFORMATION AS WE KNOW
IT NOW.
WE'LL SET UP REGULAR PRESS
BRIEFINGS A APPROPRIATE.
THE POLICE RECEIVED A 911 FOR AN
EMERGENCY AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AT 9:41 A.M.
WE CONTACTED THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE AND SURROUNDING
POLICE DEPARTMENTS.
ON AND OFF-DUTY TROOPERS
RESPONDED TO THE SCHOOL.
THEY ENTERED THE SCHOOL AND
BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE
SHOOTER'S SEARCH OF THE
BUILDING.
CHECKING EVERY PORTION OF THAT
SCHOOL.
OUR MAIN OBJECTIVE WAS TO
EVACUATE AS QUICKLY AND
EFFICIE
EFFICIENTLY AS POSSIBLE.
THE ENTIRE SCHOOL WAS SEARCHED
THAT WAS ACCOMPLISHED.
A STAGING AREA WAS SET UP.
STUDENTS AND TEACHERS WERE PUT
INTO THAT STAGING AREA.
SOON THEREAFTER, STUDENTS AND
STAFFERS WERE REUNITED WITH
THEIR LOVED ONES.
THERE WERE SEVERAL FATALITIES AT
THE SCENE, BOTH STUDENTS AND
STAFF.
NO INFORMATION RELATIVE TO THAT
BEING RELEASED AT THIS TIME.
UNTIL WE MADE COMPLETE AND
PROPER NOTIFICATION.
THE SHOOTER IS DESEASED INSIDE
THE BUILDING.
GREAT DEAL OF WORK UPON LOCATING
THE SHOOTER.
GREAT DEAL OF LAW ENFORCEMENT IN
AND OUT OF STATE TO ENSURE THAT
WE COVER ALL OF THE BASIS
RELATIVE TO THAT INDIVIDUAL.
THE SCHOOL IS SECURED.
NEWTOWN POLICE DEPARTMENT, D
DANBURY AGENCIES ARE WORKING TO
OBTAIN MORE DETAILS.
WE'LL KEEP YOU INFORMED ON A
REGULAR BASIS.
WE'LL PUT EVERYTHING VIA OUR
WEBSITE AND WITH OUR PRESS
CONFERENCES.
>> THE GOVERNOR TOOK A CALL FROM
PRESIDENT OBAMA A LITTLE WHILE
AGO WHO WAS CALLING TO EXPRESS
HIS CONDOLENCES AND CONDOLENCES
ON BEHALF OF THE NATION AND
PLEDGED WHATEVER RESOURCES THE
FEDERAL GOVERNMENT CAN BRING TO
BEAR TO ASSIST THE FAMILIES
AROUND TO ASSIST IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
WE'LL GET YOU INFORMATION AS
SOON AS WE CAN GET THE FAMILIES
THE INFORMATION.
THAT'S WHERE THE GOVERNOR IS.
AT SOME POINT LATER TODAY, THE
GOVERNOR WILL BE HERE AND WE'LL
SET UP REGULAR BRIEFINGS.
THANK YOU.
>> THAT'S THE FIRST BRIEFING
FROM AUTHORITIES AT THE SCENE
THERE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WHERE THIS MORNING, 27 PEOPLE
WERE SHOT AND KILLED.
AT LEAST 27.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ABOUT 500 STUDENTS THERE.
AS YOU HEARD THE GOVERNOR THERE
HAS ARRIVED.
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT,
MALLOY, HE'S RIGHT NOW BRIEFING
PARENTS AT THE SCENE WHICH IS
WHY WE DIDN'T SEE HIM IN FRONT
OF THE MICROPHONE THERE.
THAT WAS A SPOKESMAN FOR THE
GOVERNOR WHO SAID THAT HE
RECEIVED A PHONE CALL FROM THE
PRESIDENT.
THE WORST SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN AMERICAN
HISTORY IT'S BELIEVED.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE WITH THE
CONNECTS CUT STATE POLICE
SPEAKING A MOMENT AGO.
HE SAID EVERY DOOR, EVERY CRACK,
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL HAS BEENER IS
CHLD.
THE ENTIRE SCHOOL SEARCHED, NOW
SECURE, HE SAID, HE DID DELIVER
THE NEWS SEVERAL FATALITIES AT
THE SCENE AND HE SAID THAT THIS
NUMBER AT LEAST 27 INCLUDES
STUDENTS AND STAFF AT THE
SCHOOL.
HE SAID THAT THE SHOOTER WAS
DECEASED INSIDE THE BUILDING.
CHRIS CUOMO HAS BEEN TOLD BY
SOURCES AT LEAST INITIALLY THERE
COULD BE TWO SHOOTERS.
WHICH COULD EXPLAIN THE
SEARCHING OUTSIDE THE SCHOOL.
WE'LL KNOW LATER IN THE DAY HOW
MANY PEOPLE WERE INVOLVED IN
THIS.
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE REPORTING
THAT A SHOOTER IS DECEASED
INSIDE THE BUILDING.
IT'S BELIEVED THAT DAN HARRIS AT
THE FIRE HOUSE NOW AT THE SCENE,
WE'RE BEING TOLD THAT GOVERNOR
IS BRIEFING PARENTS AS WE SPEAK.
THE GOVERNOR HAS HEARD FROM THE
PRESIDENT, CONDOLENCES ON WHAT
IS A HORRIFIC SCENE PLAYING OUT
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> HORRIFIC IS JUST ONE OF MANY
WORDS TO DESCRIBE THIS, DAVID,
LET ME GIVE YOU A SENSE OF WHERE
WE ARE, RIGHT BEHIND ME IS A
VOLUNTEER FIRE HOUSE, JUST UP
OVER THE HILL THAT WAY IS THE
SCHOOL, SANDY HOOK.
THIS VOLUNTEER FIRE HOUSE IS
WHERE ALL OF THE CHILDREN WERE
BROUGHT IN THE MOMENTS AFTER THE
SHOOTING BROKE OUT.
WE HAVE BEEN HERE FOR SOME TIME
NOW, REALLY JUST WATCHING A
STEADY STREAM OF POIGNANT
SCENES, LEAVING WITH LOOKS ON
THEIR FACES THAT REALLY TELL THE
WHOLE STORY, THEY ARE CREST
FALLEN, THEIR FACES ARE DRAWN,
LOT OF TRYING TO SHIELD THE
CHILDREN FROM THE EYES OF THE
MEDIA GATHERED HERE.
I TALKED TO ONE WHERE WHO WAS
LEAVING WITH HER 8-YEAR-OLD.
THE 8-YEAR-OLD TOLD ME WHEN THE
SHOOTING BROKE OUT INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, THERE WERE CRYING AND
SCREAMING, BUT GENERALLY CALM.
I SPOKE TO MOTHER AS WELL.
SHE SAID THAT SHE FELT LIKE SHE
NEEDED TO PINCH HERSELF BECAUSE
OF THE UNREALITY OF THIS.
DAVID, I CAN'T ESTABLISH FIRM
ENOUGH FOR YOU HOW BEAUTIFUL AND
RURAL A TOWN THIS IS, IT'S A
SCENIC, SOUTHERN NEW ENGLAND
TOWN, VERY SMALL.
FEWER THAN 30,000 PEOPLE LIVE
HERE.
WE'RE IN A NEIGHBORHOOD CALLED
SANDY HOOK NAMED AFTER A BEND IN
THE RIVER HERE.
A VERY RURAL TOWN.
NOT A PLACE WHERE YOU WOULD EVER
EXPECT SOMETHING LIKE THIS TO
TAKE PLACE.
HERE IN SANDY HOOK.
>> DAN, FOR SO MANY PARENTS,
WHEN I GO HOME, I OFTEN TRY TO
GO PICK UP MY NIECES OR NEPHEWS,
THAT'S ONE OF THE BEST PART OF
THE DAY THAT PLAYS OUT.
A SMILE WAITING FOR YOU ON THE
OTHER SIDE.
THE FACT THAT PICKING UP YOUR
CHILDREN TODAY AT THIS
PARTICULAR ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS
TAKEN ON SUCH PROFOUND MEANING
FOR PARENTS WHO GOT THE CALL,
THE ALERT TO GO TO THAT FIRE
HOUSE AND NOT KNOW WHETHER OR
NOT THEIR CHILDREN WAS ONE OF
THE CHILDREN WHO GOT OUT.
DAN, MAYBE YOU COULD HELP US
WITH THIS, THE GOVERNOR BELIEVED
TO BE BRIEFING THE PARENTS, LOT
OF PEOPLE IN THAT COMMUNITY ARE
WAITING AND HOPING THAT THEY
DON'T SEE THEIR NAME ON THAT
LIST.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I MEAN, YOU GOT TO KEEP IN MIND,
AT LEAST ACCORDING TO THE LATEST
NUMBERS THAT WE HAVE RIGHT NOW,
THERE ARE MORE THAN 20 FAMILIES
IN THIS TINY NEIGHBORHOOD HERE
WHO ARE UNSURE WHERE THEIR
CHILDREN ARE AND AT SOME POINT
DURING THE CASE OF THIS DAY ARE
GOING TO GET SOME ASTONISH INGLY
BAD NEWS GIVEN THE LATEST
NUMBERS WE HAVE ON THE LATEST
FATALITIES.
THE NOTIFICATION PROCESS IS
GOING TO BE GRISLY.
TO AMPLIFY SOMETHING THAT YOU
WERE TALKING ABOUT BEFORE ABOUT
THE PROCESS OF PICKING UP KIDS
UP FROM SCHOOL, HOW IT'S A DAILY
JOY FOR PARENTS, SPEAKING TO A
PARENT WHO I WAS TALKING TO A
SHORT WHILE AGO, HAVING HER TELL
ME ABOUT THE COURSE OF HER DAY
WHICH STARTED WITH THIS REVERSE
911 TEXT MESSAGE THAT SHOWED UP
ON HER PHONE THERE HAD BEEN A
SHOOTING AT THE SCHOOL DIDN'T
SAY WHICH ONE, PARENTS NEEDED TO
GO PICK UP THEIR CHILDREN AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
HER HUSBAND SAID GET IN THE CAR
AND GO TO THE SCHOOL
IMMEDIATELY.
SHE GOT HER AND SAW HER HUSBAND
HOLDING HER 8-YEAR-OLD.
IT WAS SO INTERESTING TO WATCH
THE BODY LANGUAGE BETWEEN THIS
MOTHER AND THE 8-YEAR-OLD.
THE MOTHER COULDN'T TAKE HER
HANDS OFF HER CHILD.
SHE WAS SO RELIEVED THAT HER
CHILD WAS OKAY.
NOW, SHE COULD NO LONGER TAKE
FOR GRANTED.
ONE OTHER QUICK EXCHANGE WITH A
PARENT, I SAW A TRULY FRANTIC,
VERY ANXIOUS WOMAN SHOWING UP ON
THE SCENE HERE A WHILE AGO, SHE
DIDN'T HAVE ANY CHILDREN IN THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS
BUT SHE HAD FRIENDS WHO DID SHE
WAS COMING HERE TO CHECK ON
THEM.
SHE ALSO SAID THAT SHE HAD
CHILDREN AT ANOTHER SCHOOL
NEARBY, SHE WAS WAITING FOR A
FEW HOURS TO PICK THEM UP.
THESE ARE THE LAST TWO HOURS OF
THEIR CHILDHOOD, ONCE THEY HEAR
WHAT HAPPENED HERE TODAY, THEIR
INNOCENCE WILL TRULY BE LOST AND
YOU GET A SENSE OF THE LOSS.
WHEN YOU WATCH PEOPLE FILING OUT
OF THIS FIRE STAYS BEHIND ME,
DAVID, MANY OF THEM CARRYING
STUFFED ANIMALS.
THAT TELLS YOU ABOUT THE KIND OF
VICTIM WE'RE DEALING WITH THIS
IN THIS MASSACRE TODAY.
>> THERE WAS AN IMAGE AS YOU
WERE REPORTING, A FIREFIGHTER ON
THE SCENE, WRAPPING A BLANKET
AROUND THE CHILD.
THESE CHILDREN, THIS IS ABC NEWS
COVERAGE OF A SHOOTING AT A
CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, IT'S --
THE NUMBERS ARE SIMPLY
STAGGERING.
AT LEAST 27 SHOT AND KILLED.
MANY OF THEM ARE CHILDREN.
THE CHILDREN INSIDE THIS SCHOOL,
YOU KNOW WE'RE TOLD AT A
MOMENT'S NOTICE TO SIMPLY GRAB A
FRIEND AND MAKE YOUR WAY FOR THE
DOOR AND THE IMAGES OF THE
CHILDREN LISTENING TO THAT CALL
FROM THEIR TEACHERS AND LEAVING
THE SCHOOL, SINGLE, FILE, OUR
REPORTERS ON THE SCENES SAID
THEY COULD HEAR CRIES, WHIMPERS
FROM THE CHILDREN, BUT IT WAS
REMARKABLY QUIET, THIS EXIT FROM
THE SCHOOL.
MORE THAN 500 CHILDREN GO TO
SCHOOL.
THE PRESIDENT BEING BRIEFED ON
THIS MORNING.
THE PRESIDENT HAS OFTEN TALKED
ABOUT HIS OWN TWO DAUGHTERS HOW
HE SHAPES HIS OWN VIEW AS
PRESIDENT JUST MOMENTS AGO, WE
HEARD FROM WHITE HOUSE SPOKESMAN
JAY CARNEY.
AS AN INCIDENT LIKE THIS, IT
WEIGHS HEAVILY ON THE PRESIDENT.
PIERRE THOMAS CAN GIVE ME AN
IDEA ON HOW THOSE BRIEFINGS
UNFOLD.
HE TALKED WITH THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT A SHORT TIME AGO,
SENDING HIS CONDOLENCES AND
OFFERS OF HELP THAT THIS
COMMUNITY MIGHT NEED.
WE'LL CHECK BACK IN WITH PIERRE
THOMAS IN OUR WASHINGTON BUREAU.
PIERRE K YOU HEAR US.
>> YES.
>> YOU CONTINUE TO WATCH THESE
PICTURES WITH ME.
I WAS JUST TALKING ABOUT JAY
CARNEY AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
HE TALKED ABOUT THE WEIGHT THE
PRESIDENT CARRIES OFTEN TALKING
ABOUT HIS OWN TWO GIRLS, WHO ARE
IN SCHOOL, HE OFFERED HELP TO
THIS COMMUNITY TO THE GOVERNOR.
AS WE HEARD DAN HARRIS, SO MANY
FAMILIES GATHERED THERE, SIMPLY
DON'T KNOW AND ARE FEARING THE
WORST WITHOUT THEIR CHILDREN
COMING OUT OF THIS SCHOOL, WHAT
CAN YOU TELL ME ABOUT THE
PRESIDENT'S CIRCLE AT THIS
POINT, WHO HAS BEEN BRIEFING
HIM?
>> WE UNDERSTAND THE FBI
DIRECTOR HAS BRIEFED THE
PRESIDENT.
ALSO, HOME LAND SECURITY
OFFICIALS ARE ENGAGED IN THIS
PROCESS, ALSO, THE BUREAU OF
ALCOHOL, TOBACCO AND FIREARMS.
THEY STEP UP TO THE LOCAL LAW
ENFORCEMENT PEOPLE AND SAY WHAT
DO YOU NEED?
THEY HAVE BEEN GETTING
INFORMATION AND PASSING IT UP
THE FOOD CHAIN TO THE PRESIDENT
TO LET HIM KNOW THE SCALE OF IT.
TYPICALLY, IF IT WEREN'T A SCALE
THIS LARGE, THE PRESIDENT
WOULDN'T BE BRIEFED.
BUT THE FACT SO MANY DEAD AND SO
MANY CHILDREN, THE PRESIDENT HAD
TO BE BRIEFED.
IT REMIND ME OF THE VIRGINIA
TECH SHOOTING, WHERE YOU HAVE A
CLASS ROOM SITUATION, OFTEN
NOWHERE TO GO, IF THE GUNMAN
COMES THROUGH A SINGLE DOOR YOU
COULD HAVE THESE MASS
CASUALTIES.
IN VIRGINIA TECH, MANY PEOPLE
WERE SHOT AND THE SHOOTER ONLY
HAD A HANDGUN
>> I REMEMBER THAT VIVIDLY.
PIERRE, THAT WAS ONE OF THE
GREAT TRAGEDIES OF THAT
PARTICULAR SHOOTING AND SO MANY
WE REPORT ON, THAT ONE SINGLE
ENTRANCE THAT YOU DESCRIBE IT
BASICALLY SUMS UP WHAT THESE
CLASS ROOMS ARE LIKE FOR
STUDENTS AND TEACHERS.
BECAUSE THERE'S ONE DOORWAY
THERE'S REALLY LITTLE ROOM FOR
THESE CHILDREN AND THE TEACHERS
ARE IN THOSE CLASS ROOMS WITH
THEM TO ESCAPE WHEN HORROR LIKE
THIS UNFOLDS.
THE LIMIT BOY TALKED ABOUT HOW
HE GOT OUT.
SAW SOMEONE THEY DIDN'T KNOW AT
THE TIME WAS THE PARTICULAR
GUNMAN INSIDE THE SCHOOL INFL  T
INFLICTING SUCH HORROR.
HE TALKED ABOUT HOW HAPPY HE WAS
TO SEE HIS FRIENDS AND THAT HIS
FRIENDS HAD MADE IT OUT.
PROFOUND WORDS BY A CHILD.
NOW, WORDS FROM HIS FATHER.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL IN SHOCK.
I KNOW THAT THERE WERE SOME
PEOPLE MISSING.
THEY WERE TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL.
I DON'T KNOW IF EVERYONE HAS
BEEN ACCOUNTED FOR.
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE RUSHING OVER
HERE AND YOU CAN'T GET TO WHERE
YOU NEED TO GO.
YOU HAVE TO PARK DOWN HERE AND
WALK.
I'M GLAD THAT MY SON IS OKAY.
HE SEEMS TO BE HANDLING ACTUALLY
PRETTY GOOD RIGHT NOW.
I KNOW MY SON'S TEACHERS HAVE
BEEN OKAY AS WELL.
BUTTING, I HAVE HEARD OTHER
TEACHERS AREN'T OKAY THERE WERE
A FEW, THEY FOUND, I JUST FOUND
ONE, A BIG CHEER WENT UP, THEY
FOUND SOMEONE.
THEY MAY NOT BEEN AT THE FIRE
HOUSE BUT SOMEWHERE ELSE.
>> THE NUMBERS, COULD BE 27
PEOPLE.
>> PAINFUL TO WATCH.
THE DAD WHO PUT SIMPLY HIS HAND
TO HIS MOUTH AND YOU CAN ONLY
IMAGINE WHEN THE PARENTS ARE
ABLE TO GET THEIR HEADS AROUND
WHAT UNFOLDED HERE TODAY AND THE
FACT THAT SOME OF THEM HAVE BEEN
EXTRAORDINARY LUCKY TO FIND
THEIR LITTLE ONES WAITING THERE
WHEN THEY GOT THERE.
AN EXCRUCIATING DIFFICULT
PROCESS OF INFORMING PARENTS
ABOUT THE CHILDREN WHO DIDN'T
MAKE IT OUT.
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE
CONFIRMING THAT THERE ARE MANY
CHILDREN AMONG THE DEAD AND
THERE ARE STAFF MEMBERS AMONG
THE DEAD AS WELL.
THE NUMBER STILL AT LEAST 27
SHOT AND KILLED.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO KEEP YOU
UPDATED ON THAT NUMBER AS WE
CONTINUE OUR COVERAGE HERE ON
ABC NEWS THROUGHOUT THE
AFTERNOON.
I WANT TO CHECK IN WITH ONE OF
OUR COLLEAGUES AT WABC
TELEVISION HERE IN NEW YORK.
AND CONNECTICUT.
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
60 MILES NORTHEAST OF NEW YORK.
THESE COMMUNITIES ARE ALL BESIDE
ONE ANOTHER AND IN THIS
PARTICULAR TOWN, A BUCOLIC TOWN,
A PICTURESQUE TOWN, SO MANY OF
THESE FAMILIES KNOW EACH
INTIMATELY.
THE DANBURY HOSPITAL WAS ON
STAND BY.
PERHAPS YOU CAN DESCRIBE THE
SCENE FOR US AT THIS HOUR.
>> DAVID, AS WE ARRIVED HERE AT
DANBURY, WE PULLED UP TO THE
EMERGENCY ROOM, THERE WERE
POLICE OFFICERS WITH ASSAULT
RIVALS, THE ENTIRE HOSPITAL
COMPLEX IS ON LOCKDOWN, THEY SAY
THAT'S STANDARD PROCEDURE,
CERTAINLY GIVEN THE
CIRCUMSTANCES IT'S SADLY
UNDERSTANDABLE.
THE MOOD INSIDE THE HOSPITAL IS
REALLY ACTUALLY QUITE GRIME.
WE HEARD SCENES DESCRIBED TO US
AS NURSES BREAKING DOWN IN THE
CORRIDORS.
PEOPLE SIMPLY AS YOU PUT IT
CAN'T GET THEIR ARMS AROUND THE
SCOPE, THE EVIL THAT HAS BEEN
PERSON TATED ON THIS COMMUNITY.
IT WILL PLAY IT OUT OVER THE
NEXT SEVERAL DAYS.
THE NUMBER OF PEOPLE I HAVE
SPOKEN TO HERE ARE HEART BROKEN
BECAUSE THEY WEREN'T ABLE TO
TREAT MORE PATIENTS.
>> THREE PEOPLE REPORTEDLY
TREATED AT DANBURY HOSPITAL
WHICH HAD BEEN DESIGNATED A
TRIAGE CENTER.
WHICH WOULD ONLY LEAD US TO
BELIEVE THAT PEOPLE IN THE PATH
OF THIS GUNMAN INSIDE THE SCHOOL
DID NOT SURVIVE.
THAT THE NUMBER OF BEING TREATED
WOULD ONLY BE THREE AT THIS
HOUR.
AS N.J. REPORTED THERE,
DESCRIBING THE SCENES INSIDE THE
CORRIDORS.
WE KNOW THAT EVERY INCH OF THAT
SCHOOL, EVERY CRACK, EVERY
CREVICE WAS CHECKED AS THEY
CONTINUE TO SEARCH TO TRY TO
SECURE THE AREA.
QUESTIONS ABOUT HOW MANY PEOPLE
MIGHT HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN
THIS.
A QUESTION THAT WILL BE
OUTSTANDING UNTIL WE CAN GET
FURTHER INFORMATION FROM
AUTHORITIES.
THEY DID CONFIRM FOR THAT
COMMUNITY AS WE CONTINUE OUR
LIVE COVERAGE THAT THE SCENE
ITSELF HAS BEEN SECURED.
THEY WERE ARMED WITH THEIR
TACTICAL GEAR IN FRONT OF THE
CHILDREN, GOING CAR TO CAR AS
YOU'RE SEEING FROM THESE AERIAL
SHOTS FROM OUR PARTNER STATION
HERE IN NEW YORK, WABC, WHICH
HAS BEEN ON THE SCENE FROM THE
MOMENT THEY GOT WORD OF THIS.
WE DO KNOW THAT THE GOVERNOR,
DAN MALLOY IS INSIDE BRIEFING
PARENTS.
THAT HAS TO BE THE PAINFUL
MEETING SO FAR OF THE DAY, THE
PARENTS WHO DO NOT WHETHER OR
NOT THEIR CHILDREN MADE IT OUT.