PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING ♪
>> Jimmy: I WANT TO THANK
HUGH JACKMAN, JENNA FISCHER.
APOLOGIES TO MATT DAMON, WE RAN
OUT OF TIME.
TOMORROW NIGHT
SAMUEL L. JACKSON, THE CAST OF
"JERSEY SHORE."
AND MUSIC FROM ED SHEERAN.
GOOD NIGHT.
>> TONIGHT OUTPOURING OF GRIEF
IN SANDY HOOK CONNECTICUT.
MEMORANDUM TO LAST WEEK SCHOOL
SHOOTING CONTINUES TO GROW EVEN
THAT THE LATE HOUR.  GOOD
EVENING I'M DAN ASHLEY.
>> I'M CARRY WRITTEN JOHNSON.
BEGIN WITH THE LATEST
INFORMATION COMING OUT OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.  STUDENTS
IN THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL DISTRICT
WILL RETURN TO CLASSES
TOMORROW.  THEY TOOK MONDAY OFF
TO MOURN THE 20 CHILDREN AND 6
ADULTS KILLED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ON FRIDAY.  ALL
SCHOOLS IN THE DISTRICT WILL
HAVE INCREASED SECURITY.
INVESTIGATORS HAVE NOT YET SAID
WHAT SPARKED THE SHOOTING RAMP
PAGE.  THEY DID TELL REPORTERS
2 FEMALE EMPLOYEE SHOT FRIDAY
SURVIVE.  INVESTIGATORS
PREVIOUSLY SAID THERE WAS JUST
ONE WOUNDED SURVIVOR.  FUNERALS
ARE SCHEDULED ALL WEEK FOR
THOSE WHO LOST THEIR LIVES IN
THE ATTACK.  EARLIER TODAY
SERVICE MARKING THE PASSING OF
6-YEAR-OLD THE AND TWIN SISTER
IN ANOTHER CLASSROOM DURING THE
SHOOTING.  SHE SURVIVED.
>> SECOND FUNERAL TODAY WAS
HELD FOR ANOTHER YOUNG VICTIM
ANOTHER CHILD JUST 6 YEARS OLD.
LAURA IS LIVE FROM SANDY HOOK
WHERE JACK PNT 0WAS LAID TO
REST.  LAURA.
>>Reporter:  HI DAN YES.  THE
TODAY.  RALL STARTED TODAY.  TY
WILL CONTINUE THROUGH THE WEAK.
EACH WILL BE HEART BREAKING IN
THEIR OWN RIGHT.  IN THE MEAN
TIME THIS PUBLIC MEMORIAL IN
THE CENTER OF TOWN CONTINUES TO
GROW AND AN EFFORT BY MOSTLY
STRANGE INVESTIGATORS COMFORT
THE PEOPLE HERE IN AT LEAST A
SMALL WAY.  THREE DAYS INTO THE
TINY TOWN NATURE MAYOR PEOPLE
COME FROM ALL OVER TO PAY THEIR
RESPECT GROWS BY THE HOUR.
FROM NEW YORK.  INDIANA.  OHIO.
NEW JERSEY.  THROUGHOUT THE
NORTHEAST.  THEY STAND WITH
THOSE WHO LIVE IN SANDY HOOK
AND NEWTOWN.  JOINED TOGETHER
IN A COMMON SENSE OF TREMENDOUS
LOSS.
>> I'M ACTUALLY VERY GRATEFUL
FOR THE DISPLAY OF SUPPORT FOR
THE FAMILIES.  BECAUSE I DON'T
THINK THE FAMILIES ARE STRONG
ENOUGH REALLY TO COME OUT HERE
YET AND WALK AROUND BUT THEY
KNOW EVERYONE IS COMING FOR
THEM.
>>Reporter:  EARLIER THOSE
FAMILY BEGAN PRIVATELY BURYING
THEIR LOVED ONES.  IN THIS CASE
SIMPLE SERVICE FOR 6-YEAR-OLD
JACK PINTO.  A LITTLE BOY
REMEMBERED FOR HIS LOVE OF
SPORTS ENERGETIC AND EASY SMIL
SMILE.
>> FOR ALL THE KIDS INSIDE TO
SEE THEM GO THROUGH THIS IN A
WAY THEY CAN HAM IT I FEEL IN
SO HORRIBLE FOR THE FAMILY.
>>Reporter:  AMONG THE MOURNER
MANY OF JACK YOUNG FRIENDS.
>> IT WAS JUST HE WAS SO
ENTHUSIASTIC ABOUT PLAYING
BECAUSE HE LIKES THERE.
>>Reporter:  FAMILY CALLED IN A
CREDIT CARD NUMBER TO THE
NEWTOWN GENERAL STORE.  THEY
SIMPLY WANTED TO PROVIDE THE
PEOPLE HERE WITH THE COMFORT
AND WARth OF FREE COFFEE.  BY
TONIGHT FALL LARGE MOVING TRUCK
PULLED OUT OF THE ROAD THAT
LEAD TO SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
BRINGING THE FURNITURE AND
EQUIPMENT TO ANOTHER CAMPUS SO
THE STUDENTS WHO SURVIVID CAN
SOON RETURN TO CLASSES.
>> HEART BREAT THE SAME>>ReportE
THE ADULTS HERE CAN'T HELP BUT
WONDER HOW THIS COMMUNITY CAN
POSSIBLY MOVE ON.
>> HOW DO YOU MOVE ON?
FAITH IN GOD AND THROUGH THE
FAMILY AND GIVING THE KID THE
EXTRA HUG AT NIGHT AND LOVE.
>>Reporter:  WE ARE BACK LIVE
HERE IN SANDY HOOK.  2:00
O'CLOCK IN THE MORNING.
POURING RAIN BUT STILL SEEN
PEOPLE OUT HERE UP UNTIL THE
LAST FEW MINUTES THEY HAVE BEEN
COMING AND GOING SHOWING THEIR
SUPPORT.  AS WE SAY THE FUNERAL
CONTINUE TOMORROW.  FIRST ONE
FOR A TEACHER WILL BE HELD HERE
TOMORROW AND THEN SCHOOL
RESUMES AS WE SAID FOR THE REST
OF THE NEWTOWN.  NOT FOR SANDY
HOOK.  THE MOVING ADVANCE
TAKING EQUIPMENT AND FURNITURE
TO SCHOOL IN MONROE MIDDLE
SCHOOL CLOSED FOR ABOUT A YEAR A
LOCAL CRAFTS MEN DONATED TIME
AND EFFORT TO MAKE SURE THAT
SCHOOL IS READY FOR THOSE KIDS
WHEN THEY ARE READY TO RETURN
TO CLASS.  THIS IS ABC 7 NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> RELIGIOUS LEADERS IN THE BAY
AREA RECOGNIZE THE NEED FOR
SPECIAL SERVICES TO HELP PEOPLE
COPE WITH THE AFTERMATH OF THE
CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY.  TONIGHT
NON-DENOMINATION SERVICE ON THE
PENINSULA BROUGHT PEOPLE OF
DIFFERENT FAITH TOGETHER.
ALLEN IS LIVE IN BURLINGAME
WITH THAT STORY.  ALLEN?
>>Reporter:  ONE OF THE PEOPLE
WHO CAME HERE TO HEAL TONIGHT
GREW UP IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUTMENT AND SHE SAYS
NEWTOWN ACE LOT LIKE BURLINGAM
BURLINGAME.
>> DANIEL AGE 7.  IF.
>>Reporter:  CONFUSED SHAKEN TO
THE CORE THEY SAME SEARCHING
FOR WORDS TO HELP THEM COPE
WITH THE TRAGEDY THAT HAS
STRUCK THE NATION.  PERHAPS NO
ONE IS MORE SHAKEN HERE THAN
BETSY CORK WHO READ THE
SCRIPTURE.
>> CONDITIONING OF ISRAEL THE
LORD IS IN YOUR MIDST YOU WILL
HAVE NO FURTHER MISFORTUNE TO
FEAR.
>> I'M SPWNSLY PROUD OF
EVERYONE IN NEWTOWN.  I'M PROUD
TO BE FROM NEWTOWN.
>>Reporter:  SHE GREW UP WITH
FRIENDS WHO WERE THE FIRST
RESPONDERS AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY BUT IS PROUD OF THE
WAY THE ENTIRE TOWN HAS
RESPONDED.
>> THE PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN ARE SHOWING
THE WORLD HOW TO LIVE.  HOW TO
LOVE.  AND HOW TO LOVE PEOPLE.
>> OLIVIA ANGLE, 6.  SANDY HOOK
ENDURED 20 DEATHS OF 6
7-YEAR-OLDS.
7-YEAR-OLDS.  I PROSECUTE POSE
TO YOU TONIGHT WE ARE IN THE
MIDST OF AN EVIL OF BIBLICAL
PROPORTIONS.
>> I HAVE JUST BEEN IN TOUCH
WITH FRIENDS ON FACEBOOK.  I
COULDN'T REALLY WATCH ANY OF
IT.
>>Reporter:  PAIN FOR HER IS
DEEP.  SO MANY OTHERS ARE ALSO
FEELING DEEP SENSE OF SORROW
AND THAT'S WHY PASTOR PAUL SAYS
HE ORGANIZED TONIGHT'S INNER
DENOMINATIONAL SERVICE OF
REMEMBRANCE, HEALING AND HOPE.
>> WE DON'T DO IT THEN PEOPLE
DO ONE OF TWO THINGS.  EITHER
BECOME DISTANT AND DISENGAGED
OR THEY BECOME HARSH AND BITTER
AND THIS IS WHAT IS NEED SOD WE
DON'T DO THOSE 2 MISTAKES.
PISHTION THE DOCTOR SAYS THISUCM
IS A VERY CRUCIAL TIME AND
THAT'S WHY HUMAN INTERACTION IS
NEEDED.  THAT'S WHY HE SAYS WE
NEED TO ENGAGE EACH OTHER AND
TALK ABOUT THE HURT.  REPORTING
LIVE IN BURLINGAME, ABC 7 NEWS.
>> TALK BIT.  THANK YOU ALLEN.
>> NEW AT 11 TONIGHT.  BAY AREA
MAN ARRESTED ACCUSED OF MAKING
THREATS ABOUT THE MASS
SOMEWHATING ON LINE.  FAIRFIELD
POLICE ARRESTED SERGIO THIS
AFTERNOON AT HIS HOME IN SUISU
SUISUN.  POLICE SAY HE POSTED
COMMENTS ON LINE THAT HE
SUPPORTED THE SHOOTER AND HAS
HAD THOUGHTS ABOUT DOING
SOMETHING SIMILAR.  POLICE
PURSUE FELL MY CHARGES FOR
MAKING THREATS.  HE POSTED AN
APOLOGY ON THE FACE BOOK PAGE
SAYING HE WAS EDGEY AND COCKY
IN THE MESSAGE.
>> IN RESPONSE TO THE SHOOTING
CALIFORNIA DEPARTMENT OF
EDUCATION ASKED SCHOOLS TO
REVIEW THEIR SECURITY PLANS.
90 MILLION DOLLARS YEAR HELPS
PUBLIC SCHOOL MAKE SECURITY
IMPROVE.  THEY HOLD LOCK DOWN
DRILL ONCE A MONTH.  TEACHER
CLOSE CURTAIN TURN OUT LIGHTS.
DROP TO THE FLOOR AND TELL
EVERYONE TO THE REMAIN SILENT.
DISTRICT ALSO MADE CHANGES TO
DOOR LOCK AND WINDOW EVEN SO IT
PLANS TO HAVE DIFFERENT
MEASURES.
>> GUN CONTROL SUPPORT,
ACCORDING TO NEW POST POLL 54
PERCENT SUPPORT STRICTER GUN
CONTROL IN GENERAL.  71 PERCENT
OPPOSE THE OUT RIGHT BAN OF
HAND GUNS BUT 52 PERCENT FAVOR
BANNING SEMI-AUTOMATIC AND
AMMUNITION CLIP THAT HOLD MORE
THAN 10 BULLET.
>> COLORADO TRAGEDY AND GUN
CONTROL DEBATE IGNITED LED TO
INCREASE IN GUN SALES ACROSS
THE COUNTRY AND BRAY AREA.  WE
HAVE THAT STORY.
>>Reporter:  IT WAS BUSY
WEEKEND AT MARIN COUNTY ARMS IN
NOVATO WHERE GUN SALES INCREASE
SINCE THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
SHOOTING.  HE WON'T SAY HOW
MANY GUNS ARE SOLD BUT OTHER
DEALERS REPORT RECORD SALES.
NATIONWIDE HANDGUN AND SHOTGUN
ARE SELLING QUICKLY. ONCE ONCE T
ON TV AND TALK ABOUT BAN AND
TAKING THINGS AWAY AGAIN IT'S A
PUSH AND PEOPLE AREN'T
INTERESTED IN PUSHING FIREARM
THAT MIGHT BE TAKEN FROM THEM.
>> WALKING TO WAL-MART AND OUT
OF AMMUNITION.
>>Reporter:  TRAP SHOOPER ISN'T
BUYING A GUN BUT HE WORRIES THE
NATIONAL TRAGEDY COULD UNFAIRLY
PUNISH WOULD BE GUN OWNER.
>> THE GUNS SHOULDN'T HAVE BEEN
IN THE HAND OF THE YOUNG MAN
AND YOU CAN'T STOP IT.
>>Reporter:  BUT FEINSTEIN IS
PROMISING TO REINTRODUCE AN
ASSAULT WEAPON BAN THAT EXPIRED
IN 2004 PROMPTED BY 1993 MASS
SHOOTING AT SAN FRANCISCO LAW
FORM.  CONGRESSWOMAN SPEAR VOWS
COMPANION LEGISLATION IN THE
HOUSE.
>> WE HAVE TO DID SOMETHING.
ABOUT THE GUN VIOLENCE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
>> SHE WAS SHOT AND WOUND
ENTERED JONES TOWN ALONGSIDE
CONGRESSMAN KILLED.  FIGHT FOR
GUN CONTROL WASN'T EASY BACK
THEN AND WON'T BE TODAY.
>> I REMEMBER STANDING ON
ASSEMBLY FLOOR TAKING UP THE
MEASURE WHEN ONE OF MY
COLLEAGUES ASKED ME HAVE YOU
EVER ACTUALLY SHOT AN ASSAULT
WEAPON AND I TURNED TO HIM AND
SAID LET ME ASK YOU A QUESTION.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN SHOT BY AN
ASSAULT WEAPON?
AND I HAVE.
>>Reporter:  THIS IS ABC 7 NEW
NEWS.
>>> OF COURSE WE WILL CONTINUE
TO COVER THE SCHOOL SHOOTING.
TRAGEDY IF NEWTOWN AS IT UNFOL
UNFOLDS.  "NIGHTLINE"UNCOVER
NEW WITH THIS NEWSCAST.
>> ALSO EXPRESS YOUR SYMPATHY
BY POSTING THIS BAN TO FACEBOOK
WUL.
>> LET'S TURN OUR ATTENTION TO
THE WEATHER CERTAINLY WAS QUITE
WET EARLIER TODAY.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.  COOLER TOO.
SANDY IS TRACKING INDEX ROUND
OF RAIN AND FROSTY CONDITIONS.
>> SHOW YOU LIVE DOPPLER 7 HAD.
D THE RAIN EARLIER TODAY IT'S
LONG GUN.  AS WE LOOK AT OUR
RAID HERE THE CLOUD ARE PARTING
WAIVE AND WELL 15 BELOW WHERE
YOU WERE JUST 24 HOURS AGO.
TWO IN NAP A.FRINGES IN CONCORD
AND LIVERMORE.  GOES GATTOES WE
ARE HEADED TOWARDS A CHILLY
NIGHT WHERE THE TEMPERATURES
ARE GOING TO BOMB OUT ONE THING
FOR SURE ONLY GOING TO GET
COLDER AS WE HEAD INTO TUESDAY
NIGHTS NEEDS MORNING.  SHOW YOU
WHEN THE NEXT RAIN COMES BACK.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.  BREAKING
NEWS FROM THE FINANCIAL 8
PEOPLE TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL
FOLLOWING HAZARDOUS MATERIAL
SCARE.  TAKE YOU THERE LIVE.
>> PILL SCARE FOR HAD DAY
SHOPPERS.  WHAT LED TO
EVACUATION TO WEARING A
HOMELESS SIGN.  WHY AUTHORITIES
SAY THEY HAD TO
.
>> ALL RIGHT WE ARE TRACKING
SOME BREAKING NEWS ON THE
PENINSULA.  8 PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL FOLLOWING
A HAZARDOUS MATERIAL SCARE.  WE
ARE LIFE NEAR REDD WITH CITY
WITH THE LATEST ON THIS FOR US.
CORNELL?
>>Reporter:  IT HAS BEEN A VERY
CHAOTIC NIGHT HERE AT THE
SEQUOIA MOBILE HIM PARK WHERE
RESIDENT LIVING HERE ARE
RECOVERING AFTER THEY SETOFF A
CAN OF FLEA FOGGER INSIDE THEIR
UNIT AND DID FOUGHT LEAVE AS
YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO DO.  THE
CHEMICAL SICKEN THE COUPLE
LIVING THERE ALONG WITH SEVERAL
NEXT DOOR NEIGHBORS.
AUTHORITIES SAY SOME
FIREFIGHTERS RESPONDING TO THE
SCENE HAD TO BE WASHED OFF BY
HAZMAT UNITS AFTER THEY CAME
INTO CONTACT WITH THE BUG FO
FOGGER.  3 FIREFIGHTERS WERE
TRANSPORTED TO THE HOSPITAL
ALONG WITH 5 RESIDENTS, EIGHT
PEOPLE TOTAL.  WE ARE TOLD THAT
EVERYONE WILL BE OKAY TONIGHT.
2 DOG INSIDE THAT MOBILE HOME
WERE BROUGHT OUT SHORT TIME AG
AGO.  THEY ARE GOING TO BE FINE
TOO.  LIVE IN REDWOOD CITY, 7
NEWS.
>> OKAY THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> DEVELOPING NEWS FROM SAN
FRANCISCO THIS EVENING WHERE A
PHARMACY EMPLOYEE WAS SHOT
DURING AN ATTEMPTED ROBBERY.
SHOOTING HAPPENED JUST AFTER
6:30 AT THE A.G.  PHARMACY ON
CAESAR CHAVEZ STREET IN THE
MISSION DISTRICT.  POLICE LOO
LOOKING FOR 2 MEN WHO HELD UP
THE EMPLOYEE AND GET AWAY
DRIVER.  EMPLOYEE WAS SHOT IN
THE LEG AND IS EXPECTED TO
SURVIVE.
>> THEN THIS IN SAN FRANCISCO.
FIREFIGHTERS QUICKLY SNUFFED
OUT A FLEW FIRE SAYS IT BROKE
OUT IN THE MALL AFTER 8:30
TONIGHT.  WEST FIELD THEATER
WAS TEMPORARILY EVACUATED.  NO
WORD ON EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
SITUATION.  AUTHORITIES IN
SANTA CRUZ ARE LOOKING FOR THE
PERSON WHO ABANDONED A DOG
WEARING A SIGN THAT SAID HOM
HOMELESS.  TAKE A LOOK.  FEMALE
COCKER SPANIEL FOUND TIED TO
POLE IN DOWNTOWN SANTA CRUZ.
SHE HAD AN INFECTED WOUND ON
THE UNDER SIDE AND VETS
COULDN'T HEAL IT.  THEY HAD TO
PUT HER DOWN.  SHELTER MANAGER
SAYS NOT PROVIDING VETERINARY
CARE TO SUFFERING ANIMAL IS
ILLEGAL.
>> THAT'S A SHAME.  LET'S TURN
OUR ATTENTION TO THE WEATHER
FORECAST AND A LITTLE ROUGH
WEATHER TONIGHT.
>> IT'S GETTING QUITE COLD OUT
THERE.  SANDY IS HERE.
>> WE ARE INCHING TOWARDS
WINTER AND CERTAINLY ALREADY
FEELING LIKE IT WINTER ARRIVES
THIS COMING FRIDAY.  LIVE
DOPPLER SHOWING YOU THAT IT IS
CLEAR ACROSS THE BEAR EXCEPT
FOR FEW CLOUDS DOWN TOWARD THE
BAY AND INFORM RAIN RIGHT NOW
BUT OUR TOPLER ON MOUNT SAINT
HELENA COMBINED WITH NATIONAL
WEATHER SERVICE WATCHING FOR
THE NEXT STORM AND OF COURSE
TRYING TO TRACK IT WELL AHEAD
OF THE NEXT STORM SO THAT WE
CAN WARN NEW ADVANCE.  HERE'S A
LOOK AT THE SIERRA NEVADA.  YOU
CAN SEE THAT THE SNOW IS
STARTING TO PICK UP AGAIN IN
THIS SIERRA NEVADA ACROSS ENTER
NATURE 80 AND 50 SO I DO WANT
TO TELL YOU THAT THERE'S A
WINTER WEATHER THE ADVISORY FORE
LAKE TAHOE AREA THAT HAS BEEN
EXTENDED UNTIL NOOCHBILITY
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THAT IN JUST A
MOMENT.  LOOK TERRAIN FALL
TOTAL.  SANTA ROSA AIRPORT
$2,200 PICKED UP OVER AN INCH
IN THE LAST 24 HOURS.  SAN JOSE
15 HUNDREDTHS.  OAKLAND 43
HUNDRED.  OUT TO FAIRFIELD
LIVERMORE UNDER A TENTH OF AN
INCH OF RAIN IN THE PAST 24
HOURS.  HERE'S WHAT FELL IN
CLEAR LAKE THIS WAS POSTED ON
MY FACE BOOK PAGE BY ROGER KAY
HE SAID OVER THE WEEKEND THEY
RECEIVED SOME SNOW WE HAD
WARNED YOU ON FRIDAY THAT
MOUNTAINS LAKE COUNTY COULD
POSSIBLY 7 SOME SNOW.  WE ARE
HEADED TOWARDS ANOTHER NIGHT OF
SOME VERY COLD CONDITIONS AND
TOMORROW WE MAY SEE THE SNOW
LEVEL LOWERING 3000
HE DOWN TO 3000
HERE LOCALLY BUT UP TO THE
NORTH THEY COULD SEE REPEAT OF
THE SNOW THEY SAW OVER THE
WEEKEND.  SLIGHT CHANCE OF
SHOWERS.  FREEZING COLD WITH
PATCHY FROST BY WEDNESDAY
MORNING WHEN WE EXPECT UPPER
20'S.  STORM THAT BROUGHT US
THE RAIN.  SOGGY CONDITIONS FOR
THE MORNING COMMUTE.  HERE IS
THE TROUGH AND THE COLD AIR
FROM THE GULF OF ALASKA THAT
WILL BE DROPPING DOWN FOR YOUR
TUESDAY, THIS IS GOING TO BRING
US A SLIM CHANCE OF A FEW
SHOWERS AND CERTAINLY THE
CHILLY AIR TOMORROW AS WE ENTER
TUESDAY AND BEYOND.  ACTIVE
PATTERN THURSDAY THROUGH SUNDAY
AS SYSTEM ARE LINED UP IN THE
PACIFIC SO WE WILL SEE SOME
PERIODS OF WET WEATHER DURING
THAT TIME PERIOD.  EXPECTING OF
I SHOW YOU OUR COMPUTER
ANIMATION.  TONIGHT 11:00 P.M.
JUST A COUPLE CLOUDS AROUND AS
WE GET INTO 5:00 A.M.  FEW
SHOWERS SKIRT THE COAST LINE AS
THE TROUGH DROPS DOWN.  UKIAH
COULD SEE RAIN DROPS AND WE
HEAD AROUND 10 OR 11 OKAY WE
MAY SEE A LITTLE BIT OF MIX OF
RAIN AND SNOW JUST TO THE NORTH
OF UKIAH.  REALLY THE SHOWER
CHANCES VARY SLIM AND CON POOND
TO THE KEINGT FOR YOUR TUESDAY.
GRAB UMBRELLA WHEN YOU HEAD
OUT THE DOOR ON THE SAFE SIDE.
WINTER ADVISORY FOR TAHOE.  4
TO 8 INCHES OF SNOW RUNNING
UNTIL NOON TOMORROW.  BELOW
7000 2 TO 4 INCHES AND HIGHER ID
PASS MAYBE IMPACTED SO JUST BE
AWARE OF.  THAT 2 TO 12 INCHES
OF SNOW IN THE LAST 24 HOURS.
CHILLY TOMORROW MORNING.  34 IN
SANTA ROSA.  35 IN NAP A.36 IN
LIVERMORE.  COOL AROUND THE BAY
AS WELL.  BUNDLE UP WHEN YOU
HEAD OUT THE DOOR ANEXTRA LAYERP
EXTRA LAYERS HANDY.  COOL
TOMORROW AFTERNOON.  MOST AREA
LOW TO MID 50'S.  PARTLY CLOUDY
MID UPPER 40'S AROUND THE NORTH
AND FOR THE MONTEREY BAY WE
LOOK AT LOW TO MID 50'S.
PARTLY CLOUDY SLIGHT CHANCE OF
SHOWERS FROYINGT MORNING
WEDNESDAY UPPER 20'S IN THE
COLDEST VALLEY.  RAINY PATTERN
BEGINNING THURSDAY FRIDAY AND
THEN MORE SHOWERS IN THE
FORECAST RAIN TO SHOWERS OVER
THE WEEKEND.  CHRISTMAS EVE
SHAS DAY DRY.
>> GOOD.
>> LOOKING GOO LOOKING GOOD FOR.
>> THANKS SANDHYA.
>> CHECK IN NOW WITH LARRY.
>> A THROAT TALK ABOUT.  GREAT
DAY FOR THE 49ERS.
>> FORECAST WAS LIKE NEW
ENGLAND LAST NIGHT.  THE RAIN
THE SLEET THE HAIL.  ALL COMING
DOWN.  HOW SIGNIFICANT WAS THAT
WIN OVER THE PATRIOTS?
WE HEAR FROM COACH HARBAUGH ON
GAME THAT REALLY TURNED INTO AN
INSTANT CLASSIC.  SPORTS IS
NEXT.
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
>> GOOD EVENING.  THIS IS
UNDOUBTEDLY WHAT JIM HARBAUGH
HAD IN MIND WHEN HE DECIDED TO
STAY WITH COLLIN AT QUARTERBAC
QUARTERBACK.  STATEMENT WIN
AGAINST SUPER BOWL CONTENDER ON
THE ROAD IN DECEMBER.  HE THREW
4 TOUCH DOWN PASS INS RAINY
BREEZY NEW ENGLAND LAST NATURE.
POISE REMARKABLE FOR GUY IN
JUST THE FIFTH NFL START.  NOW
EASY TO UNDERSTAND WHY HARBAUGH
KEPT TRYING TO REALLY FORCE
FEED HIM IN GAMES WHEN SHIFT
WAS HEALTHY.  IF THE NINERS
BEAT SEATTLE ON SUNDAY THEY
CLINCH THE WEST.  THIS WAS A
HUGE VICTORY.
>> TEAMS THAT HAVE A LOT OF
PRIDE AND HOW THEY PLAY.
REALLY CAME OUT.  HE WAS BETTER
AND WANTED TO BE BETTER AND WIN
THE GAME.  AND IT SHOWED.
>>Reporter:  MONDAY NIGHT
FOOTBALL JETS TITAN.  SANCHEZ
AND JETS ARE SO BAD.  HE THREW
4 PICK TONIGHT.  I DON'T KNOW
SON CAN DO IS RUN REALLY FAST.
UP THE MIDDLE AND ALOHA.  94
YARDS.  TAKE IT AN UP 7-3.
JETS COMMITTED 5 TURN OVERS.
FINAL MOMENTS THE GAME IS ON
THE LINE.  PLAY OFF HOPES ARE
ON.  HE KICKED THE BALL.  OH.
THE JETS ARE OFFICIALLY OUT OF
THE PLAY OFF CHASE.  14-10.
TITANS.  SAN JOSE STATE HIRED
REPLACEMENT FOR MIKE OFF TO
COLORADO.  SOUTH BAY NATIVE RON
FROM THE UNIVERSITY OF SAN
DIEGO TAKING OVER THE SPARTANS.
>> THIS OF THIS PROGRAM
AND I KNOW THERE ARE UPS AND
DOWNS OVER THE LAST YEARS BUT
MAYBE I CAN COME IF AND BRING
SOME CONSISTENCY AND BUILD OFF
WHAT COACH MACK DID AND KEEP IT
AT HIGH LEVEL THE.  CERTAINLY
LOOKING FORWARD TO THAT
OPPORTUNITY AND EMBRACE THAT
CHALLENGE.
>> HOCKEY TONIGHT.  SAN
FRANCISCO BULLS PLAYED IN THE
SHARK TANK THIS EVENING.
ALMOST 13,000 FANS HUNGRY FOR
HOCKEY DURING THE NHL LOCK OUT
WATCH THE BULLS STOCKTON
THUNDER.  TICKETS FREE BUT SOME
STARS PAID OTHER PEOPLE TO GET
THE FREE TAX.  IN THE END LULLS
LOST 6-4 BUT AT LEAST HOCKEY
FOR A NIGHT AT HP PAVILION.
>> BASEBALL NEWS.  A 3 YEAR
DEAL IN THE NEIGHBOR OF 15
MILLION DOLLARS RESIGNING THIS
GUY AN THAT'S GOOD
NEIGHBORHOOD.  HE PITCHED IN 73
GAMES FOR THE WORLD CHAMPION
THIS PAST SEASON AND REPORTED
25 SAVES.  ABC 7 SPORTS BROUGHT
TO YOU BY RIVER ROCK CASINO.
>> FUN TO WATCH HIM BLOSSOM.
>> REMARKABLE.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> WHEN WE COME BACK WE'LL
RECAP THE LATEST HEADLINES ON
THE SCHOOL SHOOTING AND SANDY
HOOK.
>> STAY WITH US
[ Female Announcer ]
CAN YOUR PANCAKE MIX DO THIS?
SURE, BISQUICK MAKES
DELICIOUS PANCAKES,
BUT THAT'S JUST THE START.
UNLEASH THE HIDDEN POWER
OF BISQUICK.
SEE WHAT YOU CAN MAKE
AT BISQUICK.COM.
[ Female Announcer ] LET
BETTY CROCKER DO THE MEASURING
AND GET A HEAD START
ON DELICIOUS HOMEMADE COOKIES.
♪
JUST POUR, MIX...LOVE.
HERE'S THE WAKE UP WEATHER
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
CHILLY L.  COOL NEAR THE BAY.
GRAB A SWEATER OR COAT WHEN YOU
HEAD OUT THE DOOR.  SLIGHT
CHANCE OF SHOWERS.
TEMPERATURES MID 30'S TO 40'S
AT 5:00 A.M.  AND AT 8:00 A.M.
WE LOOK AT MID 30'S TO THE MID
40'S.SO STAYING ON THE CHILLY
SIDE.  MIKE WILL BE HERE FROM
4:30 TO 7:00 A.M.  TRACKING ANY
WEATHER CHANGES.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> ALL RIGHT WE WANT TO TAKE
ONE LAST LOOK AT THE LATEST ON
THE SANDY HACK SHOOT HAD GONE
IN CONNECTICUT >> NEWTOWN
POLICE WILL MONITOR THE 6
SCHOOLS IN THE DISTRICT WHEN
THEY OPEN TOMORROW N.APP
EMERGENCY MEETING TONIGHT WE
AGREED TO LET SURVIVORS ATTEND
CLASSES AT UNUSED MIDDLE
SCHOOL.
>> 2 FUNERAL ARE SCHEDULED FOR
TOMORROW FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JAMES
MATT AND JESSICA RAK O S.
FIGHT LINE UP NEXT ABSENCE AND
CYNTHIA EXPLORE NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THE SHATTER HIS MOTHER
AND THE WEAPONS HE USED IN THE
ATTACK.
>> STAY TAWN FOR THAT ON
"NIGHTLINE".  COMING UP MEDLEY
THAT'S OUR REPORT TONIGHT.
>> FOR ALL OF US SANDY AND ALL
OF US HERE.  WE YOUR TIME.  4YO
OF US HERE.  WE YOUR TIME.
4:30 AM AND ALWAYS AVAILABLE ON
OUR WEB SITE.  ON FACEBOOK AND
TWITTER AT ABC 7 NEWS BAY AREA.
>> GOOD NIGHT.
[ Female Announcer ] NOW GET
HIGH SPEED INTERNET AT HOME
ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOU CAN COUNT ON.
INTRODUCING AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
WITH MORE SPEED OPTIONS,
RELIABILITY
AND Wi-Fi HOT SPOTS THAN EVER.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW TO GET
U-verse HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
IT'S ALL THE SPEED YOU NEED
ALL AT A GREAT PRICE.
OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network
GIVES YOU MORE
OF WHAT YOU ENJOY ONLINE.
AND WITH AT&T,
OUR WIRELESS GATEWAY
TURNS YOUR HOME
INTO A PRIVATE Wi-Fi HOT SPOT
THAT CONNECTS
YOUR Wi-Fi DEVICES
AND CAN EVEN SAVE ON YOUR
SMART PHONE DATA USAGE AT HOME.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW
TO GET AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT INCLUDES ACCESS ON-THE-GO
TO OUR ENTIRE NATIONAL
Wi-Fi HOT SPOT NETWORK,
WITH OVER 30,000 HOT SPOTS.
AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET.
NOW ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOUR WHOLE HOUSE
CAN COUNT ON.
♪
RETHINK OUR LAWS.
>> I DON'T KNOW ANYBODY THAT
NEEDS 30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP TO GO
HUNTING.
>> Reporter: AND ONE REPUBLICAN
LAWMAKER SAID IF THE SANDY HOOK
PRINCIPAL HAD BEEN ARMED, SHE
COULD HAVE STOPPED THE GUNMAN.
>> SHE TAKES HIM OUT, TAKES HIS
HEAD OFF BEFORE HE CAN KILL
THOSE PRECIOUS KIDS.
>> Reporter: MAYOR MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG DEMANDED PRESIDENT
OBAMA AND CONGRESS STEP UP.
>> WORDS ALONE CANNOT HEAL OUR
NATION.
ONLY ACTION CAN DO THAT.
>> Reporter: SEVERAL DEMOCRATIC
LAWMAKERS SAID THEY WOULD
INTRODUCE AN ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
ON THE FIRST DAY OF THE NEXT
CONGRESS IN JANUARY.
ROB AND PAULA, BACK TO YOU.
>> THAT DOES BRING US TO OUR
FACEBOOK QUESTION OF THE DAY.
>> WHAT IS YOUR ADVICE TO
LAWMAKERS AS THEY DEBATE THE GUN
CONTROL LAWS.
JOIN THE HEATED DISCUSSION ON
OUR FAN PAGE AND WE'RE GOING TO
READ YOUR RESPONSES ON THE AIR.
AS SHE JUST ALLUDED TO THAT
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN WAS FROM
1994 TO 2004.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE LONG-TERM
EFFECTS, THEY SAID THERE WAS NO
CHANGE, MAYBE A SMALL DECREASE
IN THE MASS SHOOTINGS, BUT
OVERALL, NOT A DECREASE IN
VIOLENCE.
>> THE JURY IS OUT.
YESTERDAY, ACCORDING TO A 2004
UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA STUDY
ABOUT THE BAN, THE NUMBER OF
PEOPLE KILLED IN MASS SHOOTINGS
DID GO DOWN IN THE YEARS THE BAN
WAS IN EFFECT EXCEPT FOR '99.
THAT WAS COLUMBINE, AS WE ALL
REMEMBER.
BUT BECAUSE MASS SHOOTINGS ARE
RELATIVELY RARE, IT'S DIFFICULT
TO TELL WHETHER THIS WAS CAUSED
BY THE BAN.
THE PRESIDENT HAS GIVEN A LOT OF
LIP SERVICE TO GUN CONTROL
BECAUSE OF THE NATIONAL OUTRAGE.
BUT THIS IS A PRESIDENT WHO HAS
BEEN MUCH MORE FRIENDLY TO GUN
OWNERS THAN GUN CONTROL
ADVOCATES.
HE ALLOWED GUNS ON AMTRAK TRAINS
AND ALLOWED GUNS IN NATIONAL
PARKS.
HE GAVE LIP SERVICE TO GETTING
THIS BAN BACK IN EFFECT.
SO YOU HAVE TO WONDER NOW
BECAUSE THE TONE OF THE COUNTRY
BECAUSE OF SANDY HOOK WHETHER HE
WILL ACTUALLY DO SOMETHING OR
NOT.
BUT THIS HAS NOT BEEN ON HIS
AGENDA HIS FIRST TERM.
>> THAT ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN,
THERE WERE A LOT OF LOOPHOLES.
MAYBE THERE WON'T BE AS MANY
LOOPHOLES.
>>> MOVE ALONG, THE SANDY HOOK
TRAGEDY HAS HIM ON A MISSION TO
GET MORE GUNS OFF THE STREETS,
STEVEN BARTON WAS IN
COLORADO WHEN HE WAS SHOT DURING
THE MOVIE THEATER MASSACRE.
HE HAPPENS TO LIVE IN
CONNECTICUT JUST A FEW MILES
FROM NEWTOWN AND HE'S HOPING THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING WILL BRING ABOUT
CHANGE.
>> OUR COUNTRY IS LONG OVERDUE
FOR A SERIOUS DISCUSSION ABOUT
GUNS