WHO SPEAKS TO SOLD-OUT AUDIENCES
AROUND THE WORLD, WHY HE CALLS
THIS THE MOST SIGNIFICANT
DISCOVERY OF HIS LIFETIME.
INTRODUCING THE NUTRIBULLET, THE
SUPERFOOD NUTRITION EXTRACTOR.
THE NUTRIBULLET IS NOT A
BLENDER, IT'S NOT A JUICER.
IT'S A BREAKTHROUGH
IN NUTRITIONAL SCIENCE
THAT CAN CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
THE NUTRIBULLET'S HIGH-POWERED
MOTOR WITH BULLET-EXCLUSIVE
CYCLONIC ACTION BREAKS DOWN AND
PULVERIZES FOOD ON A CELLULAR
LEVEL, OPENING UP THEIR HIDDEN
NUTRITIONAL VALUE THAT CAN
REVERSE THE EFFECTS OF AGING AND
SUPERCHARGE YOUR METABOLISM TO
FIGHT OFF ACHES AND PAINS, COLDS
AND FLUS, AND EVEN IMPROVE VITAL
HEATH MARKERS LIKE CHOLESTEROL
LEVELS AND BLOOD PRESSURE.
SO, TAKE AN EXCLUSIVE SEAT AT
OUR NUTRIBULLET SEMINAR WORKSHOP
WITH LONGEVITY EXPERT DAVID
WOLFE AS HE SHOWS US HOW TO
UNLEASH THE POWER OF FOOD TO
FIGHT ARTHRITIC PAIN, BALANCE
HORMONES, SUPERCHARGE YOUR
IMMUNE SYSTEM, LOSE WEIGHT AND
TURN BACK THE HANDS OF TIME
FIVE, 10, EVEN 20 YEARS WITH
THIS INCREDIBLE MACHINE, THE
NUTRIBULLET, THE SUPERFOOD
NUTRITION EXTRACTOR.
>> GREETINGS, EVERYBODY.
I'M DAVID WOLFE.
WELCOME TO MY WORKSHOP.
TODAY WE'RE GONNA TALK
ABOUT NUTRITION.
WHY?
I'LL TELL YOU WHY.
BECAUSE OVER THE LAST 30 YEARS,
WE'VE BECOME THE MOST OVERFED
YET UNDERNOURISHED NATION
IN THE ENTIRE WORLD.
THIS HAS CREATED AN EPIDEMIC
OF HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE, OBESITY,
DEPRESSION, STRESS
AND A WHOLE LOT MORE.
THAT'S WHY I'M SO EXCITED
TO BRING YOU A MACHINE THAT'S
GOING TO CHANGE YOUR LIFE
THE WAY IT CHANGED MY LIFE.
THIS IS THE NUTRIBULLET,
THE WORLD'S FIRST
NUTRITION EXTRACTOR.
A NUTRITION EXTRACTOR IS NOT A
BLENDER, IT'S NOT A JUICER.
IT'S COMPLETELY DIFFERENT FROM
ANYTHING ELSE OUT THERE.
THIS MACHINE IS DESIGNED TO
BREAK DOWN THE CELL WALLS OF
YOUR FOOD, RELEASING, UNLEASHING
THE NUTRIENTS INSIDE,
TRANSFORMING ORDINARY FRESH
FOODS INTO SUPERFOODS.
NOW I'M GONNA SHOW YOU THE
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN SMOOTHIES
FROM A TRADITIONAL BLENDER
AND WHAT WE CAN CREATE
WITH MY NUTRIBULLET.
LET ME SHOW YOU
WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
O.K., WE'RE GONNA PUT KALE IN
FOR CHLOROPHYLL AND FIBER.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE SOME PINEAPPLE
FOR THE VITAMIN C
AND A LITTLE BIT OF FLAVOR.
WE'RE GONNA PUT IN SOME
CUCUMBERS, GREAT FOR HYDRATION,
GREAT FOR THE KIDNEYS,
PUT IN SOME CASHEWS FOR THE
CREAMINESS AND THE PROTEIN.
AND OF COURSE WE'RE GONNA ADD
SOME FLAX SEEDS IN TO GET
THE OMEGA-3 FATTY ACIDS.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA ADD
SPRING WATER.
LET'S GET THE LID ON THERE.
PUT ON THE EXTRACTOR BLADES
ONTO OUR NUTRIBULLET.
ARE YOREADY?
>> Audience: READY!
>> LOOK, THIS BLENDER IS JUST
MIXING STUFF AROUND--
IT'S NOT BREAKING ANYTHING DOWN.
BUT THE NUTRIBULLET WITH ITS
600 WATTS OF COMPACT POWER AND
BULLET-EXCLUSIVE CYCLONIC ACTION
COMBINED WITH THE SPECIALLY
DESIGNED EXTRACTOR BLADES
TURNING AT AN AMAZING 10,000
R.P.M.s PULVERIZING THE CELL
WALLS, UNLOCKING ALL THAT HIDDEN
NUTRITION SO YOUR BODY CAN
ACTUALLY ABSORB IT AND USE IT.
NOW, I'VE GOT A STRAINER HERE,
WE'RE GONNA POUR OUR BLENDED
SMOOTHIE THROUGH AND SEE
WHAT IS LEFT OVER.
WHAT'S GONNA MAKE IT THROUGH?
WE'VE GOT UNBROKEN FLAX SEEDS,
LOTS OF FIBER...
HERE, LET ME SHOW YOU THIS.
THIS, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IS WHAT WE CALL A SMOOTHIE.
[AUDIENCE EXCLAIMS]
NOW LET'S SEE WHAT HAPPENED
WITH THE NUTRIBULLET.
I TAKE OFF THE EXTRACTOR BLADES,
LOOKS LIKE WE'VE GOT QUITE
A BEVERAGE IN HERE.
LET'S BRING IT OUT AND POUR IT
THROUGH THE STRAINER.
IT'S COMPLETELY LIQUEFIED.
ALL THAT NUTRITION HAS BEEN
TURNED INSIDE OUT.
EVERYTHING'S BEEN COMPLETELY
BROKEN DOWN.
AND WHEN WE POUR IT,
WE CAN SEE JUST HOW GLOWING
IT IS, BEAUTIFUL.
THE REAL TEST IS ALWAYS
THE FLAVOR.
LET'S GIVE IT A TRY.
THAT, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IS WHAT I CALL A NUTRIBLAST.
WE'VE TAKEN ALL OF THOSE CELLS,
PULVERIZED THEM, FLIPPED THEM
INSIDE OUT, GOT ALL OF THAT
JUICE, ALL THE NUTRIENTS--
THE VITAMINS, THE MINERALS, THE
ENZYMES, THE ESSENTIAL FATTY
ACIDS, THE PROTEIN--
AND NOW WE CAN ACTUALLY
ASSIMILATE AND UTILIZE
THOSE NUTRIENTS.
WE'VE TURNED THIS
INTO A SUPERFOOD.
LISTEN, JUICERS MAKES JUICE
AND BLENDERS MAKE SMOOTHIES,
BUT THE NUTRIBULLET MAKES
NUTRIENT-PACKED NUTRIBLASTS.
ALL I'M ASKING YOU TO DO IS HAVE
ONE NUTRIBLAST A DAY AND THAT
WILL TRANSFORM YOUR LIFE.
>> ABOUT FIVE YEARS AGO
THE DOCTOR TOLD ME AFTER TAKING
MY CHOLESTEROL NUMBERS
THAT I WAS GONNA HAVE TO BE ON
CHOLESTEROL MEDICATION AND MOST
LIKELY FOR THE REST OF MY LIFE.
WE TRIED TO ADDRESS IT WITH
DIET, WE TRIED TO ADDRESS IT
WITH EXERCISE AND NEITHER
OF THEM SEEMED TO WORK.
THERE IS A HISTORY OF HEART
DISEASE IN MY FAMILY.
THERE'S A HISTORY OF HIGH
CHOLESTEROL IN MY FAMILY,
SO I FELT THIS WAS THE NATURAL
PROGRESSION OF THINGS
AND IT WAS OUT OF MY CONTROL,
THAT THERE WAS NOTHING THAT I
COULD DO, UNTIL I WENT ONTO THIS
NUTRIBULLET SYSTEM, AND THAT'S
WHEN THINGS REALLY STARTED
TO CHANGE DRAMATICALLY.
WHEN I MAKE MY NUTRIBLASTS
INCORPORATING THE NUTRIBULLET,
IT EMULSIFIES FRUITS AND
VEGETABLES SO WELL THAT I FEEL
THEM GO RIGHT INTO MY SYSTEM,
I FEEL THOSE INGREDIENTS
IMMEDIATELY, AND I STARTED
TO SEE RESULTS ACTUALLY WITHIN
THREE OR FOUR DAYS.
SIX WEEKS AGO WHEN I STARTED
THIS PROGRAM, I WEIGHED 182
POUNDS, AND AFTER SIX WEEKS ON
THE NUTRIBULLET PROGRAM,
I BELIEVE I WEIGHED IN AT 160.
SO THIS WEIGHT LOSS OVER SIX
WEEKS IS JUST A BYPRODUCT.
THE REASON THAT I INVOLVED
MYSELF IN THE NUTRIBULLET
PROGRAM WAS FOR CHOLESTEROL
PURPOSES, TO REDUCE MY
CHOLESTEROL, TO REGAIN CONTROL
OF MY LIFE AND TO GET RID OF
THE ACID REFLUX.
MY STARTING CHOLESTEROL
WAS 263 AND NOW I'M AT 208
AND WITHIN A NORMAL RANGE.
AND MY TRIGLYCERIDES
ARE ALMOST CUT IN HALF.
LOOK AT MY RESULTS
OVER SIX WEEKS.
IF I CAN ENJOY THESE RESULTS,
I HAVE TO THINK THAT
EVERYBODY CAN.
>> WHEN WE THINK OF HORMONE
IMBALANCE, WE THINK THAT'S ONLY
SOMETHING THAT HAPPENS TO OLDER
PEOPLE... AND THAT'S NONSENSE.
THIS CAN AFFECT ANY OF US
AT ANY AGE-- IN OUR TEENS,
IN OUR 20s, IN OUR 70s--
AND HORMONE IMBALANCE
LEADS TO MOOD SWINGS,
INFERTILITY, ACNE, FATIGUE,
LOW SEX DRIVE, AND THOSE THINGS
CAN AFFECT ANY OF US.
THE EMPHASIS HERE
IS ON HORMONES.
AND BOTH MEN AND WOMEN
ARE AFFECTED BY THIS.
WE'RE NOT BUILT THE SAME,
SO THE APPROACH HAS TO BE A
LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT, SO WHAT
WE'VE DONE HERE IS WE'VE CREATED
A NUTRIBLAST FOR THE GUYS AND A
NUTRIBLAST FOR THE GALS.
>> GREAT. >> WONDERFUL.
>> THERE ARE SO MANY AMAZING
HORMONE-BUILDING FOODS.
FOODS LIKE BEETS, GRAPES,
BLUEBERRIES, PUMPKIN SEEDS,
BROCCOLI TO SUPPORT THE
PROSTATE, OLIVE OIL,
WHICH HELPS KEEP GOOD HORMONES
FROM BECOMING BAD HORMONES.
WE NEED GOOD HORMONES
TO KEEP US YOUNG.
WE'VE GOT TO PUT IN
SPRING WATER.
LET'S PUT ON
THE EXTRACTOR BLADES.
WE'RE SET.
OVER HERE WE HAVE A FEMALE
NUTRIBLAST, AND THIS CONTAINS
SOME KEY DIFFERENT INGREDIENTS.
WE'VE PUT IN ARUGULA, SOMETIMES
CALLED ROCKET, WE'VE ADDED
RASPBERRIES FOR THEIR VOLATILE
OILS, WHICH HELP TO SUPPORT
FEMALE REPRODUCTIVE HEALTH,
WE'VE ADDED AVOCADO AND GOJI
BERRIES, ONE OF THE BEST
ANTIOXIDANTS ON THE PLANET.
ARE WE READY TO BLAST OFF?
>> Audience: WE'RE READY.
>> LOOK AT THE POWER!
LOOK AT THE BULLET-EXCLUSIVE
CYCLONIC ACTION.
THE NUTRIBULLET IS PULVERIZING
THESE INGREDIENTS.
ALL RIGHT...
LET'S SEE WHAT WE GOT.
>> Woman: MMM, LOVE THE COLORS.
>> REMOVE THE EXTRACTOR BLADES.
HERE IT IS,
COMING DOWN THE COUNTER.
FOR THE LADIES,
LET'S GIVE THAT A TRY. >> YEAH.
>> IF YOU HAVE A NUTRIBLAST
EVERY DAY, YOU'RE GONNA LOOK
BETTER, YOU'RE GONNA FEEL
BETTER, YOU CAN LIVE LONGER
AND YOU WILL LOVE LONGER.
>> MY HOT FLASHES STARTED
WHEN I WAS 35 YEARS OLD,
AND THROUGH THE YEARS
THEY HAVE JUST PROGRESSIVELY
GOTTEN WORSE, WHERE THERE'S
TIMES IN THE MIDDLE OF
THE NIGHT YOU JUST FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE BEING MICROWAVED.
BUT AFTER DOING SOME NUTRIBLASTS
FOR THE FIRST WEEK, I SLEPT
BETTER, I FELT MORE RESTED,
I DIDN'T HAVE A HOT FLASH.
I AM THRILLED TO DEATH BY THE
CHANGE IN MY HEALTH AND HOW
I FEEL.
IT'S THE COMBINATION OF THE
FRUITS, THE VEGETABLES AND
ALL THE VITAMINS THAT ARE ALL
BEING EMULSIFIED TOGETHER...
IT WORKS.
>> THE ANTI-DEPRESSANTS,
THE SLEEPING PILLS AND THE BLOOD
PRESSURE MEDICATION DID HELP IN
THE BEGINNING.
BUT AS IN LONG-TERM, IT WASN'T
HELPING.
WELL, WITHIN A WEEK OF DRINKING
NUTRIBLAST I SAW INCREDIBLE
CHANGES.
RIGHT NOW I'M SLEEPING A SOLID
EIGHT HOURS, I AM NO LONGER
TAKING MY SLEEPING PILLS, AND
NUTRIBULLET HAS EVERYTHING TO DO
WITH THAT.
>> I WAS DIAGNOSED WITH
FIBROMYALGIA.
IT'S EXTREMELY PAINFUL.
YOU'RE IN PAIN
A LOT OF THE TIME.
WHEN I STARTED USING THE
NUTRIBULLET, I WAS PLEASANTLY
SURPRISED BECAUSE THE FIRST
NIGHT THAT I ACTUALLY USED
THE NUTRIBULLET, I ACTUALLY
SLEPT REALLY WELL.
THAT WAS EXCITING.
THAT WAS PHENOMENAL.
IT'S ALMOST UNBELIEVABLE,
QUITE FRANKLY, THAT JUST BY
USING THE NUTRIBULLET AND JUST
PROPERLY NOURISHING YOUR BODY
THAT I GOT IMMEDIATE RESULTS AND
A RESULT THAT I WAS LOOKING FOR.
IF I HAD TO PICK ONE KITCHEN
APPLIANCE THAT I ABSOLUTELY
HAD TO HAVE, IT WOULD BE THE
NUTRIBULLET.
IT IS THE ONLY APPLIANCE OUT
THERE THAT CAN GIVE ME EXACTLY
WHAT MY BODY NEEDS IN ORDER TO
FEEL GOOD, UM, HAVE THE HEALTH
AND PROPER NUTRITION THAT IS SO
IMPORTANT IN ORDER FOR US TO BE
ABLE TO JUST LIVE LIFE.
[EMOTIONALLY] IF THE PEOPLE WERE
HERE THAT MADE THE NUTRIBULLET,
WHAT I WOULD SAY TO THEM IS
THANK YOU FOR GIVING ME MY LIFE
BACK, THANK YOU FOR ALLOWING ME
TO ENJOY MY FAMILY MORE...
THANKS FOR TAKING AWAY THE PAIN.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN
ALL MY LIFE? [LAUGHS]
>> WE ALL KNOW HOW IMPORTANT
THE IMMUNE SYSTEM IS.
IT IS THE KEY.
YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM DETERMINES
WHAT BELONGS AND WHAT DOESN'T.
WHEN IT FINDS SOMETHING BAD,
IT RELEASES WHITE BLOOD CELLS,
AND WHITE BLOOD CELLS
DETOXIFY OUR BODY.
THEY ALSO HELP US FIGHT ILLNESS,
PAIN, EVEN DISEASE.
OUR ABILITY TO CREATE AND
RELEASE WHITE BLOOD CELLS IS
AFFECTED BY A LOT OF THINGS.
IT'S AFFECTED BY A LACK OF
SLEEP, STRESS, IT'S ESPECIALLY
AFFECTED BY A LACK OF NUTRITION.
IF WE CAN INCREASE OUR
ABSORPTION FROM OUR FOOD AND
NOURISH OUR IMMUNE SYSTEM
DIRECTLY, THEN OUR BODIES CAN
HANDLE PRACTICALLY ANYTHING.
THE NUTRIBULLET IS DESIGNED
TO HELP US DO JUST THAT.
>> FOR THE PAST TWO YEARS,
I HAVEN'T BEEN VERY HEALTHY.
UNFORTUNATELY I WAS
DIAGNOSED WITH CANCER.
SO, FOR THE PAST TWO YEARS,
I HAVEN'T BEEN VERY HEALTHY
AND I'VE BEEN FEELING
OVERALL PRETTY CRUMMY.
LOST EVERY OUNCE OF MY HAIR--
I LOST EVERY HAIR ON MY HEAD
AND THEN I JUST COVERED MY HEAD
UP WITH WIGS, BUT, YOU KNOW,
AT THE END OF THE DAY WHEN
YOU'RE TAKING YOUR WIG OFF AND
YOU HAVE TO SEE THE RESULT OF
THE CHEMOTHERAPY, IT'S REALLY
HARD, YOU KNOW, ON YOUR PSYCHE.
I WAS AMAZED AT HOW QUICKLY
I SAW RESULTS FROM THE
NUTRIBULLET.
I WAS SO EXCITED, BECAUSE TO
FEEL IT AFTER THE SECOND
NUTRIBLAST WAS A MIRACLE TO ME.
I WAS SO EXCITED.
ONE OF THE BEST THINGS
ABOUT THE NUTRIBULLET
IS THAT IT'S NOT A BLENDER.
IT'S SOMETHING THAT PULVERIZES
EVERYTHING THAT YOU PUT IN IT
AND YOU'RE EXTRACTING THE
NUTRIENTS OUT OF THESE WHOLE
FOODS, SO YOU'RE GETTING THE
MAXIMUM BENEFIT BY EVERYTHING
THAT YOU'RE PUTTING IN THERE.
AND PROBABLY ABOUT THREE WEEKS
INTO THE PROGRAM, MY HAIR JUST
WENT THROUGH THIS GROWTH SPURT,
AND PEOPLE WERE ASKING ME,
YOU KNOW, WHAT HAPPENED,
BECAUSE I DIDN'T HAVE A WHOLE
LOT OF HAIR BEFORE I STARTED.
I WAS JUST TELLING SOMEBODY,
I STARTED THIS YEAR OFF FIGHTING
FOR MY LIFE... I'M ENDING
THE YEAR FEELING BETTER
THAN I'VE FELT IN YEARS.
TOTALLY GIVEN ME HOPE, YOU
KNOW, AND I DIDN'T HAVE THAT
AND I JUST FEEL WONDERFUL...
[EMOTIONALLY] AND I AM SO
GRATEFUL FOR EVERYTHING YOU'VE
DONE-- THANK YOU SO MUCH,
FROM THE BOTTOM OF MY HEART.
YOU GUYS ARE AWESOME AND I HOPE
THAT THIS CAN HELP OTHER PEOPLE.
>> ONE OF THE GREATEST KEYS
TO BOLSTERING YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM
IS HIDDEN INSIDE THE FOODS
THAT WE BUY EVERY DAY.
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO IS UNLOCK
THOSE VALUABLE NUTRIENTS SO THAT
WE CAN ACTUALLY ABSORB THEM.
THIS CAN HELP CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
IN FACT, IT COULD ACTUALLY
HELP SAVE YOUR LIFE.
>> Announcer: OVER THE LAST 30
YEARS, WE HAVE BECOME THE MOST
OVERFED YET UNDERNOURISHED
NATION ON THE PLANET, LEADING TO
A MODERN-DAY EPIDEMIC OF
OBESITY, HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE,
STRESS, DEPRESSION AND MORE.
WE'RE NOT GETTING HEALTHIER,
WE'RE GETTING SICKER, AND IT
COMES DOWN TO ONE SIMPLE NEED:
NUTRIENT ABSORPTION.
WE NEED TO INCREASE
THE NUTRITIONAL POWER OF THE
FOODS WE EAT EVERY DAY
TO DRAMATICALLY CHANGE
THE WAY WE LOOK AND FEEL... AND
THE GREAT NEWS IS NOW WE CAN!
FROM THE MAKERS OF THE ORIGINAL
MAGIC BULLET, INTRODUCING THE
NUTRIBULLET, THE SUPERFOOD
NUTRITION EXTRACTOR.
WITH THE NUTRIBULLET,
YOU CAN TURN ORDINARY FOOD INTO
SUPERFOOD THAT NOW ABSORBS
EASILY INTO YOUR BODY'S SYSTEM
SO YOU CAN LIVE A LONGER,
HEALTHIER, MORE ACTIVE LIFE.
ALL THIS FOOD IS LOADED WITH
ESSENTIAL NUTRITION, AND THE
ONLY WAY TO GET ALL OF IT IS TO
BREAK DOWN, PULVERIZE AND OPEN
UP THE FOOD'S HIDDEN NUTRITION
ON A CELLULAR LEVEL.
THIS PROCESS IS CALLED
NUTRITION EXTRACTION.
LOOK: EVEN EXPENSIVE BLENDERS
JUST MIX THINGS AROUND, THEY
DON'T BREAK THINGS DOWN,
AND WITH JUICING, MOST OF THE
VALUABLE NUTRITION AND FIBER
IS JUST THROWN AWAY.
BUT THE NUTRIBULLET IS
DIFFERENT-- WATCH.
START WITH SOME SPINACH FOR
FIBER, BANANA FOR POTASSIUM,
ADD SOME BERRIES FOR ESSENTIAL
ANTIOXIDANTS, THEN ALMONDS AND
FLAX SEEDS FOR OMEGA-3 OILS,
ADD A LITTLE WATER, AND WATCH
HOW THE POWER OF THE NUTRIBULLET
COMPLETELY BREAKS EVERYTHING
DOWN, EXTRACTING ALL THE
ESSENTIAL NUTRITION.
LOOK, EVEN THE ALMONDS AND
FLAX SEEDS HAVE BEEN BROKEN DOWN
TO FIT THROUGH THIS STRAINER,
UNLIKE TRADITIONAL BLENDERS THAT
LEAVE EVERYTHING BEHIND.
THE SECRET OF THE NUTRIBULLET
IS ITS POWERFUL 600-WATT MOTOR,
COMBINED WITH BULLET-EXCLUSIVE
CYCLONIC ACTION THAT FORCES
EVERYTHING THROUGH THE TURBO
EXTRACTOR BLADES TURNING AT AN
INCREDIBLE 10,000 R.P.M.
TO BREAK DOWN AND PULVERIZE
THE STEMS, SEEDS, AND SKINS,
WHERE MOST OF THE ESSENTIAL
NUTRITION LIES, TAKING ORDINARY
FRESH FOODS AND TURNING THEM
INTO SUPERFOODS TO GIVE YOU
THE STRENGTH, ENERGY AND
VITALITY FOR A FULL ACTIVE LIFE,
WHATEVER YOUR AGE.
JUICERS MAKE JUICE, BLENDERS
MAKE SMOOTHIES, BUT THE
NUTRIBULLET MAKES SUPERCHARGED,
SUPERFOOD NUTRIBLASTS, AND BY
DRINKING JUST ONE NUTRIBLAST A
DAY, YOU CAN SUPERCHARGE YOUR
BODY, LOWER CHOLESTEROL,
LOWER BLOOD PRESSURE, AND
SUPERBOOST YOUR ENERGY LEVELS
TO FEEL BETTER THAN YOU HAVE
IN YEARS, WITHOUT TAKING
PRESCRIPTION PILLS, WITHOUT
ANY SIDE EFFECTS.
JUST ONE A DAY
CAN CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
WE'VE ALL BOUGHT EXPENSIVE
BLENDERS AND JUICERS AND WE ALL
KNOW THE PROBLEM:
THEY'RE JUST TOO MUCH TROUBLE
TO PUT TOGETHER, AND CLEAN THEM
ONCE AND YOU'LL NEVER WANT TO
CLEAN THEM AGAIN, BUT THE
NUTRIBULLET TAKES SECONDS TO USE
AND SECONDS TO CLEAN.
WATCH: JUST LOAD YOUR
INGREDIENTS INTO THE CUP, TWIST
ON THE EXTRACTOR BLADE, POP IT
ONTO THE POWER BASE, AND WATCH
HOW THE NUTRIBULLET BLASTS
ORDINARY FOODS INTO SUPERFOODS
IN AN INSTANT, THEN JUST
SEPARATE, THROW IN THE
DISHWASHER OR GIVE IT
A QUICK RINSE AND YOU'RE READY
TO GO AGAIN IN SECONDS.
HOW EASY IS THAT?
AND WITH NEARLY TWICE THE POWER
OF THESE OTHER MACHINES,
THE NUTRIBULLET IS LESS THAN
HALF THE SIZE.
THERE'S NO OTHER MACHINE
LIKE IT.
THE NUTRIBULLET COMES WITH A
SUPERSIZED 24-OUNCE PITCHER,
WITH THE SAME SIZE AND CAPACITY
OF THIS FULL-SIZE BLENDER,
TO MAKE SUPERCHARGED NUTRIBLASTS
THE WHOLE FAMILY CAN SHARE
TO KICK-START THEIR DAY.
IT ALSO COMES WITH TWO
SINGLE-SERVE 18-OUNCE MUGS, SO
EVERYONE GETS TO ENJOY THEIR OWN
PERSONAL FAVORITE NUTRIBLASTS.
JUST TWIST ON THE CUSTOMIZED
HANDLED LIP RING AND YOUR
NUTRIBLAST IS READY TO GO
WHEN YOU ARE.
YOU ALSO GET THE SUPERFOOD
MILLING BLADE THAT INSTANTLY
GRINDS AND PULVERIZES NUTS,
SEEDS, GRAINS, RAW CHOCOLATE AND
MORE FOR SUPER-NUTRITIOUS,
SUPER-DELICIOUS ENERGY BARS.
YOU ALSO GET THE SUPERFOOD
RECIPE BOOK, PACKED FULL OF
DELICIOUS RECIPE COMBINATIONS
THE WHOLE FAMILY WILL LOVE.
YOU COULD SPEND UP TO A THOUSAND
DOLLARS ON THESE BIG, BULKY
INDUSTRIAL MACHINES THAT STILL
DON'T HAVE THE NUTRIBULLET'S
EXCLUSIVE CYCLONIC ACTION.
BUT CALL NOW AND YOU WON'T PAY
$1,000, 500, 300, OR EVEN 150!
DURING THIS TV-ONLY OFFER,
YOU CAN HAVE THE COMPLETE
NUTRIBULLET SYSTEM RUSHED
TO YOUR HOME FOR JUST SIX
PAYMENTS OF ONLY $19.99!
BUT IF YOU CALL RIGHT NOW,
YOU'LL ALSO RECEIVE THIS AMAZING
BONUS: THE NUTRIBULLET'S
NATURAL HEALING FOODS BOOK.
THIS ONE-OF-A-KIND WEALTH OF
INFORMATION WILL PUT YOU
IMMEDIATELY ON THE PATH
TO HEALTH AND VITALITY,
WITH IN-DEPTH FACTS ON HOW
THE BODY WORKS, HOW WE CAN USE
THE POWER OF FOOD AND NUTRITION
TO IMPROVE THE OVERALL
PERFORMANCE OF THE BODY,
AND EVEN HOW TO HEAL IT.
YOU'LL ALSO LEARN WHY A
NUTRIBLAST IS NOT A SMOOTHIE,
GIVING YOU POWERFUL FACTS
ON EVERY INGREDIENT,
THEIR HEALTH BENEFITS
AND WHERE YOU CAN FIND THEM.
IN THIS BOOK YOU'LL ALSO FIND
OUR GROUNDBREAKING SIX-WEEK
TRANSFORMATION PLAN, WHERE USERS
HAVE ALREADY HAD INCREDIBLE
RESULTS IN THEIR FIGHT AGAINST
DIABETES, SLEEP LOSS, MIGRAINES,
DEPRESSION, FIBROMYALGIA,
CHOLESTEROL AND BLOOD PRESSURE
LEVELS AND A WHOLE LOT MORE.
>> THERE IS NO DOUBT THAT YOU
CAN REDUCE YOUR CHOLESTEROL,
REDUCE YOUR BLOOD PRESSURE,
REDUCE YOUR SUGAR LEVELS
AND REDUCE YOUR SYMPTOMS
FROM OTHER THINGS AND
INFLAMMATION FROM WHAT WE EAT.
>> Announcer: WITH OVER 200
PAGES IN HARDBACK COVER OF
LIFE-CHANGING INFORMATION,
THIS AMAZING BOOK IS A
$40 VALUE, YOURS FREE.
BUT HOLD EVERYTHING!
IF YOU CALL IN THE NEXT 18
MINUTES, WE'LL SHIP THE COMPLETE
NUTRIBULLET SYSTEM RIGHT
TO YOUR DOOR FOR FREE.
THAT'S RIGHT, FOLKS,
FREE SHIPPING!
THIS INCREDIBLE OFFER IS
OVER A $220 VALUE,
BUT CALL RIGHT NOW AND IT
CAN BE YOURS TODAY FOR JUST
SIX PAYMENTS OF ONLY $19.99.
BUT REMEMBER TO CALL IN THE NEXT
18 MINUTES AND WE'LL SHIP THIS
LIFE-CHANGING SYSTEM RIGHT TO
YOUR DOOR FOR FREE.
THAT'S RIGHT, FOR A LIMITED
TIME, FREE SHIPPING!
THE NUTRIBULLET SYSTEM IS BUILT
TO LAST, MADE FROM QUALITY
CONSTRUCTION AND IS PROTECTED
BY A FULL ONE-YEAR WARRANTY.
DON'T WAIT ANOTHER MINUTE.
CALL OR LOG ON RIGHT NOW
TO GET THE COMPLETE NUTRIBULLET
SYSTEM FOR JUST SIX PAYMENTS
OF ONLY $19.99.
PLUS, REMEMBER TO CALL IN THE
NEXT 18 MINUTES AND HAVE
THE COMPLETE NUTRIBULLET
SYSTEM SHIPPED RIGHT TO YOUR
DOOR FOR FREE!
TRY THE NUTRIBULLET RISK-FREE
FOR A FULL 30 DAYS.
IF YOU DON'T FEEL FITTER,
HEALTHIER AND STRONGER, WITH
MORE ENERGY AND VITALITY THAN
YOU EVER IMAGINED, WHATEVER YOUR
AGE, SIMPLY RETURN IT FOR A FULL
REFUND OF THE PURCHASE PRICE,
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
SO WHAT HAVE YOU GOT TO LOSE?
YOU OWE IT TO YOURSELF TO TRY
THIS INCREDIBLE MACHINE.
[♪...]
>> INFLAMMATION IN OUR JOINTS
AND IN OUR BODIES HAS BECOME
A HUGE PROBLEM.
ANYONE WHO SUFFERS FROM
ARTHRITIS OR JOINT PAIN KNOWS
EXACTLY WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT.
I BET MOST OF YOU BELIEVE THAT
ONCE THAT PAIN STARTS, IT JUST
GETS WORSE AND WORSE, RIGHT?
>> Audience: RIGHT.
>> WRONG.
THERE ARE FOODS THAT CONTAIN
HIDDEN NUTRIENTS THAT CAN GIVE
YOUR BODY THE TOOLS IT NEEDS
TO HELP FIGHT THE EFFECTS
OF ARTHRITIS AND JOINT PAIN.
THIS NUTRIBLAST CONTAINS
THE VITAMIN C BROTHERS-- LEMON
AND LIME-- THE ANTI-INFLAMMATORY
ENZYME BROMELAIN, FOUND IN
GRAPEFRUIT AND PINEAPPLE, APPLES
WITH THEIR MALIC ACID, WHICH
CUTS RIGHT INTO ARTHRITIS,
THE ANTI-INFLAMMATORY OMEGA-3
INSIDE THE FLAX SEEDS, AND MY
PERSONAL FAVORITE, TURMERIC.
TURMERIC IS PROBABLY THE MOST
POWERFUL ANTI-INFLAMMATORY FOOD
YOU CAN FIND IN YOUR LOCAL
GROCERY STORE.
YOU READY TO TRY THIS?
>> Woman: YES.
>> YOU JUST MAKE AND YOU DRINK.
SO EASY.
SO LET'S GIVE IT A TRY.
>> Woman: O.K.
>> WOW, THAT'S POWERFUL.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU GUYS
KNOW THIS, BUT BOTH MY PARENTS
ARE MEDICAL DOCTORS.
MY MOM TOLD ME THAT HEALTH
IS OUR GREATEST ASSET.
>> Woman: ABSOLUTELY.
>> SO, LET'S TOAST TO THE BEST
HEALTH EVER-- CHEERS.
>> BRAVO. >> CHEERS.
>> I'VE HAD MIGRAINES MOST OF MY
LIFE WHERE, UM, THERE'S TIMES
WHERE JUST KEEPING MY EYES OPEN
IS, IS VERY PAINFUL.
UM, BASICALLY, BEING PUT IN A
DARK ROOM, LAYING IN A BED WITH
YOUR EYES CLOSED WOULD BE THE
ONLY RELIEF I WOULD GET FROM A
MIGRAINE.
ONCE A WEEK I WOULD SUFFER FROM
A MIGRAINE.
SINCE INCORPORATING THE
NUTRIBLAST I HAVEN'T HAD ONE
HEADACHE, NOT ONE MIGRAINE.
THE NUTRIBULLET IS DIFFERENT
BECAUSE IT EXTRACTS ALL THE
NUTRIENTS FROM THE FRUITS AND
VEGETABLES AND NUTS, AND I THINK
EVERYBODY SHOULD DO IT BECAUSE
YOU JUST FEEL GREAT.
I'VE NEVER FELT THIS GOOD IN MY
LIFE, NEVER.
NEVER.
>> LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WE ALL KNOW THAT WHAT WE EAT
IS IMPORTANT, BUT HOW WE EAT IT
MAY EVEN BE MORE IMPORTANT.
IF YOU'RE EATING HEALTHY,
GOOD-FOR-YOU SALADS, YOU MIGHT
ONLY BE ABSORBING A FRACTION
OF THE AVAILABLE NUTRITION.
BY MAKING THE AMAZING NUTRITION
CONTAINED AT THE CELLULAR LEVEL
OF THESE FOODS AVAILABLE TO YOU,
YOU'LL ABSORB THEM,
AND THEN YOU'LL FEEL A HUGE
DIFFERENCE IN HOW YOU LOOK AND
YOU'LL FEEL A HUGE DIFFERENCE
IN YOUR DAY-TO-DAY ENERGY.
YOU CAN TAKE EVERYDAY, ORDINARY
FOODS AND TURN THEM INTO
SUPERFOODS IN LITERALLY SECONDS
WITH THE NUTRIBULLET.
ALL I'M ASKING YOU TO DO IS HAVE
JUST ONE NUTRIBLAST A DAY
AND I PROMISE YOU IT CAN
CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
THANKS SO MUCH FOR BEING HERE.
HAVE THE BEST DAY EVER.
CHEERS! ALL RIGHT!
>> Announcer: FROM THE MAKERS OF
THE ORIGINAL MAGIC BULLET,
INTRODUCING THE NUTRIBULLET, THE
SUPERFOOD NUTRITION EXTRACTOR.
WITH THE NUTRIBULLET,
YOU CAN TURN ORDINARY FOOD INTO
SUPERFOOD THAT NOW ABSORBS
EASILY INTO YOUR BODY'S SYSTEM
SO YOU CAN LIVE A LONGER,
HEALTHIER, MORE ACTIVE LIFE.
WATCH: START WITH SOME SPINACH
FOR FIBER, BANANA FOR POTASSIUM,
ADD SOME BERRIES FOR ESSENTIAL
ANTIOXIDANTS, THEN ALMONDS AND
FLAX SEEDS FOR OMEGA-3 OILS,
ADD A LITTLE WATER, AND WATCH
HOW THE POWER OF THE NUTRIBULLET
COMPLETELY BREAKS EVERYTHING
DOWN, EXTRACTING ALL THE
ESSENTIAL NUTRITION.
THE SECRET OF THE NUTRIBULLET
IS ITS POWERFUL 600-WATT MOTOR,
COMBINED WITH BULLET-EXCLUSIVE
CYCLONIC ACTION THAT FORCES
EVERYTHING THROUGH THE TURBO
EXTRACTOR BLADES TURNING AT AN
INCREDIBLE 10,000 R.P.M.,
TO BREAK DOWN AND PULVERIZE
THE STEMS, SEEDS, AND SKINS,
WHERE MOST OF THE ESSENTIAL
NUTRITION LIES.
THE NUTRIBULLET MAKES
SUPERCHARGED, SUPERFOOD
NUTRIBLASTS, AND BY DRINKING
JUST ONE NUTRIBLAST A DAY,
YOU CAN SUPERCHARGE YOUR BODY,
LOWER CHOLESTEROL,
LOWER BLOOD PRESSURE, AND
SUPERBOOST YOUR ENERGY LEVELS
TO FEEL BETTER THAN YOU HAVE
IN YEARS.
THE NUTRIBULLET TAKES SECONDS
TO USE AND SECONDS TO CLEAN.
WATCH: JUST LOAD YOUR
INGREDIENTS INTO THE CUP, TWIST
ON THE EXTRACTOR BLADE, POP IT
ONTO THE POWER BASE, AND WATCH
HOW THE NUTRIBULLET BLASTS
ORDINARY FOODS INTO SUPERFOODS
IN AN INSTANT, THEN JUST
SEPARATE, THROW IN THE
DISHWASHER OR GIVE IT
A QUICK RINSE AND YOU'RE READY
TO GO AGAIN IN SECONDS.
HOW EASY IS THAT?
AND WITH NEARLY TWICE THE POWER
OF THESE OTHER MACHINES,
THE NUTRIBULLET IS LESS THAN
HALF THE SIZE.
THERE'S NO OTHER MACHINE
LIKE IT.
THE NUTRIBULLET COMES WITH A
SUPERSIZED 24-OUNCE PITCHER,
WITH THE SAME SIZE AND CAPACITY
OF THIS FULL-SIZED BLENDER.
IT ALSO COMES WITH TWO
SINGLE-SERVE 18-OUNCE MUGS, SO
EVERYONE GETS TO ENJOY THEIR OWN
PERSONAL FAVORITE NUTRIBLASTS.
YOU ALSO GET THE SUPERFOOD
MILLING BLADE THAT INSTANTLY
GRINDS AND PULVERIZES NUTS,
SEEDS, GRAINS, RAW CHOCOLATE AND
MORE FOR SUPER-NUTRITIOUS,
SUPER-DELICIOUS ENERGY BARS.
YOU ALSO GET THE SUPERFOOD
RECIPE BOOK, PACKED FULL OF
DELICIOUS RECIPE COMBINATIONS
THE WHOLE FAMILY WILL LOVE.
YOU COULD SPEND UP TO A THOUSAND
DOLLARS ON THESE BIG, BULKY
INDUSTRIAL MACHINES THAT STILL
DON'T HAVE THE NUTRIBULLET'S
EXCLUSIVE CYCLONIC ACTION.
BUT CALL NOW AND YOU WON'T PAY
$1,000, 500, 300, OR EVEN $150!
DURING THIS TV-ONLY OFFER,
YOU CAN HAVE THE COMPLETE
NUTRIBULLET SYSTEM RUSHED
TO YOUR HOME FOR JUST SIX
PAYMENTS OF ONLY $19.99!
BUT IF YOU CALL RIGHT NOW,
YOU'LL ALSO RECEIVE THIS AMAZING
BONUS: THE NUTRIBULLET'S
NATURAL HEALING FOODS BOOK.
THIS ONE-OF-A-KIND WEALTH OF
INFORMATION WILL PUT YOU
IMMEDIATELY ON THE PATH
TO HEALTH AND VITALITY,
WITH IN-DEPTH FACTS ON HOW
THE BODY WORKS, HOW WE CAN USE
THE POWER OF FOOD AND NUTRITION
TO IMPROVE THE OVERALL
PERFORMANCE OF THE BODY,
AND EVEN HOW TO HEAL IT.
YOU'LL ALSO LEARN WHY A
NUTRIBLAST IS NOT A SMOOTHIE,
GIVING YOU POWERFUL FACTS
ON EVERY INGREDIENT,
THEIR HEALTH BENEFITS
AND WHERE YOU CAN FIND THEM.
IN THIS BOOK YOU'LL ALSO FIND
OUR GROUNDBREAKING SIX-WEEK
TRANSFORMATION PLAN, WHERE USERS
HAVE ALREADY HAD INCREDIBLE
RESULTS IN THEIR FIGHT AGAINST
DIABETES, SLEEP LOSS, MIGRAINES,
DEPRESSION, FIBROMYALGIA,
CHOLESTEROL AND BLOOD PRESSURE
LEVELS AND A WHOLE LOT MORE.
WITH OVER 200 PAGES IN HARDBACK
COVER OF LIFE-CHANGING
INFORMATION, THIS AMAZING BOOK
IS A $40 VALUE, YOURS FREE.
BUT HOLD EVERYTHING!
IF YOU CALL IN THE NEXT EIGHT
MINUTES, WE'LL SHIP THE COMPLETE
NUTRIBULLET SYSTEM RIGHT
TO YOUR DOOR FOR FREE.
THAT'S RIGHT, FOLKS,
FREE SHIPPING!
THIS INCREDIBLE OFFER IS
OVER A $220 VALUE,
BUT CALL RIGHT NOW AND IT
CAN BE YOURS TODAY FOR JUST
SIX PAYMENTS OF ONLY $19.99.
BUT REMEMBER TO CALL IN THE NEXT
EIGHT MINUTES AND WE'LL SHIP
THIS LIFE-CHANGING SYSTEM RIGHT
TO YOUR DOOR FOR FREE.
THAT'S RIGHT, FOR A LIMITED
TIME, FREE SHIPPING!
DON'T WAIT ANOTHER MINUTE.
CALL OR LOG ON RIGHT NOW
TO GET THE COMPLETE NUTRIBULLET
SYSTEM FOR JUST SIX PAYMENTS
OF ONLY $19.99.
PLUS, REMEMBER TO CALL IN THE
NEXT EIGHT MINUTES AND HAVE
THE COMPLETE NUTRIBULLET
SYSTEM SHIPPED RIGHT TO YOUR
DOOR FOR FREE!
TRY THE NUTRIBULLET RISK-FREE
FOR A FULL 30 DAYS.
IF YOU DON'T FEEL FITTER,
HEALTHIER AND STRONGER, WITH
MORE ENERGY AND VITALITY THAN
YOU EVER IMAGINED, WHATEVER YOUR
AGE, SIMPLY RETURN IT FOR A FULL
REFUND OF THE PURCHASE PRICE,
NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
SO WHAT HAVE YOU GOT TO LOSE?
YOU OWE IT TO YOURSELF TO TRY
THIS INCREDIBLE MACHINE.
[♪...]
THE PRECEDING WAS
A PAID PRESENTATION
FOR THE NUTRIBULLET
BROUGHT TO YOU
BY NUTRIBULLET, LLC.
>>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
THIS MORNING, TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> I ACTUALLY PRAYED TO GOD.
>> NEW DETAILS UNFOLD OVERNIGHT
ABOUT THIS HORRIFIC CRIME.
SO HARD TO COMPREHEND.
>> WE WERE LIKE ALL SCARED.
>> Reporter: 27 DEAD.
MOST OF THEM CHILDREN.
THE PRINCIPAL GUNNED DOWN.
AND BREAKING, NEW INFORMATION
THIS MORNING ABOUT THE SHOOTER.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED.