>> Announcer: PAIN: IT ATTACKS
YOUR BODY WHEN YOU LEAST EXPECT
IT, STOPS YOU IN YOUR TRACKS,
PREYS ON YOUR MIND, ROBS YOU OF
HAPPINESS, SPIRIT AND FREEDOM.
INTRODUCING LIGHT RELIEF.
AN FDA-CLEARED, LED INFRARED
LIGHT THERAPY THAT INCREASES
CIRCULATION AND IS GUARANTEED TO
RELIEVE YOUR PAIN.
FINALLY, THERE'S A FAST, NATURAL
ALTERNATIVE TO PAIN RELIEF THAT
GETS YOU BACK TO LIVING WELL,
SPENDING TIME THE WAY YOU REALLY
WANT, HAVING FUN AND ENJOYING
THE PEOPLE YOU LOVE.
BASED ON THE SAME TECHNOLOGY
NASA'S BEEN STUDYING FOR OVER 20
YEARS TO PROMOTE CELL GROWTH AND
HEALING IN SPACE, NEWSWEEK
MAGAZINE HAILS, LIGHT THERAPY
"CAN BOOST THE BODY'S OWN
NATURAL HEALING PROCESS."
CBS NEWS IN LOS ANGELES REPORTS,
"NAVY SEALS USE LIGHT THERAPY IN
THE FIELD DAILY..."
LIGHT RELIEF USES MEDICAL GRADE
LIGHT EMITTING DIODES OR LEDs TO
CREATE A SAFE POWERFUL STREAM OF
WARM THERAPEUTIC HEALING LIGHT
THAT PENETRATES DEEP, OPENING
CAPILLARIES, INCREASING
CIRCULATION, RELIEVING PAIN
WHERE YOU NEED IT, WHEN YOU
NEED IT.
IMAGINE PAIN RELIEF WITHOUT
MESSY CREAMS AND GELS,
PRESCRIPTIONS, PILLS,
INJECTIONS OR REFILLS.
AND THE ONLY SIDE EFFECT IS HOW
GOOD LIGHT RELIEF MAKES
YOU FEEL.
IT'S GREAT FOR BACK PAIN,
ARTHRITIS, TENSION HEADACHES,
BURSITIS, TENNIS ELBOW, HIP AND
JOINT PAIN, MUSCLE STRAINS AND
SPASMS, STIFFNESS
AND TENDONITIS.
IT CAN EVEN HELP RELIEVE
STUBBORN CHRONIC PAIN.
JUST IMAGINE WHAT IT CAN DO FOR
EVERYDAY ACHES AND PAINS.
ITS INNOVATIVE COMPACT DESIGN IS
DURABLE, LIGHTWEIGHT
AND PORTABLE.
IT GOES ANYWHERE, FITS THE PALM
OF YOUR HAND FOR TEMPORARY
RELIEF OF PAIN.
EASILY REMOVE THE COMFORT PAD.
IT'S FLEXIBLE TO FIT EVERY CURVE
OF YOUR BODY.
LIGHT RELIEF IS MADE TO MEET THE
HIGHEST QUALITY STANDARDS AND IS
BACKED BY A FREE
TWO-YEAR WARRANTY.
THAT MEANS THAT IF IT GETS
DAMAGED, EVEN IF IT'S YOUR
FAULT, SEND IT BACK AND WE'LL
RUSH YOU A NEW ONE FREE.
IF YOU OR SOMEONE YOU LOVE HAS
PAIN, SIT BACK, RELAX, STAY
TUNED AND DISCOVER THE SOOTHING
POWER OF LIGHT.
LISTEN TO ORTHOPEDIC SURGEONS,
DOCTORS AND PHYSICAL THERAPISTS
WHO HAVE SEEN AMAZING RESULTS IN
THEIR PATIENTS.
HEAR ATHLETES FROM PRO JOCKEYS
TO PGA TOUR PLAYERS, EVEN SKY
DIVERS THAT RELY ON THE SECRET
OF LIGHT RELIEF TO STAY AT
THEIR PEAK.
AND MEET SOME OF THE THOUSANDS
OF PEOPLE THAT HAVE EXPERIENCED
THE MIRACLE OF LIVING PAIN-FREE
IN AS LITTLE AS 5 MINUTES A DAY,
WITH THE NATURAL, INCREDIBLE
THERAPEUTIC HEALING POWER OF
LIGHT RELIEF.
>> SUNLIGHT IS THE SOURCE
OF ALL LIFE.
IT FEELS GOOD BUT WE ALL KNOW
IT CAN HAVE DAMAGING EFFECTS.
WHAT IF YOU COULD HAVE
THE SOOTHING BENEFITS OF NATURAL
LIGHT WITHOUT ANY
OF THE DANGERS?
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT YOU GET WITH
THE THERAPEUTIC WARM HEALING
LIGHT OF LIGHT RELIEF.
I USE LIGHT RELIEF
AND I LOVE IT.
I PLAY TENNIS, GOLF,
I'M AN ACTIVE GUY AND I HAVE
NO INTENTION OF SLOWING DOWN.
I HAVE CHRONIC BACK PAIN AND
TENNIS ELBOW THAT USED
TO STOP ME.
LIGHT RELIEF ALLOWS ME TO DO
WHAT I LOVE WITHOUT PAIN.
IT'S NOW AVAILABLE TO YOU.
LISTEN TO SOME OF THE HUNDREDS
OF THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE WHO HAVE
FOUND REAL RELIEF
WITH LIGHT RELIEF.
>> IT'S BEEN ABOUT... 20 YEARS
SINCE I'VE ACTUALLY SLEPT MORE
THAN TWO HOURS A NIGHT.
THE LESS ACTIVITY YOU CAN DO AND
THE MORE DEPRESSED YOU GET
BECAUSE YOU CAN'T GET UP AND
MOVE AROUND AND THE MORE YOU
EAT, THE MORE YOU SIT.
IT IS A CYCLE AND IT'S A CYCLE
THAT I THOUGHT I WAS NEVER GONNA
GET OUT OF.
I DON'T HAVE PAIN ANYMORE.
I DON'T HAVE THE NUMBNESS IN
MY HANDS.
YOU KNOW, I CAN SLEEP, I CAN LAY
DOWN, I CAN WALK THROUGH AN
ENTIRE MALL.
TAKING MY GRANDDAUGHTER
SHOPPING, GOING TO THE BEACH
WITH MY KIDS, UH...
MY LIFE TODAY IS LIGHT-YEARS
AHEAD OF WHAT IT WAS A YEAR AGO.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
>> I'VE DEPENDED ON MY HANDS AND
ARMS FOR EVERYTHING THROUGHOUT
MY LIFE AND THEY'VE ALWAYS BEEN
THERE FOR ME-- ALL THE STRENGTH
I NEED, ALL THE ENDURANCE
I NEED.
AS THE ARTHRITIS IS BEGINNING TO
ENTER INTO MY HANDS, I SEE
CHANGES IN THE SHAPES OF
THE JOINTS.
UM, I HAVE PAIN ON A FAIRLY
REGULAR BASIS.
I FIND THAT IF I GRAB THINGS,
THAT MAYBE THE GRIP IS NOT
COMPLETE AND I'LL DROP A GLASS,
OR NOT BE ABLE TO TAKE A JAR
LID OFF.
WITH LIGHT RELIEF, I PUT THE
LIGHTS ON THE BACK OF MY HANDS,
PALMS OF MY HANDS FOR 10, 15
MINUTES AND THE FULL FLEXIBILITY
IS BACK, THE RANGE OF MOTION
IS BACK, AND THE PAIN IS GONE.
THE JAR LID THAT I HAD TO GO TO
THE NEIGHBOR TO OPEN IS OPENED
BY MY OWN HANDS.
IT'S FREEDOM.
>> I WOKE UP ONE MORNING WITH
A KINK IN MY NECK AND DIDN'T GO
AWAY-- ONE DAY, TWO DAYS.
JUST, YOU KNOW, TOUGH TIME
MOVING MY HEAD FROM SIDE TO SIDE
AND LOTS OF STIFFNESS IN MY
RIGHT SHOULDER.
I PUT THE LIGHT RELIEF RIGHT
AROUND MY NECK, RIGHT IN
MY SHOULDER.
NOT ONLY WAS THE RELIEF
COMPLETE, BUT IT WAS
SO IMMEDIATE.
UM, 15 TO 20 MINUTES AND A PAIN
I'VE HAD FOR THREE DAYS IS GONE?
AND THE NEXT THING I KNEW, I WAS
PACKING UP TO GO TO A MEETING
AND FELT GREAT.
MY ARM WAS MOVING.
MY NECK WASN'T STIFF.
AND UM... I WAS PRETTY AMAZED TO
BE HONEST WITH YOU.
>> THE FDA HAS APPROVED THIS
DEVICE AND IT'S... IT IS
BECAUSE, NUMBER ONE, IT DOES
WORK, IT'S ADVOCATIOUS
AND HAS DEMONSTRATED ITSELF TO
BE A RESOURCEFUL AUGMENTATION
OF HEALING.
NUMBER TWO: IT'S A NON-INVASIVE
TYPE OF TREATMENT.
NUMBER THREE: THE PRINCIPLES OF
LIGHT THERAPY ARE WELL
ESTABLISHED OVER THE YEARS.
AND NUMBER FOUR: IT HAS BEEN
SHOWN TO DECREASE THE TIME AND
THEREFORE IS AN EFFECTIVE DEVICE
AND IT'S SAFE.
>> NASA SCIENTISTS HAVE BEEN
DOCUMENTING THE HEALING
PROPERTIES OF INFRARED
LIGHT FOR YEARS.
DOCTORS AND RESEARCHERS FROM
LEADING MEDICAL UNIVERSITIES
FURTHERED THIS RESEARCH BY
STUDYING THE EFFECTS OF LIGHT
ON HEALING TISSUES, INCREASING
CIRCULATION AND RELIEVING PAIN.
LIGHT RELIEF IS A POWERFUL
LIGHT THERAPY DEVICE.
ITS STATE-OF-THE-ART DESIGN
INCORPORATES MEDICAL GRADE LEDs
OR LIGHT EMITTING DIODES WHICH
PRODUCE INFRARED LIGHT AND
SOOTHING HEAT TO RELIEVE PAIN.
ITS RED AND BLUE INDICATORS LET
YOU KNOW IT'S EMITTING A SPECIAL
SAFE FREQUENCY OF LIGHT THAT
PENETRATES DEEP, ELEVATING
TEMPERATURES, INCREASING
CIRCULATION AND POWERFULLY
RELAXING MUSCLES TO
RELIEVE PAIN.
LIGHT RELIEF IS COMPLETELY SAFE
AND CONTAINS NO DANGEROUS UVs
OR LASERS.
SO YOU CAN USE IT FREQUENTLY FOR
EVERYTHING, FOR MINOR ACHES AND
PAINS TO ARTHRITIS AND EVEN
CHRONIC PAIN.
IT'S EASY TO USE BECAUSE ITS
ERGONOMIC BASE FORMS TO FIT
YOUR HAND, OR JUST ATTACH THE
COMFORT PAD.
IT'S THIN ENOUGH TO LIE ON
COMFORTABLY AND FLEXIBLE ENOUGH
TO EASE PAIN RIGHT WHERE YOU
NEED IT, WHEN YOU NEED IT.
>> EVEN THOUGH I'D BEEN AROUND
AND WORKING WITH THIS TECHNOLOGY
FOR ALMOST 20 YEARS, THERE ARE
STILL TIMES WHERE IT
SURPRISES ME.
I'M... I USE IT ON SOMEBODY AND
I'LL EXPECT ONE OUTCOME,
AND THE OUTCOME WILL BE MUCH
BETTER THAN WHAT I EXPECTED WHEN
I STARTED THE TREATMENT.
THE LIGHT RELIEF DEVICE IS AS
EASY AS SHINING THE LIGHT ON THE
AREA THAT NEEDS TREATMENT.
NOW AT HOME, YOU HAVE THE SAME
TECHNOLOGY THAT CHIROPRACTORS,
PHYSICAL THERAPISTS AND DOCTORS
ARE UTILIZING WITHIN
THEIR PRACTICES.
>> LIGHT RELIEF PROVIDES A DEEP
DOWN SOOTHING WARMTH THAT
RELIEVES PAIN LIKE NOTHING ELSE.
THAT'S WHY PRO ATHLETES FROM
EVERY SPORT LOVE IT.
MEET AMERICAN HORSE RACING
LEGEND, COREY NAKATANI.
AT ONLY 36, HE'S WON OVER $145
MILLION IN PURSES AND HAS BEEN
IN THE WINNER'S CIRCLE
EVERYWHERE FROM SANTA ANITA
TO BELMONT.
HE'S BROKEN ENOUGH RECORDS AND
BONES TO LAST A LIFETIME.
>> TO BE ONLY 32 YEARS OLD AND
COMPETING AT THAT LEVEL, YOU
NEED TO BE HEALTHY.
YOU NEED TO BE PHYSICALLY SOUND,
YOU KNOW, TO BE PAIN FREE.
THE SPEEDS OF THE HORSES,
OBVIOUSLY GOING 40 MILES AN HOUR
ON THE BACK OF A HORSE WITH 10,
15 GUYS TRYING TO JOSTLE AND GET
TO THE POSITION THEY WANT
TO BE IN, YOUR BODY TAKES
A POUNDING.
YOU HAVE TO BE AGILE ENOUGH TO
BE ABLE TO MAKE A SPLIT DECISION
IN THE BLINK OF YOUR EYE.
MENTALLY AND PHYSICALLY, YOU
HAVE TO BE AT THE TOP OF
YOUR GAME.
WHEN YOU GET ANY TYPE OF INJURY,
ESPECIALLY ANYTHING TO DO WITH
YOUR BACK, YOUR HAMSTRING OR
YOUR GROIN, LIGHT RELIEF GIVES
YOU THAT OPPORTUNITY TO GET THE
RELIEF THAT YOU NEED.
...IT'S JUST A MATTER OF, YOU
KNOW, 15 TO 20 MINUTES A DAY
WITH IT AND IT RELIEVES THE PAIN
AND YOU'RE ABLE TO COMPETE AT
A TOP-NOTCH LEVEL.
SO, LIGHT RELIEF MAKES A BIG
DIFFERENCE FOR ME.
>> I'M A BELIEVER BECAUSE I KNOW
WHAT PAIN'S LIKE.
I KNOW WHAT AGONY'S LIKE.
I KNOW WHAT PAIN'S LIKE.
AND I KNOW WHAT IT DOES TO
A PERSON.
THE MINUTE I LAY DOWN AT NIGHT,
THE PAIN STARTED.
AND THAT'S WHAT REALLY SCARED ME
BECAUSE I WAS AT MY WIT'S END
UNTIL I CAME ACROSS
LIGHT RELIEF.
IT'S BEEN A MIRACLE FOR ME.
I MEAN, ABSOLUTE MIRACLE.
THERE'S LIGHT AT THE END OF THE
TUNNEL AND IT'S LIGHT RELIEF.
THANK GOD.
>> THE FIRST RESEARCH WAS DONE
BY NASA, AS WELL AS SOME OF THE
TOP SCIENTISTS AT
LIVERMORE LAB.
AND WHAT THEY DISCOVERED WAS
THAT RED AND INFRARED LIGHTS
HAVE AN IMPACT ON LIVING TISSUE.
I'VE SEEN IT DO AMAZING THINGS
WITH A LOT OF DIFFERENT
PROBLEMS, INJURIES AND SO FORTH
IN MY PRACTICE.
WHY NOT HAVE SOMETHING THAT'S
GONNA HELP YOU GET
BETTER QUICKER?
>> I WAS TO THE POINT WHERE
I THOUGHT I WAS GONNA HAVE TO
GET A SCOOTER JUST TO BE ABLE
TO GET THROUGH THE SHOP.
I HAD A CLIENT GIVE ME A CALL
AND TOLD ME THAT HE HAD A WAY OF
RELIEVING SOME PAIN IN MY LOWER
BACK, IT WAS CALLED
LIGHT RELIEF.
HE PUT THE UNIT ON ME FOR TWO
TREATMENTS, TWO 20-MINUTE
TREATMENTS AND IT'S THE FIRST
TIME IN PROBABLY 20 YEARS THAT
I COULD ACTUALLY PICK
MY KNEES UP.
I IMMEDIATELY WENT OUT
TO THE BACK OF THE SHOP
AND I WAS MARCHING AROUND,
WHICH I'VE NEVER BEEN ABLE
TO PICK MY FEET UP AND I SAID,
"LET'S GO DANCING! I'M READY!"
>> I'M A FORMER MARINE, UM...
BACK IN THE '70s.
AND, UM, I'M A VIETNAM VETERAN.
I DID SUSTAIN A GUNSHOT WOUND
THAT WAS VERY SEVERE TO MY
RIGHT KNEE.
I WAS ACTUALLY DIAGNOSED AT NOT
EVEN BEING ABLE TO WALK AT
ONE TIME.
AND I'VE BEEN SUFFERING WITH
A LOT OF PAIN THROUGH IT, UH,
FOR ABOUT 30 YEARS NOW.
MY KNEE ACTUALLY GAVE AWAY.
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT'S REAL CRITICAL FOR MY JOB
THAT I'M ABLE TO STAND ON
MY FEET.
UH, I STARTED USING THE
LIGHT RELIEF ON MY KNEE.
IT STARTED IMMEDIATELY GIVING ME
RELIEF WITHIN ABOUT THREE DAYS.
IT IS SO NATURAL.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SIT THERE AND
SAY, WELL, I GOTTA TAKE A PILL.
IT'S THREE HOURS OR IT'S
FOUR HOURS.
MY STOMACH'S UPSET.
I'M NAUSEATED, I'M SICK.
IT'S VERY SIMPLE.
IT DOESN'T HAVE ANY OF THOSE
SIDE EFFECTS AT ALL.
YOU PUT THE LIGHT ON AND IT DOES
AMAZING THINGS FOR YOU.
>> WOULDN'T YOU LOVE TO TAKE
THE YOUTH OF YOUR 30s AND
EXTEND IT INTO YOUR 40s, 50s
OR BEYOND?
NOW YOU CAN, WITH LIGHT RELIEF.
WE SENT OUR CREW OUT
TO MEET ANA DOLGINER.
SHE'S OVER 50, SUFFERS FROM
ARTHRITIS BUT STILL MANAGES
TO KEEP FLYING HIGH...
WITH LIGHT RELIEF.
>> ONE OF THE THINGS ABOUT MY
ARTHRITIS IS, IT'S LIKE
A DOUBLE-EDGED SWORD.
I HAVE TO MOVE AND STAY ACTIVE
FOR IT TO, UH... NOT TAKE
CONTROL OF ME.
BUT MOVING AND STAYING ACTIVE
MAKES IT ACHE.
ON ONE OF MY JUMPS, I BROKE MY
LEG AND I HAVE A PIN THAT GOES
TWO INCHES ABOVE THE KNEE.
AND THE ARTHRITIS SEEMS TO WANT
TO SETTLE RIGHT THERE IN
THAT AREA.
AND SKYDIVING, IT AFFECTS MY
ARTHRITIS BECAUSE I TAKE A LOT
OF JOLTS, A LOT OF BUMPS, A LOT
OF BRUISES, ESPECIALLY ON
THE LANDINGS.
AND LIGHT RELIEF HELPS WITH ALL
OF THAT SO THAT I CAN CONTINUE
TO SKYDIVE SO THAT MY JOINTS
WILL CONTINUE TO BE MOBILE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE, WHEN THEY TURN
50, THEY JUST KIND OF ROLL OVER
AND I'M 55 AND I KEEP MOVING.
MY ARTHRITIS WILL NOT FREEZE ME
UP AND LIGHT RELIEF HELPS ME TO
DO THAT.
WHEN I JUMP OUT OF THIS
AIRPLANE, I JUST GET SUCH
A FEELING OF FREEDOM THAT YOU
WOULD NOT BELIEVE.
THERE IS NO COMPARISON TO
THIS FEELING.
AND I'M ABLE TO DO THAT BECAUSE
OF LIGHT RELIEF.
I'LL CONTINUE TO MOVE AND MOVE
AND MOVE AND STAY ACTIVE
IN MY LIFE.
I'M HAVING A GREAT, GREAT LIFE.
I JUST LOVE THE LIFE I'M LIVING.
>> THE FUTURE OF PAIN RELIEF
IS HERE AND IT'S CALLED
LIGHT RELIEF.
IT'S NATURAL, IT'S SAFE
AND IT'S INCREDIBLY EFFECTIVE.
THE BEAUTY IS YOU BUY IT ONCE
AND YOU HAVE IT RIGHT BY YOUR
SIDE TO RELIEVE PAIN WHERE
YOU NEED IT WHEN YOU NEED IT.
ONCE YOU HAVE IT, YOU'LL WONDER
HOW YOU EVER LIVED WITHOUT IT.
RECAPTURE YOUR JOY OF LIVING
A HAPPY HEALTHY LIFE BY TAKING
THE FIRST STEP FOR YOU
OR SOMEONE YOU LOVE.
HERE'S HOW YOU CAN GET YOUR OWN
LIGHT RELIEF NOW.
>> Announcer: INTRODUCING
LIGHT RELIEF, YOUR POWER
OVER PAIN.
FINALLY, THERE'S A FAST, NATURAL
ALTERNATIVE TO PAIN RELIEF THAT
GETS YOU BACK TO LIVING WELL,
SPENDING TIME THE WAY YOU REALLY
WANT, HAVING FUN AND ENJOYING
THE PEOPLE YOU LOVE.
LIGHT RELIEF IS AN FDA-CLEARED
LED INFRARED LIGHT THERAPY THAT
INCREASES CIRCULATION AND IS
GUARANTEED TO RELIEVE YOUR PAIN.
WITH THE TOUCH OF A BUTTON,
LIGHT RELIEF'S RED AND BLUE LEDs
LET YOU KNOW ITS INFRARED
LIGHT IS ACTIVELY CREATING
A SAFE, POWERFUL STREAM OF WARM,
THERAPEUTIC HEALING LIGHT THAT
PENETRATES DEEP, OPENING
CAPILLARIES, INCREASING
CIRCULATION TO WASH AWAY TOXINS,
RELIEVING PAIN WHERE YOU NEED
IT, WHEN YOU NEED IT.
UNIVERSITIES, SCIENTISTS AND
DOCTORS FROM AROUND THE WORLD
HAVE FOUND LIGHT THERAPY TO BE
A SAFE, NON-INVASIVE, EFFECTIVE
TOOL FOR RELIEVING PAIN.
IT'S GREAT FOR BACK PAIN,
ARTHRITIS, TENSION HEADACHES,
BURSITIS, TENNIS ELBOW, HIP AND
JOINT PAIN, MUSCLE STRAINS
AND SPASMS, STIFFNESS
AND TENDONITIS.
IT CAN EVEN HELP RELIEVE
STUBBORN CHRONIC PAIN.
JUST IMAGINE WHAT IT CAN DO FOR
EVERYDAY ACHES AND PAINS.
EASILY REMOVE THE COMFORT PAD.
IT'S FLEXIBLE TO FIT EVERY CURVE
OF YOUR BODY.
WHEN YOU ORDER YOUR LIGHT
RELIEF, YOU'LL RECEIVE AN
ADJUSTABLE HANDS-FREE STRAP.
PLUS, YOU'LL GET OUR COMPLETE
GUIDE TO LIGHT THERAPY WITH
QUICK START INFORMATION.
HOW MUCH WOULD YOU EXPECT TO PAY
FOR THIS PROFESSIONAL
QUALITY LIGHT THERAPY SYSTEM?
COMMERCIAL UNITS THAT DOCTORS
USE SELL FOR THOUSANDS
OF DOLLARS.
BUT YOU CAN HAVE THE SOOTHING
POWER AND CONVENIENCE OF LIGHT
RELIEF IN YOUR HOME FOR LESS
THAN A FRACTION OF THAT PRICE.
THROUGH STATE OF THE ART
ENGINEERING AND FACTORY-DIRECT
PRICING, YOU'LL GET THE ENTIRE
LIGHT RELIEF SYSTEM FOR ONLY
THREE PAYMENTS OF $39.95.
CALL RIGHT NOW AND WE'LL DROP
ONE ENTIRE PAYMENT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU'LL GET THE COMPLETE
LIGHT RELIEF SYSTEM FOR ONLY
TWO PAYMENTS OF $39.95.
CALL IN THE NEXT 20 MINUTES,
WE'LL INCLUDE AS OUR SPECIAL
BONUS, OUR BODY BAND, SO YOU CAN
USE IT WHILE YOU READ, RELAX,
EVEN WATCH TV.
WE'LL EVEN INCLUDE OUR HANDY
TRAVEL BAG TO HOLD YOUR
ENTIRE LIGHT RELIEF SYSTEM.
IT'S FREE TOO!
LIGHT RELIEF IS FDA-CLEARED AND
EXCLUSIVELY MANUFACTURED IN AN
APPROVED ISO-9000 FACILITY,
WHICH MEANS IT MEETS THE MOST
STRINGENT QUALITY CONTROL
STANDARDS FOR HEALTHCARE
EQUIPMENT IN THE WORLD.
WE ARE SO CONFIDENT THAT
LIGHT RELIEF WILL WORK FOR YOU,
WE OFFER OUR 30-DAY PAIN FREE
WITH LIGHT OR WE MAKE IT RIGHT
GUARANTEE, NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
LIGHT RELIEF IS BACKED WITH
A FREE TWO-YEAR WARRANTY.
THAT MEANS IF IT GETS DAMAGED,
EVEN IF IT'S YOUR FAULT,
SEND IT BACK.
WE'LL RUSH YOU A NEW ONE FREE.
SO GET BACK TO LIVING LIFE TO
THE FULLEST AND FEELING GOOD
AGAIN, LIKE THOUSANDS
OF PEOPLE HAVE.
CLIMB THAT MOUNTAIN, SPREAD YOUR
WINGS AND FLY.
NOW YOU, OR SOMEONE YOU LOVE,
CAN HAVE THE FREEDOM TO ENJOY
THE INCREDIBLE SOOTHING POWER OF
LIGHT RELIEF.
PICK UP THE PHONE AND ORDER NOW.
TO ORDER LIGHT RELIEF RIGHT NOW,
HAVE YOUR CREDIT CARD READY AND
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN.
BE SURE TO ASK YOUR OPERATOR HOW
TO GET RUSH DELIVERY.
WHEN YOU ORDER, WE'LL SEND YOU
THE ENTIRE LIGHT RELIEF PACKAGE,
COMPLETE WITH EVERYTHING
YOU SEE HERE.
REMEMBER, YOUR LIGHT RELIEF IS
PROFESSIONAL QUALITY
AND DURABLE.
IT COMES WITH A 30-DAY
MONEY-BACK GUARANTEE AND A FREE
TWO-YEAR REPLACEMENT WARRANTY.
FIND THE RELIEF THAT THOUSANDS
ARE ALREADY ENJOYING, IN AS
LITTLE AS FIVE MINUTES A DAY.
PICK UP THE PHONE AND ORDER YOUR
LIGHT RELIEF NOW.
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN.
>> THE WORLD OF MOTOCROSS AND
SUPERCROSS IS HEART-POUNDING
AND THRILLING.
WE WENT TO MEET RYAN CLARK.
HE'S ONE OF THE TOP 10 RIDERS IN
THE WORLD.
HE USES LIGHT RELIEF DAILY TO
RELIEVE HIS ACHES AND PAINS.
HE'S EVEN USED IT TO DEAL WITH
THE RESIDUAL PAIN FROM
A BROKEN WRIST.
>> MOTOCROSS AND SUPERCROSS
RACING IS A CHALLENGING AND
BRUTAL SPORT AND YOU'RE GONNA
ENCOUNTER SOME
INJURIES SOMETIMES.
A MONTH AND A HALF BEFORE THE
SEASON STARTED, I WAS GOING
THROUGH MY RACE SIMULATION MODE
AND I MADE A SMALL MISTAKE.
I MISJUDGED A JUMP AND I CAME UP
A LITTLE BIT SHORT AND A LITTLE
BIT SIDEWAYS ON A TRIPLE JUMP.
AND ON IMPACT, IT BROKE MY WRIST
PRETTY BAD.
I DROPPED MY BIKE AND I HAVE A
REALLY GOOD DOCTOR THAT STARTED
THERAPY WITH THE LIGHTS.
THE WRIST IS SOMETHING THAT
NEEDS TO BE COMPLETELY HEALTHY
IN ORDER TO CONTROL A MOTORCYCLE
THAT WEIGHS OVER 200 POUNDS.
WORKING WITH THE LIGHTS, I WAS
ABLE TO ACTUALLY GET BACK ON THE
BIKE WITHIN FOUR OR FIVE WEEKS
AFTER A REALLY, REALLY BAD WRIST
INJURY THAT NORMALLY WOULD TAKE,
YOU KNOW, UPWARDS OF THREE
TO FOUR MONTHS TO
COMPLETELY REHAB.
>> ORTHOPEDIC SURGEON AND FORMER
TEAM DOCTOR FOR THE MINNESOTA
TWINS AND DALLAS NORTH STARS,
DR. DON MILLER, USES
LIGHT RELIEF DAILY WITH BOTH
PROFESSIONAL ATHLETES AND
HIS PATIENTS.
>> THE FDA HAS APPROVED THE USE
OF RED AND INFRARED LIGHT FOR
TWO SPECIFIC PURPOSES:
ONE IS TO DIMINISH PAIN,
AND THE SECOND IS TO INCREASE
BLOOD FLOW.
WHEN YOU'RE FIRST INJURED, YOU
DON'T WANT A LOT OF BLOOD STILL
BEING PUMPED INTO THE AREA.
SO YOU'D LIKE TO SLOW THE
CIRCULATION DOWN.
HOWEVER, ONCE THE INJURY IS,
SAY, 12 TO 24 HOURS OLD, YOU
WANT TO INCREASE THE CIRCULATION
SO YOU CAN GET ALL THAT FLUID
OUT OF THERE.
BECAUSE BY INCREASING BLOOD
FLOW, YOU CAN PROMOTE THE
HEALING TO OCCUR MUCH QUICKER.
IT'LL HELP GET RID OF ALL THIS
FLUID THAT'S ACCUMULATING AND
THE SWELLING WILL GO DOWN.
AS SWELLING GOES DOWN, YOU'RE
GONNA HAVE RELIEF OF PAIN.
>> YOU KNOW, MANY PEOPLE ARE IN
PAIN FOR MONTHS AFTER SURGERY.
LIGHT RELIEF CAN HELP WITH THE
RESIDUAL PAIN ASSOCIATED WITH
THE HEALING PROCESS.
JUST ASK BETTY ARMOUR.
SHE'S RELIED ON LIGHT RELIEF
TO EASE THE PAIN OF
RECONSTRUCTIVE SURGERY.
>> IN APRIL 2001, I WAS
DIAGNOSED WITH BREAST CANCER
AND HAD TO HAVE
A RIGHT MASTECTOMY.
I ELECTED TO HAVE A LEFT
MASTECTOMY AS WELL BECAUSE
I DIDN'T WANT A REOCCURRENCE.
IT WAS A PRETTY LOST FEELING
AND A VERY DIFFICULT TIME FOR
ME EMOTIONALLY.
I DID NOT EVEN CONTEMPLATE THE
PHYSICAL PAIN I WAS ABOUT
TO ENDURE.
I WASN'T ABLE TO DO A LOT OF THE
THINGS THAT I NEEDED TO IN JUST
MERE LIFE IN TAKING CARE OF MY
HOUSEHOLD AND MY KIDS.
AND I WAS BECOMING SEVERELY
DEPRESSED BECAUSE I WAS IN PAIN
ALL THE TIME.
I STARTED USING LIGHT RELIEF.
AND I COULDN'T EXPLAIN TO YOU
HOW IT WORKED.
I JUST MARVEL OVER THE FACT THAT
IT REDUCED MY PAIN TREMENDOUSLY.
LIGHT RELIEF HAS BEEN VERY MUCH
A MIRACLE TO ME AND HAS OFFERED
ME, YOU KNOW, A LOT OF RELIEF IN
VARIOUS AREAS, NOT JUST THE
PHYSICAL PAIN, BUT EMOTIONALLY
AND MENTALLY, TOO.
>> ONE OF OUR PATIENTS, AN
OLYMPIC ATHLETE, A VERY GIFTED
YOUNG LADY, SHE'S HAD SEVERAL
INJURIES THROUGHOUT HER
ILLUSTRIOUS CAREER.
WE IMMEDIATELY STARTED TREATING
HER WITH LIGHT RELIEF AND WITHIN
DAYS SHE STARTED FEELING BETTER.
THE RADIOLOGIST CALLED ME UP AND
HE SAID, "DR. EMERSON, YOU'VE
GOT TO COME AND LOOK AT THESE
MRIs BECAUSE THERE'S A DEFINITE
CHANGE AND WE'RE SEEING SOME
RECOVERY AND SOME HEALTHIER
HAMSTRING TENDON."
AND SURE ENOUGH, THE MRIs WERE
CHANGING FROM THAT WHITISH
APPEARANCE TO A MORE GRAY AND
DARKER APPEARANCE, WHICH IS
A MORE NORMAL-APPEARING TENDON.
SO WE ATTRIBUTE THAT TO INCREASE
VASCULARITY AND INCREASE HEALING
PROPERTIES OF THE PENETRATION OF
THE LIGHT RELIEF THAT WE KNOW
CAN OCCUR.
BUT IT DID GET HER TO THE POINT
WHERE SHE COULD COMPETE IN THAT
OLYMPIC EVENT AND THAT WAS
VERY EXCITING.
>> THE PRO ATHLETE IS A VERY,
VERY TOUGH INDIVIDUAL.
THEY DO NOT COMPLAIN ABOUT MUCH
AT ALL AND WHEN THEY DO COME AND
SEE US IN THE TRAINING, WE KNOW
THAT THERE ARE PROBLEMS, WHETHER
THEY'RE HAVING DIFFICULTIES--
EITHER THEY'LL BE SWELLING OR
A PAIN LEVEL, THEY WILL WANT
THEIR INJURIES TAKEN CARE
OF IMMEDIATELY.
THEY WANT TO BE BACK PLAYING AS
FAST AS POSSIBLE.
AFTER USING THIS PRODUCT FOR
THREE YEARS NOW, I'M A FIRM
BELIEVER IN THE LIGHT RELIEF
PATCH AND I'M GLAD TO
INCORPORATE IT WITH OUR
PROFESSIONAL ATHLETES ON A DAILY
REGIME IN OUR
TREATMENT PROTOCOLS.
>> PAIN DOESN'T SLEEP.
IT TAKES A TOLL ON YOUR MIND,
BODY AND SPIRIT.
ONE OF THE BEST THINGS ABOUT
LIGHT RELIEF IS HOW ITS SOOTHING
WARMTH WILL HELP YOU RELAX AND
WIND DOWN AT THE END OF THE DAY.
JUST PLACE THE COMFORT PAD ON
THE LOWER NECK BETWEEN THE
SHOULDER BLADES.
WITHIN MINUTES, YOU'LL FEEL THE
WARMTH OF ITS RADIANT LIGHT
PENETRATE MUSCLES AS YOUR BODY
NATURALLY RELEASES TENSION
AND STRESS.
ITS POWER TO INCREASE
CIRCULATION MAKES IT A PERFECT
WAY TO RELAX RIGHT BEFORE BED
AND IT FEELS WONDERFUL.
>> I HAD AN ACHILLES STRAIN AND
I WAS LIMPING AROUND AND IT WAS
REALLY FRUSTRATING BECAUSE I WAS
WALKING ON MY TOES.
AND I GOT MY HANDS ON THE
LIGHT RELIEF AND PUT IT
ON THERE.
IT FELT REALLY SOOTHING.
I DID IT AS MUCH AS I COULD AND
I REALIZED, MY FOOT DOESN'T
HURT ANYMORE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
THIS THINGS WORKS.
I'M HOOKED!
>> IMAGINE YOUR JOB MEANT
WALKING SIX MILES A DAY EVERY
DAY AND THEN SWINGING A GOLF
CLUB UPWARDS OF 300 TO
500 TIMES.
THAT'S A NORMAL DAY FOR
BILLY MAYFAIR.
AS A TOP PGA PRO WITH OVER
$14 MILLION IN EARNINGS, HE'S
CURRENTLY THE ONLY PLAYER TO
BEAT TIGER WOODS IN A PLAY-OFF.
HE RELIES ON LIGHT RELIEF DAILY.
>> THE THING THAT SURPRISED ME,
PROBABLY THE MOST ABOUT
LIGHT RELIEF, IS HOW WELL IT
MADE ME FEEL AFTER MY
ACTIVITIES, AFTER PLAYING
18 HOLES OF GOLF AND WALKING
SIX MILES.
UH, TO PUT IT ON MY BACK, EVEN
FOR THE 10 MINUTES IN THE CAR
RIDE HOME, THE FEW MINUTES BACK
IN THE HOTEL ROOM, AS LOOSE AS
I FELT, NO STIFFNESS OR NO PAIN.
IT WAS REALLY AMAZING.
IT'S ALWAYS IMPORTANT TO HAVE
SOME TYPE OF LITTLE EDGE OVER
THE COMPETITION THAT'S OUT THERE
IN THE PGA TOUR.
IF YOU CAN GET A PRODUCT THAT
MAKES YOUR BODY FEEL BETTER AND
IT COULD HELP YOU OVER A LONG
PERIOD OF TIME, IT STILL COMES
DOWN TO GOLF AND MAKING THE
PUTTS AND ALL THAT.
BUT, IF YOU CAN FEEL A LITTLE
BIT BETTER THAN THE OTHER GUY,
YOU HAVE A BIG ADVANTAGE.
>> IF YOU HAVE PAIN AND FEEL
LIKE YOU'VE TRIED IT ALL,
YOU HAVEN'T.
I KNOW, BECAUSE LIKE ALL
THE PEOPLE YOU'VE HEARD FROM
TODAY, I'VE HAD PAIN AND
LIGHT RELIEF IS THE ONE THING
I NOW REACH FOR
ANYTIME I WANT TO FEEL
GOOD AGAIN.
THE FACT THAT YOU DON'T NEED
A PRESCRIPTION AND IT HAS NO
NEGATIVE SIDE EFFECTS MAKE IT
A NATURAL CHOICE THAT HUNDREDS
OF THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE HAVE
TURNED TO FOR FAST EFFECTIVE
RELIEF FROM ACHES AND PAINS.
YOUR RELIEF IS ONLY
A PHONE CALL AWAY.
YOU'VE GOT NOTHING TO LOSE
BUT YOUR PAIN.
>> Announcer: INTRODUCING
LIGHT RELIEF, YOUR POWER
OVER PAIN.
FINALLY, THERE'S A FAST, NATURAL
ALTERNATIVE TO PAIN RELIEF THAT
GETS YOU BACK TO LIVING WELL,
SPENDING TIME THE WAY YOU REALLY
WANT, HAVING FUN AND ENJOYING
THE PEOPLE YOU LOVE.
LIGHT RELIEF IS AN FDA-CLEARED
LED INFRARED LIGHT THERAPY THAT
INCREASES CIRCULATION AND IS
GUARANTEED TO RELIEVE YOUR PAIN.
WITH THE TOUCH OF A BUTTON,
LIGHT RELIEF'S RED AND BLUE LEDs
LET YOU KNOW ITS INFRARED
LIGHT IS ACTIVELY CREATING
A SAFE, POWERFUL STREAM OF WARM,
THERAPEUTIC HEALING LIGHT THAT
PENETRATES DEEP, OPENING
CAPILLARIES, INCREASING
CIRCULATION TO WASH AWAY TOXINS,
RELIEVING PAIN WHERE YOU NEED
IT, WHEN YOU NEED IT.
UNIVERSITIES, SCIENTISTS AND
DOCTORS FROM AROUND THE WORLD
HAVE FOUND LIGHT THERAPY TO BE
A SAFE, NON-INVASIVE, EFFECTIVE
TOOL FOR RELIEVING PAIN.
IT'S GREAT FOR BACK PAIN,
ARTHRITIS, TENSION HEADACHES,
BURSITIS, TENNIS ELBOW, HIP AND
JOINT PAIN, MUSCLE STRAINS
AND SPASMS, STIFFNESS
AND TENDONITIS.
IT CAN EVEN HELP RELIEVE
STUBBORN CHRONIC PAIN.
JUST IMAGINE WHAT IT CAN DO FOR
EVERYDAY ACHES AND PAINS.
ITS INNOVATIVE, COMPACT DESIGN
IS DURABLE, LIGHTWEIGHT
AND PORTABLE.
IT GOES ANYWHERE, FITS THE PALM
OF YOUR HAND FOR TEMPORARY
RELIEF OF PAIN.
EASILY REMOVE THE COMFORT PAD,
IT'S FLEXIBLE TO FIT EVERY CURVE
OF YOUR BODY.
WHEN YOU ORDER YOUR LIGHT
RELIEF, YOU'LL RECEIVE AN
ADJUSTABLE HANDS-FREE STRAP.
PLUS, YOU'LL GET OUR COMPLETE
GUIDE TO LIGHT THERAPY WITH
QUICK START INFORMATION.
HOW MUCH WOULD YOU EXPECT TO PAY
FOR THIS PROFESSIONAL
QUALITY LIGHT THERAPY SYSTEM?
COMMERCIAL UNITS THAT DOCTORS
USE SELL FOR THOUSANDS
OF DOLLARS.
BUT YOU CAN HAVE THE SOOTHING
POWER AND CONVENIENCE OF LIGHT
RELIEF IN YOUR HOME FOR LESS
THAN A FRACTION OF THAT PRICE.
YOU'LL GET THE ENTIRE
LIGHT RELIEF SYSTEM FOR ONLY
THREE PAYMENTS OF $39.95.
CALL RIGHT NOW AND WE'LL DROP
ONE ENTIRE PAYMENT.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU'LL GET THE COMPLETE
LIGHT RELIEF SYSTEM FOR ONLY
TWO PAYMENTS OF $39.95.
CALL IN THE NEXT 20 MINUTES,
WE'LL INCLUDE AS OUR SPECIAL
BONUS, OUR BODY BAND, SO YOU CAN
USE IT WHILE YOU READ, RELAX,
EVEN WATCH TV.
WE'LL EVEN INCLUDE OUR HANDY
TRAVEL BAG TO HOLD YOUR
ENTIRE LIGHT RELIEF SYSTEM.
IT'S FREE TOO!
LIGHT RELIEF IS FDA-CLEARED AND
EXCLUSIVELY MANUFACTURED IN AN
APPROVED ISO-9000 FACILITY,
WHICH MEANS IT MEETS THE MOST
STRINGENT QUALITY CONTROL
STANDARDS FOR HEALTHCARE
EQUIPMENT IN THE WORLD.
WE ARE SO CONFIDENT THAT
LIGHT RELIEF WILL WORK FOR YOU,
WE OFFER OUR 30-DAY PAIN FREE
WITH LIGHT OR WE MAKE IT RIGHT
GUARANTEE, NO QUESTIONS ASKED.
LIGHT RELIEF IS BACKED WITH
A FREE TWO-YEAR WARRANTY.
THAT MEANS IF IT GETS DAMAGED,
EVEN IF IT'S YOUR FAULT,
SEND IT BACK.
WE'LL RUSH YOU A NEW ONE FREE.
SO GET BACK TO LIVING LIFE TO
THE FULLEST AND FEELING GOOD
AGAIN, LIKE THOUSANDS
OF PEOPLE HAVE.
CLIMB THAT MOUNTAIN, SPREAD YOUR
WINGS AND FLY.
NOW YOU, OR SOMEONE YOU LOVE,
CAN HAVE THE FREEDOM TO ENJOY
THE INCREDIBLE SOOTHING POWER OF
LIGHT RELIEF.
PICK UP THE PHONE AND ORDER NOW.
TO ORDER LIGHT RELIEF RIGHT NOW,
HAVE YOUR CREDIT CARD READY AND
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN.
BE SURE TO ASK YOUR OPERATOR HOW
TO GET RUSH DELIVERY.
WHEN YOU ORDER, WE'LL SEND YOU
THE ENTIRE LIGHT RELIEF PACKAGE,
COMPLETE WITH EVERYTHING
YOU SEE HERE.
REMEMBER, YOUR LIGHT RELIEF IS
PROFESSIONAL QUALITY
AND DURABLE.
IT COMES WITH A 30-DAY
MONEY-BACK GUARANTEE AND A FREE
TWO-YEAR REPLACEMENT WARRANTY.
FIND THE RELIEF THAT THOUSANDS
ARE ALREADY ENJOYING, IN AS
LITTLE AS FIVE MINUTES A DAY.
PICK UP THE PHONE AND ORDER YOUR
LIGHT RELIEF NOW.
CALL THE NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN.
>> WELL, THIS JOB TAKES A LOT OF
WALKING AND RIDING, BOTH.
AND IT DON'T MATTER WHETHER
YOU'RE WALKING OR WHETHER YOU'RE
RIDING A HORSE.
YOUR KNEES GET A LOT OF ABUSE.
BUT I FOUND OUT WITH USING THE
LIGHTS THAT THEY MAKE LIFE SO
MUCH BETTER.
AND YOU DON'T HAVE THE PAIN AND
YOU CAN DO YOUR WORK
A LOT BETTER.
I JUST SWEAR BY THE LIGHTS,
I CAN TELL YOU THIS MUCH.
IT'S THE GREATEST THAT I'VE
EVER USED.
>> I WAS DIAGNOSED WITH
SCOLIOSIS WHEN I WAS 12 YEARS
OLD AND I ACTUALLY HAD TO WEAR
A FULL BODY BRACE FOR THREE
YEARS AS A TEENAGER, SO SINCE
THAT TIME, I HAVE SUFFERED FROM
CHRONIC BACK PAIN, NECK PAIN,
HIP PAIN, AND SINCE THE LIGHT
RELIEF PAD CAME INTO MY LIFE,
I HAVE BEEN USING IT ON MY BACK,
ON MY NECK, MY KNEES, AND HAD
SUCH A SIGNIFICANT REDUCTION
IN PAIN THAT IT'S AMAZING.
JUST WITHIN A MATTER OF MINUTES,
I FEEL DEFINITELY THE MUSCLES
AND THE TENSION RELEASING AND
THEN, I'M AMAZED THAT 15 MINUTES
LATER, THE PAIN'S GONE.
BEFORE THAT, I USED TO HAVE TO
TAKE AT LEAST 8-10 IBUPROFEN
A DAY, JUST TO GET OUT OF BED
AND FUNCTION.
SO IT'S AMAZING TO ME TO BE
PAIN FREE.
>> THE SIMPLEST SOLUTIONS ARE
SOMETIMES THE BEST: INFRARED
LIGHT IS A UNIQUE, SAFE
ALTERNATIVE THAT'S ACCEPTED
WORLDWIDE AS A 21st CENTURY
THERAPY FOR PAIN.
FINALLY, THIS TECHNOLOGY
IS AFFORDABLE FOR EVERYONE.
HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS OF
SATISFIED LIGHT RELIEF USERS
AGREE, LIKE ME AND THE PEOPLE
YOU'VE HEARD FROM TODAY, BREAK
THE CYCLE OF PAIN AND GET BACK
TO LIVING.
YOUR CHANCE TO GET THE SOOTHING
POWER OF LIGHT RELIEF IS HERE.
CALL NOW.
GET YOURS.
WISHING YOU GREAT HEALTH THAT'S
LIGHT YEARS AHEAD,
I'M ROBERT WAGNER.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
>> I DON'T THINK THAT THERE'S
ANYONE THAT SHOULDN'T HAVE
LIGHT RELIEF.
>> LIGHT RELIEF IS AN
AMAZING PRODUCT.
>> I WAS AMAZED THAT
THE RELIEF WAS SO COMPLETE
AND SO TOTAL.
>> THERE'S LIGHT AT THE END OF
THE TUNNEL AND IT'S
LIGHT RELIEF.
THANK GOD.
>> Announcer: THE PRECEDING
PRESENTATION WAS PROUDLY BROUGHT
TO YOU BY LIGHT RELIEF.
[  Male  Announcer  ]  THE
FOLLOWING  PROGRAM  IS  SPONSOD
BY ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL.
NO CHILD SHOULD DIE
IN THE DAWN OF LIFE.
THAT WAS THE DREAM
BEHIND ST. JUDE
CHILDREN'S RESEARCH HOSPITAL
WHEN IT WAS FOUNDED
MORE THAN 45 YEARS AGO.
AND IT'S THE DREAM
OF EVERY PARENT
WHOSE CHILD IS FIGHTING FOR LIFE
AGAINST CANCER TODAY.
TOGETHER, WE CAN HELP THEM WIN.
STAY WITH US
WHILE WE SHARE THE JOURNEY
OF SOME AMAZING CHILDREN
AND THEIR BATTLE TO OVERCOME
THIS DEADLY DISEASE.
[ Leticia ] I THOUGHT
I WAS GONNA BURY MY CHILD.
I THOUGHT SHE WAS GONNA DIE.
[ Julie ] YOU NEVER THINK THAT
YOUR CHILD WILL HAVE CANCER.
[ David ] YOU ALWAYS THINK THAT
IT HAPPENS TO SOMEONE ELSE.
[ Kelly ]
WE DIDN'T HAVE, REALLY,
ANY HOPE
UNTIL WE CAME TO ST. JUDE.
YOU CAN'T GIVE UP,
AND ST. JUDE AND
ALL THE DOCTORS AND NURSES,
THEY DON'T GIVE UP.
♪
[ Marlo ] YOUR HEART STOPS.
THE WORLD STOPS.
THAT'S WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU LEARN
THAT YOUR CHILD
HAS A DEADLY CANCER.
EVERY SECOND BECOMES PRECIOUS.
EVERY DAY IS ANOTHER DAY
TO BE THANKFUL FOR --
ANOTHER DAY TO REACH FOR A CURE.
AND THAT'S WHAT ST. JUDE
IS ALL ABOUT,
FINDING CURES
AND SAVING CHILDREN.