OPTIMUS: Before time began,
there was the Cube.
We know not
where it comes from,
only that it holds the power
to create worlds
and fill them with life.
That is how our race was born.
For a time,
we lived in harmony,
but like all great power,
some wanted it for good,
others for evil.
And so began the war,
a war that ravaged our planet
until it was consumed
by death,
and the Cube was lost
to the far reaches of space.
We scattered
across the galaxy,
hoping to find it
and rebuild our home,
searching every star,
every world.
And just when
all hope seemed lost,
message of a new discovery
drew us
to an unknown planet
called Earth.
But we were already too late.
Oh, God, five months of this.
I can't wait to get
a little taste of home.
A plate of mama's
alligators etouffee.
You've been talking about
barbecued 'gators and crickets
for the last two weeks.
I'm never going to your
mama's house, Fig. I promise.
But Bobby, Bobby,
'gators are known to have
the most succulent meat.
I understand.
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
(TALKING IN MOCK SPANISH)
English, please. English.
I mean,
how many times have we...
We don't speak Spanish.
I told you that.
Why you got to ruin it
for me, man?
That's my heritage.
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
Go with the Spanish.
Whatever.
Hey, you guys remember
weekends? Huh?
The Sox at Fenway.
Cold hotdog and a flat beer.
Perfect day.
What about you, Captain?
You got a perfect day?
I just can't wait
to hold my baby girl
for the first time.
FIG: He's adorable.
EPPS: That's too...
Shut up!
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
EPPS: Hey,
I'm ready to do this.
Hey, any of y'all
grow some balls,
come see me on the court, man.
LENNOX: Hey, hey!
Watch this crossover, baby.
Like Jordan in his prime,
pushing through
the front line.
Step aside, ladies.
Oh, man. What?
Lennox!
Hey, what are you doing?
Water?
Thank you.
Are you gonna help me
with the gear?
Colonel Sharp, we have
an inbound unidentified
infiltrator, 10 miles out.
SHARP ON RADIO:
Unidentified aircraft,
you are in restricted
US military airspace.
Squawk ident and proceed east
out of the area.
Raptors one and two,
snap to heading
two-five-zero to intercept.
Bogie is in the weeds
ten miles out, not squawking.
Unidentified aircraft,
we will escort you
to US SOCCENT airbase.
If you do not comply,
we will use deadly force.
Copy the bogie.
Tail 4500 X-ray.
Sir, says here 4500 X was
shot down three months ago.
Afghanistan.
That's got to be a mistake.
Check again, then recheck.
I did, sir.
A friend of mine
was on that chopper.
PILOT: Unidentified aircraft,
we will escort you
to US SOCCENT airbase.
SHARP: Radar,
where's the inbound?
SOLDIER: Bogie's
five miles out, sir.
My wife on?
SOLDIER: Yes, Captain.
(EXCLAIMING) My ladies!
Look.
Oh, my goodness. Look at her.
She's getting so big.
Look at those cheeks.
I just wanna chew on them.
Baby, we made
a good-looking kid.
I know that people
say that all the time,
but, wow, we made one
good-looking kid. Nice work.
She has your laugh.
(BABY GURGLING)
She laughed?
Her first one, yeah.
You sure she didn't just fart?
No, she's a lady.
(CRYING)
She doesn't know you yet,
but she will.
4500 X.
Something's not right.
MAN ON PA:
Bogie's on the deck.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Radar's jammed.
It's coming from the chopper.
Will?
Sarah?
Hey, Sarah,
if you can hear me,
I love you
and I'll be home soon.
(SOLDIERS CLAMORING)
To the right.
Go to the right.
Check fire.
MH-53 pilot, power down now.
(ENGINE TURNING OFF)
Have your crew step out
or we will kill you.
SOLDIER: Hold your fire!
Stand by to engage!
My God.
They bombed the antenna farm!
We're under attack!
Go! Move! Move!
It's going after the files!
Cut the hard lines!
I need a key! It's locked!
Move! Move!
Here, come here! Come here!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(PANTING)
Here, hide in here!
Oh, my God. Okay.
No!
(SCREAMS)
What the...
Epps, let's go!
(SCREAMING)
HOSNEY: Okay, Mr. Witwicky,
you're up.
SAM: Sorry,
I got a lot of stuff.
(WHISPERING) Watch.
Okay.
For my family...
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
Who did... Who did that?
People! Responsibility.
Okay.
So, for my family
genealogy report,
I decided to do it
on my great-great-grandfather,
who was a famous man,
Captain Archibald Witwicky.
Very famous explorer.
In fact,
he was one of the first
to explore the Arctic Circle,
which is a big deal.
In 1897, he took
41 brave sailors straight
into the Arctic Shelf.
SAILOR: Move faster, men!
Move! Chop! Heave!
The ice is freezing
faster than it's melting!
Chop faster! Heave, men!
Heave!
No sacrifice, no victory!
We'll get to
the Arctic Circle, lads!
So that's the story, right?
And here we have
some of the basic
instruments and tools
used by 19th-century seamen.
(ALL LAUGHING)
This here is the quadrant,
which you can get
for 80 bucks.
It's all for sale, by the way.
(STUDENTS CHUCKLING)
Like the sextant here.
$50 for this,
which is a bargain.
These are pretty cool. These
are my grandfather's glasses.
I haven't quite gotten them
appraised yet, but they've
seen many cool things.
HOSNEY: Are you going
to sell me his liver?
Mr. Witwicky,
this isn't show and sell.
It's the 11th grade.
I don't think
your grandfather would be
particularly proud
of what you're doing.
I know. I'm sorry. I just,
you know, this is all
going towards my car fund.
You can tell your folks.
It's on eBay. I take PayPal.
Cold hard cash works, too.
And the compass makes
a great gift for Columbus Day.
HOSNEY: Sam!
Sorry.
Unfortunately,
my great-great-grandfather,
the genius that he was,
wound up going blind
and crazy in a psycho ward,
drawing these strange symbols
and babbling on about
some giant ice man
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
that he thought
he'd discovered.
HOSNEY: Okay. Might be a
pop quiz tomorrow. Might not.
Sleep in fear tonight.
Here, you want?
Here, 50. 40? 30?
Sam?
Yeah. Sorry, sorry.
Okay. Pretty good, right?
I'd say a solid B-.
A B-?
You were hawking
your great-grandfather's crap
in my classroom.
No, kids enjoy...
Look, can you do me a favor?
What?
Can you look out the window
for a second?
You see my father?
He's the guy
in the green car.
Yeah.
Okay, I wanna tell you
about a dream. A boy's dream.
And a man's promise
to that boy.
He looked at me in the eye.
He said, "Son,
I'm gonna buy you a car.
"But I want you to bring me
$2,000 and three As."
Okay? I got the 2,000
and I got two As.
Okay? Here's the dream.
Your B-. Pfft!
Dream gone. Kaput.
Sir, just ask yourself,
what would Jesus do?
Yes! Yes, yes.
So?
A-. It's an A, though.
Wait, wait, wait.
I can't see. It's an A.
So I'm good?
You're good.
I got a little surprise
for you, son.
What kind of...
Yeah, a little surprise.
No. No, no, no, no. Dad!
Oh, you got to be kidding me.
See?
Yeah. I am.
You're not getting a Porsche.
(LAUGHING)
You think that's funny?
Yeah, I think it's funny.
What's wrong with you?
You think I'd really get you
a Porsche for your first car?
I don't want to talk to you
for the rest
of this whole thing.
(LAUGHING) Oh, come on.
It's just a practical joke.
It's not a funny joke.
Manny!
What?
Get your cousin out of
that damn clown suit.
He's having
a heat stroke again.
Scaring white folks.
I'm hot! Makeup's melting.
It hurts my eyes.
Here? No, no, no,
what is this?
You said...
You said half a car,
not half a piece of crap, Dad.
When I was your age,
I'd have been happy with
four wheels and an engine.
Okay, let me explain
something to you. Okay?
You ever see
40-Year-Old Virgin?
Yeah.
Okay, that's what this is.
And this is
50-year-old virgin.
Okay.
You want me to live that life?
No sacrifice, no victory.
Yeah, no victory.
You know, I got it.
The old Witwicky motto, Dad.
Right.
Gentlemen.
Bobby Bolivia,
like the country,
except without the runs.
How can I help you?
Well, my son here,
looking to buy his first car.
You come to see me?
I had to.
That practically
makes us family.
Uncle Bobby B, baby.
Uncle Bobby B.
Sam.
Sam, let me talk to you.
Sam, your first
enchilada of freedom
awaits underneath
one of those hoods.
Let me tell you
something, son.
(ENGINE REVVING)
A driver don't pick the car.
The car'll pick the driver.
It's a mystical bond
between man and machine.
Son, I'm a lot of things,
but a liar's not one of them.
Especially not
in front of my mammy.
That's my mammy. Hey, Mammy!
Oh, don't be like that.
If I had a rock,
I'd bust your head, bitch.
I tell you, man,
she deaf, you know?
(LAUGHING)
Well, over here,
every piece of car
a man might want or need.
This ain't bad.
This one's got
racing stripes.
Yeah.
It got racing...
Yeah, what's this?
What the heck is this?
I don't know nothing
about this car. Manny!
What?
What is this?
This car!
Check it out!
I don't know, boss!
I've never seen it!
That's loco!
Don't go Ricky Ricardo on me,
Manny! Find out!
Feels good.
RON: How much?
(GROANS) Well,
considering the semi-classic
nature of the vehicle,
with the slick wheels
and the custom paint job...
SAM: Yeah,
but the paint's faded.
Yeah, but it's custom.
It's custom faded?
Well, this is your first car.
I wouldn't expect you
to understand.
Five grand.
No, I'm not paying
over four. Sorry.
Kid, come on, get out.
Get out the car.
No, no, no. You said
cars pick their drivers.
Well, sometimes
they pick a driver
with a cheap-ass father.
Out the car.
Now, this one here
for four Gs is a beaut.
There's a Fiesta with
racing stripes over there.
No, I don't want a Fiesta
with racing stripes.
This is a classic engine
right here.
I sold a car
the other day...
(CAR HORN HONKING)
Gee. Holy cow.
No, no, no. No worries.
You all right?
I'll get a sledgehammer
and knock this right out.
Hey, hey, Manny!
Get your clown cousin
and get some hammers
and come bang
this stuff out, baby!
MAN ON RADIO:
...greater than man...
That one's my favorite,
drove all the way
from Alabammy.
(BEEPING)
(CAR ALARMS BLARING)
$4,000.
Steve.
Hello, Mr. Secretary.
They're so young.
AIDE: They're the top
subject matter experts, sir.
NSA's recruiting right out of
high school these days.
Guys, that's
the Secretary of Defense.
I am so underdressed.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Secretary of Defense.
Please be seated.
I'm John Keller.
Obviously, you're wondering
why you're here,
so these are the facts.
At 1900 local time yesterday,
the SOCCENT Forward Operations
Base in Qatar was attacked.
So far as we know,
there were no survivors.
The objective of the attack
was to hack
our military network.
We're not sure exactly
what they're after,
but we do know that they were
cut off during the assault,
which would lead us to assume
that they're going
to try it again.
Now, no one's taken
responsibility for the attack.
And the only real lead
we have so far is this sound.
(ELECTRONIC SCREECHING)
That's the signal
that hacked our network.
NSA's working at full capacity
to analyze it
and intercept
further communications,
but we need your help
to find out who did this.
Now, you've all shown
considerable ability
in the area of
signals analysis.
We're on a hair-trigger here,
people.
The President has dispatched
battle groups
to the Arabian Gulf
and Yellow Sea.
This is as real
as it's ever gonna get.
Now I'm gonna leave you
to your officer-in-charge.
You'll break up into teams
and you'll start your work.
Good luck to us all.
YOU WANNA SEE IF WALMART HAS
SIMILAR GIFTS FOR LESS?
YEAH.
LET'S GO.
SAMSUNG GALAXY S3 --
OVER FIFTY DOLLARS LESS
THAN BEST BUY!
WOW! FIFTY BUCKS!
YEAH!
THAT'S A PAIR OF SHOES.
SEE FOR YOURSELF IF YOU COULD
SAVE ON THE GIFTS YOU WANT.
WALMART.
GET $100 OFF ANY 4G LTE TABLET
WHEN YOU BUY ANY SMARTPHONE.
AND GET A TABLET DATA PLAN
STARTING AT JUST $10/MO.
NO SHARING REQUIRED.
HURRY INTO A Sprint STORE
OR VISIT sprint.com/tabletoffer
TODAY.
All right, Mojo.
I got the car.
Now I need the girl.
I need money to take out
the girl is what I need.
Zero bids.
(SIGHS)
Great. Broke.
(SNARLING)
Come on, Mojo.
You want your pain pills?
No. Premature.
Good. What's up?
Nothing. You know,
just driving my car.
Driving my car.
It's like clockwork.
All right, I know you get
wasted on these things,
but if you piss
in my bed again,
you're sleeping outside. Okay?
That's it for today.
No more. Crackhead.
Ron, this one is uneven.
Yeah. Probably.
This one is wobbly.
Yeah. I'll take
care of that real soon.
(LAUGHS)
Couldn't we have hired
a professional?
Sam...
What?
I do not like footprints
on my grass.
What foot...
There's no footprints.
That's why I built my path.
So why don't you go from
my grass onto my path, okay?
It's family grass, Dad.
Well, when you own
your own grass,
you'll understand.
This...
I can't do it anymore.
You're putting girl jewelry
on a boy dog.
What?
He's got enough self-esteem
issues as a Chihuahua, Mom.
JUDY: That's his bling.
I want you home at 11:00!
Yeah, all right.
11:00!
JUDY: Please, for the love
of God, drive safely.
Seat belt on!
Wow. You are so cheap.
Well, it's his first car.
Supposed to be like that.
KELLER ON TV: At this time,
we can't confirm whether
there were any survivors.
Oh, my God.
Our bases worldwide are,
as of now, at DEFCON Delta,
our highest readiness level.
We're dealing with a very
effective weapons system
that we have not
come across before.
But our prayers
are with the families
of the brave men and women...
(CRYING)
Honey, Daddy's gonna be okay.
EPPS: I've never seen
a weapons system like this.
The thermal shows this weird
aura around the exoskeleton
like it's cloaked
by some kind of
invisible force field.
That's impossible.
There's no such thing
as invisible force fields
except in, like,
comic book stuff, right?
FIG: Man, I don't know.
What is that?
My mama, she had the gift,
you know?
She saw things.
I got the gene, too,
and that thing
that attacked us?
I got a feeling it ain't over.
DONNELY: How about you use
those magic voodoo powers
and get us the hell
out of here, huh?
When I took that picture,
I think it saw me.
It looked right at me.
All right, we got to get
this thing back
to the Pentagon right away.
They got to know what
we're dealing with here.
EPPS: My radio's fried.
I got no communication
with aerial.
LENNOX: Hey, Mahfouz.
How far do you live from here?
Not far.
Just up that mountain.
Do they have a phone?
Yes.
All right, let's hit it.
MILES: Dude, are you sure
we're invited to this party?
SAM: Of course, Miles.
It's a lake. Public property.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God, dude,
Mikaela's here.
Just don't do
anything weird, all right?
I'm good, right?
Yeah, you're good.
Okay.
Hey, guys, check it out.
Oh, hi.
TRENT: Hey, bro. That car.
It's nice. Hey.
So, what are you guys
doing here?
We're here
to climb this tree.
I see that.
It looks... It looks fun.
Yeah.
You know, I thought
I recognized you.
You tried out for
the football team
last year, right?
(GRUNTING)
COACH: Let's go call your mom.
Oh, no, no, that...
No. That wasn't like
a real tryout.
I was researching a book
I was writing.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah? What's it about?
Sucking at sports?
(CHUCKLES)
No, it's about
the link between
brain damage and football.
No, it's a good book.
Your friends'll love it.
You know,
it's got mazes in it
and, you know,
little coloring areas,
sections, pop-up pictures.
It's a lot of fun.
That's funny.
Okay, okay.
You know what? Stop.
Hey, guys, I know of a party.
Let's go, let's head.
You got to get out
of the tree right now. Get...
Just get out of the tree
right now, please.
What are you doing?
Did you see that dismount?
All the chicks were watching.
You're making me
look like an idiot.
We both looked
like idiots just now.
Hey, how about
you let me drive?
Oh, no. No, no, no.
This is not a toy.
These 22s, I don't want you
grinding them. No.
Why doesn't my little bunny
just hop in the back seat?
Oh, God, I can't even tell you
how much I'm not
your little bunny.
Okay. You'll call me.
(DRIVE PLAYING ON RADIO)
♪ Who's gonna drive you
home tonight?
Hey, man, what's wrong
with your radio?
I'm gonna drive her
home tonight.
What?
She's an evil jock concubine,
man. Let her hitchhike.
She lives 10 miles from here.
It's my only chance.
You got to be understanding.
All right. We'll put her
in the back. I'll be quiet.
Did you say,
"Put her in the back"?
I called shotgun.
I'm not putting her
in the back. You got
to get out of my car.
That's a party foul.
What rules?
Bros before hos.
Miles, I'm begging you
to get out of my car. Okay?
You can't do this to me.
You got to get out
of my car right now.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
♪ Who's gonna come around
when you break? ♪
Mikaela! It's Sam.
Witwicky.
I hope I didn't get you
stranded or anything. You sure?
So, listen, I was wondering
if I could ride you home.
I mean, give you a ride home
in my car, to your house.
There you go.
(SAM CLEARS THROAT)
So...
I can't believe that
I'm here right now.
You can duck down
if you want.
I mean,
it won't hurt my feelings.
Oh, no, no, no.
I didn't mean here with you.
I just meant here,
like, in this situation,
this same situation
that I'm always in.
'Cause, I don't know,
I guess I just have
a weakness for hot guys,
for tight abs
and really big arms.
Big arms?
Well, there's a couple new
additions in the car.
Like, I just put in
that light there.
And that disco ball.
And so the light reflects
off the disco ball.
Ah.
Yeah.
Are you new
to school this year?
It's your first year here?
Oh, no, no.
We've been in the same school
since first grade.
Really?
Yeah.
Yeah, a long time.
Well, do we have
any classes together?
Yeah, yeah.
Really? Which?
History. Language arts.
Math. Science.
Sam.
Sam. Yeah.
Sam Wilkicky.
Witwicky.
God, you know what?
I'm so sorry. I just...
No, it's cool.
I just didn't recognize you.
Yeah, well, I mean,
that's understandable.
(ENGINE STALLING)
No, no, no. No. Come on.
(SEXUAL HEALING PLAYING)
Sorry, I'm just
working out the kinks.
You know, it's a new car.
♪ When I get that feeling
I want sexual healing
This radio is,
like, you know...
It's an old radio, too, so...
♪ Sexual healing
Look, this isn't something
that I, you know...
I can't get this
radio to stop.
Look, I wouldn't
try this on you.
'Cause this is like
a romantic thing
that I'm not trying to do.
Uh-huh.
Not that you're not worthy of
trying something like this on.
No, of course not.
I'm a friend of yours.
I'm not a romantic friend.
Romantic friends do this.
I mean, I'm not that friend.
I mean, we... I could be.
(I GOT YOU PLAYING)
Just pop the hood.
Stupid. Shut up,
shut up, shut up.
MIKAELA: Whoa, nice headers.
You've got a high-rise
double-pump carburetor.
That's pretty impressive, Sam.
Double-pump?
It squirts the fuel in
so you can go faster.
Oh.
I like to go faster.
And it looks like
your distributor cap's
a little loose.
Yeah? How'd you know that?
My dad. He was
a real grease monkey.
He taught me all about this.
I could take it
all apart, clean it,
put it back together.
That's weird. I just wouldn't
peg you for mechanical.
(WHISPERS) Oh, my God.
Well, you know,
I don't really broadcast it.
Guys don't like it
when you know more
about cars than they do.
Especially not Trent.
He hates it.
Yeah, no, I'm cool with,
you know, females
working on my engine.
I prefer it, actually.
Okay. You want to
fire it up for me?
Oh, yeah, yeah, no problem.
Thanks.
You know, I was thinking.
You know,
if Trent's such a jerk,
why do you
hang out with him?
(ENGINE FAILING TO IGNITE)
You know what? I'm just...
I'm gonna walk.
Good luck with your car.
All right.
Walking's healthy, right?
Oh, God, no, no,
no, no, no, no.
Come on, please. Please,
you gotta work for me now.
Don't let her walk away.
Come on, come on,
come on. Please, please.
(BABY COME BACK
PLAYING ON RADIO)
♪ Baby come back
♪ Any kind of fool could see
Hey!
♪ There was something
in everything about you
♪ Baby come back
Hey!
♪ You can blame it all on me
Wait a second!
♪ I was wrong
♪ And I just can't
live without you ♪
There it is.
I had fun. So, you know,
thanks for listening.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
You... You think I'm shallow?
I think you're...
No, no, no. I think...
I think there's a lot more
than meets the eye with you.
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
Yeah.
All right,
I'll see you at school.
All right.
That's stupid.
That was a stupid line.
"There's more than meets
the eye with you." Stupid.
Oh, God.
(CHUCKLES EXCITEDLY)
Oh, my God. I love my car.
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLY DON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDS ONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOU NEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15 ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OO! THE TILAPIA
WITH ROASTED VEGETABLES!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WOOD GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
THAT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY!
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
KAY JEWELERS PRESENTS THE RING
THAT LIVES UP TO THE MOMENT.
NEIL LANE BRIDAL --
FROM HOLLYWOOD'S PREMIER
JEWELRY DESIGNER.
THE SETTING HAS TO BE PERFECT.
IT'S WHERE THE DIAMOND LIVES.
[ Female Announcer ]
UNIQUELY BEAUTIFUL,
HAND-CRAFTED RINGS.
WITH DIAMONDS HAND-SELECTED
BY KAY.
THE NEWEST REASON KAY IS
THE NUMBER ONE
JEWELRY STORE IN AMERICA.
NEIL LANE BRIDAL.
FOREVER BEGINS HERE.
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
Hey, guys, I think the other
team figured it out. Iran.
Come on, man. This is way too
smart for Iranian scientists.
Think about it.
What do you think, kid?
Chinese?
No way. This is nothing like
what the Chinese are using.
PILOT: This is Air Force One.
Level of flight,
level three-three-zero.
KELLER ON TV: We will
hunt down this enemy.
And when we do,
we'll know just
what to do with them.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
REPORTER ON TV:
Apparently, there are
very few survivors.
Yes, Mr. President?
Yeah, can you wrangle me up
some Ding Dongs, darling?
(SNORING)
(TALKING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
I joined the Air Force
to bring the man Ding Dongs.
I'll be in storage.
Shoot.
Ugh. Gross.
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(ELECTRONIC WHIRRING)
Do you hear that?
Are you getting this?
I think they're hacking
the network again.
Uh-oh.
Oh, my God.
This is a direct match
to the signal in Qatar.
Are you running
a diagnostic?
Should I be?
Yes, you should.
So I am.
(BEEPING)
Someone! They're hacking
into Air Force One!
We need a senior analyst.
I think they're
planting a virus.
A virus?
It's streaming right now.
They are planting a virus
and stealing a whole lot
of data from your system
at the same time.
Code Red. We have a breach.
MAN: Air Force One,
someone onboard has breached
the military network.
I'm in the cargo hold.
Clear. Clear.
You got to cut
the hard lines.
What?
Whatever they want,
they are getting it.
Sir?
Permission to take down
the Defense Network.
Cut all server hard lines now.
(BEEPING)
Someone's tampered
with the POTUS mainframe.
What the...
(GRUNTING)
MAN ON RADIO: Shots fired
in the underdeck.
Repeat, shots fired.
CAPTAIN: Crew, prepare
for emergency descent.
I want our President
in that bunker.
And I don't want to discuss
a damn thing other
till that becomes reality.
That's our first priority.
That's our only priority
right now.
Air Force One
is on the ground.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(SPEAKING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
(SIREN BLARING)
(ENGINE STARTING)
(ENGINE REVVING)
Oh, God. No, no,
no, no, no, no, no!
That's my car!
No!
No, no, no, no.
Dad, call the cops!
Where you going with my car,
buddy? Where you going?
Hello? 911 emergency!
My car has been stolen!
I'm in pursuit! Right?
I need all units,
the whole squadron.
Bring everyone! No, don't
ask me questions, all right?
My father's the head
of the neighborhood watch!
(BELL RINGING)
Oh, my God.
My name is Sam Witwicky.
Whoever finds this,
my car is alive, okay?
You saw that?
Since this is my last words
on Earth, I just wanna say,
Mom, Dad, I love you,
and if you find Busty Beauties
under my bed, it wasn't mine.
I'm holding it for Miles.
No, no, wait that...
Okay, that's not true.
It's mine and Uncle Charles
gave it to me.
I'm sorry. Mojo, I love you.
(GROWLING)
(BARKING)
No! No! No! No!
Oh, my God.
No, you're a good dog!
Good dog! Good dog!
Oh, my God.
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey!
All right! Oh! No! No!
Okay. Please,
please don't kill me!
I'm sorry! Take the keys!
I don't want them!
Car's yours!
Listen, listen, listen.
Good, you're here.
Let me see your hands!
No, no, no! It's not me!
Let me see your hands.
The guy's inside.
Shut up!
Walk towards the car.
Put your head
on the hood.
Whoever did this finally
managed to infiltrate
our defense network,
which is what they
tried to do in Qatar,
only this time it worked.
What did they get?
We still don't know.
Talk to me
about the virus.
It's a Spider-bot virus.
We're not sure
what it's going to do,
but it may cripple the system.
KELLER: Can we stop it?
Every time
we try an antivirus,
it adapts and speeds up. It's
like it's not a virus anymore.
It's become the system.
BRIGHAM: Obviously
the first phase of a major
attack against the US.
The only countries
with this kind of capability
are Russia, North Korea,
maybe China.
I'm sorry,
that's not correct.
Excuse me, young lady.
I didn't see you standing
there. You would be who?
I'm just the analyst
who detected the hack.
Hold on. It was you?
You did it?
Her team.
Sir, I was just
trying to say,
they hacked your firewall
in 10 seconds.
Okay. Even a supercomputer
with a brute force attack
would take 20 years
to do that.
Maybe you can explain, then,
how our latest
satellite imagery
shows North Korea
doubling its naval activity.
Maybe it's a precaution,
because isn't that
what we're doing?
The signal pattern
is learning.
It's evolving on its own.
And you need to move
past Fourier transfers
and start considering
quantum mechanics.
There is nothing on Earth
that complex.
What about an organism?
A living organism?
Maybe some kind of
DNA-based computer?
And I know that
that sounds crazy...
That's enough.
We have six floors of analysts
working on this thing.
Now, if you can find proof
to back up your theory,
I'm gonna be happy
to listen to you.
But if you don't get a filter
on that brain-mouth thing,
you're gonna be off the team.
You understand?
Look, I can't be any clearer
than how crystal clear
I am being.
It just stood up.
Wow. That's really neat.
Okay, chiefie.
Time to fill her up.
And no drippy-drippy.
What are you rolling?
Whippets? Goofballs?
A little wowie sauce
with the boys?
No, I'm not on any drugs.
What's these?
Found it in your pocket.
"Mojo."
Is that what the kids are
doing now? Little bit of Mojo?
Those are my dog's pain pills.
You know, a Chihuahua.
A little...
What was that?
You eyeballing my piece,
50 Cent?
You wanna go?
Make something happen. Do it.
'Cause I promise you
I will bust you up.
Are you on drugs?
Get ready for a feeling of
clean like nothing else.
Extreme Clean from Aquafresh.
It showers your whole
mouth with rich
Micro-Active foam.
Thousands of
germ-killing bubbles
seek out hard to reach places
and help kill the
sources of bad breath
then rinse clean away
Leaving a cool tingling
that just won't quit
Extreme Clean from Aquafresh.
Take the feeling of
clean to the extreme.
Extreme Clean from Aquafresh.
For thos...this...ions of doing
this...
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
THE ONE FOR ALL.
MCDONALD'S DOLLAR MENU.
HOME OF THE MEATY, MELTY
MCDOUBLE YOU LOVE.
AND OTHER AMAZING TASTES
FOR JUST A DOLLAR EACH.
♪
EVERY DAY, AS ALWAYS,
THERE'S A LOT TO LOVE
FOR A LITTLE
ON MCDONALD'S DOLLAR MENU.
♪
AND THIS IS
THE NOKIA LUMIA 920 FROM AT&T.
IT'S GOT LIVE TILES
SO ALL MY STUFF'S
ALWAYS RIGHT THERE IN REAL-TIME.
IT'S LIKE
THE ULTIMATE PERSONAL ASSISTANT.
BUT I'M ME,
AND ME NEEDS HANDLERS.
SO I HIRED TODD
TO HANDLE IT FOR ME.
TODD, GIMME THAT HOLLYWOOD NEWS!
WHAT'S HAPPENING ON TWITTER?
YOU'RE TRENDING!
YES!
YOU CAN'T HAVE A TODD,
BUT YOU CAN HAVE YOUR
OWN PERSONAL ASSISTANT.
I GUESS
YOU COULD CALL IT TODD.
[ Male Announcer ] THE NEW
NOKIA LUMIA 920 WITH LIVE TILES
THAT DELIVER WHAT YOU WANT
IN REAL TIME.
ONLY FROM AT&T.
RETHINK POSSIBLE.
Let's hope this
telephone line works.
FIG: Hey, heads up!
Heads up! Hey! Heads up!
What the heck was that?
(SPEAKING IN SPANISH)
English, dude. English.
Whoa!
Watch out!
Open fire!
Contact! Contact!
LENNOX:
Everybody, quiet. Settle.
EPPS: Whoa...
What the hell...
(SCREAMS)
(ALL SHOUTING)
Get up! Get up! Come on!
Go! Move it!
(ALL CLAMORING)
(SCREECHING)
Take cover!
Fig! Cover the rear!
Cover fire! Move it!
Fig, cover the rear!
Epps! Cover the rear! Move it!
Come on! Give me a mag!
Where's your papa?
Papa!
Sir, we need...
I need a telephone.
Telephone,
telephone, yes!
Telephone!
EPPS: Hey, I need a mag!
Give me a mag!
Cell phone!
I don't know
how to thank you.
EPPS: Fire!
This is an emergency
Pentagon call!
I need you to...
Do you understand?
It's an emergency Pentagon...
I don't have a credit card!
Sir, the attitude is not
going to speed things up
any bit at all.
I'm going to ask you to
speak into the mouthpiece
very clearly.
I'm in the middle of a war!
This is frigging ridiculous!
Ammo!
I need a credit card!
Epps! Where's your wallet?
Pocket!
Which pocket?
My back pocket!
You got 10 back pockets!
Left cheek! Left cheek!
Left cheek!
LENNOX: All right,
keep shooting! Keep shooting!
Okay, it's Visa.
Also, sir,
have you heard about
our premium plus
world-service gold package?
No, I don't want a premium
package! Epps! Pentagon!
Give me a status.
Sir, we're tracking
a Special Ops team
under fire in Qatar.
They say they're survivors
of the base attack.
Survivors?
I ain't never seen this
in my life!
Need gunships
on station ASAP!
SERGEANT: Predator's coming up
in a minute.
We're linking the call
to the nearest AWACS.
Unknown, man. I don't... man...
Predator ETA two minutes.
Hey! Make way!
What is that?
I don't know.
We need air support
and we need it now.
Roll in strike package Bravo
on unknown target.
I authenticate Tango Whiskey
at time 0300 Zulu.
MAN 1: Attention,
all aircraft.
This will be a danger
close-fire mission.
MAN 2: Weapons, I just got
a call from Falcon Ops.
Who's closer
to Kill Box One Alpha?
Send the Hogs, sir.
Okay, send the Hogs over
to Kill Box One Alpha.
It's a danger close...
MAN 3: Switch the Hogs
to Kill Box One Alpha,
300 feet danger close.
PILOT: Friendlies in the area.
Seven-man team
north of orange smoke!
Received Kill Box One Alpha.
Engage hostile.
Attack direction west!
You're clear and hot!
Strike, tell me status
of Hog right now.
Hog One-One Dark Star status.
Lennox! The heat's coming!
Laze the target!
We got a beam-rider incoming!
Laze target!
Ready! Heat's coming!
What? Bring it!
PILOT: Receiving radar jamming
in vicinity of target.
LENNOX: No frigging way
that thing's still not down.
Spooky Three Two,
use 105 shells.
Bring the rain.
PILOT: Be advised,
ground team is requesting
105 sabot rounds.
Did we lose them?
SERGEANT: Warthog One
confirm visual on friendlies.
LENNOX: Where's Fig?
Fig? Fig?
FIG: Oh, God!
Get a medic!
FIG: I'm sorry.
EPPS: Black Hawk...
We'll get a medic.
Just hold on.
He's got a pulse.
EPPS: We need a medevac.
Bring them home.
You get those men
stateside right now.
I want them debriefed
in 10 hours.
MAGGIE: There's only
one hacker in the world
who can break this code.
I am sorry to bother you.
Maggie?
Listen, I need your help.
No! This is my private area,
my place of Zen and peace.
Listen to me.
GRANDMA: Glen! Who is it?
Shut up, Grandma!
Special Ops got a thermal
snapshot of whatever
hit the base in Qatar.
I want to see it.
Well, the imager
was damaged, sir.
The rangers are en route
with the imager,
but we also have
a security issue.
Circle logs indicate one of
the analysts made a copy
of the network
intrusion signal.
The signal strength
is through the roof.
Where did you say
you got this?
It hacked the national
military air-guard frequency
in less than a minute.
No way.
Yeah.
Looks like there's a message
embedded in the signal.
Let me work my magic.
"Project Iceman"?
What's Sector Seven?
Who is Captain Witwicky?
(SHUSHING)
Are you playing
those video games again?
Cops! Cops!
FBI! Clear right!
(SCREAMING)
AGENT: Lock it down!
Lock it down!
OMAR: Cops!
Lock it down.
Wait! I'm just a cousin!
I'm just a...
Get off my Grandmama's carpet!
She don't like nobody
on the carpet!
Especially police!
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
[ coughs ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU CAN'T LET A COLD
KEEP YOU UP TONIGHT.
VICKS NYQUIL --
POWERFUL NIGHTTIME
6-SYMPTOM COLD & FLU RELIEF.
♪
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
AND THEN THERE'S JUICY CHICKEN
WITH BEST FOODS
♪
BEST FOODS IS THE SECRET
TO MAKING
PARMESAN CRUSTED CHICKEN...
[ bell dings ]
...SO CRISPY
SO JUICY
SO DELICIOUS
IT'S YOUR SECRET
TO MAKING DINNER
DISAPPEAR
BEST FOODS.
BRING OUT THE BEST
le here  TO MAKING DINNER
DISAPPEAR
an hour ago
when over 40 C-17s lifted off
of this very base.
We're not told
where they're going.
Morning, Mo.
The government has been
very quiet about what's
going on but in our...
Mojo. Mojo.
They were headed directly
(BARKS)
towards North Korea.
Stop with the barking, Mojo.
It's too early. Please?
(ENGINE REVVING)
Miles? Miles, listen to me.
Listen.
My car, it stole itself, okay?
What are you
talking about, man?
Satan's Camaro. In my yard.
It's stalking me.
Stop!
No, no, no, no, no, no.
(SHOUTING)
GIRL: Oh, my God!
(GROANING)
Sam?
Hi.
That was...
That was really awesome.
(GROANING)
Well, it felt awesome.
Are you okay?
I'm not okay, all right?
I'm losing my mind
a little bit.
I'm getting chased by my car
right now. I got to go.
You know what? I'm gonna
catch up with you guys later.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(POLICE SIREN BLARING)
Oh, great. Cops.
(ENGINE REVVING)
Officer!
Listen!
(GRUNTING)
Oh, that hurt.
Listen to me!
Thank God you're here!
I've had the worst day ever!
I've been...
I've been followed here
on my mother's bike! Right?
And my car's right there and
it's been following me here!
So get out of the car!
(ENGINE ROARING)
No! Stop! Oh, God.
Okay, okay! Okay, all right!
Okay! I'm sorry! I'm...
I didn't mean to
hit your car! Look!
Okay, look, look, look!
Stop, stop!
(EXCLAIMING)
Please! Okay,
what do you want from me?
Okay.
Oh, God, no! No!
Oh, God!
(SCREAMING)
It's a bad dream.
Are you username
LadiesMan217?
I don't know what
you're talking about!
Are you username
LadiesMan217?
Yeah.
Where is eBay item 21153?
Where are the glasses?
Get back!
Stop!
(GRUNTING)
God!
What is your problem, Sam?
Okay, there's a
monster right there!
It just attacked me!
Here he comes!
All right, get up.
Get up and run!
You have to run! Okay.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Sam, what is that thing?
You have to get
in the car. Get in.
I don't want to.
Trust me. Trust me!
Sam.
Get in! Go, go, go, go, go.
Go, go, go, go!
Oh, God! We're gonna die!
We're gonna die!
No, we're not.
No, we're not gonna die.
Oh, my God!
Trust me.
He's a kick-ass driver!
Oh, my God! No!
We're gonna die!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Oh, my God!
We're locked in.
(CAR PASSING)
The car won't start. At least
we ditched the monster, right?
Okay.
Time to start.
(SHOUTING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
(SPEAKING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
He's got me! Oh, God!
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
He's going to kill me!
No. No, no, no!
Get off!
Kill it! Kill it!
Get it, get it,
get it, get it!
(CHATTERING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Not so tough
without a head, are you?
(SCREECHING)
Here, come on.
MIKAELA: What is it?
It's a robot.
But like a...
Like a different... You know,
like a super-advanced robot.
It's probably Japanese.
Yeah, it's definitely
Japanese.
What are you doing?
I don't think
it wants to hurt us.
It would have
done that already.
Really? Well,
do you speak robot?
Because they just had, like,
a giant droid death match.
I think it wants
something from me.
What?
Well, 'cause the other one was
talking about my eBay page.
You are the strangest boy
I have ever met.
SAM: Can you talk?
ANNOUNCER:
XM Satellite Radio...
(RADIO CHANNELS SWITCHING)
Digital cable brings you...
...Columbia Broadcasting
System...
So you...
You talk through the radio?
Thank you, you're beautiful.
You're wonderful,
you're wonderful.
So, what was that last night?
What was that?
Message from Starfleet,
Captain...
Throughout the inanimate
vastness of space...
Angels will rain down
like visitors from heaven!
Hallelujah!
Visitors from
heaven? What...
What are you, like,
an alien or something?
Any more questions
you want to ask?
He wants us
to get in the car.
And go where?
Fifty years from now,
when you're looking back
at your life,
don't you want to be able
to say you had the guts
to get in the car?
(MUTTERING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
WITH BRANDY WHO IS STOCKING UP
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
LOOK AT THAT PRICE.
THAT'S GREAT!
IF YOU FIND A LOWER
ADVERTISED PRICE,
WALMART WILL MATCH IT
AT THE REGISTER.
REALLY?
YEAH.
THERE YOU HAVE IT.
OH MY GOODNESS!
THAT'S THE WALMART
LOW PRICE GUARANTEE.
SEE FOR YOURSELF.
BRING IN YOUR LAST RECEIPT
AND SEE HOW MUCH
YOU CAN SAVE.
BE READY. WITH THE SEASON'S
TASTIEST BRANDS.
LIKE FARM RICH
MOZZARELLA BITES.
BITE-SIZED AND LOADED
WITH MOZZARELLA CHEESE.
WALMART HAS EVERYTHING YOU NEED
TO BE READY FOR HOLIDAY HOSTING.
WITH OUR LOW PRICE GUARANTEE
BACKED BY AD MATCH.
WALMART.
WITH OUR LOW PRICE GUARANTEE
BACKED BY AD MATCH.
You could keep your phone and
I lonumber.hone.
But for half of what we pay now.
Half?
Really good progress today.
Welcome to the next generation
of family plans.
visit Net10Wireless.com
FOR THEIR ANNUAL FOOTBALL TRIP.
THAT'S DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
TRAGICALLY, THEIR BUDDY
GOT SACKED BY BLACKOUTS.
BUT IT'S OUR TRADITION!
THAT'S ROUGHING
THE CARD HOLDER.
BUT WITH
THE Capital One Venture Card
YOU GET DOUBLE MILES
YOU CAN ACTUALLY USE.
[ cheering ]
ANY FLIGHT, ANYTIME.
THE SCOREBOARD DOESN'T LIE.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET? HUT!
I HAVE ME ON MY FANTASY TEAM.
♪ SPREAD A LITTLE LOVE MY WAY
♪ SPREAD A LITTLE SOMETHING
TO REMEMBER ♪
♪ SPREAD A LITTLE JOY AND SEE
♪ NEED A LITTLE HAPPINESS
TO BE ♪
♪ LIVING THE LIFE WITH ME
[ Female Announcer ]
PHILADELPHIA CREAM CHEESE.
MADE WITH FRESH MILK
AND REAL CREAM.
IT MAKES YOUR HOLIDAY RECIPES,
EVERYONE'S HOLIDAY FAVORITES.
♪
This car's
a pretty good driver.
I know.
Why don't you go
sit in that seat, there?
I'm not going to sit
in that seat. He's driving.
Yeah.
You're right.
Well, maybe you should
sit in my lap.
Why?
Well, I have the only
seat belt here.
You know, safety first.
(SIGHS)
Yeah, all right.
Right?
Yeah.
Okay.
There, see?
That's better.
Okay.
You know, that seat belt thing
was a pretty smooth move.
(CHUCKLING)
Thank you.
You know what
I don't understand?
Why, if he's supposed
to be, like, this
super-advanced robot,
does he transform back into
this piece-of-crap Camaro?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
SAM: Whoa! Whoa!
Oh, see? No. Get...
No, that doesn't work. See?
MAN: Move it, you moron!
Great, now... See?
Fantastic.
Now you pissed him off.
That car is sensitive.
I mean, $4000 just drove off.
What?
This is you...
(ALL SCREAMING)
Oh, my God!
Come on, let's go.
This is the coolest thing
I've ever seen!
Explosions everywhere!
This is easily a hundred times
cooler than Armageddon.
I swear to God!
Fire, fire, fire, fire!
Whoa! Sweet!
Oh, dude,
I hope this guy's got
asteroid insurance,
'cause he is so boned!
What is that?
There's something
in the tree, dude.
No, there's something
in the thing by the tree!
Could you guys just give me
a space rock?
Excuse me, are you
the tooth fairy?
Hey, sweetheart,
what are you doing
out here by yourself?
Holy God! What happened
to the pool?
Are you
Samuel James Witwicky,
descendent of
Archibald Witwicky?
They know your name.
Yeah.
My name is Optimus Prime.
We are autonomous
robotic organisms
from the planet Cybertron.
But you can call us
Autobots for short.
Autobots.
What's cracking,
little bitches?
OPTIMUS: My first lieutenant.
Designation, Jazz.
JAZZ: This looks like
a cool place to kick it.
What is that?
How did he learn
to talk like that?
We've learned
Earth's languages through
the World Wide Web.
My weapons specialist,
Ironhide.
You feeling lucky, punk?
Easy, Ironhide.
Just kidding. I just wanted
to show him my cannons.
(SNIFFING)
OPTIMUS:
Our medical officer, Ratchet.
The boy's pheromone level
suggests he wants to
mate with the female.
You already know
your guardian, Bumblebee.
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
Bumblebee, right?
BUMBLEBEE: ♪ Check on the rep
Yep, second to none ♪
So you're my guardian, huh?
His vocal processors
were damaged in battle.
I'm still working on them.
Why are you here?
We are here
looking for the All Spark.
And we must find it
before Megatron.
Mega-what?
OPTIMUS: Our planet was
once a powerful empire,
peaceful and just,
until we were betrayed
by Megatron,
leader of the Decepticons.
All who defied them
were destroyed.
Our war finally
consumed the planet,
and the All Spark
was lost to the stars.
Megatron followed it to Earth,
where Captain Witwicky
found him.
My grandfather.
It was an accident
that intertwined our fates.
(YELPING)
Come back!
I think the dogs
have found something.
(ICE CRACKING)
The ice is cracking!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Captain!
Grab my rope, Captain!
I'm all right, lads!
Can we throw you
a rope, Captain?
Megatron crash-landed before
he could retrieve the Cube.
Men! We've made a discovery!
He accidentally activated
his navigation system.
(MEGATRON SPEAKING
IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
(SCREAMING)
OPTIMUS: The coordinates to
the Cube's location on Earth
were imprinted on his glasses.
How'd you know
about his glasses?
eBay.
If the Decepticons
find the All Spark,
they will use its power
to transform Earth's machines
and build a new army.
And the human race
will be extinguished.
Sam Witwicky, you hold
the key to Earth's survival.
Please tell me that
you have those glasses.
with Lively Colombian.
It's a morning breeze
smooth as Black Silk.
With Folgers Gourmet Selections
K-Cup packs
You can turn any day gourmet.
New roasts, a new look...
available
where you buy groceries.
WELCOME TO CHEVY'S
YEAR-END EVENT.
SO, THE 5.3-LITER V8 SILVERADO
CAN TOW UP TO 9,600 POUNDS?
315 HORSEPOWER.
WHAT'S THAT IN
REINDEER-POWER?
[ laughs ]
[ pencil scratches ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHEVY'S GIVING MORE.
GET THE BEST OFFER
OF THE YEAR --
0% APR FINANCING FOR 60 MONTHS
PLUS $1,000 HOLIDAY BONUS CASH.
PLUS TRADE UP FOR AN ADDITIONAL
$1,000 TRADE-IN ALLOWANCE.
HURRY.
BONUS CASH ENDS JANUARY 2ND.
HELLO?
[ Sea ] HI!
THIS IS THE SEA CALLING.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU VISITED ME?
WHEN I WENT SURFING.
I LOVE TO SURF.
CAN YOU IMAGINE
SURFING IN THE MIDDLE OF ME?
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOU?
OH YES!
[ giggles ] NICE MOVES!
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
OUR BIGGEST DECEMBER
SALES EVENT EVER.
GOING ON NOW.
CALL 1-800-ROYAL-CARIBBEAN.
It's like a self-regenerating
molecular armor.
Look at the scorch mark
where the sabot round hit.
Melted right through.
Hey, aren't sabots hot-loaded
for, like, a 6,000-degree
magnesium burn?
Close to it.
It melts tank armor.
So this metal skin must
react to extreme heat.
Heads up!
Oh!
I thought you said
that thing was dead, man!
Strap it down! Strap it!
This thing is wicked.
All right, get on the horn
with Northern Command.
Tell them that
our effective weapon
is high-heat sabot rounds.
Recommend we load them
on all the gunships. Go.
Whatever fell out of the sky
ended up right behind...
What did he say?
What?
Did he hear it, too?
Yeah, Jack heard it, too.
Yeah.
What does he think it is?
He thinks it's
a military experiment.
What a knucklehead.
Yeah, well,
I think it's a plane.
Still no official word as to
what happened. You can see...
Yeah!
Call Sam.
Yeah. Why?
He should be home in 15 minutes.
Well, I'll call him
in 15 minutes.
If you wait 15 minutes,
he'll be late and
you'll have to ground him.
Well, I can't ground him
if he's not late, can I?
I need you to stay here,
all right?
You got to stay here
and you're gonna watch them.
Okay, okay.
All of them.
Do you hear
what I'm saying?
Yeah, okay, okay.
Five minutes,
all right?
Thanks for
staying on my path.
Oh, yeah.
No, no, Dad. Hey!
The... Oh, the path.
I'm sorry. I forgot
about the path.
I'm gonna sweep
the whole thing right now.
How about that?
You know,
I buy half your car...
Yeah.
...then I bail you out of jail
and then I just decided
to do all your chores.
The chores.
Yeah. Life is great, huh?
Life... Life is fantastic,
is how good it is.
It's so... Oh, the trash cans.
Sorry, Dad. I'm gonna do
the trash cans now.
No, no, I don't want you
to strain yourself.
No, no, I won't
strain myself, Dad.
I'll do it.
It would hurt my feelings
if you do it.
You sure?
I don't mind, I don't...
I promise...
No, no, no,
I'm gonna do it.
I'm gonna do the trash cans
and I'm gonna scrape the grill
and I'm gonna...
I'm gonna sweep up
the whole house right now.
Tonight, right now?
Right now.
The...
(SHUSHING)
I love you.
God, I love you
just so much right now.
You know, Mom wanted
me to ground you.
You're three minutes late.
Right?
Oh, well, just another thing
you did for me, Dad,
because you're
such a swell guy.
One more thing, huh?
All right, I love you!
Sleep good, handsome man!
What are you doing?
No, watch the path!
Watch the path!
Watch the...
Please, please, please.
No, no, wait.
No, no, no! Oh, no!
OPTIMUS: Oops.
Sorry. My bad.
Oh, I... You couldn't...
You couldn't wait for five...
You couldn't wait
for five minutes?
I told you to just stay!
Just stay! God!
I told you to watch them.
I told you.
Okay, you know what?
They seem to be
in a little bit of a rush.
(BARKING)
Oh, this is bad. No!
Mojo, Mojo!
Off the robot! God!
Oh, wet.
No, no, no, no, no!
Easy! Easy!
Hold on! Hold!
This is Mojo.
He's a pet of mine.
He's a pet. Okay?
That's all.
If you could just
put the guns away...
Put the...
Put them away. Please.
IRONHIDE: You have
a rodent infestation.
A what?
Shall I terminate?
No, no, no, no.
He's not a rodent,
he's a Chihuahua.
This is my...
This is my Chihuahua.
We love Chihuahuas!
Don't we?
He's leaked lubricants
all over my foot.
He peed on you?
Bad Mojo. Bad Mojo!
Bad Mojo!
I'm sorry. He's got
a male dominance thing.
That's all it is.
My foot's gonna rust.
All right.
Okay, okay.
(SHUSHING)
Shut up and go hide!
Just hurry.
Autobots, recon.
RON: I hope he's okay.
He's in the kitchen.
Got some ice on his nose.
I had to slap him
around a little bit.
You did not.
You didn't even
ground him.
Almost, almost.
Where are they?
No, no, no, no, no.
Come on, come on.
SAM: What? What is this?
OPTIMUS: Time is short.
They really
want those glasses.
Come on.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna help you.
Okay.
Please hurry.
SAM: Okay.
Yeah, no, no.
It's definitely gone.
What do you mean?
My glasses
were in the bag.
They were in the backpack
and now the backpack isn't here.
Well, they're gonna be pissed,
so what do you wanna do?
So what I think you should do
is you should...
You should check this whole...
This whole section here.
Just give it a clean sweep,
and I'll get the corner here.
Yeah, no, no, no.
Not there. That's my...
That's my private...
Sorry. That's nothing.
You just...
You just told me to look...
I know, but I didn't
mean to look inside
of my treasure chest.
MIKAELA: You should be way
more specific so I don't get
in trouble in your room.
I'm already
stressed out enough.
SAM: Okay. What now?
No. No, no. No, no, no.
This isn't hiding.
This is my backyard,
not a truck stop.
Oh, God. Oh!
Okay, I saw it. The UFO landed
right here and now it's gone.
My moped's under there, man!
Who's gonna pay for that?
Sam? Sam, Sam, Sam, Sam.
He's back here.
I can't deal with this.
I can't...
What? Oh, no, no, no.
This is my mother's flower...
Oops.
Okay, listen.
You got to listen to me.
If my parents
come out here and see you,
they're gonna freak out.
My mother's
got a temper, okay?
We must have the glasses.
I know you need the glasses.
I've been looking everywhere.
They're not here.
They're definitely not here.
Keep searching.
I need you to be quiet
for five minutes.
Ten minutes. Okay?
Please, I'm begging you.
You got to...
You're making a racket.
I can't concentrate.
You want me to look
and I'm hearing...
Calm down, calm down.
You got to do something here.
Autobots, fall back.
Thank you.
Please, for five minutes.
Good? Good? Okay.
Move!
Get away!
What's the matter with you?
Can't you be quiet?
He wants us to be quiet.
Earthquake! Move, move,
move, move, move! Earthquake!
Judy! Judy, get under
the table! Move it!
Duck and cover right now!
How did you get
over there so fast?
Wow! That was tingly!
You got to try that!
Yeah, that looks fun.
RON: Sam?
JUDY: Sammy?
What the hell is that?
I don't know.
Sam?
That's weird.
Sam!
OPTIMUS: Ratchet,
point the light.
Come on, hurry.
SAM: Listen, we got
a major issue in here.
What's with the light?
You gotta stop the light.
What's going on? Turn it off.
You gotta tell him
to shut it off.
Shut it off.
RON: Sam, are you in there?
How come the door's locked?
You know the rules.
No doors locked in my house!
You know
he'll start counting
if you don't open the door!
One more chance. Five... four
Oh, dear.
It's coming off the hinges, pal.
He's counting!
Sam, just open the door.
Three.
Oh, my.
Two.
He's counting.
Stand back.
What's up?
What's with the bat?
RON: Who were you
talking to?
I'm talking to you.
JUDY: Why are you
so sweaty and filthy?
I'm a child.
You know, I'm a teenager.
We heard voices and noises and
we thought maybe you were...
It doesn't matter what we
thought. What was that light?
No, what light? What?
There's no light, Dad!
There's no light!
You got two lights
in your hand!
That's what it is.
Maybe it bounced...
There was light
under the door.
Look, you can't...
You can't just bounce
into my room like that.
You got to knock.
You got to communicate.
We knocked for five minutes.
I'm a teenager.
We knocked.
You didn't knock.
You were screaming
at me, okay?
No.
This is repression,
what you're doing here.
You're ruining my youth, okay?
Oh, for Pete's sakes!
You are so defensive!
Were you masturbating?
Judy.
Was I...
No, Mom.
Zip it, okay?
It's okay.
No, I don't masturbate!
That's not something
for you to bring up.
That's a father-and-son
thing, okay?
Father-son thing.
I mean, you don't have
to call it that word
if that makes you
uncomfortable.
You can call it
Sam's happy time or...
Happy time?
...my special alone time...
Stop.
Mom.
Judy, stop.
...with myself.
Mom, you can't come in and...
I'm sorry.
It's just been a weird night.
I've had
a little bit to drink.
No, no, Dad.
Yeah, well, we saw a light.
Oh, parents.
I don't know where it was,
but we saw it.
Earthquake! It's another one!
Another earthquake!
Get in the doorway!
JUDY: Okay!
Aftershock! Aftershock!
Oh, I hate these.
Got to ride it out.
Ride it out!
Quick, hide.
JUDY: Hey, the lights
are back on.
Hide? What?
Where?
Come on, get out of that tub.
RON: Can't you take
safety seriously?
Good Lord, this floor
is filthy, Sam.
Oh, oh, man! Man. Oh.
Oh, no! Look at the yard.
The yard is destroyed.
Judy? Better call the city.
We got a blown transformer!
Power pole's sparking
all over the place!
Oh, man. Yard's a waste.
Trashed. Gone.
It's a wash.
The whole yard.
JUDY: You're kidding.
The parents
are very irritating.
RATCHET: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Can I take them out?
Ironhide, you know
we don't harm humans.
What is with you?
Well, I'm just saying
we could. It's an option.
We heard you talking
to somebody, Sam.
We wanna know who.
Mom, I told...
Hi. I'm Mikaela.
I'm a...
I'm a friend of Sam's.
Gosh, you're gorgeous.
Isn't that the prettiest girl?
She can hear you
talking, Mom.
Thank you.
Oh, my goodness.
I'm sorry you had to hear
our little family discussion
about...
RON: Sorry that
we're bugging you.
Do you have my backpack?
Come on, hon. Let's go.
Oh, it's in the kitchen.
AWW MAN.
[ Male Announcer ] RETURNS
ARE EASY WITH FREE PICKUP
FROM THE U.S. POSTAL SERVICE.
WE'LL EVEN DROP OFF BOXES
IF YOU NEED THEM.
VISIT USPS.COM
PAY, PRINT,
AND HAVE IT PICKED UP FOR FREE.
ANY TIME OF YEAR.
♪
NICE SWEATER.
THANK YOU.
♪
FAMILY PARTY IN FIFTEEN.
OK LET'S DO IT!
[ Female Announcer ] IT'S
THE HOLIDAY SALE AT PAYLESS.
GRAB ALL THE STYLES YOU NEED
IN A FLASH
AT FESTIVELY LOW PRICES.
RIGHT NOW AT PAYLESS.
GHIRARDELLI SQUARES
PEPPERMINT BARK.ZVOUS ♪
RICH CHOCOLATE LAYERS AND
FESTIVE PEPPERMINT.
A GHIRARDELLI ORIGINAL.
♪ A LITTLE REWARD FOR ALL THE
THINGS YOU DO ♪
GET THEM
BEFORE THEY DISAPPEAR.
OUT FOR DRINKS, EATS.
I HAVE
VERY WELL FITTING DENTURES.
I LIKE TO EAT A LOT OF FRUITS.
LOVE THEM ALL.
THE SEAL I GET
WITH THE SUPER POLIGRIP FREE
KEEPS THE SEEDS
FROM GETTING UP UNDERNEATH.
EVEN WELL-FITTING DENTURES
LET IN FOOD PARTICLES.
SUPER POLIGRIP IS ZINC FREE.
WITH JUST A FEW DABS,
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO SEAL OUT MORE FOOD PARTICLES
SO YOU'RE MORE COMFORTABLE
AND CONFIDENT WHILE YOU EAT.
A LOT OF THINGS
GOING ON IN MY LIFE
AND THE LAST THING
I WANT TO BE THINKING ABOUT
IS MY DENTURES.
[ Charlie ]
TRY ZINC FREE SUPER POLIGRIP.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
GET $100 OFF ANY 4G LTE TABLET
WHEN YOU BUY ANY SMARTPHONE.
AND GET A TABLET DATA PLAN
STARTING AT JUST $10/MO.
NO SHARING REQUIRED.
HURRY INTO A Sprint STORE
OR VISIT sprint.com/tabletoffer
TODAY.
SHE'S NOT FAMOUS.
♪
SHE'S NEVER BEEN
ON A RED CARPET.
♪
BUT SHE'S THE STAR OF MY LIFE.
[ Female Announcer ]
KAY JEWELERS PRESENTS
A NEW COLLECTION
FROM HOLLYWOOD'S
PREMIER JEWELRY DESIGNER --
NEIL LANE DESIGNS.
MY DESIGNS ARE INSPIRED
BY HOLLYWOOD'S GLAMOROUS PAST.
[ Female Announcer ]
HAND-CRAFTED DIAMOND RINGS,
EARRINGS, AND NECKLACES
WITH A VINTAGE LOOK.
AT KAY, THE NUMBER-ONE
JEWELRY STORE IN AMERICA.
FOR THE STAR IN YOUR LIFE.
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
Mommy! I went potty!
That's great, honey....
Where?
For life's bleachable moments.
Oh, yes. Okay. Okay.
Yeah.
Your mom's so nice.
I want you to distract
my parents
while I slip out and get
these glasses to them, okay?
(DOORBELL RINGING INCESSANTLY)
Ronald Wickity?
It's Witwicky. Who are you?
We're the government.
Sector Seven.
Never heard of it.
Never will.
Your son's the great-grandson
of Captain Archibald Wickity,
is he not?
It's Witwicky.
May I enter the premises, sir?
Ron, there's guys
all over the front yard.
What the heck
is going on here?
Your son filed a stolen
car report last night.
We think it's involved in
a national security matter.
JUDY: They're ripping up
my rose bushes!
National security?
That's right.
National security.
My God, Ron,
they're everywhere.
There's guys in suits
all around the house!
Look at this!
Could you stay
off the grass?
Get me a sample
and some isotope readings.
They're pulling bushes out
of the ground!
Good Lord! They've got to get
their hands off my bush!
Drop the bat, ma'am.
Hey, hey, hey,
that's my...
I'm carrying
a loaded weapon.
But you'd better get those
guys out of my garden
or I am gonna beat the crap
out of them!
Are you experiencing
any flu-like symptoms?
Aching joints? Fever?
JUDY: No!
What is this?
How you doing, son?
Is your name Sam?
Yeah.
Well, I need you
to come with us.
Whoa, way out of line.
Sir, I am asking politely.
Back off.
You're not taking my son.
Really?
You gonna try to get
rough with us?
No, but I'm gonna
call the cops
because there's something
fishy going on around here.
Yeah. There's something
a little fishy about you,
your son,
your little Taco Bell dog
and this whole operation
you got going on here.
What operation?
That is what
we are gonna find out.
I think direct contact.
Son?
SAM: Yeah.
Step forward, please.
Just stand?
(MACHINE BEEPING)
Fourteen rads.
Bingo! Tag them and bag them!
If you hurt my dog,
I'll kick your ass!
SIMMONS: Get me a sample on
that vegetation ASAP!
RON: Sam!
Do not say anything, Sam!
Yeah.
Not a word
until we get a lawyer!
So,
LadiesMan217.
That is your eBay
username, right?
Yeah, but, you know,
it was a typo
and I ran with it.
What do you make of this?
My name is Sam Witwicky, okay?
And my...
Is that you?
Yeah, that sounds
like LadiesMan.
Last night at the station,
you told the officer
your car transformed.
Enlighten me.
Well, here's what
I said, okay?
'Cause this is
a total misunderstanding
that my car had been stolen...
Really?
...from me, from my home,
but it's fine now because
it's back! It came back!
Well, not by itself.
Well, no.
Because cars don't do that
because that would be crazy.
(ALL LAUGHING)
That's funny.
That is so funny.
So what do you kids
know about aliens, huh?
Oh, you mean, like a Martian?
Like what, E.T.? No.
It's an urban legend.
Yeah.
You see this?
This is an I-can-do-
whatever-I-want and-
get-away-with-it badge.
Right.
I'm gonna lock you up forever.
Oh, God. You know what?
Don't listen to him.
He's just pissy
'cause he's got to get back
to guarding the mall.
You, in the training bra,
do not test me.
Especially with your daddy's
parole coming up.
What? Parole?
It's nothing.
Oh, grand theft auto,
that ain't nothing?
You know those cars
my dad used to
teach me to fix?
Well, they...
They weren't always his.
You stole cars?
Well, we couldn't always
afford a babysitter,
so sometimes he had
to take me along.
She's got her own juvie record
to prove it!
She's a criminal.
Criminals are hot.
That'd be a real shame
if he had to rot in jail
the rest of his natural life.
It is time to talk!
Big! It's big!
(ALL SCREAMING)
Go, go, go, go!
I can't see it!
Shift your weight
towards the front!
All right! All right!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
You in trouble now.
Gentlemen, I want to
introduce you to my friend,
Optimus Prime.
OPTIMUS: Taking the children
was a bad move.
Autobots, relieve them
of their weapons.
Freeze!
Whoa! Whoa!
Give me those!
Whoa!
Hi, there.
You don't seem afraid. Are you
not surprised to see us?
Look, there are
S-Seven protocols, okay?
I'm not authorized
to communicate with you
except to tell you
I can't communicate with you.
Get out of the car.
All right.
Me? You want me to get...
Now!
All right, all right.
Get out. Hey.
All right, I'm...
I'm getting out.
I'm getting out. You see?
Very nifty how you put us down
without really killing us.
You're good with handcuffs,
too, now, huh?
SIMMONS: How you doing?
You weren't supposed
to hear all that.
Yeah.
This is real.
Now, listen. If I choose
to engage with him,
mum is the word, all right?
Sam, I have a record because
I wouldn't turn my dad in.
When have you had to
sacrifice anything
in your perfect little life?
Big guys. Big guys
with big guns, huh?
What is Sector Seven?
Answer me.
I'm the one who asks
questions around here.
Not you, young man!
How'd yoknow
about the aliens?
Where did you
take my parents?
I am not at liberty
to discuss it.
No?
Hey. You touch me,
that's a federal offense.
Do-whatever-you-want and-
get-away-with-it badge, right?
Yeah. Brave now
all of a sudden,
with his big alien friend
standing over there.
Where is Sector Seven?
Wouldn't you like to know?
All right, tough guy,
take it off.
What are you
talking about?
Your clothes,
all of it, off.
For what?
For threatening my dad.
Little lady,
this is the beginning
of the end of your life.
You're a criminal.
Let's face facts.
It's in your gene pool.
Those are nice.
Now get behind the pole.
This is such a felony,
what you're doing.
I will hunt you down, okay?
He'll hunt you down.
Without any remorse!
No remorse.
Enjoy.
Okay?
We have got
to alert everyone.
They already know.
Speaker.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
DISCOVER THE TEMPTING LAYERS
OF FERRERO ROCHER.
A WHOLE HAZELNUT,
SMOOTH CHOCOLATY CREAM
INSIDE A WAFER SHELL,
COVERED IN MILK CHOCOLATE
AND HAZELNUT PIECES.
♪
FERRERO ROCHER.
MAKE YOUR MOMENTS GOLDEN.
[ GPS ] HELLO DAVE.
OH, NOT AGAIN.
[ GPS ] DAVE, DO YOU KNOW WHERE
YOUR WIFE WENT LAST WEEK?
SHE WENT TO JARED TO LOOK AT
A BEAUTIFUL DIAMOND NECKLACE.
I'M NOT GOING TO
THE CLEANERS ANYMORE, AM I?
[ GPS ] NO DAVE, YOU'RE NOT.
[ wheels screech ]
RIGHT TURN.
[ engine revs ]
[ Male Announcer ]
JARED THE GALLERIA OF JEWELRY
HAS FIVE TIMES THE SELECTION
OF ORDINARY JEWELRY STORES...
SO YOU'LL FIND
THE PERFECT GIFT EVERY TIME.
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
WHO KNOWS YOU LIKE I DO?
[ horn honks ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THAT'S WHY HE WENT TO JARED,
THE GALLERIA OF JEWELRY.
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE LOVES TO DUNK.
♪
[ Game announcer ]
WILL HE DUNK IT?
YES, HE WILL.
[ Male Announcer ] McDonald's
TENDER, JUICY Chicken McNuggets
IN CREAMY RANCH
AND SPICY BUFFALO SAUCE.
JUST $4.99
FOR 20 OF YOUR FAVORITE
Chicken McNuggets.
♪
[ Game announcer ]
WILL HE DUNK IT?
YES, HE WILL.
[ Male Announcer ]
MORE WAYS TO LOVE McNuggets.
♪
TIME FOR CITI PRICE REWIND.
BECAUSE YOUR DAUGHTER REALLY
WANTS THAT PINK CASTLE THING.
AND YOU REALLY DON'T WANT
TO PAY MORE THAN YOU HAVE TO.
ONLY CITI PRICE REWIND
AUTOMATICALLY SEARCHES
FOR THE LOWEST PRICE.
AND IF IT FINDS ONE, YOU GET
REFUNDED THE DIFFERENCE.
JUST USE YOUR CITI CARD
AND REGISTER YOUR PURCHASE
ONLINE.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
OK.
[ Male Announcer ] NOW ALL
YOU NEED IS A MAGIC CARRIAGE.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
START SAVING
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
We need to leave our contract
Doug's family doesn't have that.
You could have any of these
top smartphones
at half the cost of our plan.
You aren't bad parents.
You just fell in with the wrong
wireless plan.
Welcome to the next generation
of family plans.
Visit Net10Wireless.com.
Roll out.
PILOT 1: Okay, I'm picking up
rad readings under that
bridge right down there.
(SIRENS BLARING)
Okay, I'm getting
really good rad readings.
Forty-two and higher.
Up you get.
PILOT 2: Okay,
we're dropping in.
Really strong readings
right down below us.
There he is.
Ship one and two,
come on in.
That's it, right there.
Mark him, mark him.
Okay, there he is. 11:30.
11:30. Right off the nose.
I got it. 12:00.
Okay, I'm tracking him.
I've got him.
Got him going
down the street.
Okay. Where'd he go, guys?
I lost him.
Got no IR signature.
Where'd he go?
Okay, I lost him.
I lost him.
Okay, we're coming around.
OPTIMUS: Easy, you two.
No! No! No, Sam!
Sam, don't drop me!
Sam, don't! Sam, don't!
I'm slipping! I'm slipping!
OPTIMUS: Hold on!
No!
I got you!
Sam!
All right,
we've got him pinned.
We've got him pinned
in the river.
I'm in for the shot.
Stop! Stop!
Wait! No!
Take the shot, get him.
Take the shot.
No!
(GROANING)
No! Stop!
AGENT: Get down on the ground!
Get down! Get down!
What? Okay.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Look, he's not
fighting back!
COMMANDO 1: Freeze it!
Freeze it! Freeze it!
Stop hurting him!
COMMANDO 2:
Don't let him move!
I got him here!
(WHIMPERING)
No!
Happy to see me again?
Put him in a car with his
little criminal friend.
I want that thing frozen
and ready for transport!
JAZZ: Hang back.
Let me check it out.
Optimus,
are we just gonna stand here
and do nothing?
OPTIMUS: There's no way
to free Bumblebee
without harming the humans.
But it's not right. He...
Let them leave.
The Chinese and the Russians
are nearing our area
of operations
in the western Pacific.
We feel like this could get
out of hand real fast.
But the next couple of hours
may just define
his presidency.
US and Chinese task forces
approaching 100 nautical miles
of cruise missile range.
Tell the strike
group commander
that he's not to engage
unless fired on first.
Yes, sir!
Mr. Secretary?
Tom Banachek.
I'm with Sector Seven,
Advanced Research Division.
Never heard of it.
I'm a little busy, Tom.
I think you can see that.
What's going on here?
I don't know.
Sit rep! Talk to me!
The whole room's
gone down, sir.
I can see that!
The virus was coded
to shut us down.
General?
I'll take a seat.
What do you mean,
"shut us down"?
They used our network to
spread out to the whole world.
The blackout's global.
We have no communications,
satellite and land lines
are dead.
You mean to tell me that I
cannot pick up this telephone
and call my family?
(DEAD TONE)
Mr. Secretary? I'm here
under direct order
from the President.
You really need to see
what I have in the case.
BANACHEK: You'll have
to accept that
there are certain things
you won't understand
right away.
Sector Seven
is a special-access
division of the government
convened in secret under
President Hoover 80 years ago.
You may remember NASA JPL
lost the Beagle 2 Mars Rover.
We told them to report
the mission a complete failure.
It wasn't.
Beagle 2 transmitted
13 seconds.
This was classified
above top secret.
MAN: EDA ended at 170 hours,
48 minutes.
More than just a pile
of Martian rocks.
This is the image from Mars.
Here's the image
your Special Ops team
was able to retrieve
from the base attack.
We believe they are of
the same exoskeletal type,
and obviously not Russian
or North Korean.
Are we talking about
an invasion?
We intercepted the message
from your Special Ops team.
These things can be
hurt by our weapons
and now they know it.
That's why the virus
shut us down,
so we can't coordinate
against their next attack,
which I would bet my
ridiculous government salary
is coming soon.
Get word to our
fleet commanders over
the National Guard frequency.
It's a shortwave
radio channel.
It might be still working.
Tell them to turn their ships
around and come home. ASAP!
And inform all commands to
prepare for imminent attack.
♪
I MUST HAVE
THE WRONG HOUSE.
SISTER?
WE MISSED YOU.
THEY WAITED UP ALL NIGHT
FOR YOU, YOU KNOW.
IT'S A LONG WAY
FROM WEST AFRICA.
AHH...COFFEE.
[ inhales deeply ]
HE'S HERE.
I BROUGHT YOU SOMETHING.
[ chuckles ]
REALLY?
♪
[ chuckles ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU'RE MY PRESENT
THIS YEAR.
♪ THE BEST PART OF WAKIN' UP
♪ IS FOLGERS IN YOUR CUP
TO PRACTICE MATH
MORE?
I LOVE MATH!
BUT TWO iPADS
MEANS TWO DATA PLANS?
THAT'S CRAZY.
MAYBE NOT.
WITH AT&T MOBILE SHARE,
ADDING AN iPAD
IS JUST $10 A MONTH.
BUT HONESTLY, MOM AND DAD'S LOVE
IS ALL I REALLY NEED.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE
FOR US.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE.
WHAT?!
[ Male Announcer ]
AT&T MOBILE SHARE.
ADD AN iPAD
FOR JUST $10 A MONTH.
ONE PLAN. UP TO 10 DEVICES.
AT&T. RETHINK POSSIBLE.
Even though our mom tries,
she doesn't really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
They're so awesome!
Wow!
Yeahhhh!
Thank you!
Who's your mommy now?
It's a
Christmas miracle.
Give Victoriously.
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
I'M GOING TO DREAM
ABOUT THAT STEAK.
ABOUT THAT TIRAMISU.
WHAT A NIGHT, HUH?
BUT, UM, CAN THE TEST DRIVE
BE OVER NOW?
HEAD BACK
TO THE DEALERSHIP?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S PRACTICALLY YOURS.
BUT WE STILL NEED
YOUR SIGNATURE.
VOLKSWAGEN SIGN THEN DRIVE
IS BACK.
AND IT'S NEVER BEEN EASIER
TO GET A PASSAT.
THAT'S THE POWER
OF GERMAN ENGINEERING.
GET $0 DOWN, $0 DUE AT SIGNING,
$0 DEPOSIT,
AND $0 FIRST MONTH'S PAYMENT
ON ANY NEW VOLKSWAGEN.
VISIT VWDEALER.COM TODAY.
TO DECORATE YOUR HOME
LAST CHRISTMAS?
AROUND THE FIRE PLACE.
I HAVE NO IDEA.
GOING UP THE STAIRS.
HOW DO YOU FIGURE THAT OUT?
SPOOLS AND SPOOLS!
WE DON'T KNOW
EXACTLY HOW MUCH GARLAND.
DON'T WORRY,
MYLOWE'S AUTOMATICALLY TRACKS
AND STORES
ALL OF YOUR LOWE'S PURCHASES
SO YOU CAN GET THAT SAME
GREAT LOOK AGAIN THIS YEAR.
I THINK IT'S WONDERFUL.
YEA, THAT IS AWESOME.
YAY!
[ Male Announcer ]
WE SCAN.
MYLOWE'S REMEMBERS.
YOUR LIFE GETS EASIER.
MYLOWE'S, SIGN UP
IN YOUR LOWE'S STORE TODAY.
LOWE'S.
NEVER STOP IMPROVING.
MYLOWE'S, SIGN UP
IN YOUR LOWE'S STORE TODAY.
Online Outfit
Piccolo
Headphones
Buy Now
Broadway Show
Megapixels
Place to Sleep
Little Roadster
War and Peace
Deep Sea Diving
Ninja App
Hipster Glasses
5% cash back
Sign up to get 5% everywhere
online through December. Only
from Discover.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
[ sigh of relief ]
Captain Lennox,
we need you and your team
to come with us right now!
Let's go!
She's in here.
What's going on?
You're coming with me.
You're going to be my advisor.
Me, too?
Who's this?
He's my advisor.
He comes, too.
So...
What'd they get you for?
I bought a car.
Turned out to be
an alien robot.
Wow.
Who knew?
(BUMBLEBEE GROANING)
COMMANDO: Make a hole!
Watch your back!
Please, let this work.
Fire it up, Optimus.
The code.
The code on these glasses
indicates the All Spark
is 230 miles from here.
I sense the Decepticons
are getting ready to mobilize.
They must know it's here,
as well.
What about Bumblebee?
We can't just
leave him to die
and become some
human experiment!
OPTIMUS: He'll die in vain
if we don't accomplish
our mission.
Bumblebee is a brave soldier.
This is what he would want.
Why are we fighting
to save the humans?
They're a primitive
and violent race.
Were we so different?
They're a young species.
They have much to learn.
But I've seen
goodness in them.
Freedom is the right
of all sentient beings.
You all know there's only
one way to end this war.
We must destroy the Cube.
If all else fails,
I will unite it with
the spark in my chest.
That's suicide.
The Cube is raw power.
It could destroy you both.
A necessary sacrifice to bring
peace to this planet.
We cannot let the humans
pay for our mistakes.
It's been an honor
serving with you all.
Autobots, roll out!
We rolling!
(CHATTERING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
EPPS: Team attention!
Present arms!
At ease. Captain, Sergeant.
Got your intel.
Excellent work.
Thank you, sir.
What about the gunships?
They're being retrofitted
with sabot rounds now.
If they hit us again,
we'll be ready for them.
But it won't do us much good
if we can't get
world communications back up.
Hey, kid.
I think we got off
to a bad start, huh?
You must be hungry?
You want a latte? HoHo?
Double venti macchiato?
Where's my car?
Son, I need you to
listen to me very carefully.
People can die here.
We need to know
everything you know.
We need to know it now.
Okay.
But first, I'll take my car,
my parents.
Maybe you should
write that down.
Oh, and her juvie record.
That's got to be gone.
Like, forever.
Come with me.
We'll talk about your car.
Thank you.
The man's an extortionist.
SIMMONS: All right,
here's the situation.
You've all had direct contact
with the NBEs.
NBEs?
Non-Biological
Extraterrestrials.
Try and keep up
with the acronyms.
What you're about to see
is totally classified.
Dear God. What is this?
BANACHEK: We think when
he made his approach
over the north pole,
our gravitational field
screwed up his telemetry.
He crashed in the ice,
probably a few
thousand years ago.
We shipped him here
to this facility in 1934.
SIMMONS: We call him NBE One.
SAM: Well, sir, I don't mean
to correct you on everything
you think you know,
but, I mean,
that's Megatron.
He's the leader
of the Decepticons.
He's been in cryostasis
since 1935.
Your great-great-grandfather
made one of
the greatest discoveries
in the history of mankind.
Fact is, you're looking at
the source of the modern age,
the microchip, lasers,
spaceflight, cars,
all reverse-engineered
by studying him.
NBE One.
That's what we call it.
And you didn't think
the United States military
might need to know
that you're keeping
a hostile alien robot
frozen in the basement?
Until these events,
we had no credible threat
to national security.
Well, you got one now.
So why Earth?
SAM: It's the All Spark.
All Spark? What is that?
Well, yeah, they came here
looking for some sort of
cube-looking thing.
Anyway, Mr. NBE One here,
AKA Megatron,
that's what they call him,
who's pretty much
the harbinger of death,
wants to use the Cube
to transform human technology
to take over the universe.
That's their plan.
And you're sure about that?
Yeah.
You guys know
where it is, don't you?
Follow me.
SIMMONS: You're about to see
our crown jewel.
TOM: Carbon dating
puts the Cube here
around 10,000 BC.
The first Seven
didn't find it until 1913.
They knew it was alien
because of the matching
hieroglyphics on the Cube
as well as NBE One.
President Hoover had
the dam built around it.
Four football fields
thick of concrete.
A perfect way to hide
its energy from being
detected by anyone
or any alien species
on the outside.
(IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
Wait, back up.
You said the dam
hides the Cube's energy.
What kind exactly?
TOM: Good question.
Please step inside.
They have to lock us in.
Oh, wow.
What's that? Freddy Krueger
done been up in here
or something?
Oh, no, man.
Freddy Krueger
have four blades, man.
(SNARLS)
That's only three.
That's Wolverine!
Right? That's Wolverine!
That's very funny.
Anybody have any
mechanical devices?
BlackBerry? Key alarm?
Cell phone?
I got a phone.
SIMMONS: We're able to take
the Cube radiation
and funnel it into that box.
Mean little sucker, huh?
That thing is freaky!
Kind of like the itty-bitty
Energizer Bunny
from hell, huh?
(EXCLAIMS)
He's breaking the box.
For thos...this...ions of doing
this...
...and this,
dancing in their heads...
...we have these.
Home Depot gift cards.
Give the gift of doing,
in-store or online.
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15 ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OO! THE TILAPIA
WITH ROASTED VEGETABLES!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WOOD GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
THAT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY!
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
(EXPLOSIONS)
Gentlemen, they know
the Cube is here.
Banachek. What's going on?
Well, the NBE One hangar
has lost power...
What?
...and the backup generator
is just not gonna cut it.
Do you have an arms room?
Megatron! Megatron! Megatron!
I'll bring security to the...
Get everyone to
the NBE One chamber now!
The lights are out!
Move it! Move it!
Let's go!
They're popping
our generators!
Megatron melting!
MAN ON PA: 16502.
We're losing pressure.
Stand by! Set!
We're losing pressure!
The cryogenic system
is failing!
We're losing NBE One!
Forty millimeter sabot rounds
on that table!
SOLDIER: That's good.
Get all the ammo you got.
Everything you can carry.
Bring it.
(RUMBLING)
You got to take me to my car.
You have to take me to my car.
He's gonna know what to do
with the Cube.
Your car?
It's confiscated.
Then unconfiscate it.
We do not know
what will happen
if we let it near this thing!
You don't know.
Maybe you know,
but I don't know.
You just wanna sit here
and wait and see what happens?
I have people's lives
at stake here, young man.
Take him to his car!
Drop it.
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Drop your weapon, soldier.
There's an alien war going on
and you're gonna shoot me?
You know,
we didn't ask to be here.
I'm ordering you under S-Seven
executive jurisdiction.
S-Seven don't exist.
Right.
And we don't take orders
from people that don't exist.
I'm gonna count to five.
I'm gonna count to three.
KELLER: Simmons?
Yes, sir?
I'd do what he says.
Losing's really not an option
for these guys.
All right. Okay.
Hey, you want to lay
the fate of the world
on the kid's Camaro?
That's cool.
SAM: No, no!
Stop! You got to stop!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
No, no, stop, stop, stop!
Let him go! Let him go!
Are you okay?
They didn't hurt you, right?
Listen to me.
The Cube is here
and the Decepticons
are coming.
No, no, don't worry
about them.
They're okay. Right?
They're not gonna hurt you.
Just back up a little bit.
He's friendly. He's fine.
Okay, come on.
Put the guns down.
They're not gonna hurt you.
Here, come with me. I'm gonna
take you to the All Spark.
Okay, here we go.
He doing something.
Oh, my God.
WOMAN: Message from Starfleet,
Captain.
MAN: Let's get to it.
He's right. We stay here,
we're screwed with Megatron
in the other hangar.
Mission City is 22 miles away.
We're gonna sneak that Cube
out of here
and we're gonna hide it
somewhere in the city.
Good! Right.
But we cannot make a stand
without the Air Force.
This place must have
some kind of radio link!
Yes. Shortwave, CB.
Right, yes.
Sir, you got to figure out
some way to get word
out to them. Let's move!
In the alien archive, sir!
The alien...
There's an old
Army radio console.
Will it work?
Anything's possible!
Did you see that...
LENNOX: All right, Sam,
get it in the car!
Mr. Secretary!
Get our birds in the air.
When we get to the city,
we're gonna find a radio,
and I'll have Epps
vector them in, okay?
KELLER: Affirmative!
MAN ON PA: Warning! NBE One
cryo-containment failing.
Check that backup system!
MAN: The cryo's failing!
You got to bump up the cryo!
The cryo's failing!
MAN 2: Come on!
Get out of here!
Heads up! Look out!
Set a perimeter around
the yellow vehicle!
This way, this way,
this way!
Up there! Let's go!
(ROARING)
I am Megatron!
(ALL SCREAMING)
SAM: The Cube's okay?
Yeah, it's fine.
Well, put the seat belt on.
Pour it on him!
STARSCREAM: I live to
serve you, Lord Megatron.
Where is the Cube?
The humans have taken it.
You fail me yet again,
Starscream. Get them!
GLEN: Come on, Mags!
Over here, sir!
Give me a minute.
Come to me, Maxwell,
come to me. Plugged in there.
We're hot! We're live!
Where are the mikes?
Mikes?
This doesn't work
without mikes, Simmons.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
KELLER: Let's find them.
Kid, get in the chair!
Just get in the chair,
all right?
Okay, I'll sit. I'll sit.
They steal everything
out of this place.
How do we get the signal out?
How do we call the Air Force?
Glen?
Huh?
Can you hotwire this computer
to transmit a tone
through the radio?
What good is that?
Morse code!
You can use this
to transmit it through that!
Okay, I'll do it!
Turn it around.
Okay, let's see.
Simmons, I need a screwdriver!
(TRUCK HORN BLOWING)
There's Optimus.
GLEN: Almost done.
(CLANGING)
What the hell was that?
Barricade the door!
(GRUNTING)
KELLER: Get something.
Watch out!
Six, five, four, six, three.
Here! Put some rounds in!
Master search.
I got it! We're transmitting!
Send exactly what I say!
Get out of the way!
Burn, you little sucker! Burn!
"This is Defense
Secretary Keller."
Uh-huh.
"Get me NORTHCOM commander."
Whoa!
What was that?
Authenticate emergency action.
Blackbird 1195...
Sir, I have an authenticated
air strike order from Sec Def.
(SIREN BLARING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
No, no, no, no, no.
What?
It's the same cop! Block them,
block them, block them.
(GRUNTING)
Oh, my God.
Cool, Mom!
(ROARING)
I made the clear choice.
I'm getting Claritin Clear
with Claritin-D.
Nasal congestion keep me away ?
Not since I made
the clear choice.
Non-drowsy Claritin-D.
Decongestant products on
the shelf can take hours
to start working.
Claritin-D starts to work
in just 30 minutes.
I can't wait hours for
a nasal decongestant.
That's why I made the clear
choice and got Claritin-D.
It has the best
decongestant for colds.
This cold season, get Claritin-D
at the pharmacy counter.
Live Claritin Clear.
♪
[ chirping ]
[ bleating ]
[ meowing, barking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
UNLIMITED PHONE...
UNLIMITED DATA...
UNLIMITED GIFTS OF JOY.
BUY ONE SAMSUNG GALAXY PHONE...
GET THE SAME MODEL FREE.
VISIT A SPRINT STORE
OR SPRINT.COM/HOLIDAY TODAY.
FAMILY PARTY IN FIFTEEN.
OK LET'S DO IT!
[ Female Announcer ] IT'S
THE HOLIDAY SALE AT PAYLESS.
GRAB ALL THE STYLES YOU NEED
IN A FLASH
AT FESTIVELY LOW PRICES.
RIGHT NOW AT PAYLESS.
This is so not good.
(SCREAMS)
He's behind the pillar!
Maggie, cover fire!
GLEN: It's the Air Force!
They're responding!
Sucker, burn!
(EXCLAIMS)
Yes! They're sending
F-22s to the city!
PILOT ON RADIO:
Raptors, let's scramble,
scramble, scramble.
PILOT 2: Strike and Dark Star
roll call.
PILOT 3: Looking out
the right side.
PILOT 4:
Push to Kill Box One Alpha...
Come on, let's go! Mount up!
SOLDIER: Move out!
Move out! Go! Go!
Here, I got shortwave radios.
Wait. What am I
supposed to do with these?
Well, use them!
It's all we got!
EPPS: This is like
RadioShack dinosaur radios
or something, man.
I'm only gonna get 20 or
30 miles out of these things.
Are there any aircraft
orbiting the city?
F-22 at 12:00.
I want planes for air cover and
get Black Hawks on station
to extract that Cube.
You got it?
Air Force has arrived!
Pop smoke!
Raptor, Raptor, do you copy?
EPPS: We have you visual.
Green smoke is the mark.
Provide air cover and vector
Black Hawks for extraction.
It's Starscream!
Please tell me you copy.
Back up! Take cover!
Bumblebee!
No, no, no, no, no! Move!
Back up! Back up!
LENNOX: Retreat! Fall back!
IRONHIDE: Incoming!
(GRUNTING)
LENNOX: Anybody hurt?
Everyone okay?
SOLDIER: Clear the area!
(BUMBLEBEE GROANING)
SAM: Oh, my God.
Bumblebee? No. Your legs!
Your legs.
Here. Here, back, back,
back, back! You all right?
Please get up.
Bumblebee? Get up!
Ratchet!
What the hell was that?
What are you talking about?
What do you mean,
what am I talking about?
They shot at us!
F-22 pilots would never
fly below buildings.
That's alien.
That ain't friendly!
You got to get up.
You're okay. You're okay.
Come on!
PILOT: Army Black Hawk inbound
to your location. Over.
Alpha 273 degrees, 10 miles.
November Victor,
1.2 clicks north.
(TANK FIRING)
Move out! Let's go!
SOLDIER: Let's go! Move!
I'm not gonna leave you.
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
Come on, Decepticon punk!
Oh, my God!
Concentrate your fire!
Come on. Come on.
Megatron!
(SPEAKING IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
OPTIMUS: It's Megatron!
Retreat! Move! Fall back!
Fall back!
(JAZZ GROANING)
Get our guys out of the way!
Get out of here! Go!
Get them out of the buggy!
Move out!
EPPS: We need air cover
down here now!
Sam, help me with this.
JAZZ: That all you got,
Megatron?
Come here, little cretin.
You want a piece of me?
You want a piece?
No! I want two!
LENNOX: What's going on?
Sir! That tank thing's
getting back up.
Oh, these things
just don't die.
Oh, we're so dead.
Wrap it around the head.
Sam! Where's the Cube?
Right there.
Okay.
And take that and wrap it
around the base and then put it
around his neck.
Epps, get those
Black Hawks here!
That building.
Okay.
What?
All right, I can't leave
my guys back there,
so here, take this flare.
Okay, there's a tall, white
building with statues on top.
Go to the roof.
Set the flare.
No.
Signal the chopper
and set the flare.
No, no. I can't do this!
Listen to me!
You're a soldier now!
All right? I need you
to take this Cube.
Get it into military hands
while we hold them off,
or a lot of people
are gonna die.
You got to go.
No, I'm not leaving.
You need to go. Go.
No, I'm not leaving
till I get Bumblebee
out of here, okay?
Army Black Hawk requested.
Immediate evac
for civilian boy
with precious cargo.
Headed to rooftop
marked by flare.
Sam, we will protect you.
Okay.
LENNOX: Epps,
where are those planes?
Sam!
No matter what happens,
I'm really glad I got
in that car with you.
Sam! Get to
the building! Move!
MEGATRON: Decepticons, attack!
Hit it!
RATCHET: Cover fire!
SOLDIER: Move to cover!
Watch out!
LENNOX: Girl, get that
tow truck out of here!
I'm going! I'm going!
Get out of here now!
Megatron!
Prime.
Humans don't
deserve to live.
They deserve to
choose for themselves.
Then you will die
with them!
Join them in extinction!
(GROANING)
Keep moving, Sam!
Don't stop!
No!
Sam, get to the building!
Give me that Cube, boy!
Did that jerk just
dent my car?
(SCREAMING)
HELLO?
[ Sea ] HI!
THIS IS THE SEA CALLING.
WHEN'S THE LAST TIME
YOU VISITED ME?
WHEN I WENT SURFING.
I LOVE TO SURF.
CAN YOU IMAGINE
SURFING IN THE MIDDLE OF ME?
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOU?
OH YES!
[ giggles ] NICE MOVES!
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
OUR BIGGEST DECEMBER
SALES EVENT EVER.
GOING ON NOW.
CALL 1-800-ROYAL-CARIBBEAN.
I WANT TO GET
A BIG TV
FOR MY BIG FAMILY,
FOR THE BIG HOLIDAY.
WE LIKE TO WATCH BIG GAMES.
WE GOT A BIG SPREAD TOGETHER...
SO IT'S GOTTA BE BIG.
HOW ABOUT
THE 55-INCH LG TV.
IT'S LED AND HAS
INCREDIBLE PICTURE QUALITY...
THAT'S BIG...
BUT I GOT A LITTLE BUDGET.
WITH THE WALMART CREDIT CARD
SPECIAL FINANCING
YOU CAN GO BIG
THIS YEAR.
THAT'S BIG TIME!
ALRIGHT!
[ Male Announcer ] GET
THE SEASON'S HOTTEST BRANDS,
LIKE AN LG 55-INCH LED TV.
MAKE AN ELECTRONICS PURCHASE
OF $599 OR MORE
ON YOUR WALMART CREDIT CARD
AND GET NO INTEREST IF PAID
IN FULL WITHIN 24 MONTHS.
AMERICA'S GIFT HEADQUARTERS.
WALMART.
TRUST DURACELL TO POWER
THEIR DONATED TOYS?
DURALOCK POWER PRESERVE.
IT LOCKS IN POWER
FOR UP TO 10 YEARS IN STORAGE.
GUARANTEED.
DURACELL WITH DURALOCK.
TRUSTED EVERYWHERE.
You're not gonna get me.
You're not gonna get me!
(EXCLAIMS IN ALIEN LANGUAGE)
MEGATRON: I smell you, boy!
Maggot!
(GRUNTING)
Oh, no!
(GROANING)
I'll drive! You shoot!
This isn't going well!
Shoot! Shoot!
(PANTING)
Nice shot.
SOLDIER: That tank
is definitely dead now.
LENNOX: All right, let's go!
We got business!
Hey!
Hey! I'm over here!
We've got the boy.
Watch out!
Missile!
(SHOUTING)
Hang on, Sam!
No! No!
Is it fear or courage
that compels you, fleshling?
Where do I go?
Give me the All Spark
and you may live to be my pet.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I'm never giving you
this All Spark!
Oh, so unwise.
(SCREAMING)
I got you, boy.
Hold on to the Cube!
(GRUNTING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
SAM: Oh, no. Oh, no!
Disgusting.
Sam?
You risked your life
to protect the Cube.
No sacrifice,
no victory.
If I cannot defeat Megatron,
you must push the Cube
into my chest.
I will sacrifice myself
to destroy it.
Get behind me.
It's you and me, Megatron.
No, it's just me, Prime.
OPTIMUS:
At the end of this day,
one shall stand,
one shall fall.
You still fight for the weak!
That is why you lose!
Fighter jets in 60 seconds.
We got friendlies
mixed with bad guys.
Targets will be marked.
Hey.
Bring the rain. All right?
All right,
let's kill these things.
Move, move, move!
Remember, aim low.
Armor's weak under the chest.
EPPS: Target marked.
Still waiting.
PILOT: Time on target,
20 seconds.
F-22s, we're still waiting.
Move out!
Incoming!
PILOT: Weapons armed.
Status green.
(YELLING)
Run! Move!
(GRUNTING)
Second wave's on approach.
What is that? Break off!
Copy.
It's either a massive
amount of...
Two, get a lock!
Pop that guy!
Stay on him.
Keep him in your sights.
Take him out!
Two's down!
I'll kill you!
Mine! All Spark!
Sam! Put the Cube
in my chest! Now!
Sam!
No, Sam!
Hold up.
OPTIMUS: You left me
no choice, brother.
Sam, I owe you my life.
We are in your debt.
Prime, we couldn't save him.
Aw, Jazz.
We lost a great comrade
but gained new ones.
Thank you, all of you.
You honor us
with your bravery.
Permission to speak, sir?
Permission granted,
old friend.
You speak now?
I wish to stay with the boy.
If that is his choice.
Yes.
Gentlemen, the President
has ordered Sector Seven
be terminated
and the remains of the
dead aliens disposed of.
The Laurentian Abyss is
seven miles below sea level,
deepest place on our planet.
The massive depth
and pressure there,
coupled with
subfreezing temperatures,
would crush and entomb them,
leaving no evidence.
OPTIMUS:
With the All Spark gone,
we cannot return
life to our planet.
And fate has
yielded its reward,
a new world to call home.
We live among its people now,
hiding in plain sight,
but watching over them
in secret,
waiting, protecting.
I have witnessed
their capacity for courage.
And though
we are worlds apart,
like us, there's more to them
than meets the eye.
I am Optimus Prime
and I send this message
to any surviving Autobots
taking refuge among the stars.
We are here.
We are waiting.
(WHAT I'VE DONE PLAYING)
♪ What I've done
♪ I'll face myself
♪ Erase myself
♪ And let go of what I've done
>> BREAKING NEWS, A NEIGHBORHOOD
SHUT DOWN AFTER POLICE SEARCH
FOR A SUSPECTED GUNMAN.
AB