>> BARTON ADMITS THAT GUN REFORM
MIGHT NOT HAVE BEEN ENOUGH TO
PREVENT THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY BUT
SAYS THERE SHOULD BE A BALANCE
BETWEEN OUR SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHT AS WELL AS PUBLIC SAFETY.
>> AND IN A MOMENT, OUR OTHER
BIG HEADLINE.
A MAJOR LOSS ON CAPITOL HILL.
>> AND SENDING HEARTFELT
CHRISTMAS GREETINGS TO NEWTOWN
FAMILIES STRUGGLING OVER THE
HOLIDAYS.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
WE'RE GOING TO MOVE TO OTHER
NEWS.
DANIEL INOUYE IS BEING
REMEMBERED FROM WASHINGTON TO
HIS HOME STATE OF HAWAII.
HE WAS A WORLD WAR II MEDAL OF
HONOR WINNER WHO LOST AN ARM TO
A GERMAN HAND GRENADE IN ITALY.
HE BECAME THE FIRST JAPANESE
AMERICAN IN CONGRESS AND SERVED
50 YEARS IN THE U.S. SENATE.
HIS DEATH WAS ANNOUNCED BY HARRY
REID.
>> THE KINDNESS THAT HE HAS
SHOWN ME FOR ME TIME HERE IN THE
SENATE HAS BEEN SOMETHING I WILL
CHERISH ALWAYS.
A MAN WHO HAS LIVED AND BREATHED
THE SENATE.
HE WAS THAT PATRIOT.
>> VERY KIND WORDS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ALSO A NATIVE OF
HAWAII TWEETED ALOHA YESTERDAY.
HE DIED YESTERDAY AT 88 YEARS
OLD.
>>> THERE IS PROGRESS IN TALKS
ON THE FISCAL CLIFF, BUT MAJOR
STICKING POINTS STILL REMAIN
WITH JUST TWO WEEKS TO GO.
A TOP REPUBLICAN SAYS THERE IS
DISAGREEMENT OVER SPENDING CUTS
VERSUS NEW TAXES AND UNTIL THAT
COULD BE WORKED OUT, THERE WON'T
BE ANY TALKS ABOUT THE SPECIFIC
DETAILS.
AND WALL STREET CLOSED HIGHER
OVER SIGNS OF THE TALKS.
THE DOW JONES ROSE 100 POINTS
FOR ITS BIGGEST GAIN OF THE
MONTH.
EARLY MARKETS OVERSEAS ALSO
HIGHER BECAUSE OF CAPITOL HILL
OPTIMISM.
AND A BOUNCE BACK IN CHINA'S
ECONOMY.
>>> A HOLIDAY MIRACLE FOR
DRIVERS AS PLUNGING GAS PRICES
HIT THEIR LOWEST POINT OF THE
YEAR.
AAA REPORTS THE PRICE OF GAS
FELL MORE THAN NINE CENTS A
GALLON LAST WEEK.
THE NATIONAL AVERAGE IS $3.25.
THE COST OF GAS IS DOWN 16%
SINCE SEPTEMBER.
THANKS TO INCREASING SUPPLIES,
GAS PRICES HAVE FALLEN EVERY DAY
THIS MONTH.
AND IT'S A SAFE BET THAT THE
MAKERS OF THE iPHONE RECOGNIZE A
MISTAKE WHEN THEY SEE IT.
THE NEW VERSION OF GOOGLE MAPS
THAT WAS DOWNLOADED, GET THIS,
10 MILLION TIMES IN THE FIRST 48
HOURS OF ITS RELEASE, THE APP IS
MAKING A TRIUMPHANT RETURN AFTER
APPLE REPLACED IT WITH ITS OWN
APPLICATION THREE MONTHS AGO.
THE MOVE WAS SUCH A DEBACLE, ONE
EXECUTIVE WAS FIRED AND APPLE
CEO TIM COOK WAS FORCED TO ISSUE
AN APOLOGY.
EVERYONE HATED THAT APP.
IT'S GOOD THEY RETURNED TO WHAT
WE ALL LIKE.
SO GOOD GOING, APPLE.
>> DID YOU DOWNLOAD IT YET?
>> I HAVE NOT, BUT TODAY I WILL.
>> THERE ARE INSTRUCTIONS.
>>> RETURNING TO OUR TOP STORY
IN JUST A MOMENT.
>> WHEN WE COME BACK, SOME
UNDERSTANDABLE JITTERS ON THE
WAY BACK TO CLASSROOMS.
MILLIONS OF STUDENTS AND PARENTS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY IN THE WAKE
OF SANDY HOOK.
STAY WITH US, EVERYBODY.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
>>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" CONTINUES
AFTER THIS FROM OUR ABC
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
IT IS EASY TO FORGET THAT
CHRISTMAS IS JUST ONE WEEK AWAY,
AND SCHOOLS, THEY'RE IN THEIR
FINAL DAYS BEFORE HOLIDAY BREAK.
>> DOESN'T SEEM A LOT LIKE
CHRISTMAS TIME.
BUT NONE OF THOSE DAYS ARE
LIKELY TO BE AS NERVE-RACKING AS
YESTERDAY WAS.
THAT WAS THE FIRST DAY BACK
SINCE THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTINGS.
ABC'S AMY ROBACH REPORTS ON WHAT
WAS AN ANXIOUS MONDAY FOR MANY.
>> Reporter: PARENTS AROUND
INNATION DROPPED THEIR CHILDREN
OFF AT SCHOOL.
MANY HOLDING ON A LITTLE MORE
TIGHTLY.
A DAY OF JITTERS.
SCHOOLS FROM NEW YORK TO
TENNESSEE TO TEXAS ALL WENT ON
ALERT AFTER FEAR IGNITED SEVERAL
FALSE ALARMS, SOME BOMB THREATS.
OTHERS AS MINOR AS AN UMBRELLA
MISTAKEN FOR A GUN.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
RICHFIELD, CONNECTICUT, JUST 20
MILES FROM NEWTOWN, WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN AFTER SOMEONE REPORTED
A SUSPICIOUS PERSON.
SECURITY ON THE MINDS OF
PRINCIPAL, IT WAS A PRIORITY OF
SANDY HOOK'S OWN PRINCIPAL,
KILLED IN THE MASS SHOOTING.
WE SPOKE WITH HER BEST FRIEND.
SAFETY WAS IMPORTANT TO HER.
>> SAFETY WAS HER NUMBER ONE
PRIORITY.
SHE WANTED SCHOOL TO BE A SAFE
HAVEN.
A PLACE WHERE STUDENTS COULD
COME AND FEEL COMFORTABLE, LIKE
IT WAS THEIR SECOND HOME.
>> Reporter: FROM COAST TO
COAST, PRINCIPALS WERE
RE-EVALUATING SECURITY AND
TAKING EXTRA MEASURES TO PROTECT
THEIR STUDENTS.
IN PITTSBURGH, SECURITY GUARDS
NOW HAVE GUNS.
IN THIS CALIFORNIA SCHOOL, THE
DAY STARTED WITH THE MOCK
LOCKDOWN DRILL.
>> STAY IN LOCKDOWN MODE UNTIL
YOU HEAR AN ALL-CLEAR
ANNOUNCEMENT.
>> Reporter: THE OTHER CHALLENGE
FOR TEACHERS AND PRINCIPALS,
WHAT TO SAY TO STUDENTS.
>> WE TELL THEM THAT SOMEBODY
WHO WAS A VERY SICK PERSON MADE
SOME VERY POOR CHOICES, AND THAT
IS RARE THAT NORMALLY, USUALLY
SCHOOLS ARE SAFE PLACES.
>> Reporter: AND IN GEORGIA,
PARENTS LEFT NOTHING TO CHANCE,
WALKING THEIR KIDS ALL THE WAY
INTO SCHOOL, HAND IN HAND.
WHILE SOME PARENTS DECIDED TO
KEEP THEIR CHILDREN OUT OF
CLASS, EXPERTS RECOMMEND IT'S
BEST TO GET THEM BACK TO THEIR
NORMAL ROUTINE.
THAT'S MADE PARTICULARLY HARD
HERE IN CONNECTICUT WHERE THE
GOVERNOR ANNOUNCED A MOMENT OF
SILENCE ON FRIDAY.
>> THAT'S A NATIONAL MOMENT OF
SILENCE THAT HE WANTS THE NATION
TO RECOGNIZE THAT, AND HAVE
CHURCHES RING THE BELL 26 TIMES
IN HONOR OF THOSE KILLED.
I ASKED SUNNY YESTERDAY WHAT DID
YOU TELL YOUR KIDS?
>> YOU DON'T WANT TO TELL KIDS 7
YEARS OR UNDER NECESSARILY.
BUT FOR US THAT WORK IN THE
BUSINESS, THEY DIDN'T SEE WHAT
WAS GOING ON BUT THEY REACTED TO
WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
I SAID A BAD MAN DID VERY BAD
THINGS.
THESE KIDS WENT TO HEAVEN.
WE SAID A LITTLE PRAYER FOR
THESE CHILDREN.
I SAID, BUT THAT BAD MAN IS GONE
AND YOU CAN FEEL SAFE BECAUSE
WE'LL TAKE CARE OF YOU.
♪
>>> YOU SEE A LOT OF THOSE GREEN
AND WHITE BALLOONS, THE SCHOOL
COLORS FOR SANDY HOOK, YOU SEE A
LOT OF THOSE IN MEMORIALS AROUND
THAT TOWN.
FINALLY THIS HALF HOUR, SHOWING
EMPATHY AND OFFERING COMFORT IN
THE WAKE OF THIS TRAGEDY.
THEY HELD A CEREMONY HONORING
THE VICTIMS LAST NIGHT BEFORE
THE UCONN MEN'S BASKETBALL GAME.
>> PLAYERS WORE SPECIAL PATCHES
ON THEIR UNIFORMS.
A RECTANGLE WITH A GREEN
BACKGROUND AND THE LETTERS SH
RIGHT THERE ON THEIR FACE FOR
SANDY HOOK.
THE LADY HUSKIES WILL WEAR THE
GAME PATCH IN THEIR GAME
TOMORROW.
>> NICELY DONE.
>>> A MOTHER AND HER CHILDREN IN
GEORGIA ARE ABOUT TO SEND SOME
LOVE TO NEWTOWN, IN THE FORM OF
TEDDY BEARS AND OTHER STUFFED
ANIMALS, AS WELL.
>> IT'S A WORK OF MICHELLE AND
HER 9-YEAR-OLD SON AND
5-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER.
THEY COLLECTED MORE THAN 100
STUFFED ANIMALS ALREADY AND
THEY'LL CONTINUE COLLECTING THEM
FOR THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS.
>>> AND FURTHER NORTH IN NORTH
CAROLINA, 26 CHRISTMAS TREES ARE
BEING PREPARED TO BE SENT TO
CONNECTICUT.
THEY WERE SET UP JUST OUTSIDE
THE FIRE DEPARTMENT IN SANFORD,
NORTH CAROLINA AND DECORATED
WITH HAND MADE ORNAMENTS.
>> THE ORGANIZER SAID SHE GOT
INVOLVED BECAUSE SHE'S A MOTHER
AND HER WORST FEAR AS A MOTHER
CAN AND WORST FEAR AS A MOTHER
WOULD BE TO LOSE A CHILD.
>> I GOT INVOLVED BECAUSE I
WANTED THE FAMILY TO KNOW THAT
THERE IS GOODNESS IN THIS WORLD
AND THROUGH THIS TRAGEDY, I
WANTED THEM TO FEEL LOVE FROM
ALL OVER.
>> SHE SAYS SHE'S HOPING MORE
PEOPLE WILL FEEL COMPELLED TO
DONATE MORE ORNAMENTS BEFORE
BEING SENT TO NEWTOWN.
WE'VE SAID SO MANY TIMES HOW
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS BRINGS OUT THE
BEST IN PEOPLE AROUND THE
COUNTRY.
THE GENERAL STORE FROM NEWTOWN
SAYS THEY'RE GETTING CALLS FROM
ALL OVER THE WORLD.
ONE CALLER GAVE A CREDIT CARD
FOR 500 BUCKS FOR FIRST
RESPONDERS AND CALLER FROM
CALIFORNIA CALLED THAT STORE AND
DONATED 125 BUCKS JUST FOR
COFFEE FOR CUSTOMERS.
>> WE FEEL SO POWERLESS IN THIS
SITUATION, BUT A WAY TO DO
SOMETHING ABOUT IT IS THE RANDOM
ACTS OF KINDNESS, THE TEDDY
BEARS, THE DONATIONS, BE A PART
OF IT.
IT FEELS LIKE YOU'RE PROVIDING
WHATEVER COMFORT YOU CAN, EVEN
THOUGH WE FEEL SOMEWHAT HELPLESS
IN THIS SITUATION.
>> MAYBE THE SMALLEST ACT MEANS
SO MUCH.
THE NATION IS WITH YOU AND
THINKING ABOUT YOU AND CARING
FOR YOU.
MORE FROM ABC NEXT.
It's time
to change the way we clean.
It's time to free ourselves
from the smell
and harshness of bleach.
And free ourselves from worrying
about the ones we love.
New Lysol Power & Free has more
cleaning power than bleach.
How?
The secret
is the hydrogen peroxide
formula.
It attacks tough stains
and kills 99.9% of germs.
New Lysol Power & Free.
Powerful cleaning that's
family friendly.
Another step forward
in our Mission for Health.
>>> THIS MORNING ON "WORLD NEWS
NOW," TROUBLED PAST.
ADAM LANZA'S UPBRINGING, HIS
UNUSUAL BEHAVIOR AND NEW DETAILS
ABOUT HIS FAMILY.
>> THE YOUNG GUNMAN FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND THE
MANY UNANSWERED QUESTIONS SINCE
THE DEADLY TRAGEDY AT SANDY
HOOK.
IT'S TUESDAY, DECEMBER 18th.
>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS "WORLD
NEWS NOW."
>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
I'M PAULA FARIS.
>> AND I'M ROB NELSON.
WE'LL UPDATE THE INVESTIGATION
IN CONNECTICUT IN OUR TOP STORY
COMING UP IN JUST A SECOND.
AS OF COURSE, MOURNERS OVERCOME
WITH GRIEF PAY THEIR RESPECTS TO
THE FIRST TWO VICTIMS OF THE
SANDY HOOK SHOOTING.
A TOWN COMING TOGETHER IN SOME
ATTEMPT TO CARRY ON.
BUT AS YOU CAN SEE, THEIR
EMOTIONS STILL SO VERY RAW.
>> WE'RE GOING TO SEE SO MANY
FUNERALS THROUGHOUT THE WEEK.
IT WILL DEFINITELY BE A TRAGIC
SIGHT.
>> TWO DOWN, BUT 25, 24 MORE TO
GO FOR THOSE PEOPLE KILLED IN
THE SCHOOL.
>>> ALSO THIS MORNING, SCHOOL
CAMPUSES ON EDGE FROM COAST TO
COAST.
SECURITY IS FIRST AND FOREMOST
AS COPYCATS POSE THREATS THAT
POLICE ARE TAKING SERIOUSLY.
SAD THAT COWARDS OUT THERE WOULD
TAKE ADVANTAGE OF SUCH A TRAGIC
SITUATION.
>> THERE WAS ANOTHER SCARE AT A
SCHOOL DISTRICT LESS THAN 20
MILES FROM SANDY HOOK.
THEY HAD SCHOOLS ON LOCKDOWN.
ON TOP OF THAT, I COULDN'T GET
MY MIND AROUND THE IDEA, THERE
WAS A BOMB THREAT CALLED INTO
THAT VIGIL SUNDAY NIGHT.
SO UNBELIEVABLY SAD MOMENT,
SOMEONE WAS SICK ENOUGH TO CALL
IN AND THREATEN THE VIGIL AND
THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS
INSIDE.
>> SICK AND DEPRAVED.
>>> ANOTHER MAJOR HEADLINE THIS
MORNING.
NASTY STORMS NEAR SEATTLE.
A TREE JUST MISSED A BABY'S
CRIB.
THE PARENTS ARE COUNTING THEIR
BLESSINGS, WHILE THE NATION'S
MIDSECTION GEARS UP FOR A MAJOR
SNOWSTORM.
WINTER STARTS THE 21st OR 22nd.
>> FRIDAY OR SATURDAY.
>> I HATE WINTER.
>> BUT THAT'S THE MAYAN
CALENDAR.
>> EXACTLY, YEAH.
>>> FIRST ON THIS TUESDAY, NEW
DETAILS ABOUT GUNMAN ADAM LANZA.
A LIFETIME OF BEHAVIORAL ISSUES
AND HIS MOTHER'S LOSING BATTLE
TO KEEP CONTROL OF HER YOUNGEST
SON.
>> AS MOURNERS GATHERED FOR THE
FIRST FUNERALS IN NEWTOWN,
INVESTIGATORS ARE UNCOVERING
TROUBLING DETAILS ABOUT THE
GUNMAN WHO TOOK SO MANY YOUNG
LIVES.
HERE'S ABC'S BRIAN ROSS.
>> Reporter: INCREASINGLY, ADAM
WAS SO TROUBLED HE WOULD NOT
LEAVE THE HOUSE.
AND HIS MOTHER, NANCY, THE LAST
FEW MONTHS, TOLD FRIENDS SHE WAS
LOSING CONTROL OF HER
20-YEAR-OLD SON.
>> IT WAS JUST GETTING A LITTLE
HARDER FOR HER AS TIME WENT ON.
>> Reporter: NANCY LANZA WAS A
REGULAR HERE AT THIS NEWTOWN BAR
AND RESTAURANT WHERE THE OWNERS
SAY SHE TOLD THEM ABOUT HER
STRUGGLES WITH ADAM'S BEHAVIORAL
AND EMOTIONAL PROBLEMS FOR
YEARS.
>> SHE HOME SCHOOLED HIM AND
EVERYTHING.
I KNEW HE WAS ON MEDICATION, BUT
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
>> Reporter: SINCE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AT SANDY HOOK THROUGH
HIGH SCHOOL, ADAM WAS KNOWN BY
CLASSMATES AS STRANGE, SEVERELY
SHY.
>> HE HATED LOOKING AT YOUR EYES
FOR MORE THAN A COUPLE SECONDS.
HE WOULD ALWAYS LOOK DOWN AT HIS
PAPER OR WHATEVER HE WAS DOING.
>> Reporter: A FORMER BABYSITTER
SAYS HE WAS TOLD BY THE MOTHER
TO NEVER LEAVE ADAM ALONE.
>> NEVER GO TO THE BATHROOM OR
TURN YOUR BACK ON HIM AT ANY
TIME.
>> Reporter: THE FORMER SCHOOL
SECURITY DIRECTOR, WHO BECAME
CLOSE TO ADAM WHEN HE WAS IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL TECH CLUB, SAID ADAM
HAD SEVERAL DISORDERS, INCLUDING
THE INABILITY TO FEEL PAIN.
>> IF HE CUT HIMSELF OR HURT
HIMSELF, HE WOULD NOT KNOW IT OR
FEEL IT.
SO WE WERE BEING VERY CAREFUL
WITH HIM.
>> Reporter: BUT DESPITE ADAM'S
ISSUES, NANCY LANZA TOOK HER SON
TO LOCAL FIRING RANGES AND
INTRODUCED HIM TO THE WORLD OF
HIGH POWERED GUNS, INCLUDING THE
BUSHMASTER AR-15 ASSAULT STYLE
WEAPON HE USED TO KILL HIS
VICTIMS.
ILLUSTRATED HERE IN A VIDEO
POSTED ON THE COMPANY YOUTUBE
CHANNEL, THE BUSHMASTER CAN FIRE
45 ROUNDS PER MINUTE, AND IT'S
THE MOST POPULAR STYLE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE IN THE
COUNTRY.
POLICE AND FEDERAL AGENTS ARE
WORKING ON ANOTHER KEY PIECE OF
EVIDENCE, A COMPUTER HARD DRIVE
FOUND IN THE LANZA HOME.
WHEN THEY FOUND IT, SOMEONE HAD
TRIED TO DESTROY IT WITH A
HAMMER OR SCREWDRIVER.
BUT AGENTS SAY WHILE THAT WILL
SLOW THEM DOWN, IT WILL NOT STOP
THEM FROM RECOVERING WHAT WAS ON
THE HARD DRIVE.
PERHAPS THE SECRETS THAT ADAM
LANZA WANTED NO ONE TO SEE.
BRIAN ROSS, ABC NEWS, NEW YORK.
>> PERHAPS FURTHER PROOF HOW
PREMEDITATED THIS THING WAS,
THAT HE TOOK THE TIME TO DAMAGE
THAT HARD DRIVE.
>> HE MENTIONED A FORMER ADVISER
SAID HE HAD A BIZARRE CONDITION
WHERE HE HAD THE INABILITY TO
TOUCH AND FEEL AND EMPATHIZE
WITH ANYTHING.
ANOTHER NEIGHBOR AND CLASSMATE
SAID ADAM LANZA HAD BEEN A WEIRD
KID SINCE WE WERE 5 YEARS OLD.
AS HORRIBLE AS THIS WAS, I CAN'T
SAY I'M SURPRISED.
WHY DIDN'T ANYBODY REACH OUT?
SO MANY OF THESE KIDS THAT ARE
LONERS AND WE KNOW THEY'RE
POSSIBLY GOING THROUGH A TOUGH
SITUATION, PEOPLE NEED TO REACH
OUT TO THEM.
AND BEFRIEND THEM.
>> HOPEFULLY THE GUN CONTROL/
MENTAL HEALTH DEBATE THIS
COUNTRY IS ABOUT TO HAVE WILL
ANSWER SOME OF THOSE QUESTIONS.
>>> OLDER STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN
RETURNED TO CLASSES TODAY, BUT
THOSE WHO ATTENDED SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ITSELF ARE STILL
WAITING FOR THEIR NEW SCHOOL TO
GET READY.
ADMINISTRATORS HAVE NOT DECIDED
WHEN CLASSES AT NEARBY CHALK
HILL SCHOOL WILL BEGIN, BUT
STUDENTS WILL GET A CHANCE THIS
WEEK TO SEE THEIR NEW SCHOOL AND
BECOME MORE COMFORTABLE WITH THE
TRANSITION.
STILL NO WORD IF SANDY HOOK WILL
EVER OPEN AGAIN.
>>> THE SHOOTING HAS PEOPLE
TALKING AGAIN ABOUT GUN
OWNERSHIP IN AMERICA.
GUN STORES REPORT THAT SALES ARE
WAY UP AND TEXAS GOVERNOR RICK
PERRY SAYS HE'S OKAY WITH ARMING
TEACHERS IF IT KEEPS CHILDREN
SAFE.
HOWEVER, IN WASHINGTON, THERE'S
NEW PRESSURE ON THE PRESIDENT TO
DO SOMETHING TO CONTROL ACCESS
TO FIREARMS.
HERE'S ABC'S JAKE TAPPER.
>> Reporter: STANDING BEFORE THE
DEVASTATED FAMILIES OF SANDY
HOOK, THE PRESIDENT PLEDGED
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE
TRAGEDIES, TO SAVE FUTURE
CHILDREN.
>> BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE DO WE
HAVE?
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
>> Reporter: BUT A COUPLE
HUNDRED PEOPLE WHO MARCHED FROM
CAPITOL HILL TO THE OFFICES OF
THE NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION,
AND NEW YORK CITY MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG STANDING WITH VICTIMS
OF GUN VIOLENCE, THERE IS ONE
ISSUE TO CONFRONT -- ACCESS TO
GUNS.
>> THIS IS JUST RIDICULOUS.
THIS IS AN OUTRAGE.
WE ARE KILLING EACH OTHER.
AND WE'RE THE ONLY
INDUSTRIALIZED COUNTRY IN THE
WORLD DOING IT.
>> Reporter: PROPOSALS BEING
PUSHED IN CONGRESS INCLUDE
REINSTATING THE BAN ON CERTAIN
TYPES OF SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES,
WHICH EXPIRED IN 2004.
AND BANNING HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZINES.
EVEN SOME GUN STALWARTS SUCH AS
WEST VIRGINIA DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
JOE MANCHIN SOUNDED A BIT MORE
COMPROMISING.
>> I DON'T KNOW ANYONE IN THE
SPORTING OR HUNTING ARENA THAT
GOES OUT WITH AN ASSAULT RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW ANYBODY THAT NEEDS
30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP TO GO
HUNTING.
>> Reporter: WHITE HOUSE
OFFICIALS SAY THE PRESIDENT DOES
NOT ONLY VIEW THIS TRAGEDY
THROUGH THE LENS OF ACCESS TO
GUNS, BUT EDUCATION AND A
VIOLENT POPULAR CULTURE.
WHILE THE PRESIDENT HAS
OCCASIONALLY TALKED ABOUT GUN
CONTROL --
>> WEAPONS THAT WERE DESIGNED
FOR SOLDIERS IN WAR THEATERS
DON'T BELONG ON THE STREETS.
>> Reporter: ACTION IS A
DIFFERENT MATTER.
CAN YOU NAME ONE THING THE
PRESIDENT HAS DONE IN THE LAST
FOUR YEARS TO HELP REMOVE
WEAPONS OF WAR FROM OUR STREET?
>> THERE'S NO QUESTION, JAKE,
THAT THE SKIRRAGE OF GUN VIANCE
IS A PROBLEM THAT HAS NOT
SUFFICIENTLY BEEN ADDRESSED.
>> Reporter: IN OTHER WORDS, NO.
MANY AMERICANS ARE TURNING IN
THEIR GRIEF TO WASHINGTON FOR
ANSWERS AS TO WHAT THEY CAN DO,
WHAT SOCIETY CAN DO TO PREVENT
FUTURE SANDY HOOKS.
THEY ARE SO FAR NOT HEARING ANY
ANSWERS FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
JAKE TAPPER, ABC NEWS, THE WHITE
HOUSE.
>> WELL DONE, JAKE.
>> WE WANT TO INVOLVE YOU IN THE
NATION'S DISCUSSION OVER
FIREARMS.
EVERYONE HAS AN OPINION ABOUT
THIS.
>> WHAT IS YOUR ADVICE TO
LAWMAKERS AS THEY DEBATE THE GUN
CONTROL LAWS?
VISIT OUR FAN PAGE AND LET US
KNOW WHAT YOU THINK.
WE MAY READ SOME OF YOUR
RESPONSES ON THE AIR.
YOU HOPE THAT WE LOOK OUTWARD AS
A COUNTRY AND FIND OUT WHAT
OTHER COUNTRIES HAVE DONE.
IN FACT, IN AUSTRALIA IN '96,
AWFUL SHOOTING THERE, 35 DEAD IN
THAT.
THEY WENT ON A MASSIVE BUYBACK
PROGRAM AND STRENGTHENED THEIR
GUN LAWS THERE.
SO WHAT DID THEY DO?
SO THEY PROHIBITED PRIVATE
SALES, THEY REQUIRED THAT ALL
WEAPONS BE INDIVIDUALLY
REGISTERED TO THEIR OWNERS AND
THEY REQUIRED THAT GUN BUYERS
PRESENT A GENUINE REASON FOR
NEEDING EACH WEAPON AT THE TIME
OF PURCHASE.
SELF-DEFENSE DID NOT COUNT.
IN THE WAKE OF THE TRAGEDY,
SHOOTINGS WENT DOWN AND IT HAS A
90% PUBLIC SUPPORT.
THAT'S PERHAPS A MODEL WE CAN
LOOK TO.
>> AND THEY HAVEN'T HAD A
TRAVESTY SINCE.
SUICIDES ALSO WENT DOWN.
>>> AND SOME HEALING SPIRITS ON
FOUR LEGS HAVE ARRIVED TO
COMFORT THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN.
THERAPY DOGS, SOME WHO TRAVELED
FROM THE MIDWEST ARE PROVIDING
THAT SPECIAL KIND OF SUPPORT
THAT ONLY A LOVING CANINE CAN
PROVIDE.
>> THE ESPECIALLY TRAINED GOLDEN
RETRIEVERS ARE GETTING PLENTY OF
HUGS AND CUDDLES WHEREVER THEY
GO.
THEIR HANDLERS SAY JUST PETTING
THE DOGS CAN HELP PEOPLE FOCUS
ON SOMETHING ELSE, IF ONLY FOR A
FEW FLEETING SECONDS.
THERE WAS ANOTHER RESIDENT THAT
WAS TAKING HIS BULL DOG AROUND
JUST LETTING KIDS PET THE DOG.
JUST ANY SHORT DISTRACTION WOULD
HELP IN A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS.
SO WHATEVER IT TAKES IS A GOOD
THING.
>> A BREAK FROM REALITY.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, ANOTHER BIG
STORY WE'RE FOLLOWING.
THE INTENSE STORMS POUNDING THE
NORTHWEST.
>> AND LATER, GOING TO SCHOOL
WILL NEVER BE THE SAME SINCE
THIS NEWTOWN TRAGEDY.
THE SECURITY MEASURES TO KEEP
YOUR KIDS SAFE IS COMING UP ON
"WORLD NEWS NOW."
I LOVE HOW CLEAN MY MOUTH IS
AFTER A DENTAL CLEANING...
I JUST WISH
I COULD KEEP IT THIS WAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW YOU CAN.
WITH THE CREST PRO-HEALTH
CLINICAL LINE.
USED TOGETHER,
THEY HELP KEEP YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
THE TOOTHPASTE
ACTUALLY REDUCES PLAQUE.
AND THE RINSE REACHES ALL AREAS
AND IS CLINICALLY PROVEN TO
HELP PREVENT PLAQUE REGROWTH.
CREST PRO-HEALTH CLINICAL LINE.
TOGETHER, THEY HELP KEEP
YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
♪
>>> AND HE'S YOUR TUESDAY
FORECAST, EVERYBODY.
RAIN AND SOME LIGHT SNOW FROM
SEATTLE TO PORTLAND.
WINDY WITH RAIN IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
UP TO 10 INCHES OF SNOW IN SALT
LAKE CITY.
WINTER STORM WATCHES FROM DENVER
TO GREEN BAY.
SHOWERS TAPER OFF FROM D.C. TO
NEW YORK.
SNOW SHOWERS IN NORTHERN NEW
ENGLAND.
>> 40s IN THE NORTHEAST.
NORTHWEST 70S FROM DALLAS TO NEW
ORLEANS.
AND JUST 20s IN SALT LAKE CITY
AND FARGO.
>>> THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST IS
GETTING A BREAK IN THE STORMY
WEATHER TODAY AFTER GETTING
SLAMMED BY BLINDING MOUNTAIN
SNOW, DRENCHING RAIN AND SOME
DAMAGING WINDS TO BOOT.
WINDS GUSTING AS HIGH AS 80
MILES AN HOUR, KNOCKED OUT POWER
TO THOUSANDS AND TOPPLED A HUGE
TREE THAT CRASHED INTO A HOME IN
WESTERN WASHINGTON.
THE LIMBS PUNCHED THROUGH THE
CEILING OF A BABY'S ROOM, JUST
NARROWLY MISSING THAT CRIB.
AND THE NEXT DOOR NEIGHBORS
WATCHED IT ALL UNFOLD.
>> MY MOTHER COMES SCREAMING,
ASKED ME TO COME DOWNSTAIRS AND
I SEE A TREE FALL INTO THE
NEIGHBOR'S YARD, HIT THEIR HOUSE
AND LOW AND BEHOLD IT'S THE
BABY'S ROOM.
THE BABY IS OKAY.
IT'S SO GREAT.
>> DESPITE THE DEBRIS THAT FELL
INTO HIS CRIB, THE BABY DIDN'T
SUFFER A SCRATCH.
GOOD ENDING.
>>> AND THE NORTHWEST BLIZZARD
HAS LEFT FOUR CONSTRUCTION
WORKERS STUCK ON A SNOWY OREGON
MOUNTAIN.
RESCUE WORKERS GOT WITHIN A FEW
HUNDRED YARDS OF THE CREW BUT
FORCED TO TURN AROUND WHEN THE
CONDITIONS WORSENED.
THE CREW WAS WORKING ON A CELL
PHONE TOWER.
THEY ARE SAFE, HOWEVER, IN A
SMALL CONCRETE BUILDING.
>>> THE $60 BILLION AID DEAL TO
HELP HURRICANE SANDY SURVIVORS
IS HITTING A SNAG IN THE SENATE.
THE DEBATE ON THE EMERGENCY
SPENDING BILL BEGAN YESTERDAY.
DEMOCRATS ARE TRYING TO PASS IT
BEFORE CHRISTMAS, BUT SEVERAL
REPUBLICANS ARE CONCERNED ABOUT
MEASURES ATTACHED TO THE BILL
AND THAT SEEMS TO BE THE HOLDUP.
>>> IN NEW JERSEY, SIGNS OF
PROGRESS IN THE RECOVERY.
SOME BUSINESSES REOPENED FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE SUPER STORM
SANDY HIT ABOUT SEVEN WEEKS AGO
NOW.
FAMILIES MAY BE ALLOWED TO MOVE
BACK TO THE COASTAL TOWN NEXT
MONTH.
PROGRESS IS SLOW AND COMING BUT
GOOD WHEN IT ARRIVES.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, WE'RE
RETURNING TO OUR TOP STORY, THE
TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK.
>> THE HEARTBREAKING FAREWELLS
AND THE BIG CHANGES IN THE
CLASSROOM ACROSS THE NATION,
COMING UP.
>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" CONTINUES
AFTER THIS, FROM OUR ABC
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
THERE ARE FOUR MORE FUNERALS
TODAY FOR VICTIMS OF LAST
FRIDAY'S MASSACRE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THREE MORE OF THOSE INNOCENT
LITTLE CHILDREN AND THE FIRST
TEACHER, VICKI SOTO, WILL BE
LAID TO REST TODAY.
JUJU CHANG WAS IN NEWTOWN.
AS THE FUNERALS GOT STARTED.
>> Reporter: UNDER A COLD,
STEADY RAIN, A WAVE OF COMMUNAL
GRIEF CONTINUES TO WASH OVER
NEWTOWN.
MEMORIALS GROWING IN SETS OF 20
FOR THE CHILDREN.
20 CHRISTMAS TREES.
20 POINSETTIAS.
20 ANGELS.
THE FIRST FUNERALS IN A TOWN
WHOSE FAITH IS BEING TESTED IN
WAYS IT COULD HAVE NEVER
IMAGINED.
FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO, A
HUGE NEW YORK GIANTS FAN, WHOSE
FAVORITE PLAYER PAID TRIBUTE ON
HIS CLEAT.
AND NOAH POZNER, WHOSE TWIN
SISTER SURVIVED IN ANOTHER
CLASSROOM.
>> MAY THEIR SOULS BE BOUND UP
IN THE BOND OF LIFE ETERNAL.
>> Reporter: THE RABBI STRUGGLED
TO FIND THE RIGHT WORDS AT THE
PRAYER VIGIL FOR A NATION THAT
PAUSED TO JOIN NEWTOWN IN
MOURNING.
A MUCH TOUGHER TASK --
A EULOGY FOR A 6-YEAR-OLD, AS A
WOMAN COLLAPSED OUTSIDE IN
GRIEF, THE RABBI INSIDE TRIED TO
FIND WORDS TO COMFORT NOAH'S
GRIEVING MOTHER.
>> I WHISPERED TO HER, I LOOKED
AT HER WITHOUT FLINCHING AND I
SAID, YOU KNOW, I PERSONALLY
BELIEVE IN THE ETERNITY OF THE
SOUL.
>> Reporter: DID NOAH'S FAMILY
RESPOND TO THAT?
>> YES.
THAT WAS HELPFUL TO HER.
AT THE END, SHE RELEASED BLUE
AND WHITE BALLOONS INTO THE SKY,
UNTIL WE COULDN'T SEE THEM
ANYMORE.
THAT WAS A GOOD -- YOU KNOW, TO
LET IT GO.
SHE SAID, YOU KNOW, GO MY SON,
INTO THE BLUE SKIES.
GO, MY SON, INTO THE GREEN
PASTURES.
>> Reporter: JESSICA LOVED
HORSES AND ORCAS AND WAS DEVOTED
TO HER TWO YOUNGER SIBLINGS AND
LEFT BEHIND AN UNEXPECTED GIFT,
A DIARY.
>> I JUST OPENED THE BOOK AND IT
WAS EXACTLY WHAT I NEEDED,
BECAUSE IT SAYS I LOVE YOU SO
MUCH, MOMMA.
LOVE, JESSICA.
WITH A LITTLE HEART.
IT WAS LIKE SHE WAS, YOU KNOW,
TELLING ME THAT SHE'S WATCHING
US AND KNOWS HOW HARD THIS MUST
BE FOR US, AND SHE WANTS US TO
KNOW HOW MUCH SHE LOVED US AND
SHE KNOWS HOW MUCH SHE WAS
LOVED.
>> Reporter: OTHERS ARE TELLING
STORIES OF SURVIVAL.
>> THEY WERE SITTING THERE, AND
I HAD NO IDEA WHY THEY WERE
THERE.
>> Reporter: A NEIGHBOR FOUND
SIX CHILDREN HUDDLED AT THE END
OF HIS DRIVEWAY AND TOOK THEM
IN.
THEY HAD BEEN IN VICKI SOTO'S
FIRST GRADE CLASS.
>> THESE TWO BOYS KEPT SAYING,
WE CAN'T GO BACK TO SCHOOL, WE
CAN'T GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
OUR TEACHER IS DEAD.
MRS. SOTO, WE DON'T HAVE A
TEACHER.
AND I COULDN'T BELIEVE IT.
>> Reporter: THE SCHOOL NURSE
TOLD ABC'S GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS
HOW SHE CROUCHED UNDER HER DESK
AND HELD HER BREATH.
>> WHILE YOU'RE UNDER THERE, YOU
ACTUALLY SEE THE FEET OF THE
SHOOTER?
>> I COULD SEE HIM FROM THE
KNEES DOWN.
SEE THE LEGS.
>> RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU?
>> 20 FEET AWAY, FACING -- HIS
BOOTS WERE FACING MY DESK.
>> THEN HE TURNED AND WALKED
AWAY?
>> IT WAS SECONDS.
HE TURNED AND WALKED OUT.
AND I HEARD THE DOOR CLOSE.
>> Reporter: AND FOR THE RABBI,
THE TOUGH TASK OF EXPLAINING TO
THE FAITHFUL WHERE THE EVIL THAT
STRUCK LAST FRIDAY COMES FROM.
>> I DON'T BELIEVE THAT GOD DID
THIS.
I BELIEVE A CRAZY MAN DID THIS.
THE MEANING IN IT IS NOT TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND WHY GOD DOES
SOMETHING.
SOMEHOW WE GOT HERE.
WE HAVE TO NOT NECESSARILY
ALWAYS LOOK TOWARDS GOD BUT LOOK
TOWARDS HUMANITY AND SAY WHAT IS
IT THAT WE'VE DONE THAT HAS
CREATED THIS ENVIRONMENT.
>> Reporter: THE CLERGY OF THE
SMALL NEW ENGLAND TOWN SAY THAT
THE HORRORS OF LAST WEEK HAVE
HELPED BOND PEOPLE TOGETHER
SPIRITUALLY.
THE RABBI'S WORDS FOR ALL OF US
ARE THE SAME HE DELIVERED AT
NOAH'S FUNERAL.
>> DON'T TAKE ANYTHING FOR
GRANTED.
YOU HUG YOUR CHILDREN MORE.
YOU BECOME EVER PRESENT TO THE
FRAGILITY OF LIFE.
AND YOU LIVE LIFE FULLER.
>> Reporter: JUJU CHANG IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> IT'S STILL HEART WRENCHING.
AND SEEING THE FACES OF THOSE
PEOPLE.
WE SHOULD CLARIFY.
THE FUNERALS FOR THREE OF THE
KIDS WILL BE TODAY.
THE TEACHER, VICKI SOTO, HER
WAKE BEGINS TODAY.
SO THAT IS WHAT NEWTOWN WILL BE
DOING.
ALSO, ACCORDING TO A LOCAL PAPER
THERE, THE PARENTS WHOSE KIDS
SURVIVED CREATED A FUND CALLED
MY SANDY HOOK FAMILY FUND.
THE GOAL IS TO RAISE $2 MILLION.
ALREADY $21,000 ON THE FIRST
DAY.
It's time
to change the way we clean.
It's time to free ourselves
from the smell
and harshness of bleach.
And free ourselves from worrying
about the ones we love.
New Lysol Power & Free has more
cleaning power than bleach.
How?
The secret
is the hydrogen peroxide
formula.
It attacks tough stains
and kills 99.9% of germs.
New Lysol Power & Free.
Powerful cleaning that's
family friendly.
Another step forward
in our Mission for Health.
YOU'RE PLAYING TOMORROW.
[ coughs ]
♪
YOU CAN'T LET A COLD
KEEP YOU UP TONIGHT.
[ snores ]
VICKS NYQUIL.
POWERFUL NIGHTTIME 6-SYMPTOM
COLD & FLU RELIEF.
♪
[ sniffles, coughs ]
EXCUSE ME.
I NEED SOMETHING FOR
MY COLD SYMPTOMS. [ sniffles ]
WE'VE GOT DAYQUIL FOR DAY
AND NYQUIL FOR NIGHT.
[ thuds ]
YOU DIDN'T SEE THAT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RIGHT NOW AT WALGREENS
DAYQUIL AND NYQUIL
ARE JUST $10.99 WITH CARD.
♪
>>> AND FINALLY THIS HALF HOUR,
FOR MOST SCHOOLS AROUND THE
COUNTRY AND FOR MILLIONS OF
SCHOOL KIDS, THE LONG HOLIDAY
BREAK IS TANTALIZING CLOSE.
>> THE FINAL FEW DAYS BEFORE
VACATION BEGAN YESTERDAY WITH
UNDERSTANDABLE NERVES, AS WELL
AS INCREASED SECURITY.
ABC'S BRANDY JOINS US WITH MORE.
HI, BRANDY.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
THIS HAS BEEN A NERVE-RACKING
TIME FOR A LOT OF PARENTS
FOLLOWING THE SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
MANY ARE WONDERING IF THEIR
CHILDREN ARE SAFE.
SCHOOLS FROM COAST TO COAST
LOOKED VERY DIFFERENT MONDAY
MORNING.
FOLLOWING FRIDAY'S DEADLY
SHOOTING SPREE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> WE HAVE A HEIGHTENED PRESENCE
AROUND THE SCHOOLS AND CAMPUSES.
>> Reporter: NOT ONLY ARE MORE
OFFICERS MAKING THE ROUNDS,
>> STAY IN LOCKDOWN MODE UNTIL
YOU HEAR AN ALL-CLEAR
ANNOUNCEMENT.
>> Reporter: SEVERAL SCHOOLS ARE
PERFORMING LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME IN
BUTLER, PENNSYLVANIA, ARMED
GUARDS ARE NOW STANDING OUTSIDE.
>> WHAT THIS INCIDENT HAS
PROMPTED US TO DO IS NOT ONLY
ARM OUR OFFICERS, BUT NOW TO
POSITION ONE OF THOSE IN ALL OF
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS.
>> Reporter: THE HEIGHTENED
SECURITY COMES AFTER 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA SHOT AND KILLED 20
YOUNG CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
LAST FRIDAY AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THE FACULTY AT SANDY HOOK HAD
TRAINED FOR THIS SCENARIO AND
INSTALLED A SECURITY CAMERA AT
THE LOCKED FRONT DOOR REQUIRING
PICTURE I.D.s TO GET IN.
DESPITE THAT, LANZA BROKE IN AND
NOW MANY PARENTS AT OTHER
SCHOOLS ARE ANXIOUS ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN'S SAFETY.
>> I'M REALLY SCARED, BUT I HOPE
IT DOESN'T HAPPEN HERE.
>> Reporter: CITY LEADERS ACROSS
THE COUNTRY SPENT MONDAY
ASSURING PARENTS THEIR CAMPUSES
ARE SECURE.
>> WE HAVE SCHOOL SAFETY
OFFICERS.
WE HAVE AN EXTENSIVE
INTELLIGENCE OPERATION.
>> WE'RE GOING TO MAKE SURE OUR
KIDS ARE SAFE.
>> HAVE A GOOD DAY.
>> Reporter: AND MANY PARENTS
FEEL THEY CAN'T KEEP THEIR
CHILDREN FROM LEARNING BECAUSE
OF ONE KILLER.
>> THINGS HAPPEN IN THIS WORLD,
AND NO MATTER WHAT, YOU'VE GOT
TO KEEP GOING.
>> Reporter: SAFETY EXPERTS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE ANALYZING
WHAT WENT WRONG AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY AND WHAT SECURITY
CHANGES CAN BE MADE AT SCHOOLS
NATIONWIDE.
ROB AND PAULA?
>> WHAT'S SO SAD IS THEY HAD
JUST BEEFED UP THEIR SECURITY.
BUT I WASN'T ABLE TO TAKE MY
KIDS TO SCHOOL MONDAY MORNING.
I WAS WORKING.
BUT I ASKED MY HUSBAND, WAS
ANYTHING DIFFERENT?
HE SAID NO, THEY TRIED TO KEEP
IT AS NORMAL AS POSSIBLE.
BUT I NOTICED AS I WAS DRIVING
BY LATER IN THE AFTERNOON THAT
THEY DO HAVE BARS ON ALL OF THE
WINDOWS ON THE FIRST FLOOR.
THAT REASSURED ME A LITTLE BIT.
I HAD NEVER NOTICED THAT BEFORE,
BUT I'M NOW MORE COGNIZANT THAN
EVER.
>> IT USED TO BE FIRE DRILLS
WHEN WE WERE IN SCHOOL.
NOW IT'S LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
BUT AS SAD AS IT I;x
>>> THIS MORNING ON "WORLD NEWS
NOW," SAYING GOODBYE.
MOURNERS PAY THEIR RESPECTS TO
THE FIRST VICTIMS OF THE SANDY
HOOK SHOOTING TRAGEDY.
>> FRIENDS, FAMILY AND STRANGERS
ARE CROWDING THE SMALL TOWN IN A
PAINFUL DISPLAY OF GRIEF.
IT'S TUESDAY, DECEMBER 18.
>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS "WORLD
NEWS NOW."
>>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYBODY.
I'M ROB NELSON.
>> AND I'M PAULA FARIS.
WE'LL CAPTURE THE SOMBER SCENE
IN NEWTOWN IN A MOMENT.
AND FROM CONNECTICUT TO
ILLINOIS, WHERE ADAM LANZA'S
AUNT IS EXPRESSING FAMILY
CONCERNS OF HER OWN AND ADDING
SOME INSIGHT INTO THE GUNMAN'S
FAMILY, AS WELL AS HOW CLOSE HER
FAMILY WAS TO ADAM AND NANCY,
HIS MOTHER AT THE TIME OF THIS
EVENT.
>> WE DON'T WANT TO GLORIFY THIS
GUY OR WORSE-CASE SCENARIO
ENCOURAGE ANY COPYCATS.
BUT WE KNOW THEY'RE OUT THERE
SOMEWHERE.
BUT THERE IS A FASCINATION WITH
HOW THIS GUY'S LIFE GOT SO DARK
AND SO TWISTED AND SO DEMENTED.
SO WE'RE JUST SEARCHING FOR
INSIGHT TO HOPEFULLY PREVENT
THIS FROM HAPPENING AGAIN BY
UNDERSTANDING WHAT WENT WRONG
WITH ADAM.
>>> ALSO THIS MORNING, AS
LAWMAKERS RENEW AN INTENSE
DEBATE ABOUT GUN LAWS IN THIS
COUNTRY, FIREARM SALES ARE UP.
YOU'LL SEE WHAT'S HAPPENING IN
GUN SHOPS AROUND AMERICA, AND
WHY.
>>> LATER, AGAIN, ANOTHER BIG
HEADLINE THIS HALF HOUR.
WHO UNCOVERED A GIANT SHIPMENT
OF COCAINE, ONE TON OF IT?
WHERE IT WAS HEADED, AS WELL AS
THE UNUSUAL WAY THAT SMUGGLERS
PACKAGED IT.
THEY ALMOST DIDN'T CATCH IT.
>>> BUT FIRST, NEWTOWN HAS SAID
GOODBYE TO TWO LITTLE BOYS.
THE FIRST OF A LONG, LONG,
SADLY, LONG LINE OF FUNERALS
THAT TOWN WILL FACE THIS WEEK.
>> TODAY, CLASSES RESUMED FOR
MIDDLE AND HIGH SCHOOL STUDENTS
BUT THOSE WHO ATTENDED SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY ARE WAITING FOR
THEIR NEW SCHOOL TO REOPEN.
ABC'S T.J. WINICK IS LIVE IN
NEWTOWN WITH MORE.
HI, T.J.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
HERE OUTSIDE THE LOCAL
FIRESTATION, THERE IS YET
ANOTHER MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL TO
THE VICTIMS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, A SCHOOL BUILDING
WHICH COULD POSSIBLY NEVER OPEN
AGAIN.
THIS IS THE LIVING MEMORIAL IN
DOWNTOWN SANDY HOOK, WHERE A
CONSTANT STREAM OF LOCALS AND
VISITORS COME TO REMEMBER THOSE
LOST IN FRIDAY'S HORROR.
IN NEWTOWN, A FUNERAL FOR
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER, WHO WAS
EULOGIZED AS A BOY WHO LIKED
ANIMALS, VIDEO GAMES AND MEXICAN
FOOD.
AT HIS FUNERAL, AN ONLOOKER
COLLAPSED AS THE PROCESSION
PAST.
INSIDE, HIS MOTHER SHARED
STORIES THAT HAD EVERYONE IN
TEARS.
>> SHE TOLD HIM, I LOVE YOU.
>> Reporter: A FEW MILES AWAY,
ANOTHER FUNERAL.
JACK PINTO, ALSO 6, A BIG SPORTS
FAN WHOSE FAVORITE NEW YORK
GIANTS PLAYER, VICTOR CRUZ, WORE
HIS NAME ON HIS CLEATS DURING
SUNDAY'S GAME.
>> I WAS HONORED, MAN.
I COULDN'T EXPRESS TO THEM HOW
GREAT THAT MADE ME FEEL.
>> Reporter: JACK'S FRIENDS FROM
THE WRESTLING TEAM SHOWED UP IN
THEIR LITTLE UNIFORMS.
AT A NEWS CONFERENCE, THE
NORMALLY STOIC STATE TROOPER WHO
HAS BEEN BRIEFING REPORTERS,
CHOKED UP WHEN ASKING FOR
PRIVACY FOR THE FAMILIES.
>> AT THIS TIME I CAN TAKE A
COUPLE OF QUESTIONS.
>> Reporter: HE REVEALED THERE
WERE TWO ADULT SURVIVORS, NOT
ONE.
BOTH FEMALE EMPLOYEES WITH
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
>> CERTAINLY, THEY WILL SHED A
GREAT DEAL OF LIGHT ON THE FACTS
AND CIRCUMSTANCES OF THIS TRAGIC
INVESTIGATION.
>> Reporter: THE SCHOOL ITSELF
REMAINING A CRIME SCENE LIKELY
FOR SEVERAL MONTHS, SANDY HOOK
STUDENTS WILL BE MOVED TO AN
UNUSED MIDDLE SCHOOL IN A
NEIGHBORING COMMUNITY AND START
CLASSES THERE ON WEDNESDAY.
ROB AND PAULA?
>> NO WORD YET IF THEY'RE EVER
GOING TO OPEN THAT SCHOOL AGAIN.
THAT'S GOING TO BE A TOUGH
DECISION.
BUT THE GOVERNOR IS CALLING FOR
A NATIONAL MOMENT OF REMEMBRANCE
THIS WEEK, RIGHT?
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT,
ASKING FOR A MOMENT OF SILENCE
ON FRIDAY, THE ONE-WEEK
ANNIVERSARY OF THE MASSACRE.
HE'S ALSO ASKING CHURCHES TO
RING THEIR BELLS 26 TIMES, ONCE
FOR EACH VICTIM OF THAT
SLAUGHTER.
>> T.J., OVERNIGHT WE LEARNED
NEW DETAILS ABOUT WHAT APPEARS
TO BE A BIZARRE FAMILY DYNAMIC
IN THE LANZA HOUSEHOLD.
CAN YOU TELL US EXACTLY WHAT WE
DID LEARN?
>> Reporter: WELL, THAT'S RIGHT.
WE KNOW ADAM LANZA'S FATHER
ACTUALLY MOVED OUT OF THE HOME
IN 2001.
BUT THEN HE BASICALLY SPENT
EVERY WEEKEND WITH YOUNG ADAM UP
UNTIL 2010.
THAT'S WHEN THERE WAS A
NOTICEABLE CHANGE IN THE FAMILY
DYNAMIC.
THAT'S WHEN ADAM'S PARENTS
OFFICIALLY GOT DIVORCED AND WHEN
HIS FATHER AND BROTHER, RYAN,
STOPPED SEEING ADAM.
AND WE FOUND OUT THE DAY AFTER
THIS MASSACRE OVER THE WEEKEND,
THAT THEY HAD NOT SEEN HIM FOR
TWO WHOLE YEARS.
>> NO CONTACT WITH HIM
WHATSOEVER.
T.J. WINICK, THANK YOU FOR THAT
REPORT.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA LEFT BEHIND
A VERY SPECIAL MESSAGE WHEN HE
ATTENDED SUNDAY'S MEMORIAL AT
THE NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL.
TWO TEACHERS, STEVE GEORGE AND
BOBBY PATTERSON, LEFT HIM A NOTE
ON A CLASSROOM BOARD.
YOU SEE IT THERE.
THEY THANKED HIM FOR HIS
LEADERSHIP AND HELPING THE
COMMUNITY TO HEAL.
WELL, THE PRESIDENT RESPONDED
WITH A NOTE OF HIS OWN, WRITING
"YOU'RE IN OUR THOUGHTS AND
PRAYERS" AND THEN SIGNED HIS
NAME.
>>> AND THE AUNT OF GUNMAN ADAM
LANZA IS FEARING FOR THE SAFETY
OF HER FAMILY.
MARSHA LANZA LIVES IN ILLINOIS,
HAS THREE SONS AND SAYS THEY ARE
HEARTBROKEN OVER THE SHOOTINGS.
SHE ALSO SAYS THE TRAGEDY HAS
BROUGHT SHAME TO THE FAMILY.
LANZA SAYS SHE HAD NOT SEEN HER
NEPHEW SINCE HE WAS 3 YEARS OLD
AND SHE'S WORRIED ABOUT POSSIBLE
REPERCUSSIONS THAT HER TWO
YOUNGEST SONS MAY FACE AT
SCHOOL.
>> WE HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH IT.
YES, WE'RE RELATED, BUT MY BOYS,
MY THREE YOUNGER BOYS DID NOT
KNOW THEIR COUSINS.
>> SHE ALSO SAYS SHE HAS NOT
HEARD FROM THE GUNMAN'S FATHER,
PETER LANZA, ABOUT FUNERAL
ARRANGEMENTS.
>>> IN LIGHT OF THE TRAGEDY, GUN
CONTROL IS ONCE AGAIN A HOT
TOPIC FOR PUBLIC DEBATE RIGHT
NOW.
A NEW ABC NEWS POLL FOUND THAT
54% OF AMERICANS FAVOR STRICTER
GUN CONTROL LAWS, AND MORE THAN
HALF SAY THE SHOOTING REFLECTS
BROADER PROBLEMS IN OUR SOCIETY,
NOT JUST ONE TROUBLED PERSON.
WEST VIRGINIA'S DEMOCRATIC
SENATOR JOE MANCHIN IS A STAUNCH
GUN RIGHTS ADVOCATE, SAID THE
SHOOTING MAY BE THE TIPPING
POINT.
>> I DON'T KNOW ANYONE IN THE
SPORTING ON HUNTING ARENA THAT
GOES OUT WITH AN ASSAULT RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW ANYBODY THAT NEEDS
30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP TO GO
HUNTING.
>> BUT TEXAS GOVERNOR RICK PERRY
IS TAKING THE OPPOSITE VIEW.
HE SAYS HE'S FINE WITH ARMING
TEACHERS IF THAT'S THE WAY TO
KEEP STUDENTS SAFE.
>>> CONCERNS ABOUT NEW GUN LAWS
POSSIBLY GO INTO EFFECT ARE
LEADING TO A SURGE IN FIREARMS
SALES.
MANY STORES, INCLUDING THIS ONE
IN INDIANA, ARE REPORTING A
SIGNIFICANT INCREASE IN THE SALE
OF SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPONS,
INCLUDING THE AR-15, WHICH WAS
USED IN FRIDAY'S NEWTOWN
TRAGEDY.
MANY GUN SUPPORTERS ARE ADAMANT
THAT ASSAULT STYLE RIFLES SHOULD
NOT BE OUTLAWED.
>> IF YOU READ THE FEDERALIST
PAPERS, OUR FOREFATHERS WANTED
TO PROTECT THE SAME TYPE OF GUNS
THAT OUR MILITARY HAD.
THEY WERE CONCERNED ABOUT
TYRANNY.
THEY WERE CONCERNED ABOUT A
GOVERNMENT OUT OF CONTROL.
>> GUN CONTROL JUST TAKES THE
GUNS OUT OF HANDS THAT OBEY THE
LAWS.
IT'S NOT GOING TO CONTROL THE
OUTLAWS THAT TAKE THE GUNS AND
DO THE CRIMES WITH THEM.
>> 1 IN EVERY 209 AMERICANS HAS
AN AR-15.
PRESIDENT CLINTON PLACED A BAN
ON ASSAULT RIFLES IN 1994 AND IT
EXPIRED IN 2004.
>> AND PEOPLE DEBATE ITS REAL
IMPACT.
DID IT HAVE ANY IMPACT?
YOU SEE CONFLICTING REPORTS
ABOUT THAT.
>> THERE WERE A LOT OF
LOOPHOLES.
I WOULD IMAGINE IF IT WENT DOWN
THIS ROAD AGAIN, THEY WOULD
CLOSE THESE LOOPHOLES.
>> AND SOME SENATORS SAY FIRST
DAY OF THE NEW CONGRESS, THAT'S
GOING TO BE BACK ON THE TABLE.
>> AND OUR FACEBOOK QUESTION
LOOKS SPECIFICALLY AT GUN
CONTROL.
>> WHAT IS YOUR ADVICE TO
LAWMAKERS AS THEY DEBATE THE
NATION'S GUN CONTROL LAWS?
CHECK OUT OUR FACEBOOK FAN PAGE
AT WNNFANS.COM.
TO GIVE YOUR COMMENTS ON THE
ISSUE.
WE MAY READ SOME OF YOUR
RESPONSES RIGHT HERE ON THE AIR.
>>> ALSO, THE SCHOOL SHOOTING
RAMPAGE IS TOUCHING YOUNG HEARTS
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE GLOBE.
A SCHOOL IN WARSAW, POLAND
OBSERVED A MOMENT OF SILENCE IN
HONOR OF THOSE KILLED FRIDAY.
THE CHILDREN SAY THEY WANTED TO
SHOW SOLIDARITY BECAUSE THE
TRAGEDY COULD HAVE HAPPENED IN
THEIR COUNTRY.
PEOPLE HAVE ALSO BEEN PLACING
FLOWERS AND CANDLES AT THE U.S.
EMBASSY THERE IN WARSAW.
>>> COMING UP THIS TUESDAY
MORNING, FORMER PRESIDENT GEORGE
H.W. BUSH, STILL IN THE HOSPITAL
AFTER SEVERAL WEEKS.
>>> LATER THES HALF HOUR, WE
RETURN TO OUR TOP STORY,
TROUBLED YOUNG PEOPLE LINKED TO
FRIGHTENING CRIMES.
WHAT CAN BE DONE WHEN PARENTS
THINK THEY'VE LOST CONTROL.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
[ laughing ]
AHH, CLOUDY GLASSES.
YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME OVER!
EASY.
HI. CASCADE KITCHEN COUNSELOR.
LOOK!
OVER TIME, CASCADE COMPLETE PACS
FIGHT FILM BUILDUP TWO TIMES
BETTER THAN FINISH QUANTUM
TO HELP LEAVE GLASSES SPARKLING.
CASCADE. THE CLEAR CHOICE.
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
TRIBUTES ARE POURING IN FOR
LONG-TIME SENATOR DANIEL INOUYE
FROM HAWAII.
THE SENATOR WAS A WORLD WAR II
MEDAL OF HONOR WINNER WHO LOST
AN ARM TO A GERMAN HAND GRENADE
DURING A BATTLE IN ITALY.
HE WAS THE FIRST
JAPANESE-AMERICAN IN CONGRESS.
AND SERVED 50 YEARS IN THE
SENATE.
HE PLAYED A KEY ROLE ON TWO
MAJOR CONGRESSIONAL
INVESTIGATORS, WATERGATE AND
IRAN CONTRA.
DANIEL INOUYE DIED YESTERDAY.
HE WAS 88 YEARS OLD.
>>> IT LOOKS LIKE THE FIRST
PRESIDENT BUSH WILL GET TO SPEND
CHRISTMAS AT HOME WITH HIS
FAMILY.
THE 88-YEAR-OLD FORMER PRESIDENT
COULD BE RELEASED FROM A TEXAS
HOSPITAL ANY DAY NOW.
MR. BUSH HAS BEEN IN THE
HOSPITAL SINCE THE DAY AFTER
THANKSGIVING.
DOCTORS HAVE BEEN TREATING HIM
FOR BRONCHITIS.
HE COULD BE SENT HOME NEXT WEEK.
>>> TWO KANSAS POLICE OFFICERS
GUNNED DOWN WHILE ON THE JOB
WERE REMEMBERED LAST NIGHT IN
TOPEKA.
THEY WERE BOTH SHOT IN THE HEAD
WHILE INVESTIGATING A SUSPICIOUS
VEHICLE IN A GROCERY STORE
PARKING LOT.
THE SHOOTER, A MAN WITH A
HISTORY OF THEFT AND WEAPONS
CONVICTIONS, WAS LATER KILLED IN
A SHOOTOUT WITH POLICE.
>>> A HUGE DRUG BUST IN COLOMBIA
WHERE AUTHORITIES SEIZED
LITERALLY A TON AND A HALF OF
COCAINE.
THE SHIPMENT WAS SET TO GO TO
HONDURAS, THEN MEXICO, WHERE IT
WOULD HAVE BEEN DELIVERED TO A
DRUG TRAFFICKING CARTEL.
THE DRUGS HAVE AN ESTIMATED
STREET VALUE OF $5 MILLION.
SMUGGLERS HID THE DRUGS IN
PACKAGES MARKED WITH THE FOX
SPORTS LOGO, BUT THERE WAS NO
CONNECTION TO THE NETWORK.
>>> A COMPUTER HACKER WHO
TARGETED SOME OF HOLLYWOOD'S
BIGGEST STARS IS HEADING TO
PRISON.
CHRISTOPHER CHENEY HACKED INTO
THE PERSONAL ACCOUNTS OF A
NUMBER OF ACTRESSES, INCLUDING
SCARLETT JOHANSSON AND MILA
KUNIS AND NUDE PHOTOS OF
JOHANSON HAD TAKEN FOR HER THEN
HUSBAND RYAN REYNOLDS WOUND UP
ON THE INTERNET.
A FEDERAL JUDGE IN LOS ANGELES
SENTENCED HIM TO TEN YEARS IN
PRISON.
>>> A HOLIDAY HEIST IS UNDER
INVESTIGATION IN SEATTLE.
THOUSANDS OF NINTENDO Wii GAME
CONSOLES WERE STOLEN FROM A
DISTRIBUTION WAREHOUSE NEAR THE
SEATTLE AIRPORT LAST WEEKEND.
THE THIEVES TOOK OFF WITH 64
PALATES OF CONSOLES.
IN FACT, THEY WERE LOADED INTO
TWO BIG RIGS AND THEN A BOX VAN.
POLICE SAY THEY'VE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING QUITE LIKE IT.
>> I'VE BEEN A COP FOR 28 YEARS,
AND I HONESTLY CAN'T REMEMBER
THE LAST TIME WE HAD SOMETHING
LIKE THIS WHERE PEOPLE PULLED IN
AND LITERALLY TOOK A WAREHOUSE
FULL OF MERCHANDISE OUT.
>> POLICE SAY THE THIEVES KNEW
WHAT THEY WERE DOING BUT WILL
NOT SAY IF IT WAS AN INSIDE JOB.
>> NOT A SMART JOB, BECAUSE THE
CONSOLES CAN BE TRACED.
>> OH, REALLY, LIKE MONEY STOLEN
FROM A BANK.
THEY CAN TRACE THAT STUFF.
>> FILE THAT UNDER OUR DUMB
CRIMINALS.
IT'S GETTING LARGER, ISN'T IT?
>> WELL DONE, FELLOWS.
ENJOY THAT TENNIS.
>>> STRAIGHT AHEAD, BACK TO OUR
SERIOUS NEWS, THE NATION'S
TROUBLED CHILDREN.
>> AND ONE MOTHER'S STUNNINGLY
PERSONAL WORDS ABOUT HER SON,
GETTING LOTS OF ATTENTION.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
N.
♪
>>> AS WE ATTEMPT TO START A
NATIONAL CONVERSATION IN THE
WAKE OF THE CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY,
HERE'S A FACT TO CONSIDER.
15 MILLION AMERICAN CHILDREN
HAVE SOME SORT OF MENTAL HEALTH
DISORDER.
>> AND MANY OF THOSE GOING
UNDIAGNOSED OR EVEN IF THEY HAVE
DIAGNOSED, THEY HAVEN'T GOTTEN
THE HELP THEY NEED.
SOME OF THE PARENTS ARE
EXPRESSING CONCERNS ABOUT WHAT
COULD HAPPEN IF THEY DON'T GET
HELP.
ABC'S JOHN DONVAN REPORTS.
>> Reporter: THERE ARE HOMES
THAT KNOW NOTHING OF RAISING A
TROUBLED CHILD.
THEN THERE ARE THOSE THAT DO.
LIZA LONG PUT HER HOME IN THE
SECOND GROUP IN A BLOG POSTING
TITLED "I AM ADAM LANZA'S
MOTHER" THAT ROCKETED AROUND THE
WORLD.
I LOVE MY SON, SHE WROTE.
BUT HE TERRIFIES ME.
>> MY BIGGEST FEAR IS THAT SOME
DAY HE'LL FLY INTO A RAGE AND
HURT ME OR HIMSELF.
>> Reporter: HE IS MENTALLY ILL
AND HAS THREATENED HER, EVEN
PULLED A KNIFE ON HER.
SHE CALLED THIS A CRY FOR HELP.
ONE THAT WAS IMMEDIATELY ECHOED
IN A REMARKABLE WAY BY PARENTS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY, BOTH ONLINE
AND TALKING WITH ABC NEWS.
>> I'M AFRAID FOR MY DAUGHTER.
I'M FEARFUL FOR MY DAUGHTER.
THIS COULD HAVE BEEN MY SON.
I'M FEARFUL WHAT WILL HAPPEN TO
HER OR ANYBODY THAT'S AROUND
HER.
WOULD THIS BE HER THAT I'M
GETTING A PHONE CALL ABOUT?
>> Reporter: IT WAS CONNECTICUT
THAT TRIGGERED THIS.
YET THESE PARENT'S FEARS
CONFLICT WITH ALL EXPERT OPINION
ABOUT THE MENTALLY ILL.
STATISTICALLY THEY ARE NOT
DANGEROUS TO THE COMMUNITY AT
LARGE NOR TO PERPETRATORS OF
LARGE SCALE KILLINGS EXHIBIT THE
EXPLOSIVE BEHAVIOR THE PARENTS
ARE WORRIED ABOUT.
ONE OF THE MOTHERS OF THE TWO
COLUMBINE KILLERS SAID --
>> SUE KLEBOLD HAD NO SENSE THAT
DYLAN WAS CAPABLE OF DOING
ANYTHING LIKE HE DID.
SHE WAS SHOCKED WHEN IT
HAPPENED.
>> Reporter: YET LONG DID TOUCH
ON SOMETHING.
SHE WAS, SAYS THE HEAD OF
AMERICA'S OLDEST MENTAL HEALTH
ORGANIZATION --
>> SPEAKING ON BEHALF OF
THOUSANDS OF FAMILIES.
>> Reporter: THOUSANDS?
>> THOUSANDS OF FAMILIES THAT
FIND THE SYSTEM TO BE EXTREMELY
FRAGMENTED.
>> Reporter: WHICH IS NOT
DIFFERENT FROM HOW THE MENTALLY
ILL USED TO BE SEGREGATED IN NOW
SHUT DOWN STATE INSTITUTIONS.
THERE ARE BETTER SOLUTIONS, DAY
PROGRAMS WHERE KIDS CAN GET
COUNSELING IN BIG DOSES, BUT
THOSE ARE IN SHORT SUPPLY IN
MANY STATES.
WYOMING, FOR EXAMPLE, HAS SIX
CHILD PSYCHIATRISTS FOR ITS HALF
MILLION POPULATION.
TODAY, A CALL FOR ACTION.
A SUMMIT ON CHILDHOOD MENTAL
HEALTH BY THE AMERICAN ACADEMY
OF ADOLESCENT AND CHILD
PSYCHIATRY.
>> YEAH, THERE'S A LOT WE DO
KNOW.
IT'S JUST THAT WE DON'T
COMPREHENSIVELY APPLY WHAT IT IS
WE DO KNOW.
>> Reporter: THAT'S BECAUSE OF
MONEY?
>> YES, I BELIEVE SO.
>> Reporter: MONEY THAT HAS BEEN
SHRINKING WHILE BEHIND SOME OF
THOSE FRONT DOORS THE FEARS ONLY
GET BIGGER.
JOHN DONVAN, ABC NEWS,
WASHINGTON.
>> MONEY AGAIN THE ISSUE.
SO AS WE GO THROUGH THE NEXT
COUPLE OF DAYS, ALL THIS TALK
ABOUT TAXES AND BUDGET CUTS, YOU
WOULD HOPE THEY SAY LET'S NOT
CUT FROM WHATEVER POT OF MONEY
GOES TOWARDS MENTAL HEALTH
SERVICES.
PARTICULARLY IN SCHOOLS WITH OUR
YOUNG PEOPLE WITH AN ATTEMPT TO
SAVE THEM AND TREAT THEM WHILE
THEY'RE YOUNG.
WE'LL SEE HOW IT PLAYS OUT IN
D.C.
>> THAT'S GOING TO BRING US TO
OUR FACEBOOK QUESTION OF THE
DAY.
WE'VE BEEN ASKING YOUR ADVICE AS
THEY DISCUSS THE GUN CONTROL
LAWS.
>> FIRST UP, JENNIFER, WHO NOTES
THAT CONNECTICUT HAS SOME OF THE
TOUGHEST GUN LAWS IN THE ENTIRE
COUNTRY, SHE SAYS, "IT'S NOT
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
IT'S ABOUT GETTING A COUNTRY TO
EMBRACE VALUABLE CHARACTER
TRAITS AND PRACTICE THEM.
>> PAUL IS STRAIGHTFORWARD IN
SAYING, DETERRENCE IS THE
ANSWER.
NOT MORE GUN LAWS THAT CRIMINALS
WON'T ABIDE BY.
HIS FACEBOOK PROFILE, BY THE
WAY, SHOWS A MAN FIRING A RIFLE.
>> COMFORTING.
AND CALLING IT A COMPLEX ISSUE,
LISA SAYS CONGRESS NEEDS TO BE
THE PUBLIC SERVANTS THEY PURPORT
TO BE BY BANNING ASSAULT WEAPONS
AND HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES AND
INCREASING THE MENTAL HEALTH
TREATMENT SAFETY.
AND THE CONVERSATION WE'VE SEEN
SINCE FRIDAY, WHATEVER IS GOING
TO HAPPEN, WE DON'T KNOW WHAT
WILL HAPPEN, BUT IT'S GOING TO
BE SOMEWHERE WHERE GUN CONTROL
MEETS MENTAL HEALTH.
>> AND KEEP IN MIND, THE LAST
TWO MASSACRES THAT WE'VE HAD,
THIS ONE IN NEWTOWN, AND THE ONE
IN OREGON, WHICH WOUND UP WITH
TWO DEAD, AS WELL AS THE
SHOOTER, BOTH OF THOSE GUYS
STOLE THE WEAPONS.
SO THEY MAY HAVE BEEN IN THE
HANDS OF A RESPONSIBLE USER.
HOWEVER, THEY GOT THEIR HANDS ON
THEM.
>> THAT'S THE ABUNDANCE OF GUNS
IN THIS COUNTRY, 200 MILLION
GUNS.
THAT'S A SCARY STAT.
WE'LL BE BACK.
200 MILLION
GUNS.
WE'LL BE BACK.
HEY SIS,
IT'S SO GREAT
TO SEE YOU.
YOU, TOO!
OH, CLOUDY GLASSES.
YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME OVER!
ACTUALLY, HONEY,
I THINK I DID...
OH? YOU DID?
WHOA, LADIES, EASY.
HI.
CASCADE KITCHEN COUNSELOR.
WE CAN HELP AVOID THIS
WITH CASCADE COMPLETE PACS.
SEE, OVER TIME,
CASCADE COMPLETE PACS
FIGHT FILM BUILDUP TWO TIMES
BETTER THAN FINISH QUANTUM.
TO HELP LEAVE GLASSES SPARKLING
SHINY!
TOO BAD IT DOESN'T WORK
ON WINDOWS.
OKAY, I'M OUTTA HERE.
CASCADE. THE CLEAR CHOICE.
WHEN YOU GIVE A CHILD A TOY,
IT HAS TO WORK.
♪ MAKE JUST ONE SOMEONE HAPPY
AND WHEN
IT'S A TOYS FOR TOTS CHILD,
WELL, WHAT COULD BE
MORE IMPORTANT?
SO THIS YEAR, EVERY HASBRO TOY
DONATED TO TOYS FOR TOTS
WILL BE POWERED BY DURACELL.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
DURACELL WITH DURALOCK.
TRUSTED EVERYWHERE.
>>> MORE INTERESTING NEWS COMING
OUT OF THE BIG APPLE.
MAYOR BLOOMBERG HERE IS ALL
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
A FEW MONTHS AGO HE WAS ALL
ABOUT LIMITING THE SIZE OF SODAS
YOU CAN GET IN NEW YORK CITY.
NOW HIS OTHER PET ISSUE IS, HE'S
DONATED A LOT OF MONEY TO THIS,
STOPPING SMOKING.
ACCORDING TO A NEW YORK POLICE
REPORT, HE WANTS TO BAN NEW
YORKERS FROM SMOKING IN THEIR
OWN HOMES.
THEIR PRIVATE RESIDENCES.
THIS IS ACCORDING TO "THE POST"
HERE.
THE COMMUNITY GROUPS ARE GOING
TO BE SENT OUT TO CONVINCE
LANDLORDS ACROSS THE CITY TO
TURN THEIR PRIVATE BUILDINGS
INTO SMOKE-FREE ZONES.
THIS IS ACCORDING TO DOCUMENTS
OBTAINED BY "THE NEW YORK POST."
THESE GROUPS WOULD WORK WITH
PROPERTY MANAGERS AND TENANTS ON
THE ADOPTION OF VOLUNTARY
SMOKE-FREE POLICIES AND GET A
$10,000 BOUNTY IN RETURN FOR
THEIR WORK.
THE ADMINISTRATION, BLOOMBERG
FOLKS SAY THIS IS NOT TRUE, YOU
KNOW, THEY'VE BANNED IT IN
BEACHES AND PARKS BUT WE'RE NOT
GOING INTO PRIVATE RESIDENCES,
THEY SAY.
BUT ANTI-SMOKING IS A BIG
BLOOMBERG CRUSADE.
I DON'T THINK IT'S GOING TO GET
FAR.
BUT THERE ARE REPORTS OUT THERE.
>> IS HE GOING TO GO INTO MY
FRIDGE AND MAKE SURE I DON'T
HAVE TWO LITERS OF SODA?
>>> WE'VE SEEN THE AMAZING
ADVANCES IN TECHNOLOGY WHEN IT
COMES TO OUR PHONES.
IN JUST SIX YEARS, IBM IS
PREDICTING THERE COULD BE A
PHONE THAT COULD SMELL, HEAR,
TASTE, TOUCH, ALL THE SENSES,
ALL FIVE OF THEM.
FOR EXAMPLE, YOU COULD
EXPERIENCE THE SILKINESS OF
EGYPTIAN COTTON SHEETS JUST BY
TOUCHING YOUR PHONES.
DON'T WANT TO KNOW WHAT ELSE YOU
CAN EXPERIENCE.
IT'S GETTING DEEP HERE.
INFRARED TECHNOLOGY WILL ENABLE
THE TOUCH SCREEN TECHNOLOGY.
VIBRATION CAPABILITIES WILL BE
ABLE TO STIMULATE THE PHYSICAL
SENSATION OF TOUCHING SOMETHING.
AND WHILE WE'RE ON THE SUBJECT
OF PHONES, HERE'S AN APP THAT
MAYBE ANY OF US CAN DOWNLOAD ON
OUR iPHONE OR ANDROID AND THE
JAPANESE CAME UP WITH THIS.
IT'S AN APP THAT YOU CAN
DOWNLOAD ALLOWING YOU TO FLUSH
THE TOILET FROM YOUR PHONE AND
CLOSE THE LID.
>> I CAN PUT THE SEAT DOWN?
>> IT GOES ON SALE IN THE
SPRING, THIS TOILET CAN BE
COMPLETELY CONTROLLED BY THE
SMARTPHONE APP.
THE JAPANESE PUT AN EMPHASIS ON
YOUR GASTROINTESTINAL HEALTH,
TOO, AND IT'S GOING TO TRACK
YOUR MOVEMENTS AND YOUR
GASTROINTESTINAL HEALTH.
>> YOUR LITERAL MOVEMENTS.
>> YES.
>> THAT'S A LITTLE PERSONAL.
THAT'S A BIT MUCH.
WOULD YOU WANT SOMETHING THAT
PERSONAL ALL IN YOUR --
>> NO, NOT REALLY.
>> INTESTINAL TRACT AND ALL THAT
STUFF?
>> NO.
>> MAN.
ONE TRIP TO TACO BELL WOULD
CAUSE IT TO MALFUNCTION.
I DON'T THINK YOU WANT THAT.
MORE FROM ABC
>>> THIS MORNING ON "WORLD NEWS
NOW," UNSPEAKABLE GRIEF.
THE TEARFUL GOODBYES BEGIN IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WITH THE
FIRST FUNERALS SINCE FRIDAY'S
TRAGEDY.
>> WITH SO MANY SAD SCENES IN
NEWTOWN THIS WEEK, HOW CAN THIS
SMALL TOWN EVER RECOVER?
IT IS TUESDAY, DECEMBER 18.
>>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS
"WORLD NEWS NOW."
>>> GOOD TUESDAY MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
I'M ROB NELSON.
>> AND I'M PAULA FARIS.
IN JUST A MOMENT WE'LL TAKE YOU
LIVE TO NEWTOWN FOR THE LATEST
ON THE MEMORIALS AND WE'RE
GETTING NEW DETAILS EACH HOUR,
EACH MINUTE ON THE SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA, AND HIS MOTHER.
THE FAMILY HAD QUITE A TROUBLED
PAST.
WE'LL DIG INTO THAT COMING UP.
>> THE CENTER OF THIS IS THE
RELATIONSHIP THAT HE HAD WITH
HIS MOM THAT LED TO WHY HE
KILLED HER AND THE DIVORCE AND
THE ESTRANGED RELATIONSHIP WITH
THE DAD AND BROTHER.
THERE'S A FAMILY DYNAMIC HERE
THAT YOU HAVE TO WONDER IF
THAT'S WHAT LED TO THE VIOLENCE
WE SAW FRIDAY MORNING.
>>> ALSO TODAY, A SURVIVOR OF
THE AURORA, COLORADO MOVIE
THEATER SHOOTING ARRIVES NEAR
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
HE WANTS EVERYONE TO HEAR HIS
MESSAGE ABOUT GUN VIOLENCE,
CERTAINLY SPEAKING FROM
EXPERIENCE AFTER HE SURVIVED
THAT.
BEING HERE THAT MORNING WITH
AURORA.
THAT AWFUL SCENE.
>> SADLY, WE HAVE TO CLARIFY
WHICH MASSACRE WE'RE TALKING
ABOUT.
>>> AND REMEMBERING SENATOR
DANIEL INOUYE FROM HAWAII.
HIS LONG CAREER AND THE FOND
MEMORIES HIS COLLEAGUES ON
CAPITOL HILL ARE SHARING AND HIS
FINAL WORDS.
>> A LONG STORIED CAREER FOR THE
SENATOR THERE.
WE'LL GET TO THAT IN A SECOND.
BUT FIRST, OUR BIG STORY OF THE
WEEK, OF THE DAY, OF THE YEAR IN
MANY WAYS AND IN MANY CASES.
MIDDLE AND HIGH SCHOOL STUDENTS
RETURN TO CLASS THIS MORNING IN
NEWTOWN.
BUT THE CHILDREN WHO ATTENDED
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WILL BE
HOME FOR ANOTHER DAY.
>> AND THERE'S A MASSIVE
VOLUNTEER EFFORT TO GET THEIR
NEW SCHOOL READY FOR CLASSES AND
THERE ARE MANY MORE FUNERALS
TODAY.
ABC'S T.J.WINICK JOINS US FROM
NEWTOWN WITH THE LATEST.
HI, T.J.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
AS YOU MENTIONED, THE FIRST TWO
OF WHAT WILL EVENTUALLY BE OVER
TWO DOZEN SOMBER FUNERALS WERE
HELD YESTERDAY.
♪
THIS IS THE LIVING MEMORIAL IN
DOWNTOWN SANDY HOOK, WHERE A
CONSTANT STREAM OF LOCALS AND
VISITORS COME TO REMEMBER THOSE
LOST IN FRIDAY'S HORROR.
IN NEWTOWN, A FUNERAL FOR
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER, WHO WAS
EULOGIZED AS A BOY WHO LIKED
ANIMALS, VIDEO GAMES AND MEXICAN
FOOD.
AT HIS FUNERAL, AN ONLOOKER
COLLAPSED AS THE PROCESSION
PASSED.
INSIDE, HIS MOTHER SHARED
STORIES THAT HAD EVERYONE IN
TEARS.
>> SHE TOLD HIM, I LOVE YOU.
>> Reporter: A FEW MILES AWAY,
ANOTHER FUNERAL.
JACK PINTO, ALSO 6, A BIG SPORTS
FAN, WHOSE FAVORITE NEW YORK
GIANTS PLAYER, VICTOR CRUZ, WORE
HIS NAME ON HIS CLEATS DURING
SUNDAY'S GAME.
>> I WAS HONORED, MAN.
I COULDN'T EVEN EXPRESS TO THEM
HOW GREAT THAT MADE ME FEEL.
>> Reporter: JACK'S FRIEND FROM
THE WRESTLING TEAM SHOWED UP IN
THEIR LITTLE UNIFORM.
AT A NEWS CONFERENCE, THE
NORMALLY STOIC STATE TROOPER
CHOKED UP WHEN ASKING FOR
PRIVACY FOR THE FAMILIES.
>> AT THIS TIME, I CAN TAKE A
COUPLE QUESTIONS.
>> Reporter: HE ALSO REVEALED
THAT THERE WERE ACTUALLY TWO
ADULT SURVIVORS OF FRIDAY'S
RAMPAGE, NOT ONE.
BOTH FEMALE EMPLOYEES WITH
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
>> CERTAINLY THEY WILL SHED A
GREAT DEAL OF LIGHT ON THE FACTS
AND CIRCUMSTANCES OF THIS TRAGIC
INVESTIGATION.
>> Reporter: WITH THE SCHOOL
ITSELF REMAINING A CRIME SCENE
LIKELY FOR SEVERAL MONTHS, SANDY
HOOK STUDENTS WILL ATTEND AN
UNUSED MIDDLE SCHOOL IN A
NEIGHBORING COMMUNITY AND RETURN
TO CLASSES THERE ON WEDNESDAY.
ROB AND PAULA?
>> T.J., WHAT CAN YOU TELL US
ABOUT THIS FAMILY DYNAMIC, THE
GUNS, AS WELL AS WHAT
INVESTIGATORS FOUND IN THE LANZA
HOME?
>> Reporter: WELL, WHAT WE KNOW
IS THAT ADAM LANZA ACTUALLY
DIDN'T SEE HIS BROTHER, RYAN, OR
HIS FATHER PETER FOR TWO YEARS.
WE KNOW THOSE GUNS FOUND IN THE
HOME WERE PURCHASED OVER THE
LAST TWO YEARS, LEGALLY BY
ADAM'S MOTHER.
AND AS FOR THE COMPUTER THAT
INVESTIGATORS HAVE BEEN LOOKING
AT IN THE HOME, IT APPEARS THAT
WAS INTENTIONALLY DAMAGED.
LIKELY BY ADAM USING EITHER A
HAMMER OR A SCREWDRIVER.
WHAT INVESTIGATORS WILL
EVENTUALLY PULL FROM THAT HARD
DRIVE REMAINS TO BE SEEN.
>> THANKS TO ABC'S T.J. WINICK
LIVE FOR US IN NEWTOWN THIS
MORNING.
THANK YOU.
APPRECIATE THAT.
>>> IN TERMS OF THE GUNS IN THE
FAMILY, IF THE MOM KNEW HE WAS
TROUBLED AND KNEW SHE WAS LOSING
CONTROL OF HIM, WHY THEN WOULD
YOU LEAVE THE GUNS IN A PLACE
THAT HE WOULD HAVE ACCESS TO?
BUT WHO KNOWS -- NO ONE KNOWS
THE RELATIONSHIP OF THAT NATURE
EXCEPT THOSE TWO AND WE'LL NEVER
KNOW FROM THEIR MOUTHS WHAT IT
WAS.
BUT A LOT OF QUESTIONS.
SOME PEOPLE SAY THE SHOOTER
SHOULD NOT GET AS MUCH ATTENTION
AS THE VICTIMS, BUT IT'S SO
NATURAL TO WONDER WHAT LED
SOMEONE TO GET THAT DARK AND
THAT DAMAGED TO SHOOT UP A
CLASSROOM OF KIDS.
THOSE ARE FAIR, LOGICAL, NATURAL
QUESTIONS TO WONDER ABOUT.
>> YOU WANT TO GET INTO HIS HEAD
TO MAKE SURE WE PREVENT THIS
SORT OF TRAGEDY AGAIN.
>>> WE ARE LEARNING EVEN MORE
ABOUT GUNMAN ADAM LANZA, AS
POLICE STRUGGLE TO FIND A
POSSIBLE MOTIVE FOR HIS KILLING
SPREE.
THOSE WHO KNEW THE 20-YEAR-OLD
DESCRIBE HIM AS TROUBLED AND
INTENSELY SHY.
THEY SAY HE BARELY LEFT THE
HOUSE IN THE LAST FEW MONTHS.
FOR YEARS, HIS MOTHER NANCY TOLD
FRIENDS ABOUT HIS BEHAVIOR
PROBLEMS AND WORRIED SHE WAS
LOSING CONTROL OF HIM.
A FORMER BABYSITTER WAS TOLD,
DON'T LET HIM OUT OF YOUR SIGHT.
>> NEVER GO TO THE BATHROOM OR
TURN YOUR BACK ON HIM.
>> SHE HOME SCHOOLED HIM AND
EVERYTHING.
SO LIKE I SAY, I KNEW HE WAS ON
MEDICATION, BUT THAT'S ALL I
KNOW.
>> FRIENDS SAY IT WAS NANCY
LANZA WHO TOOK HER SON TO THE
FIRING RANGE AND INTRODUCED HIM
TO HIGH POWERED WEAPONS,
INCLUDING THE AR-15 RIFLE THAT
HE USED TO KILL HIS VICTIMS.
>> AS WIDELY EXPECTED, THIS
TRAGEDY HAS REIGNITED THE DEBATE
OVER GUN CONTROL IN THIS
COUNTRY.
FAMILY MEMBERS WHO HAVE LOST
LOVED ONES AND SURVIVORS GATHER
ON CAPITOL HILL LATER TODAY TO
DEMAND SOME KIND OF CHANGE.
>> AS LAWMAKERS OBSERVED A
MOMENT OF SILENCE, HONORING THE
VICTIMS, A NEW ABC NEWS POLL
FINDS MOST AMERICANS FAVOR
STRICTER LAWS.
KAREN TRAVERS HADS MORE ON THIS.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING ROB.
GOOD MORNING, PAULA.
ON SUNDAY NIGHT PRESIDENT OBAMA
SAID TRAGEDIES LIKE THE ONE THAT
HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, NEED TO END.
NOW THE BATTLE IS HEATING UP IN
WASHINGTON OVER HOW TO ACTUALLY
MAKE THAT HAPPEN.
HE DIDN'T USE THE WORD GUN
ONCE, BUT PRESIDENT OBAMA
PROMISED ACTION.
>> IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
IN AN EFFORT AIMED AT PREVENTING
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
>> Reporter: ASKED WHAT EXACTLY
THE PRESIDENT WILL DO, HIS
SPOKESMAN DIDN'T PROVIDE
SPECIFICS.
>> NO SINGLE PIECE OF
LEGISLATION, NO SINGLE ACTION
WILL FULLY ADDRESS THE PROBLEM.
>> Reporter: THERE ARE AN
ESTIMATED 200 MILLION PLUS GUNS
IN CIRCULATION IN THIS COUNTRY.
UNLESS YOU HAVE A FELONY
CONVICTION OR ARE DEEMED
MENTALLY INCOMPETENT BY A COURT,
YOU CAN GET ONE.
BUT COULD THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY BE
A TURNING POINT?
A NEW ABC NEWS/"WASHINGTON POST"
POLL FOUND THAT 54% OF AMERICANS
FAVOR STRICTER GUN
CONTROL LAWS IN GENERAL.
AND A MAJORITY SAY THE TRAGEDY
IN NEWTOWN INDICATES BROADER
PROBLEMS IN AMERICAN SOCIETY.
RATHER THAN THE ISOLATED ACT OF
A TROUBLED INDIVIDUAL.
WEST VIRGINIA DEMOCRAT JOE
MANCHIN SAID IT'S TIME TO
RETHINK OUR LAWS.
>> I DON'T KNOW ANYBODY THAT
NEEDS 30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP TO GO
HUNTING.
>> Reporter: AND ONE REPUBLICAN
LAWMAKER SAID IF THE SANDY HOOK
PRINCIPAL HAD BEEN ARMED, SHE
COULD HAVE STOPPED THE GUNMAN.
>> SHE TAKES HIM OUT, TAKES HIS
HEAD OFF BEFORE HE CAN KILL
THOSE PRECIOUS KIDS.
>> Reporter: MAYOR MICHAEL
BOOMBERING HAS BEEN A LONG-TIME
ADVOCATE FOR TOUGHER GUN LAWS.
DEMANDED PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
CONGRESS TO STEP UP.
>> WORDS ALONE CANNOT HEAL OUR
NATION.
ONLY ACTION CAN DO THAT.
>> Reporter: SEVERAL DEMOCRATIC
LAWMAKERS SAID THEY WOULD
INTRODUCE AN ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN
ON THE FIRST DAY OF THE NEXT
CONGRESS IN JANUARY.
ROB AND PAULA, BACK TO YOU.
>> THAT DOES BRING US TO OUR
FACEBOOK QUESTION OF THE DAY.
>> WHAT IS YOUR ADVICE TO
LAWMAKERS AS THEY DEBATE THE GUN
CONTROL LAWS?
JOIN THE HEATED DISCUSSION ON
OUR FAN PAGE AND WE'RE GOING TO
READ YOUR RESPONSES ON THE AIR.
AS SHE JUST ALLUDED TO THAT
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN WAS FROM
1994 TO 2004.
EXPIRED UNDER BUSH.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE LONG-TERM
EFFECTS, THEY SAID THERE WAS NO
CHANGE, MAYBE A SMALL DECREASE
IN THE MASS SHOOTINGS, BUT
OVERALL, NOT A DECREASE IN
VIOLENCE.
>> THE JURY IS OUT.
YESTERDAY, ACCORDING TO A 2004
UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA STUDY
ABOUT THE BAN, THE NUMBER OF
PEOPLE KILLED IN MASS SHOOTINGS
DID GO DOWN IN THE YEARS THE BAN
WAS IN EFFECT EXCEPT FOR '99.
THAT WAS COLUMBINE, AS WE ALL
REMEMBER.
BUT BECAUSE MASS SHOOTINGS ARE
RELATIVELY RARE, IT'S DIFFICULT
TO TELL WHETHER THIS WAS CAUSED
BY THE BAN.
THE PRESIDENT HAS GIVEN A LOT OF
LIP SERVICE TO GUN CONTROL
BECAUSE OF THE NATIONAL OUTRAGE.
BUT THIS IS A PRESIDENT WHO HAS
BEEN MUCH MORE FRIENDLY TO GUN
OWNERS THAN GUN CONTROL
ADVOCATES.
HE ALLOWED GUNS ON AMTRAK TRAINS
AND ALLOWED GUNS IN NATIONAL
PARKS.
HE GAVE LIP SERVICE TO GETTING
THIS BAN BACK IN EFFECT.
SO YOU HAVE TO WONDER NOW
BECAUSE THE TONE OF THE COUNTRY
BECAUSE OF SANDY HOOK WHETHER HE
WILL ACTUALLY DO SOMETHING OR
NOT.
BUT THIS HAS NOT BEEN ON HIS
AGENDA HIS FIRST TERM.
>> THAT ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN,
THERE WERE A LOT OF LOOPHOLES.
MAYBE THERE WON'T BE AS MANY
LOOPHOLES.
>>> MOVING ALONG, THE SANDY HOOK
TRAGEDY HAS HIM ON A MISSION TO
GET MORE GUNS OFF THE STREETS,
STEVEN BARTON WAS VISITING
AURORA, COLORADO, WHEN HE WAS
SHOT DURING THE MOVIE THEATER
MASSACRE.
HE HAPPENS TO LIVE IN
CONNECTICUT JUST A FEW MILES
FROM NEWTOWN AND HE'S HOPING THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING WILL BRING ABOUT
CHANGE.
>> OUR COUNTRY IS LONG OVERDUE
FOR A SERIOUS DISCUSSION ABOUT
GUNS, ABOUT MENTAL HEALTH.
>> BARTON ADMITS THAT GUN REFORM
MIGHT NOT HAVE BEEN ENOUGH TO
PREVENT THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY BUT
SAYS THERE SHOULD BE A BALANCE
BETWEEN OUR SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHT AS WELL AS PUBLIC SAFETY.
>> AND IN A MOMENT, OUR OTHER
BIG HEADLINE.
A MAJOR LOSS ON CAPITOL HILL.
>>> AND SENDING HEARTFELT
CHRISTMAS GREETINGS TO NEWTOWN
FAMILIES STRUGGLING OVER THE
HOLIDAYS.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
WE'RE GOING TO MOVE TO OTHER
NEWS ON THIS TUESDAY MORNING.
DANIEL INOUYE IS BEING
REMEMBERED FROM WASHINGTON TO
HIS HOME STATE OF HAWAII.
HE WAS A WORLD WAR II MEDAL OF
HONOR WINNER WHO LOST AN ARM TO
A GERMAN HAND GRENADE IN ITALY.
HE BECAME THE FIRST JAPANESE
AMERICAN IN CONGRESS AND SERVED
50 YEARS IN THE U.S. SENATE.
HIS DEATH WAS ANNOUNCED ON THE
SENATE FLOOR BY MAJORITY LEADER
HARRY REID.
>> THE KINDNESS THAT HE HAS
SHOWN ME FOR ME TIME HERE IN THE
SENATE HAS BEEN SOMETHING I WILL
CHERISH ALWAYS.
A MAN WHO HAS LIVED AND BREATHED
THE SENATE.
HE WAS THAT PATRIOT.
>> VERY KIND WORDS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ALSO A NATIVE OF
HAWAII TWEETED ALOHA YESTERDAY.
HE DIED YESTERDAY AT 88 YEARS
OLD.
>>> THERE IS PROGRESS IN TALKS
ON THE FISCAL CLIFF, BUT MAJOR
STICKING POINTS STILL REMAIN
WITH JUST TWO WEEKS TO GO.
A TOP REPUBLICAN SAYS THERE IS
DISAGREEMENT OVER SPENDING CUTS
VERSUS NEW TAXES AND UNTIL THAT
COULD BE WORKED OUT, THERE WON'T
BE ANY TALKS ABOUT THE SPECIFIC
DETAILS.
AND WALL STREET CLOSED HIGHER
OVER SIGNS OF THE TALKS.
THE DOW JONES ROSE 100 POINTS
FOR ITS BIGGEST GAIN OF THE
MONTH.
EARLY MARKETS OVERSEAS ALSO
HIGHER BECAUSE OF CAPITOL HILL
OPTIMISM.
AND A BOUNCE BACK IN CHINA'S
ECONOMY.
>>> A HOLIDAY MIRACLE FOR
DRIVERS AS PLUNGING GAS PRICES
HIT THEIR LOWEST POINT OF THE
YEAR.
AAA REPORTS THE PRICE OF GAS
FELL MORE THAN NINE CENTS A
GALLON LAST WEEK.
THE NATIONAL AVERAGE IS $3.25.
THE COST OF GAS IS DOWN 16%
SINCE SEPTEMBER.
THANKS TO INCREASING SUPPLIES,
GAS PRICES HAVE FALLEN EVERY DAY
THIS MONTH.
AND IT'S A SAFE BET THAT THE
MAKERS OF THE iPHONE RECOGNIZE A
MISTAKE WHEN THEY SEE IT.
THE NEW VERSION OF GOOGLE MAPS
THAT WAS DOWNLOADED, GET THIS,
10 MILLION TIMES IN THE FIRST 48
HOURS OF ITS RELEASE, THE APP IS
MAKING A TRIUMPHANT RETURN AFTER
APPLE REPLACED IT WITH ITS OWN
APPLICATION THREE MONTHS AGO.
THE MOVE WAS SUCH A DEBACLE, ONE
EXECUTIVE WAS FIRED AND APPLE
CEO TIM COOK WAS FORCED TO ISSUE
AN APOLOGY.
EVERYONE HATED THAT APP.
IT'S GOOD THEY RETURNED TO WHAT
WE ALL LIKE.
SO GOOD GOING, APPLE.
>> DID YOU DOWNLOAD IT YET?
>> I HAVE NOT, BUT TODAY I WILL.
>> THERE ARE INSTRUCTIONS FOR
OUR TECHNOLOGICALLY CHALLENGED
FOLKS.
>>> RETURNING TO OUR TOP STORY
IN JUST A MOMENT.
>> WHEN WE COME BACK, SOME
UNDERSTANDABLE JITTERS ON THE
WAY BACK TO CLASSROOMS.
MILLIONS OF STUDENTS AND PARENTS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY IN THE WAKE
OF SANDY HOOK.
STAY WITH US, EVERYBODY.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
STAY WITH US, EVERYBODY.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
>>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" CONTINUES
AFTER THIS FROM OUR ABC
STATIONS.
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYONE.
IT IS EASY TO FORGET THAT
CHRISTMAS IS JUST ONE WEEK AWAY,
AND SCHOOLS, THEY'RE IN THEIR
FINAL DAYS BEFORE HOLIDAY BREAK.
>> DOESN'T SEEM A LOT LIKE
CHRISTMAS TIME.
BUT NONE OF THOSE DAYS ARE
LIKELY TO BE AS NERVE-RACKING AS
YESTERDAY WAS.
THAT WAS THE FIRST DAY BACK
SINCE THE CONNECTICUT SHOOTINGS.
ABC'S AMY ROBACH REPORTS ON WHAT
WAS AN ANXIOUS MONDAY FOR MANY.
>> Reporter: PARENTS AROUND
INNATION DROPPED THEIR CHILDREN
OFF AT SCHOOL.
MANY HOLDING ON A LITTLE MORE
TIGHTLY.
A DAY OF JITTERS.
SCHOOLS FROM NEW YORK TO
TENNESSEE TO TEXAS ALL WENT ON
ALERT AFTER FEAR IGNITED SEVERAL
FALSE ALARMS, SOME BOMB THREATS.
OTHERS AS MINOR AS AN UMBRELLA
MISTAKEN FOR A GUN.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
RICHFIELD, CONNECTICUT, JUST 20
MILES FROM NEWTOWN, WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN AFTER SOMEONE REPORTED
A SUSPICIOUS PERSON.
SECURITY ON THE MINDS OF
PRINCIPAL, IT WAS A PRIORITY OF
SANDY HOOK'S OWN PRINCIPAL,
KILLED IN THE MASS SHOOTING.
WE SPOKE WITH HER BEST FRIEND.
SAFETY WAS IMPORTANT TO HER.
>> SAFETY WAS HER NUMBER ONE
PRIORITY.
SHE WANTED SCHOOL TO BE A SAFE
HAVEN.
A PLACE WHERE STUDENTS COULD
COME AND FEEL COMFORTABLE, LIKE
IT WAS THEIR SECOND HOME.
>> Reporter: FROM COAST TO
COAST, PRINCIPALS WERE
RE-EVALUATING SECURITY AND
TAKING EXTRA MEASURES TO PROTECT
THEIR STUDENTS.
IN PITTSBURGH, SECURITY GUARDS
NOW HAVE GUNS.
IN THIS CALIFORNIA SCHOOL, THE
DAY STARTED WITH THE MOCK
LOCKDOWN DRILL.
>> STAY IN LOCKDOWN MODE UNTIL
YOU HEAR AN ALL-CLEAR
ANNOUNCEMENT.
>> Reporter: THE OTHER CHALLENGE
FOR TEACHERS AND PRINCIPALS,
WHAT TO SAY TO STUDENTS.
>> WE TELL THEM THAT SOMEBODY
WHO WAS A VERY SICK PERSON MADE
SOME VERY POOR CHOICES, AND THAT
IS RARE THAT NORMALLY, USUALLY
SCHOOLS ARE SAFE PLACES.
>> Reporter: AND IN GEORGIA,
PARENTS LEFT NOTHING TO CHANCE,
WALKING THEIR KIDS ALL THE WAY
INTO SCHOOL, HAND IN HAND.
WHILE SOME PARENTS DECIDED TO
KEEP THEIR CHILDREN OUT OF
CLASS, EXPERTS RECOMMEND IT'S
BEST TO GET THEM BACK TO THEIR
NORMAL ROUTINE.
THAT'S MADE PARTICULARLY HARD
HERE IN CONNECTICUT WHERE THE
GOVERNOR ANNOUNCED A MOMENT OF
SILENCE ON FRIDAY.
>> THAT'S A NATIONAL MOMENT OF
SILENCE THAT HE WANTS THE NATION
TO RECOGNIZE THAT, AND HAVE
CHURCHES RING THE BELL 26 TIMES
IN HONOR OF THOSE KILLED.
I ASKED SUNNY YESTERDAY WHAT DID
YOU TELL YOUR KIDS?
>> YOU DON'T WANT TO TELL KIDS 7
YEARS OR UNDER NECESSARILY.
BUT FOR US THAT WORK IN THE
BUSINESS, THEY DIDN'T SEE WHAT
WAS GOING ON BUT THEY REACTED TO
WHAT WAS HAPPENING.
I SAID A BAD MAN DID VERY BAD
THINGS.
THESE KIDS WENT TO HEAVEN.
WE SAID A LITTLE PRAYER FOR
THESE CHILDREN.
I SAID, BUT THAT BAD MAN IS GONE
AND YOU CAN FEEL SAFE BECAUSE
WE'LL TAKE CARE OF YOU.
♪
>>> YOU SEE A LOT OF THOSE GREEN
AND WHITE BALLOONS, THE SCHOOL
COLORS FOR SANDY HOOK, YOU SEE A
LOT OF THOSE IN MEMORIALS AROUND
THAT TOWN.
FINALLY THIS HALF HOUR, SHOWING
EMPATHY AND OFFERING COMFORT IN
THE WAKE OF THIS TRAGEDY.
THEY HELD A CEREMONY HONORING
THE VICTIMS LAST NIGHT BEFORE
THE UCONN MEN'S BASKETBALL GAME.
>> PLAYERS WORE SPECIAL PATCHES
ON THEIR UNIFORMS.
A RECTANGLE WITH A GREEN
BACKGROUND AND THE LETTERS SH
RIGHT THERE ON THEIR FACE FOR
SANDY HOOK.
THE LADY HUSKIES WILL WEAR THE
GAME PATCH IN THEIR GAME
TOMORROW.
>> NICELY DONE.
>>> A MOTHER AND HER CHILDREN IN
GEORGIA ARE ABOUT TO SEND SOME
LOVE TO NEWTOWN, IN THE FORM OF
TEDDY BEARS AND OTHER STUFFED
ANIMALS, AS WELL.
>> IT'S A WORK OF MICHELLE AND
HER 9-YEAR-OLD SON AND
5-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER.
THEY COLLECTED MORE THAN 100
STUFFED ANIMALS ALREADY AND
THEY'LL CONTINUE COLLECTING THEM
FOR THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS.
>>> AND FURTHER NORTH IN NORTH
CAROLINA, 26 CHRISTMAS TREES ARE
BEING PREPARED TO BE SENT TO
CONNECTICUT.
THEY WERE SET UP JUST OUTSIDE
THE FIRE DEPARTMENT IN SANFORD,
NORTH CAROLINA AND DECORATED
WITH HAND MADE ORNAMENTS.
>> THE ORGANIZER SAID SHE GOT
INVOLVED BECAUSE SHE'S A MOTHER
AND HER WORST FEAR AS A MOTHER
WOULD BE TO LOSE A CHILD.
>> I GOT INVOLVED BECAUSE I
WANTED THE FAMILY TO KNOW THAT
THERE IS GOODNESS IN THIS WORLD
AND THROUGH THIS TRAGEDY, I
WANTED THEM TO FEEL LOVE FROM
ALL OVER.
>> SHE SAYS SHE'S HOPING MORE
PEOPLE WILL FEEL COMPELLED TO
DONATE MORE ORNAMENTS BEFORE
BEING SENT TO NEWTOWN.
WE'VE SAID SO MANY TIMES HOW
TRAGEDY LIKE THIS BRINGS OUT THE
BEST IN PEOPLE AROUND THE
COUNTRY.
THE GENERAL STORE FROM NEWTOWN
SAYS THEY'RE GETTING CALLS FROM
ALL OVER.
ONE CALLER GAVE A CREDIT CARD
FOR 500 BUCKS FOR FIRST
RESPONDERS AND CALLER FROM
CALIFORNIA CALLED THAT STORE AND
DONATED 125 BUCKS JUST FOR
COFFEE FOR CUSTOMERS.
>> WE FEEL SO POWERLESS IN THIS
SITUATION, BUT A WAY TO DO
SOMETHING ABOUT IT IS THE RANDOM
ACTS OF KINDNESS, THE TEDDY
BEARS, THE DONATIONS, BE A PART
OF IT.
IT FEELS LIKE YOU'RE PROVIDING
WHATEVER COMFORT YOU CAN, EVEN
THOUGH WE FEEL SOMEWHAT HELPLESS
IN THIS SITUATION.
>> MAYBE THE SMALLEST ACT MEANS
SO MUCH.
THE NATION IS WITH YOU AND
THINKING ABOUT YOU AND CARING
FOR YOU.
MORE FROM ABC NEXT.
>>> THIS MORNING ON "WORLD NEWS
NOW," TROUBLED PAST.
ADAM LANZA'S UPBRINGING, HIS
UNUSUAL BEHAVIOR AND NEW DETAILS
ABOUT HIS FAMILY.
>> THE YOUNG GUNMAN FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT AND THE
MANY UNANSWERED QUESTIONS SINCE
THE DEADLY TRAGEDY AT SANDY
HOOK.
IT'S TUESDAY, DECEMBER 18th.
>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS "WORLD
NEWS NOW."
>> GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
I'M PAULA FARIS.
>> AND I'M ROB NELSON.
WE'LL UPDATE THE INVESTIGATION
IN CONNECTICUT IN OUR TOP STORY
COMING UP IN JUST A SECOND.
AS OF COURSE, MOURNERS OVERCOME
WITH GRIEF PAY THEIR RESPECTS TO
THE FIRST TWO VICTIMS OF THE
SANDY HOOK SHOOTING.
A TOWN COMING TOGETHER IN SOME
ATTEMPT TO CARRY ON.
BUT AS YOU CAN SEE, THEIR
EMOTIONS STILL SO VERY RAW.
>> WE'RE GOING TO SEE SO MANY
FUNERALS THROUGHOUT THE WEEK.
IT WILL DEFINITELY BE A TRAGIC
SIGHT.
>> TWO DOWN, BUT 25, 24 MORE TO
GO FOR THOSE PEOPLE KILLED IN
THE SCHOOL.
>>> ALSO THIS MORNING, SCHOOL
CAMPUSES ON EDGE FROM COAST TO
COAST.
SECURITY IS FIRST AND FOREMOST
AS COPYCATS POSE THREATS THAT
POLICE ARE TAKING SERIOUSLY.
SAD THAT COWARDS OUT THERE WOULD
TAKE ADVANTAGE OF SUCH A TRAGIC
SITUATION.
>> THERE WAS ANOTHER SCARE AT A
SCHOOL DISTRICT LESS THAN 20
MILES FROM SANDY HOOK.
THEY HAD SCHOOLS ON LOCKDOWN.
ON TOP OF THAT, I COULDN'T GET
MY MIND AROUND THE IDEA, THERE
WAS A BOMB THREAT CALLED INTO
THAT VIGIL SUNDAY NIGHT.
SO UNBELIEVABLY SAD MOMENT,
SOMEONE WAS SICK ENOUGH TO CALL
IN AND THREATEN THE VIGIL AND
THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS
INSIDE.
>> SICK AND DEPRAVED.
>> JUST CAN'T YOUR MIND AROUND
SOME THINGS, FOLKS.
>>> ANOTHER MAJOR HEADLINE THIS
MORNING.
NASTY STORMS NEAR SEATTLE.
A TREE JUST MISSED A BABY'S
CRIB.
THE PARENTS ARE COUNTING THEIR
BLESSINGS, WHILE THE NATION'S
MIDSECTION GEARS UP FOR A MAJOR
SNOWSTORM.
WINTER STARTS THE 21st OR 22nd.
>> FRIDAY OR SATURDAY.
>> I HATE WINTER.
>> BUT THAT'S THE MAYAN
CALENDAR.
>> EXACTLY, YEAH.
>>> FIRST ON THIS TUESDAY, NEW
DETAILS ABOUT GUNMAN ADAM LANZA.
A LIFETIME OF BEHAVIORAL ISSUES
AND HIS MOTHER'S LOSING BATTLE
TO KEEP CONTROL OF HER YOUNGEST
SON.
>> AS MOURNERS GATHERED FOR THE
FIRST FUNERALS IN NEWTOWN,
INVESTIGATORS ARE UNCOVERING
TROUBLING DETAILS ABOUT THE
GUNMAN WHO TOOK SO MANY YOUNG
LIVES.
HERE'S ABC'S BRIAN ROSS.
>> Reporter: INCREASINGLY, ADAM
WAS SO TROUBLED HE WOULD NOT
LEAVE THE HOUSE.
AND HIS MOTHER, NANCY, THE LAST
FEW MONTHS, TOLD FRIENDS SHE WAS
LOSING CONTROL OF HER
20-YEAR-OLD SON.
>> IT WAS JUST GETTING A LITTLE
HARDER FOR HER AS TIME WENT ON.
>> Reporter: NANCY LANZA WAS A
REGULAR HERE AT THIS NEWTOWN BAR
AND RESTAURANT WHERE THE OWNERS
SAY SHE TOLD THEM ABOUT HER
STRUGGLES WITH ADAM'S BEHAVIORAL
AND EMOTIONAL PROBLEMS FOR
YEARS.
>> SHE HOME SCHOOLED HIM AND
EVERYTHING.
I KNEW HE WAS ON MEDICATION, BUT
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
>> Reporter: SINCE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AT SANDY HOOK THROUGH
HIGH SCHOOL, ADAM WAS KNOWN BY
CLASSMATES AS STRANGE, SEVERELY
SHY.
>> HE HATED LOOKING AT YOUR EYES
FOR MORE THAN A COUPLE SECONDS.
HE WOULD ALWAYS LOOK DOWN AT HIS
PAPER OR WHATEVER HE WAS DOING.
>> Reporter: A FORMER BABYSITTER
SAYS HE WAS TOLD BY THE MOTHER
TO NEVER LEAVE ADAM ALONE.
>> NEVER GO TO THE BATHROOM OR
TURN YOUR BACK ON HIM AT ANY
TIME.
>> Reporter: THE FORMER SCHOOL
SECURITY DIRECTOR, WHO BECAME
CLOSE TO ADAM WHEN HE WAS IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL TECH CLUB, SAID ADAM
HAD SEVERAL DISORDERS, INCLUDING
THE INABILITY TO FEEL PAIN.
>> IF HE CUT HIMSELF OR HURT
HIMSELF, HE WOULD NOT KNOW IT OR
FEEL IT.
SO WE WERE BEING VERY CAREFUL
WITH HIM.
>> Reporter: BUT DESPITE ADAM'S
ISSUES, NANCY LANZA TOOK HER SON
TO LOCAL FIRING RANGES AND
INTRODUCED HIM TO THE WORLD OF
HIGH POWERED GUNS, INCLUDING THE
BUSHMASTER AR-15 ASSAULT STYLE
WEAPON HE USED TO KILL HIS
VICTIMS.
DEMONSTRATED HERE IN A VIDEO
POSTED ON THE COMPANY YOUTUBE
CHANNEL, THE BUSHMASTER CAN FIRE
45 ROUNDS PER MINUTE, AND IT'S
THE MOST POPULAR STYLE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE IN THE
COUNTRY.
POLICE AND FEDERAL AGENTS ARE
WORKING ON ANOTHER KEY PIECE OF
EVIDENCE, A COMPUTER HARD DRIVE
FOUND IN THE LANZA HOME.
WHEN THEY FOUND IT, SOMEONE HAD
TRIED TO DESTROY IT WITH A
HAMMER OR SCREWDRIVER.
BUT AGENTS SAY WHILE THAT WILL
SLOW THEM DOWN, IT WILL NOT STOP
THEM FROM RECOVERING WHAT WAS ON
THE HARD DRIVE.
PERHAPS THE SECRETS THAT ADAM
LANZA WANTED NO ONE TO SEE.
BRIAN ROSS, ABC NEWS, NEW YORK.
>> PERHAPS FURTHER PROOF HOW
PREMEDITATED THIS THING WAS,
THAT HE TOOK THE TIME TO DAMAGE
THAT HARD DRIVE.
>> HE MENTIONED A FORMER ADVISER
SAID HE HAD A BIZARRE CONDITION
WHERE HE HAD THE INABILITY TO
TOUCH AND FEEL AND EMPATHIZE
WITH ANYTHING.
ANOTHER NEIGHBOR AND CLASSMATE
SAID ADAM LANZA HAD BEEN A WEIRD
KID SINCE WE WERE 5 YEARS OLD.
AS HORRIBLE AS THIS WAS, I CAN'T
SAY I'M SURPRISED.
WHY DIDN'T ANYBODY REACH OUT?
SO MANY OF THESE KIDS THAT ARE
LONERS AND WE KNOW THEY'RE
POSSIBLY GOING THROUGH A TOUGH
SITUATION, PEOPLE NEED TO REACH
OUT TO THEM.
AND BEFRIEND THEM.
>> HOPEFULLY THE GUN
CONTROL/MENTAL HEALTH DEBATE
THIS
COUNTRY IS ABOUT TO HAVE WILL
ANSWER SOME OF THOSE QUESTIONS.
>>> OLDER STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN
RETURNED TO CLASSES TODAY, BUT
THOSE WHO ATTENDED SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ITSELF ARE STILL
WAITING FOR THEIR NEW SCHOOL TO
GET READY.
ADMINISTRATORS HAVE NOT DECIDED
WHEN CLASSES AT NEARBY CHALK
HILL SCHOOL WILL BEGIN, BUT
STUDENTS WILL GET A CHANCE THIS
WEEK TO SEE THEIR NEW SCHOOL AND
BECOME MORE COMFORTABLE WITH THE
TRANSITION.
STILL NO WORD IF SANDY HOOK WILL
EVER OPEN AGAIN.
>>> THE SHOOTING HAS PEOPLE
TALKING AGAIN ABOUT GUN
OWNERSHIP IN AMERICA.
GUN STORES REPORT THAT SALES ARE
WAY UP AND TEXAS GOVERNOR RICK
PERRY SAYS HE'S OKAY WITH ARMING
TEACHERS IF IT KEEPS CHILDREN
SAFE.
HOWEVER, IN WASHINGTON, THERE'S
NEW PRESSURE ON THE PRESIDENT TO
DO SOMETHING TO CONTROL ACCESS
TO FIREARMS.
HERE'S ABC'S JAKE TAPPER.
>> Reporter: STANDING BEFORE THE
DEVASTATED FAMILIES OF SANDY
HOOK, THE PRESIDENT PLEDGED
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE
TRAGEDIES, TO SAVE FUTURE
CHILDREN.
>> BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE DO WE
HAVE?
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
>> Reporter: BUT A COUPLE
HUNDRED PEOPLE WHO MARCHED FROM
CAPITOL HILL TO THE OFFICES OF
THE NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION,
AND NEW YORK CITY MICHAEL
BLOOMBERG STANDING WITH VICTIMS
OF GUN VIOLENCE, THERE IS ONE
ISSUE TO CONFRONT -- ACCESS TO
GUNS.
>> THIS IS JUST RIDICULOUS.
THIS IS AN OUTRAGE.
WE ARE KILLING EACH OTHER.
AND WE'RE THE ONLY
INDUSTRIALIZED COUNTRY IN THE
WORLD DOING IT.
>> Reporter: PROPOSALS BEING
PUSHED IN CONGRESS INCLUDE
REINSTATING THE BAN ON CERTAIN
TYPES OF SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES,
WHICH EXPIRED IN 2004.
AND BANNING HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZINES.
EVEN SOME GUN STALWARTS SUCH AS
WEST VIRGINIA DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
JOE MANCHIN SOUNDED A BIT MORE
COMPROMISING.
>> I DON'T KNOW ANYONE IN THE
SPORTING OR HUNTING ARENA THAT
GOES OUT WITH AN ASSAULT RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW ANYBODY THAT NEEDS
30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP TO GO
HUNTING.
>> Reporter: WHITE HOUSE
OFFICIALS SAY THE PRESIDENT DOES
NOT ONLY VIEW THIS TRAGEDY
THROUGH THE LENS OF ACCESS TO
GUNS BUT FOCUS ON EDUCATION,
MENTAL HEALTH AND VIOLENT
POPULAR CULTURE.
WHILE THE PRESIDENT HAS
OCCASIONALLY TALKED ABOUT GUN
CONTROL --
>> WEAPONS THAT WERE DESIGNED
FOR SOLDIERS IN WAR THEATERS
DON'T BELONG ON THE STREETS.
>> Reporter: ACTION IS A
DIFFERENT MATTER.
CAN YOU NAME ONE THING THE
PRESIDENT HAS DONE IN THE LAST
FOUR YEARS TO HELP REMOVE
WEAPONS OF WAR FROM OUR STREET?
>> THERE'S NO QUESTION, JAKE,
THAT THE SCOURGE OF GUN VIOLENCE
IS A PROBLEM THAT HAS NOT
SUFFICIENTLY BEEN ADDRESSED.
>> Reporter: IN OTHER WORDS, NO.
MANY AMERICANS ARE TURNING IN
THEIR GRIEF TO WASHINGTON FOR
ANSWERS AS TO WHAT THEY CAN DO,
WHAT SOCIETY CAN DO TO PREVENT
FUTURE SANDY HOOKS.
THEY ARE SO FAR NOT HEARING ANY
ANSWERS FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
JAKE TAPPER, ABC NEWS, THE WHITE
HOUSE.
>> WELL DONE, JAKE.
>> WE WANT TO INVOLVE YOU IN THE
NATION'S DISCUSSION OVER
FIREARMS.
EVERYONE HAS AN OPINION ABOUT
THIS.
>> WHAT IS YOUR ADVICE TO
LAWMAKERS AS THEY DEBATE THE GUN
CONTROL LAWS?
VISIT OUR FAN PAGE, WNNFANS.COM.
AND LET US KNOW WHAT YOU THINK.
WE MAY READ SOME OF YOUR
RESPONSES ON THE AIR.
YOU HOPE THAT WE LOOK OUTWARD AS
A COUNTRY AND FIND OUT WHAT
OTHER COUNTRIES HAVE DONE.
IN FACT, IN AUSTRALIA IN '96,
AWFUL SHOOTING THERE, 35 DEAD IN
THAT.
THEY WENT ON A MASSIVE BUYBACK
PROGRAM AND STRENGTHENED THEIR
GUN LAWS THERE.
SO WHAT DID THEY DO?
SO THEY PROHIBITED PRIVATE
SALES, THEY REQUIRED THAT ALL
WEAPONS BE INDIVIDUALLY
REGISTERED TO THEIR OWNERS AND
THEY REQUIRED THAT GUN BUYERS
PRESENT A GENUINE REASON FOR
NEEDING EACH WEAPON AT THE TIME
OF PURCHASE.
SELF-DEFENSE DID NOT COUNT.
IN THE WAKE OF THE TRAGEDY,
SHOOTINGS WENT DOWN AND IT HAS A
90% PUBLIC SUPPORT.
THAT'S PERHAPS A MODEL WE CAN
LOOK TO.
>> AND THEY HAVEN'T HAD A
TRAVESTY SINCE.
SUICIDES ALSO WENT DOWN.
>>> AND SOME HEALING SPIRITS ON
FOUR LEGS HAVE ARRIVED TO
COMFORT THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN.
THERAPY DOGS, SOME WHO TRAVELED
FROM THE MIDWEST ARE PROVIDING
THAT SPECIAL KIND OF SUPPORT
THAT ONLY A LOVING CANINE CAN
PROVIDE.
>> THE ESPECIALLY TRAINED GOLDEN
RETRIEVERS ARE GETTING PLENTY OF
HUGS AND CUDDLES WHEREVER THEY
GO.
THEIR HANDLERS SAY JUST PETTING
THE DOGS CAN HELP PEOPLE FOCUS
ON SOMETHING ELSE, IF ONLY FOR A
FEW FLEETING SECONDS.
THERE WAS ANOTHER RESIDENT THAT
WAS TAKING HIS BULL DOG AROUND
JUST LETTING KIDS PET THE DOG.
JUST ANY SHORT DISTRACTION WOULD
HELP IN A TRAGEDY LIKE THIS.
SO WHATEVER IT TAKES IS A GOOD
THING.
>> A BREAK FROM REALITY.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, ANOTHER BIG
STORY WE'RE FOLLOWING.
THE INTENSE STORMS POUNDING THE
NORTHWEST.
>> AND LATER, GOING TO SCHOOL
WILL NEVER BE THE SAME SINCE
THIS NEWTOWN TRAGEDY.
THE SECURITY MEASURES TO KEEP
YOUR KIDS SAFE IS COMING UP ON
"WORLD NEWS NOW."
I LOVE HOW CLEAN MY MOUTH IS
AFTER A DENTAL CLEANING...
I JUST WISH
I COULD KEEP IT THIS WAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW YOU CAN.
WITH THE CREST PRO-HEALTH
CLINICAL LINE.
USED TOGETHER,
THEY HELP KEEP YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
THE TOOTHPASTE
ACTUALLY REDUCES PLAQUE.
AND THE RINSE REACHES ALL AREAS
AND IS CLINICALLY PROVEN TO
HELP PREVENT PLAQUE REGROWTH.
CREST PRO-HEALTH CLINICAL LINE.
TOGETHER, THEY HELP KEEP
YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
♪
>>> AND HE'S YOUR TUESDAY
FORECAST, EVERYBODY.
>>> AND HERE'S YOUR TUESDAY
RAIN AND SOME LIGHT SNOW FROM
SEATTLE TO PORTLAND.
WINDY WITH RAIN IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
UP TO 10 INCHES OF SNOW IN SALT
LAKE CITY.
WINTER STORM WATCHES FROM DENVER
TO GREEN BAY.
SHOWERS TAPER OFF FROM D.C. TO
NEW YORK.
SNOW SHOWERS IN NORTHERN NEW
ENGLAND.
>> 40s IN THE NORTHEAST.
NORTHWEST 70S FROM DALLAS TO NEW
ORLEANS.
AND JUST 20s IN SALT LAKE CITY
AND FARGO.
>>> THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST IS
GETTING A BREAK IN THE STORMY
WEATHER TODAY AFTER GETTING
SLAMMED BY BLINDING MOUNTAIN
SNOW, DRENCHING RAIN AND SOME
DAMAGING WINDS TO BOOT.
WINDS GUSTING AS HIGH AS 80
MILES AN HOUR, KNOCKED OUT POWER
TO THOUSANDS AND TOPPLED A HUGE
TREE THAT CRASHED INTO A HOME IN
WESTERN WASHINGTON.
THE LIMBS PUNCHED THROUGH THE
CEILING OF A BABY'S ROOM, JUST
NARROWLY MISSING THAT CRIB.
AND THE NEXT DOOR NEIGHBORS
WATCHED IT ALL UNFOLD.
>> MY MOTHER COMES SCREAMING,
ASKED ME TO COME DOWNSTAIRS AND
I SEE A TREE FALL INTO THE
NEIGHBOR'S YARD, HIT THEIR HOUSE
AND LOW AND BEHOLD IT'S THE
BABY'S ROOM.
THE BABY IS OKAY.
IT'S SO GREAT.
>> DESPITE THE DEBRIS THAT FELL
INTO HIS CRIB, THE BABY DIDN'T
SUFFER A SCRATCH.
GOOD ENDING.
>>> AND THE NORTHWEST BLIZZARD
HAS LEFT FOUR CONSTRUCTION
WORKERS STUCK ON A SNOWY OREGON
MOUNTAIN.
RESCUE WORKERS GOT WITHIN A FEW
HUNDRED YARDS OF THE CREW BUT
FORCED TO TURN AROUND WHEN THE
CONDITIONS WORSENED.
THE CREW WAS WORKING ON A CELL
PHONE TOWER.
THEY ARE SAFE, HOWEVER, IN A
SMALL CONCRETE BUILDING.
>>> THE $60 BILLION AID DEAL TO
HELP HURRICANE SANDY SURVIVORS
IS HITTING A SNAG IN THE SENATE.
THE DEBATE ON THE EMERGENCY
SPENDING BILL BEGAN YESTERDAY.
DEMOCRATS ARE TRYING TO PASS IT
BEFORE CHRISTMAS, BUT SEVERAL
REPUBLICANS ARE CONCERNED ABOUT
MEASURES ATTACHED TO THE BILL
AND THAT SEEMS TO BE THE HOLDUP.
>>> IN NEW JERSEY, SIGNS OF
PROGRESS IN THE RECOVERY.
SOME BUSINESSES REOPENED FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE SUPER STORM
SANDY HIT ABOUT SEVEN WEEKS AGO
NOW.
FAMILIES MAY BE ALLOWED TO MOVE
BACK TO THE COASTAL TOWN NEXT
MONTH.
PROGRESS IS SLOW AND COMING BUT
GOOD WHEN IT ARRIVES.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, WE'RE
RETURNING TO OUR TOP STORY, THE
TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK.
>> THE HEARTBREAKING FAREWELLS
AND THE BIG CHANGES IN THE
CLASSROOM ACROSS THE NATION,
COMING UP.
>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" CONTINUES
AFTER THIS, FROM OUR ABC
STATIONS.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVODY.
>>> WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
THERE ARE FOUR MORE FUNERALS
TODAY FOR VICTIMS OF LAST
FRIDAY'S MASSACRE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THREE MORE OF THOSE INNOCENT
LITTLE CHILDREN AND THE FIRST
TEACHER, VICKI SOTO, WILL BE
LAID TO REST TODAY.
JUJU CHANG WAS IN NEWTOWN.
AS THE FUNERALS GOT STARTED.
>> Reporter: UNDER A COLD,
STEADY RAIN, A WAVE OF COMMUNAL
GRIEF CONTINUES TO WASH OVER
NEWTOWN.
MEMORIALS GROWING IN SETS OF 20
FOR THE CHILDREN.
20 CHRISTMAS TREES.
20 POINSETTIAS.
20 ANGELS.
THE FIRST FUNERALS IN A TOWN
WHOSE FAITH IS BEING TESTED IN
WAYS IT COULD HAVE NEVER
IMAGINED.
FOR 6-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO, A
HUGE NEW YORK GIANTS FAN, WHOSE
FAVORITE PLAYER PAID TRIBUTE ON
HIS CLEAT.
AND NOAH POZNER, WHOSE TWIN
SISTER SURVIVED IN ANOTHER
CLASSROOM.
>> MAY THEIR SOULS BE BOUND UP
IN THE BOND OF LIFE ETERNAL.
>> Reporter: THE RABBI STRUGGLED
TO FIND THE RIGHT WORDS AT THE
PRAYER VIGIL FOR A NATION THAT
PAUSED TO JOIN NEWTOWN IN
MOURNING.
A MUCH TOUGHER TASK --
A EULOGY FOR A 6-YEAR-OLD, AS A
WOMAN COLLAPSED OUTSIDE IN
GRIEF, THE RABBI INSIDE TRIED TO
FIND WORDS TO COMFORT NOAH'S
GRIEVING MOTHER.
>> I WHISPERED TO HER, I LOOKED
AT HER WITHOUT FLINCHING AND I
SAID, YOU KNOW, I PERSONALLY
BELIEVE IN THE ETERNITY OF THE
SOUL.
>> Reporter: DID NOAH'S FAMILY
RESPOND TO THAT?
>> YES.
THAT WAS HELPFUL TO HER.
AT THE END, SHE RELEASED BLUE
AND WHITE BALLOONS INTO THE SKY,
UNTIL WE COULDN'T SEE THEM
ANYMORE.
THAT WAS A GOOD -- YOU KNOW, TO
LET IT GO.
SHE SAID, YOU KNOW, GO MY SON,
INTO THE BLUE SKIES.
GO, MY SON, INTO THE GREEN
PASTURES.
>> Reporter: JESSICA LOVED
HORSES AND ORCAS AND WAS DEVOTED
TO HER TWO YOUNGER SIBLINGS AND
LEFT BEHIND AN UNEXPECTED GIFT,
A DIARY.
>> I JUST OPENED THE BOOK AND IT
WAS EXACTLY WHAT I NEEDED,
BECAUSE IT SAYS I LOVE YOU SO
MUCH, MOMMA.
LOVE, JESSICA.
WITH A LITTLE HEART.
IT WAS LIKE SHE WAS, YOU KNOW,
TELLING ME THAT SHE'S WATCHING
US AND KNOWS HOW HARD THIS MUST
BE FOR US, AND SHE WANTS US TO
KNOW HOW MUCH SHE LOVED US AND
SHE KNOWS HOW MUCH SHE WAS
LOVED.
>> Reporter: OTHERS ARE TELLING
STORIES OF SURVIVAL.
>> THEY WERE SITTING THERE, AND
I HAD NO IDEA WHY THEY WERE
THERE.
>> Reporter: A NEIGHBOR FOUND
SIX CHILDREN HUDDLED AT THE END
OF HIS DRIVEWAY AND TOOK THEM
IN.
THEY HAD BEEN IN VICKI SOTO'S
FIRST GRADE CLASS.
>> THESE TWO BOYS KEPT SAYING,
WE CAN'T GO BACK TO SCHOOL, WE
CAN'T GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
OUR TEACHER IS DEAD.
MRS. SOTO, WE DON'T HAVE A
TEACHER.
AND I COULDN'T BELIEVE IT.
>> Reporter: THE SCHOOL NURSE
TOLD ABC'S GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS
HOW SHE CROUCHED UNDER HER DESK
AND HELD HER BREATH.
>> WHILE YOU'RE UNDER THERE, YOU
ACTUALLY SEE THE FEET OF THE
SHOOTER?
>> I COULD SEE HIM FROM THE
KNEES DOWN.
SEE THE LEGS.
>> RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU?
>> 20 FEET AWAY, FACING -- HIS
BOOTS WERE FACING MY DESK.
>> THEN HE TURNED AND WALKED
AWAY?
>> IT WAS SECONDS.
HE TURNED AND WALKED OUT.
AND I HEARD THE DOOR CLOSE.
>> Reporter: AND FOR THE RABBI,
THE TOUGH TASK OF EXPLAINING TO
THE FAITHFUL WHERE THE EVIL THAT
STRUCK LAST FRIDAY COMES FROM.
>> I DON'T BELIEVE THAT GOD DID
THIS.
I BELIEVE A CRAZY MAN DID THIS.
THE MEANING IN IT IS NOT TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND WHY GOD DOES
SOMETHING.
SOMEHOW WE GOT HERE.
WE HAVE TO NOT NECESSARILY
ALWAYS LOOK TOWARDS GOD BUT LOOK
TOWARDS HUMANITY AND SAY WHAT IS
IT THAT WE'VE DONE THAT HAS
CREATED THIS ENVIRONMENT.
>> Reporter: THE CLERGY OF THE
SMALL NEW ENGLAND TOWN SAY THAT
THE HORRORS OF LAST WEEK HAVE
HELPED BOND PEOPLE TOGETHER
SPIRITUALLY.
THE RABBI'S WORDS FOR ALL OF US
ARE THE SAME HE DELIVERED AT
NOAH'S FUNERAL.
>> DON'T TAKE ANYTHING FOR
GRANTED.
YOU HUG YOUR CHILDREN MORE.
YOU BECOME EVER PRESENT TO THE
FRAGILITY OF LIFE.
AND YOU LIVE LIFE FULLER.
>> Reporter: JUJU CHANG IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> IT'S STILL HEART WRENCHING.
AND SEEING THE FACES OF THOSE
PEOPLE.
WE SHOULD CLARIFY.
THE FUNERALS FOR THREE OF THE
KIDS WILL BE TODAY.
THE TEACHER, VICKI SOTO, HER
WAKE BEGINS TODAY.
SO THAT IS WHAT NEWTOWN WILL BE
DOING.
ALSO, ACCORDING TO A LOCAL PAPER
THERE, THE PARENTS WHOSE KIDS
SURVIVED CREATED A FUND CALLED
MY SANDY HOOK FAMILY FUND.
THE GOAL IS TO RAISE $2 MILLION.
ALREADY $21,000 ON THE FIRST
DAY.
It's time
to change the way we clean.
It's time to free ourselves
from the smell
and harshness of bleach.
And free ourselves from worrying
about the ones we love.
New Lysol Power & Free has more
cleaning power than bleach.
How?
The secret
is the hydrogen peroxide
formula.
It attacks tough stains
and kills 99.9% of germs.
New Lysol Power & Free.
Powerful cleaning that's
family friendly.
Another step forward
in our Mission for Health.
YOU'RE PLAYING TOMORROW.
[ coughs ]
♪
YOU CAN'T LET A COLD
KEEP YOU UP TONIGHT.
[ snores ]
VICKS NYQUIL.
POWERFUL NIGHTTIME 6-SYMPTOM
COLD & FLU RELIEF.
♪
[ sniffles, coughs ]
EXCUSE ME.
I NEED SOMETHING FOR
MY COLD SYMPTOMS. [ sniffles ]
WE'VE GOT DAYQUIL FOR DAY
AND NYQUIL FOR NIGHT.
[ thuds ]
YOU DIDN'T SEE THAT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RIGHT NOW AT WALGREENS
DAYQUIL AND NYQUIL
ARE JUST $10.99 WITH CARD.
♪
>>> AND FINALLY THIS HALF HOUR,
FOR MOST SCHOOLS AROUND THE
COUNTRY AND FOR MILLIONS OF
SCHOOL KIDS, THE LONG HOLIDAY
BREAK IS TANTALIZING CLOSE.
>> THE FINAL FEW DAYS BEFORE
VACATION BEGAN YESTERDAY WITH
UNDERSTANDABLE NERVES, AS WELL
AS INCREASED SECURITY.
ABC'S BRANDY JOINS US WITH MORE.
HI, BRANDY.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING.
THIS HAS BEEN A NERVE-RACKING
TIME FOR A LOT OF PARENTS
FOLLOWING THE SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
MANY ARE WONDERING IF THEIR
CHILDREN ARE SAFE.
SCHOOLS FROM COAST TO COAST
LOOKED VERY DIFFERENT MONDAY
MORNING.
FOLLOWING FRIDAY'S DEADLY
SHOOTING SPREE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> WE HAVE A HEIGHTENED PRESENCE
AROUND THE SCHOOLS AND CAMPUSES.
>> Reporter: NOT ONLY ARE MORE
OFFICERS MAKING THE ROUNDS,
>> STAY IN LOCKDOWN MODE UNTIL
YOU HEAR AN ALL-CLEAR
ANNOUNCEMENT.
>> Reporter: SEVERAL SCHOOLS ARE
PERFORMING LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
AND FOR THE FIRST TIME IN
BUTLER, PENNSYLVANIA, ARMED
GUARDS ARE NOW STANDING OUTSIDE.
>> WHAT THIS INCIDENT HAS
PROMPTED US TO DO IS NOT ONLY
ARM OUR OFFICERS, BUT NOW TO
POSITION ONE OF THOSE IN ALL OF
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS.
>> Reporter: THE HEIGHTENED
SECURITY COMES AFTER 20-YEAR-OLD
ADAM LANZA SHOT AND KILLED 20
YOUNG CHILDREN AND SIX ADULTS
LAST FRIDAY AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THE FACULTY AT SANDY HOOK HAD
TRAINED FOR THIS SCENARIO AND
INSTALLED A SECURITY CAMERA AT
THE LOCKED FRONT DOOR REQUIRING
PICTURE I.D.s TO GET IN.
DESPITE THAT, LANZA BROKE IN AND
NOW MANY PARENTS AT OTHER
SCHOOLS ARE ANXIOUS ABOUT THEIR
CHILDREN'S SAFETY.
>> I'M REALLY SCARED, BUT I HOPE
IT DOESN'T HAPPEN HERE.
>> Reporter: CITY LEADERS ACROSS
THE COUNTRY SPENT MONDAY
ASSURING PARENTS THEIR CAMPUSES
ARE SECURE.
>> WE HAVE SCHOOL SAFETY
OFFICERS.
WE HAVE AN EXTENSIVE
INTELLIGENCE OPERATION.
>> WE'RE GOING TO MAKE SURE OUR
KIDS ARE SAFE.
>> HAVE A GOOD DAY.
>> Reporter: AND MANY PARENTS
FEEL THEY CAN'T KEEP THEIR
CHILDREN FROM LEARNING BECAUSE
OF ONE KILLER.
>> THINGS HAPPEN IN THIS WORLD,
AND NO MATTER WHAT, YOU'VE GOT
TO KEEP GOING.
>> Reporter: SAFETY EXPERTS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE ANALYZING
WHAT WENT WRONG AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY AND WHAT SECURITY
CHANGES CAN BE MADE AT SCHOOLS
NATIONWIDE.
ROB AND PAULA?
>> WHAT'S SO SAD IS THEY HAD
JUST BEEFED UP THEIR SECURITY.
BUT I WASN'T ABLE TO TAKE MY
KIDS TO SCHOOL MONDAY MORNING.
I WAS WORKING.
BUT I ASKED MY HUSBAND, WAS
ANYTHING DIFFERENT?
HE SAID NO, THEY TRIED TO KEEP
IT AS NORMAL AS POSSIBLE.
BUT I NOTICED AS I WAS DRIVING
BY LATER IN THE AFTERNOON THAT
THEY DO HAVE BARS ON ALL OF THE
WINDOWS ON THE FIRST FLOOR.
THAT REASSURED ME A LITTLE BIT.
I HAD NEVER NOTICED THAT BEFORE,
BUT I'M NOW MORE COGNIZANT THAN
EVER.
>> IT USED TO BE FIRE DRILLS
WHEN WE WERE IN SCHOOL.
NOW IT'S LOCKDOWN DRILLS.
BUT AS SAD AS IT IS, THOSE
HIGH SPEED INTERNET AT HOME
ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOU CAN COUNT ON.
INTRODUCING AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
WITH MORE SPEED OPTIONS,
RELIABILITY
AND Wi-Fi HOT SPOTS THAN EVER.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW TO GET
U-verse HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
IT'S ALL THE SPEED YOU NEED
ALL AT A GREAT PRICE.
OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network
GIVES YOU MORE
OF WHAT YOU ENJOY ONLINE.
AND WITH AT&T,
OUR WIRELESS GATEWAY
TURNS YOUR HOME
INTO A PRIVATE Wi-Fi HOT SPOT
THAT CONNECTS
YOUR Wi-Fi DEVICES
AND CAN EVEN SAVE ON YOUR
SMART PHONE DATA USAGE AT HOME.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW
TO GET AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT INCLUDES ACCESS ON-THE-GO
TO OUR ENTIRE NATIONAL
Wi-Fi HOT SPOT NETWORK,
WITH OVER 30,000 HOT SPOTS.
AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET.
NOW ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOUR WHOLE HOUSE
CAN COUNT ON.
♪
>>> MAKING NEWS IN AMERICA THIS
MORNING.
>> IT WILL BE ANOTHER DAY OF
HEARTBREAKING FAREWELLS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AS FOUR
MORE FAMILIES PREPARE TO LAY TO
REST THEIR LITTLE ONES.
>>> PLUS, A MIXED MESSAGE.
FRIDAY'S MASSACRE PROMPTS CALLS
FOR SWIFT ACTION ON GUN CONTROL.
BUT SALES OF GUNS ARE SURGING.
>>> THE WIND, THE SNOW, SURE
SIGNS OF THE SEASON.
A SNOWSTORM IS MOVING ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, RIGHT IN TIME FOR THE
HOLIDAYS.
WE'LL SHOW YOU WHERE IT WILL
HIT.
>>> AND SWEET SUCCESS.
A LITTLE GIRL TAKES ON A BIG