>> Spinelli: OOH.
>> Ellie: I THOUGHT SANTA LIKED
MILK AND COOKIES.
>> Spinelli: YES. AND KISSING.
>> Ellie: I'D KISS YOU ALL THE
WAY TO THE NORTH POLE IF I
COULD.
>> Spinelli: WELL, YOU CAN.
>> Ellie: NO. NOT HERE.
PUBLIC DISPLAYS OF AFFECTION ARE
FROWNED UPON.
>> Spinelli: WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
GENERAL HOSPITAL IS NOTORIOUS
FOR ITS FRATERNIZING STAFF.
>> Ellie: WELL, THIS IS MY PLACE
OF WORK, DAMIAN, AND I TAKE MY
PROFESSIONAL IMAGE VERY
SERIOUSLY.
>> Spinelli: AS DO I.
WELL, MAYBE NOT TODAY.
>> Ellie: [ CHUCKLES ]
WELL, I THINK YOU LOOK ADORABLE.
>> Spinelli: IN A SEXY, BURLY
KIND OF WAY, RIGHT?
>> Ellie: ABSOLUTELY.
>> Spinelli: RIGHT.
>> Ellie: SO, GO TO PEDIATRICS
AND PASS OUT THOSE GIFTS.
>> Spinelli: OKAY.
YES, I AM DUE ALMOST ANY MOMENT,
I SUPPOSE.
>> Ellie: AND I AM DUE, AS WELL.
ON THE FOURTH FLOOR, DETECTIVE
FALCONERI'S SPERM AWAITS.
>> Lulu: HI.
>> Maxie: YOU GUYS JUST GOT
FINISHED DOING SOMETHING
NAUGHTY, DIDN'T YOU?
>> Dante: NO. WE DIDN'T.
>> Lulu: WHAT?
>> Maxie: YOU MISSED A FEW
BUTTONS.
>> Lulu: HAVE YOU GUYS BEEN
WAITING OUT HERE THE WHOLE TIME?
>> Olivia: WE JUST WANTED TO
MAKE SURE THAT EVERYTHING WENT
OKAY.
>> Dante: MOM --
>> Olivia: SORRY.
AND THEN I RAN INTO MAXIE, WHO
APPARENTLY HAS SOMETHING TO TELL
YOU.
>> Mac: I CAN'T MAKE THIS
DECISION FOR YOU, BUT YOU HAVE
TO BE TRUTHFUL -- TO YOURSELF,
TO LULU AND DANTE.
IF YOU DON'T WANT TO CARRY THEIR
CHILD, TELL THEM NOW SO THEY CAN
FIND SOMEONE ELSE.
>> Lulu: WHAT'S UP?
>> Sabrina: I HOPE YOU'RE RIGHT
ABOUT HER.
>> Felix: I'VE NEVER BEEN WRONG.
BUT THERE'S A FIRST TIME FOR
EVERYTHING.
>> Sabrina: WELL, DON'T LET IT
BE THIS TIME, BECAUSE WE NEED
HER.
>> Felix: WE?
>> Sabrina: THE NURSES BALL.
A COLLECTIVE "WE."
>> Felix: MM-HMM.
>> Sabrina: THIS ISN'T ABOUT
PATRICK.
I MEAN, IT IS --
IN A WAY.
WELL, A BIG WAY, ACTUALLY.
THE NURSES BALL WAS SO IMPORTANT
TO HIS WIFE.
AND WITHOUT LUCY COE, WE WON'T
BE ABLE TO GET IT OFF THE
GROUND.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
>> Anna: IS DUKE LAVERY ALIVE?
>> DR. Obrecht: I FEAR YOU'VE
LOST YOUR GRIP ON REALITY.
>> Anna: TELL ME!
>> Robert: SHE'S PERFECTLY SANE,
BUT YOU'RE IN THIS UP TO YOUR
NECK, SO START TALKING!
>> DR. Obrecht: NONSENSE.
I REFUSE TO JUSTIFY ANY OF THIS!
NO! DON'T!
>> Robert: NO!
I'LL BE DAMNED.
>> Anna: DUKE?
>> Duke: ANNA.
>> Robin: HEY, YOU.
[ Female Announcer ] THERE ARE
LOTS OF DIFFERENT WAYS
TO SAY GET WELL
TO YOUR LOVED ONES.
♪
THIS CAME FOR YOU, MOMMY.
[ Female Announcer ]
BUT IT TAKES THE TOUCH
OF KLEENEX® BRAND,
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE,
TO TURN A GESTURE
INTO A COMPLETE GIFT OF CARE.
[ barks ]
SEND YOUR OWN FREE
KLEENEX® CARE PACK...
FULL OF SOOTHING ESSENTIALS
AT KLEENEX.COM.
KLEENEX®.
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE.
AT KLEENEX.COM.
MAYBMAYBE YOU CAN'T.RE;
WHEN YOU HAVE MIGRAINES
WITH FIFTEEN OR MORE
HEADACHE DAYS A MONTH,
YOU MISS OUT ON YOUR LIFE.
YOU MAY HAVE CHRONIC MIGRAINE.
GO TO MYCHRONICMIGRAINE.COM
TO FIND A HEADACHE
SPECIALIST.
AND DON'T LIVE
A MAYBE LIFE.
BUT ALL YOU NOTICE IS HER
BEAUTIFUL, HEALTHY SKIN.
JERGENS ULTRA HEALING
MOISTURIZER
MAKES EVEN YOUR DRIEST SKIN
LOOK HEALTHIER, INSTANTLY.
WITH BEAUTIFUL SKIN
FROM JERGENS,
YOU'LL ALWAYS MAKE AN ENTRANCE.
JERGENS®.
THE BEAUTIFUL DIFFERENCE.
Here's a better idea.
Pillsbury Grands!
Flaky Layers Biscuits
In just 15 minutes
the light delicate layers
add a layer of warmth
to your next dinner.
Pillsbury Grands Biscuits
Let the making begin.
♪
Get her 1/3rd carat
diamond earrings
this week only just $29.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
DISCOVER THE TEMPTING LAYERS
OF FERRERO ROCHER.
A WHOLE HAZELNUT,
SMOOTH CHOCOLATY CREAM
INSIDE A WAFER SHELL,
COVERED IN MILK CHOCOLATE
AND HAZELNUT PIECES.
♪
FERRERO ROCHER.
MAKE YOUR MOMENTS GOLDEN.
>> Sabrina: WHY AM I SO NERVOUS?
I LOOK OKAY, RIGHT?
SHOULD I CHANGE?
>> Felix: INTO WHAT?
>> Sabrina: DON'T YOU THINK I
SHOULD?
>> Felix: EVEN IF I DID, THERE'S
NO TIME.
>> Sabrina: [ SIGHS ]
>> Felix: MAYBE IT'LL MAKE YOU
MORE RELATABLE.
LOOK, THE WOMAN BEHIND DECEPTION
AND CoeCoe HAS EVEN HAD A BAD
DAY.
>> Sabrina: THAT WOMAN?
>> Felix: USED TO BE A
LIBRARIAN.
>> Sabrina: WOW.
SHE'S COME A LONG WAY.
>> Felix: THERE'S LONG, AND THEN
THERE'S LUCY COE.
YOU EVER HEAR ABOUT THE RED
WEDDING?
>> Sabrina: ELIZABETH TOLD ME.
APPARENTLY, SHE WAS MARRYING
DR. QUARTERMAINE'S HUSBAND.
>> Felix: DON'T YOU MENTION A
WORD ABOUT THAT.
>> Sabrina: OH, NO, NO.
I WOULD NEVER -- THE LAST THING
I WOULD EVER WANT TO DO IS
EMBARRASS LUCY.
>> Felix: THAT'S MISS COE TO YOU
AND ME, OKAY?
>> Sabrina: AREN'T YOU GUYS
FRIENDS?
>> Felix: MM.
I MIGHT HAVE, UH, EMBELLISHED A
TAD.
>> Sabrina: HOW MUCH IS A TAD?
>> Felix: A LOT.
>> Sabrina: WAIT, BUT -- BUT YOU
WORK FOR HER, THOUGH, RIGHT?
LIKE, SHE KNOWS YOU.
>> Felix: [ SIGHS ]
I NEVER MET HER BEFORE IN MY
LIFE.
>> Lulu: IS EVERYTHING OKAY?
>> Maxie: PHYSICALLY, YES.
>> Lulu: IS SOMETHING ON YOUR
MIND?
>> Maxie: IT'S NOT A BIG DEAL.
IT'S ACTUALLY KIND OF A BIG DEAL
IN THE GRAND SCHEME OF LIFE.
>> Lulu: OKAY.
I'M SO SORRY, BUT I DON'T HAVE A
LOT OF TIME BECAUSE DANTE JUST
MADE THE -- DONATION.
I'M ABOUT TO GET MY EGGS
HARVESTED.
SO CAN WE TALK ABOUT THIS AFTER?
>> Maxie: IT WOULD MAKE ME FEEL
A LOT BETTER IF I COULD GET IT
OFF MY CHEST.
>> Ellie: EXCUSE ME. SORRY.
ARE YOU DETECTIVE FALCONERI?
>> Dante: YES, I AM.
>> Ellie: HI!
I DON'T BELIEVE WE'VE OFFICIALLY
MET.
ELLIE TROUT.
>> Dante: HI. [ CHUCKLES ]
>> Ellie: HERE TO WASH YOUR
SPERM.
>> Lulu: [ CHUCKLES ]
>> Dante: IT'S NOT VERY, UH,
FUNNY.
>> Ellie: OH, NO, DON'T BE
EMBARRASSED.
IT'S ALL PART OF THE PROCESS.
IS THAT THE SAMPLE?
>> Dante: YES.
>> Ellie: I WILL GO PREPARE THE
SPECIMEN.
>> Lulu: DO YOU KNOW IF
DR. WESTBOURNE IS READY FOR ME?
>> Ellie: YEAH.
YOU CAN HEAD TO PRE-OP.
AND AS SOON AS YOU'RE DONE WITH
THE EGG EXTRACTION, WE'LL GET TO
FERTILIZING.
>> Dante: W-WHY ARE YOU CRYING?
>> Olivia: OH, IT'S JUST SO
EXCITING!
IN A COUPLE OF HOURS, MAXIE IS
GONNA BE CARRYING YOUR BABY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR DOING THIS
FOR THEM.
IT SEEMS LIKE I'M THE ONE ON
HORMONES NOW, BUT I'M SERIOUS,
REALLY.
>> Maxie: IT'S REALLY NOTHING.
>> Lulu: NO. IT'S EVERYTHING.
>> Dante: WE SHOULD, UH, GET
MOVING.
>> Lulu: WE CAN BE A MINUTE
LATE.
DID YOU WANT TO TALK TO ME ABOUT
SOMETHING?
>> Maxie: I JUST WANTED TO WISH
EVERYONE WELL --
AND TELL OLIVIA THAT NO MATTER
WHAT SHE SAW AT KELLY'S, I WON'T
BE CARRYING A TALKING DOG.
>> Robin: AREN'T YOU GONNA HELP
ME?
[ DOOR OPENS ]
>> Mac: SPECIAL DELIVERY.
IS THIS A BAD TIME?
>> Emma: DADDY?
>> Patrick: IT'S NEVER A BAD
TIME TO SEE MY LITTLE GIRL,
RIGHT?
HI, HONEY.
HOW ARE YOU?
>> Emma: HI. GOOD.
>> Patrick: HOW WAS SCHOOL
TODAY?
>> Emma: GOOD.
WE MADE ORNAMENTS.
CAN WE HANG IT UP ON THE TREE?
>> Patrick: OF COURSE WE CAN.
TAKE THIS OFF, OKAY?
WHY DON'T YOU GO PUT YOUR
PAJAMAS ON FIRST, AND THEN YOU
CAN COME BACK DOWN, AND WE'LL
HANG THOSE ORNAMENTS UP, OKAY?
>> Emma: OKAY, DADDY.
>> Patrick: GIVE ME A KISS.
ALL RIGHT.
>> Mac: THANKS FOR A GREAT DAY.
I'D DO ANYTHING FOR THAT LITTLE
PRINCESS.
FOR YOU, TOO.
SO, LAY IT ON ME.
YOU LOOK LIKE YOU'VE SEEN A
GHOST.
>> Patrick: I DID.
I JUST SAW ROBIN.
>> Robin: PROBLEMS?
>> DR. Obrecht: APOLOGIES FOR
THE DELAY.
I RAN INTO A BIT OF TROUBLE.
>> Robin: MAYBE I WAS RIGHT.
MAYBE YOU ACTUALLY DO HAVE A
HEART AND ARE HAVING SECOND
THOUGHTS ABOUT KILLING ME.
>> DR. Obrecht: APPEALS TO MY
SENSITIVE SIDE WILL GET YOU
NOWHERE.
>> Robin: SO YOU ADMIT YOU HAVE
A SENSITIVE SIDE.
>> DR. Obrecht: I HAVE NO CHOICE
IN THE MATTER.
YOU HAVE TO BE ELIMINATED BEFORE
YOUR PARENTS FIND YOU.
>> Anna: OH, GOD.
IS IT REALLY YOU?
>> Duke: ANNA, YOU ARE SO
BEAUTIFUL.
>> Anna: OH, GOD, IS IT HIM?
>> Duke: IT'S ME.
>> Anna: IS IT HIM?
>> Duke: ANNA, IT'S ME.
ANNA!
IT'S REALLY ME.
I'M A LITTLE BIT WORSE FOR WEAR,
BUT IT'S ME.
>> Anna: ARE YOU HURT?
>> Duke: I'VE NEVER FELT BETTER
IN MY LIFE.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA HOW MUCH I'VE
WANTED TO SEE YOU.
>> Anna: IT'S YOU.
>> Duke: I KNEW YOU WOULD COME.
I KNEW THIS WOULD HAPPEN.
I KNEW IT.
MY HERO.
WHAT'S IT LIKE?
YEAH.
THE KITCHEN?
IT'S AMAZING.
LOTS OF UNEXPLORED SURFACES
AND TOUGH, GREASY MESSES
TO CLEAN.
OH.
WOW!
[ Male Announcer ] NOW
Scrubbing Bubbles HAS Fantastik
IN A HEAVY DUTY SPRAY THAT
EASILY CUTS THROUGH GREASE
OR A FOAM THAT LIFTS
AND PENETRATES GRIME.
SO ALL YOU DO IS WIPE.
LET ME AT THAT GREASE.
[ Male Announcer ] Scrubbing
Bubbles WITH Fantastik.
WE WORK HARD SO
YOU DON'T HAVE TO.
IN THE KITCHEN.
[ Female Announcer ]
SC Johnson, A FAMILY COMPANY.
[ Female Announcer ] LET
BETTY CROCKER DO THE MEASURING
AND GET A HEAD START
ON DELICIOUS HOMEMADE COOKIES.
♪
JUST POUR, MIX...LOVE.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
Natural dog food is the smart
choice.
Let's look at the brand that
proves it.
Nutro Natural Choice Dog Food.
It has natural sunflower oil and
B Vitamins
that guarantee a visibly shiny
coat.
With natural ingredients,
guaranteed to promote healthy
digestion.
Make the Natural Choice today.
YOUR MOUTH HAS BEEN
SNACKING, GIFT STACKING,
NUTCRACKING AND YELLOWING.
BECAUSE IF YOU'RE NOT
WHITENING, YOU'RE YELLOWING.
CREST WHITESTRIPS
REMOVE OVER 10 YEARS OF STAINS,
JUST IN TIME
FOR A WHITE HOLIDAY.
CREST 3D WHITE WHITESTRIPS.
JUST IN TIME
FOR A WHITE HOLIDAY.
SOFT, SWEET COCONUT COVERED
IN RICH, CREAMY CHOCOLATE.
ALMOND JOY AND MOUNDS.
UNWRAP PARADISE.
WHEN THE DOCTOR TOLD ME
THAT I COULD SMOKE
FOR THE FIRST WEEK...
I'M LIKE...YEAH, OK...
LITTLE DID I KNOW
THAT ONE WEEK LATER
I WASN'T SMOKING.
[ Male Announcer ]
ALONG WITH SUPPORT,
CHANTIX IS PROVEN
TO HELP PEOPLE QUIT SMOKING.
IT REDUCES THE URGE TO SMOKE.
SOME PEOPLE HAD CHANGES
IN BEHAVIOR,
THINKING OR MOOD,
HOSTILITY, AGITATION,
DEPRESSED MOOD AND SUICIDAL
THOUGHTS OR ACTIONS
WHILE TAKING
OR AFTER STOPPING CHANTIX.
IF YOU NOTICE ANY OF THESE
STOP TAKING CHANTIX AND CALL
YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY HISTORY OF DEPRESSION
OR OTHER
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS,
WHICH COULD GET WORSE
WHILE TAKING CHANTIX.
DON'T TAKE CHANTIX IF
YOU'VE HAD A SERIOUS ALLERGIC
OR SKIN REACTION TO IT.
IF YOU DEVELOP THESE
STOP TAKING CHANTIX
AND SEE YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
AS SOME CAN BE
LIFE-THREATENING.
IF YOU HAVE A HISTORY OF HEART
OR BLOOD VESSEL PROBLEMS,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
NEW OR WORSE SYMPTOMS.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU HAVE SYMPTOMS
OF A HEART ATTACK.
USE CAUTION WHEN DRIVING
OR OPERATING MACHINERY.
COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
INCLUDE NAUSEA,
TROUBLE SLEEPING
AND UNUSUAL DREAMS.
IT HELPS TO HAVE PEOPLE
AROUND YOU...
THEY SAY,
YOU'RE MUCH BIGGER THAN THIS.
AND YOU ARE.
[ Male Announcer ]
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF CHANTIX
IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
>> Sabrina: OKAY, SO, LET ME GET
THIS STRAIGHT.
YOU DON'T KNOW LUCY COE?
>> Felix: NOT IN THE "LET'S GET
DRUNK AND DISH" WAY, NO.
>> Sabrina: YOU SAID YOU NEVER
MET HER.
>> Felix: I HAVEN'T MET HER, BUT
I READ HER BIOGRAPHY.
>> Sabrina: NOT THE SAME THING.
>> Felix: YOU'D BE SURPRISED.
THE LADY GOT INTIMATE.
I DON'T KNOW HER, BUT I KNOW
HER.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
>> Sabrina: NO!
YOUR CLOSE PERSONAL RELATIONSHIP
WAS SUPPOSED TO GET ME IN THE
DOOR.
>> Felix: I BELIEVE I SAID I
WOULD GET US IN THE DOOR, AND I
WILL.
HAVE FAITH.
I'M CoeCoe's TOP SELLER.
>> Sabrina: ARE YOU?
>> Felix: MAYBE NOT TOP SELLER.
>> Sabrina: OH, MY GOD!
I THINK I'M HYPERVENTILATING!
>> Felix: NO.
YOU'RE GONNA TAKE A DEEP BREATH,
SQUARE YOUR SHOULDERS, CHANNEL
YOUR INNER OPRAH.
MARCH INTO THAT OFFICE AND
DEMAND THAT MISS LUCY COE
RESURRECT THE NURSES BALL.
>> Sabrina: WELL, MAYBE NOT
DEMAND, BUT FIRMLY SUGGEST.
>> Felix: LET'S NAIL THIS
MOTHER.
>> Bree: EXCUSE ME.
WHERE DO YOU THINK YOU'RE GOING?
>> Dante: EXCUSE ME.
YOU HAD ANOTHER VISION?
>> Lulu: WHAT WAS IT THIS TIME?
>> Olivia: THE S-SAME.
THE BABY OF A CANINE VARIETY.
>> Maxie: A DOG.
>> Olivia: IT WAS SITTING IN A
HIGH CHAIR AT KELLY'S, AND IT --
>> Dante: AND WHAT?
>> Olivia: IT -- SPOKE TO ME.
>> Dante: IN ENGLISH?
>> Lulu: WHAT DID IT SAY?
>> Olivia: IT SAID IT WAS REALLY
EXCITED FOR BABY-MAKING DAY.
HAND TO GOD, YOU GUYS.
IT -- IT CAN'T WAIT TO BE BORN.
>> Dante: OKAY, OKAY.
NO MORE. THAT'S IT.
NO MORE VISIONS, NO MORE DOGS,
NO MORE TALKING, OKAY?
>> Maxie: NO MORE TALKING DOGS.
>> Dante: WE'RE GONNA HAVE A
BEAUTIFUL, HEALTHY, HAPPY BABY,
OKAY, WITH TWO ARMS, TWO LEGS,
AND NO FUR.
YOU GOT IT?
>> Olivia: I KNOW.
HONEY, IT'S NOT LIKE I WANT THIS
TO KEEP HAPPENING.
IT JUST -- IT DOES. I'M SORRY.
>> Lulu: IT'S ALL RIGHT.
DON'T APOLOGIZE.
WE KNOW THAT YOU CAN'T HELP IT.
>> Olivia: IT PROBABLY DOESN'T
MEAN ANYTHING, YOU GUYS.
IT'S JUST THAT I'M SO EXCITED
ABOUT A PROSPECTIVE GRANDBABY.
IT'S JUST MAKING MY VISIONS GO
ALL WONKY OR SOMETHING.
>> Dante: OKAY. YOU READY?
>> Lulu: LET'S GO.
>> Dante: ALL RIGHT.
>> Maxie: I'LL BE THERE IN ONE
MINUTE.
I JUST NEED TO CALL MY MOM.
I TOLD HER I'D KEEP HER UPDATED.
>> Olivia: I LOVE YOU GUYS BOTH
SO MUCH.
>> Maxie: HEY! BREAK AN EGG!
IT'S FERTILITY HUMOR.
>> Mac: WHAT DO YOU MEAN, YOU
SAW ROBIN?
>> Patrick: RIGHT THERE.
RIGHT ACROSS THE ROOM, CLEAR AS
DAY.
AND I'M SOBER, MAC.
I HAVEN'T TAKEN ANY DRUGS IN
MONTHS.
>> Mac: I KNOW YOU HAVEN'T.
>> Patrick: THEN WHAT IS WRONG
WITH ME?
>> Mac: ARE YOU FEELING OKAY?
>> Patrick: ASIDE FROM SEEING MY
DEAD WIFE --
THE ONLY TIME I HAD
HALLUCINATIONS -- WHEN I WAS ON
THE DRUGS.
AND I HAVEN'T TAKEN ANY.
>> Mac: YOU AND EMMA HAVE BEEN
DOING GREAT.
>> Patrick: YEAH, SO WHY AM I
SEEING ROBIN NOW?
>> Mac: I'LL TELL YOU WHY.
>> Duke: I WISH WE COULD ENJOY
THIS REUNION, BUT, UH, WE BETTER
GET OUT OF HERE.
I'M SURE FAISON'S PREPARED FOR
MY POTENTIAL ESCAPE.
>> Anna: YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT HIM.
>> Robert: HE'S BEEN
NEUTRALIZED.
>> Duke: I DON'T KNOW HOW TO
THANK YOU, ROBERT.
>> Robert: WELL, YOU SHOULD
THANK ANNA.
SHE'S THE ONE THAT FIGURED THAT
THERE MIGHT BE ONE MORE PIECE
LEFT IN FAISON'S PUZZLE AND YOU
COULD ACTUALLY BE ALIVE.
I HOPE YOU DON'T MIND.
>> Duke: MIND WHAT?
OW!
>> Anna: ROBERT! REALLY!
>> Robert: JUST CHECKING.
>> Duke: I UNDERSTAND, AFTER
WHAT YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH.
YOU CAN DO ANY TEST THAT YOU
LIKE, BUT I THINK WE SHOULD DO
THEM ELSEWHERE.
>> Anna: FAISON IS IN CUSTODY.
HE CAN'T HURT US.
>> Duke: YES, BUT HE HAS PEOPLE.
HE HAS PEOPLE HERE.
HE HAS A WOMAN HERE THAT WOULD
DO ANYTHING FOR HIM.
I THINK SHE RUNS THE PLACE.
>> Robert: DR. OBRECHT.
>> Robin: DO MY PARENTS KNOW I'M
ALIVE?
ARE THEY HERE?
>> DR. Obrecht: WORD OF
ADVICE -- DON'T SPEND TIME
FRETTING OVER THINGS YOU CAN'T
CONTROL.
>> Robin: I HAVE A LIFE WAITING
FOR ME IN PORT CHARLES.
I HAVE A HUSBAND AND A DAUGHTER
WHO LOVE ME.
UHH!
PLEASE. I'M BEGGING YOU.
>> DR. Obrecht: I KNOW WHAT YOU
MUST THINK, ROBIN, BUT I'M NOT A
ROBOT.
I UNDERSTAND THE BOND BETWEEN
MOTHER AND CHILD.
>> Robin: WELL, THEN LET ME GET
BACK TO MY DAUGHTER.
>> DR. Obrecht: I CAN'T.
>> Robin: WHY NOT?!
>> DR. Obrecht: FAISON LEFT
INSTRUCTIONS.
FAILURE TO COMPLY COULD MEAN MY
OWN LIFE.
>> Robin: NO. PLEASE.
PLEASE.
>> DR. Obrecht: I'M SORRY FOR
ALL THE PAIN I'VE CAUSED YOU,
ROBIN.
THERE WON'T BE ANY MORE.
>> Robin: PLEASE.
YOU CAN'T DO THIS. PLEASE!
>> DR. Obrecht: I HAVE NO
CHOICE.
>> Robin: I'M BEGGING YOU.
>> DR. Obrecht: CLOSE YOUR EYES,
AND IT WILL BE LIKE FALLING
ASLEEP.
>> Robin: PLEASE.
MOM!
MOM! DAD!
[ GRUNTS ]
HELP ME!
I'M HERE! HELP!
HELP! STOP! LET GO!
♪
There's a place where the
sky is always blue
and the kids always eat their
vegetables.
Because the salad there is
always  served
with the
Original Hidden Valley Ranch.
It's the way Ranch is supposed
to taste.
And try Italians and
Vinaigrettes from Hidden Valley.
I'd like to thank eating right,
whole grain,
Multigrain Cheerios!
Mom, are those my jeans?
[ Female Announcer ] People
who choose more whole grain
tend to weigh less
than those who don't.
Multigrain Cheerios
YOU'RE PLAYING TOMORROW.
[ coughs ]
♪
YOU CAN'T LET A COLD
KEEP YOU UP TONIGHT.
[ snores ]
VICKS NYQUIL.
POWERFUL NIGHTTIME 6-SYMPTOM
COLD & FLU RELIEF.
♪
[ sniffles, coughs ]
EXCUSE ME.
I NEED SOMETHING FOR
MY COLD SYMPTOMS. [ sniffles ]
WE'VE GOT DAYQUIL FOR DAY
AND NYQUIL FOR NIGHT.
[ thuds ]
YOU DIDN'T SEE THAT.
[ Male Announcer ]
RIGHT NOW AT WALGREENS
DAYQUIL AND NYQUIL
ARE JUST $10.99 WITH CARD.
Whatever it takes, get to
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
[ Male Announcer ]
RIGHT NOW AT WALGREENS
Don't judge me!
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
>> Ellie: CAN I HELP YOU?
>> Olivia: UH, YEAH.
I'M -- I'M SORRY.
WE WEREN'T FORMALLY INTRODUCED.
I'M, UH, OLIVIA FALCONERI,
DANTE'S MOTHER.
>> Ellie: HI.
OH, YOU KNOW, THIS IS JUST THE
LAB HERE.
IF YOU'RE LOOKING FOR YOUR
FAMILY, THEY'RE IN --
>> Olivia: OH, NO, NO, NO, NO.
I KNOW WHERE MY FAMILY IS.
YOU'RE ACTUALLY THE PERSON THAT
I WANTED TO TALK TO.
>> Ellie: ME?
>> Olivia: YEAH.
I WAS HOPING THAT YOU COULD PUT
MY MIND AT EASE ABOUT SOMETHING.
>> Ellie: UH, YEAH. I'LL TRY.
ABOUT WHAT?
>> Olivia: I'M JUST A LITTLE BIT
CONCERNED ABOUT THE GOINGS-ON IN
THE LAB, YOU KNOW?
I JUST WANT TO KNOW FOR SURE
THAT NOTHING SCREWY GOES ON IN
THERE, YOU KNOW, LIKE SOME KIND
OF MIX-UP.
YOU KNOW, THE RIGHT EGG AND
WRONG SPERM.
YOU KNOW WHAT I'M TALKING ABOUT?
>> Ellie: HEAVENS NO.
IN FACT, THE HOSPITAL JUST
REVIEWED ITS PROTOCOL FOR ALL
HANDLING OF BIOLOGICAL
MATERIALS, AFTER, UH, A RECENT
SITUATION, AND CLOSED SOME
LOOPHOLES IN CHAIN OF CUSTODY.
>> Olivia: OKAY.
OKAY, GOOD. GOOD.
THAT IS EXACTLY WHAT I WANTED TO
HEAR.
[ CHUCKLING ] OKAY, THANK YOU.
>> Ellie: YEAH, YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> Olivia: YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU WOULD LAUGH IF YOU KNEW WHY
I WAS ASKING.
TO THINK I -- I THOUGHT THAT MY
GRANDBABY WAS GONNA --
[ GASPS ]
>> Felix: HELLO!
>> Bree: HELLO.
>> Felix: UH, WE'RE HERE TO SEE
THE FABULOUS MISS COE.
>> Bree: DO YOU HAVE AN
APPOINTMENT?
>> Felix: I DIDN'T QUITE GET
YOUR NAME.
>> Bree: PROBABLY BECAUSE I
DIDN'T GIVE IT.
BREE FLANDERS, CoeCoe SENIOR
VICE PRESIDENT OF MARKETING.
AND YOU ARE?
>> Felix: FELIX DuBOIS, BRAND
AMBASSADOR FOR CoeCoe PAR
EXCELLENCE.
>> Sabrina: SABRINA SANTIAGO,
STUDENT NURSE --
WITH VERY HIGH MARKS.
>> Bree: I WASN'T AWARE MISS COE
HAD A MEETING ON THE BOOKS WITH
A SALES REP AND -- CANDY
STRIPER.
>> Sabrina: WELL, IF WE COULD
JUST BEG A MOMENT OF MISS COE'S
TIME, WE -- UH, IT'S FOR A
REALLY GREAT CAUSE.
>> Bree: SO YOU DON'T HAVE AN
APPOINTMENT.
>> Felix: THE NEED JUST AROSE,
LIKE SO MANY MEN IN THE PRESENCE
OF MISS COE HERSELF.
>> Bree: SHOULD I BE CALLING
SECURITY?
>> Felix: AND FOR THE RECORD,
I-I'M NO MERE SALES REP.
I BROKE THE UPSTATE RECORD WIDE
OPEN.
I COULD SELL ROUGE TO MOTHER
TERESA.
>> Bree: SHE'S DEAD.
>> Felix: EXACTLY.
>> Bree: I KNOW ALL THE GOLDEN
DUCK-LEVEL SELLERS.
YOU ARE NO GOLDEN DUCK.
SO YOU CAN LEAVE OF YOUR OWN
ACCORD, OR SECURITY CAN ESCORT
YOU OUT.
AND FOR THE RECORD, YOUR
TERRITORY IS GETTING A NEW SALES
REP.
>> Felix: NO NEED TO GO NUCLEAR.
WE KNOW WHEN WE'RE NOT WANTED.
COME ON, SABRINA.
>> Sabrina: SPEAK FOR YOURSELF.
LET'S NAIL THIS MOTHER.
>> Felix: PLEASE HELP US.
>> Sabrina: I'M ON A MISSION TO
ORGANIZE A GALA BALL, AND IF I
NEED TO BUST THROUGH YOU TO DO
IT, THEN SO BE IT.
YEAH.
YOU BETTER GET USED TO THIS
FACE, MISS SENIOR V.P., 'CAUSE
I'M NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
>> Felix: ACTUALLY, I DON'T KNOW
HER VERY WELL.
>> Patrick: MAC, AM I GOING
CRAZY?
>> Mac: NO.
NO.
YOU'RE IN MOURNING.
>> Patrick: RIGHT.
MOURNING.
SO ARE YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE VISIONS OF ROBIN?
>> Mac: NO, BUT HER DEATH HAS
HIT ME IN OTHER WAYS.
YOU KNOW, THE THING I'VE LEARNED
ABOUT LOSS IS THAT ONCE YOU
THINK YOU GOT A HANDLE ON IT, IT
BLINDSIDES YOU ALL OVER AGAIN.
>> Patrick: I GET MISSING HER,
YOU KNOW.
I GET WANTING TO TALK TO HER AND
EVERYTHING, BUT -- WHEN I SEE
HER, IT'S LIKE SHE'S R-REAL.
>> Mac: HMM.
YOU KNOW, I, UM --
I WENT SHOPPING FOR CHRISTMAS
PRESENTS THE OTHER DAY.
I PICKED SOMETHING OUT FOR
FELICIA AND MAXIE --
YOU --
ANNA, EMMA.
AND AS I WAS LUGGING ALL MY BAGS
BACK TO THE CAR, I, UH, STOPPED
SHORT.
AND I MEAN I PHYSICALLY STOPPED
WALKING -- BECAUSE I REALIZED I
DIDN'T GET ANYTHING FOR ROBIN.
I MEAN, I DIDN'T EVEN HAVE A
PRESENT ON THE LIST FOR HER.
AND I PULLED MY PHONE OUT IN A
PANIC.
I WAS GONNA CALL YOU.
AND THEN --
AND ONLY THEN DID REALITY HIT
ME.
HEY.
THIS IS YOUR FIRST CHRISTMAS
WITHOUT ROBIN, OKAY?
YOU GOT TO CUT YOURSELF SOME
SLACK.
>> Patrick: I REMEMBER IT CLEAR
AS DAY LAST YEAR.
UH --
WE HAD BEEN THROUGH SO MUCH, AND
WE HAD COME OUT THE OTHER SIDE.
BUT SHE GOT ME AN EARLY
CHRISTMAS PRESENT.
SHE GOT ME A VIDEO CAMERA.
AND I DIDN'T REALLY PUT TWO AND
TWO TOGETHER AT THE TIME, BUT --
SHE KNEW THAT HER H.I.V. WAS
PROGRESSING TO AIDS, AND --
>> Mac: BUT IT HADN'T.
IT HADN'T.
ROBIN WASN'T SICK.
SHE WAS STRONG.
>> Patrick: BUT IT WAS OUR LAST
CHRISTMAS TOGETHER ANYWAY.
>> Robin: MOM! DAD! I'M IN HERE!
COME FIND ME!
MOM!
>> DR. Obrecht: IT'S NO USE.
YOUR PARENTS ARE BUSY ELSEWHERE.
[ GRUNTS ]
>> Duke: AS SOON AS I FIGURED
OUT WHO FAISON WAS, WHAT HE
WANTED, I TRIED TO STOP HIM, BUT
IT WAS ALMOST FUTILE.
HE WANTED YOU, ANNA.
HE HAD ME RELIVE EVERY MINUTE OF
OUR LIVES AND OUR ENTIRE
HISTORY.
AND, WELL, THE HARD PART WAS, AS
I DID THAT, I WANTED TO BE WITH
YOU.
IT MADE ME MISS YOU AND MISS US,
AND IT MADE IT HARDER, BECAUSE
THAT PSYCHOPATH WANTED TO BE
WITH YOU.
>> Anna: IN THE END, THAT ENDED
UP TO BE YOUR BEST WEAPON,
BECAUSE IT WAS THOSE LITTLE
INCONSISTENCIES YOU PUT IN THE
STORIES THAT -- I MEAN, THAT'S
WHAT TRIGGERED EVERYTHING.
IT WAS BRILLIANT.
>> [ CHUCKLING ] NO.
YOU WERE BRILLIANT.
I PUT LITTLE CODED MESSAGES IN
THERE JUST FOR YOU, IN AMONGST
THE TRUTH, AND YOU PICKED UP ON
THEM.
>> Anna: I THOUGHT THERE WAS
SOMETHING WRONG.
I COULDN'T, YOU KNOW -- BUT,
ACTUALLY, TO GIVE HIM HIS DUE,
IT WAS ROBERT THAT FIGURED IT
OUT.
>> Duke: OH, THEN I'M GRATEFUL
TO ROBERT.
>> Anna: I WISH I HAD REALIZED,
YOU KNOW.
I JUST --
>> Duke: I THOUGHT YOU HAD
REALIZED IT SOONER.
>> Anna: WHY DO YOU SAY THAT?
>> Duke: WELL, A COUPLE OF WEEKS
AGO, FAISON CAME HERE.
HE WAS FURIOUS.
I THOUGHT HE WAS GONNA KILL ME.
HE SAID I HAD RUINED HIS PLAN.
HE SAID ONE OF THE MEMORIES THAT
I HAD GIVEN HIM WAS FALSE AND
SOMEBODY PICKED UP ON IT.
I THOUGHT HE WAS TALKING ABOUT
YOU, AND, NO, HE WASN'T.
HE WAS TALKING ABOUT SOMEBODY
ELSE.
>> DR. Obrecht: SOON IT WILL ALL
BE OVER.
>> Robin: [ GRUNTING ]
>> Robert: ROBIN?
OH, YOU HAVE
A KEURIG VUE BREWER?
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
♪
This week only, the years
hottest games, each just $39.99.
Plus, members earn points
on every purchase.
At Kmart.
SOME AEROSOLS
MAY JUST MIX WITH THEM.
CAN FEBREZE REALLY REMOVE THEM?
WE ASKED REAL PEOPLE
WHAT THEY THOUGHT.
TAKE A DEEP BREATH FOR ME.
DESCRIBE THE SMELL.
IT'S VERY PLEASANT.
FRESH.
SOME KIND OF FLOWER MAYBE?
REMOVE THE BLINDFOLD...
AWWW, OH YUCK!
I DIDN'T SMELL ANY OF THAT!
FEBREZE AIR EFFECTS
DOESN'T MIX,
IT ACTUALLY REMOVES ODORS.
[ laughs ]
WOW, THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
JUST ANOTHER WAY FEBREZE
HELPS YOU BREATHE HAPPY.
Aunt Sally's
singing again.
It's a tradition,
honey.
[ singing
Christmas carols ]
mmmm.
[ Female Announcer ]
Make new traditions
with Pillsbury Grands!
Cinnamon Rolls.
[ Female Announcer ]
CURÉL ULTRA HEALING LOTION
REPAIRS AND RENEWS DRY SKIN
TWO TIMES BETTER THAN THE
LEADING ADVANCED LOTION.
DEVELOPED WITH
ADVANCED CERAMIDE THERAPY,
IT EVEN HELPS PREVENT
DRY SKIN FROM COMING BACK.
THANK YOU CURÉL.
SEE THE CURE IN CURÉL.
♪
[ Female Announcer ] WITH
ITS RICH, SILKY SMOOTH TASTE
THERE'S MAGIC IN EVERY PIECE
OF DOVE® DARK CHOCOLATE.
♪
>> Patrick: WHOA. WHOA.
LOOK WHO'S READY TO DECORATE.
>> Emma: ARE YOU STAYING, PAPA
MAC?
>> Mac: OH, SWEETHEART, I WISH I
COULD.
NO ONE LOVES STRINGING POPCORN
MORE THAN ME.
BUT I'VE GOT TO GO TO THE
HOSPITAL AND CHECK ON MAXIE,
OKAY?
>> Emma: IS SHE SICK?
>> Mac: UH, NO, NO.
MAXIE'S THE PICTURE OF HEALTH.
DON'T YOU WORRY.
>> Emma: THEN WHY IS SHE AT THE
HOSPITAL?
>> Patrick: WELL, BECAUSE, UM,
MAXIE'S DOING SOMETHING VERY
SPECIAL.
SHE'S HELPING SOMEONE OUT.
ACTUALLY, TWO PEOPLE.
AND IT'S VERY BRAVE, AND IT'S
SELFLESS.
AND I REALLY HOPE IT WORKS.
>> Emma: ME TOO, DADDY.
>> Mac: ME TOO.
GOODBYE.
>> Emma: BYE.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
>> Maxie: COFFEE?
[ CHUCKLES ]
>> Dante: [ EXHALES DEEPLY ]
THANKS.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
IS THIS SUPPOSED TO BE TAKING
THIS LONG?
>> Maxie: IT HASN'T BEEN THAT
LONG.
>> Dante: WELL, IT'S BEEN, LIKE,
20 MINUTES.
>> Maxie: SHE'S IN SURGERY.
>> Dante: NO. NOT SURGERY.
IT'S A PROCEDURE.
MINOR -- MINOR PROCEDURE.
>> Maxie: RIGHT, ONE THAT HAS
NEXT TO NO RISKS, SO SHE'LL BE
FINE.
JUST DRINK YOUR COFFEE.
>> Dante: THAT -- THAT -- IS
THAT --
>> Maxie: DECAF? YEAH.
YOU'RE SHAKY ENOUGH.
I AM, TOO, FOR THAT MATTER.
>> Dante: THANK YOU.
>> Maxie: I'M TRYING TO CUT DOWN
ON MY CAFFEINE INTAKE, TOO.
>> Dante: NO, I'M NOT TALKING
ABOUT THE COFFEE.
I'M --
I'M JUST -- I'M TALKING ABOUT
ALL OF IT.
MAXIE, YOU'RE LITERALLY MAKING
OUR DREAMS COME TRUE.
>> Maxie: YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> Dante: IF IT WORKS.
>> Maxie: DANTE, IT'S GONNA
WORK.
EVERYTHING WILL BE FINE, I
PROMISE.
>> Dante: YEAH?
NO DOG BABIES?
>> Maxie: NO DOG BABIES.
>> Olivia: IT'S HIM.
>> Spinelli: HUH?
>> Olivia: AGAIN!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WHAT ARE -- WHAT ARE YOU TRYING
TO TELL ME ABOUT MY GRANDCHILD,
HUH?!
YOU TALK TO ME!
>> Spinelli: I-I DON'T THINK
HE -- HE TALKS.
I-I -- PERHAPS TO OTHER CANINES.
>> Olivia: YOU'RE ACTUALLY
HOLDING THAT PUPPY.
>> Spinelli: UH, I AM. MM-HMM.
>> Olivia: HE IS NOT A
HALLUCINATION.
>> Spinelli: NO. NO.
I ASSURE YOU, ROCCO IS VERY
REAL.
>> Olivia: HIS NAME IS ROCCO?
>> Spinelli: YEAH.
HIS OWNERS LOANED HIM OUT FOR A
VERY -- A VERY WORTHY CAUSE.
ROCCO AND I WENT UP TO THE
PEDIATRIC WING AND HANDED OUT
PRESENTS TOGETHER, AND YOU WERE
QUITE THE HIT, WEREN'T YOU, CUTE
BOY?
>> Olivia: THERE'S NOTHING CUTE
ABOUT THAT THING!
>> Ellie: I TAKE IT YOU'RE NOT
A -- A DOG PERSON.
>> Olivia: OH, I LIKE DOGS JUST
FINE.
I JUST DON'T LIKE DOGS THAT RIDE
AROUND IN BABY CARRIERS, AND I
DEFINITELY DON'T LIKE DOGS THAT
MAXIE GIVES BIRTH TO.
>> Bree: WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
>> Felix: SABRINA, GET UP.
>> Sabrina: I'M COMMITTING AN
ACT OF CIVIL DISOBEDIENCE.
FELIX, SIT.
>> Felix: I DON'T SIT IN THESE
PANTS.
THEY'RE COUTURE.
>> Bree: THIS IS OUTRAGEOUS.
PROTESTING FOR A PARTY?
>> Sabrina: IT'S NOT A PARTY.
IT'S A BALL.
>> Felix: AND NOT JUST ANY BALL.
>> Sabrina: IT'S A NURSES BALL,
FOR CHARITY.
DOESN'T THIS COMPANY HAVE A
PROUD HISTORY OF CORPORATE
PHILANTHROPY?
>> Felix: HELL TO THE YES.
AND A MISSION STATEMENT.
"TO EVEN OUT THE LINES OF ALL
FACES -- AND THE WORLD."
>> Sabrina: WELL, WE'VE GOT A
PRETTY LONG LINE IN NEED OF
EVENING OUT.
OR IS THIS COMPANY NO LONGER IN
THE GOOD-DEEDS BUSINESS?
>> Bree: YES, IT IS, AND I
ADMIRE YOUR DEDICATION.
BUT CONNING YOURSELVES INTO THIS
OFFICE -- NOT THE WAY TO GO.
>> Felix: SO TELL US THE WAY.
PLEASE. TELL US THE WAY.
>> Bree: WE HAVE AN ENTIRE
DEPARTMENT DEDICATED TO
CHARITABLE GIVING.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST CALL --
>> Sabrina: NO!
WE NEED TO SPEAK TO LUCY COE.
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE WHO CAN
RESURRECT THE NURSES BALL.
>> Bree: AND YOU BELIEVE THIS
BECAUSE WHY?
>> Sabrina: BECAUSE SHE WAS THE
ORIGINAL FORCE BEHIND THE NURSES
BALL.
IT WAS CREATED TO BENEFIT THE
FIGHT AGAINST H.I.V. AND AIDS.
LUCY COE SAW PEOPLE DEAR TO HER
HEART WHO WERE SUFFERING FROM
THIS AWFUL DISEASE.
AND EVEN WHEN PEOPLE DIDN'T KNOW
MUCH ABOUT IT BACK THEN, EVEN
WHEN PEOPLE WERE SCARED, SHE HAD
THE GUTS TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT
IT.
AND THE BEST PART -- IT WORKED.
THE GENERAL HOSPITAL NURSES BALL
RAISED HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS OF
DOLLARS.
>> Felix: BUT THERE HASN'T BEEN
A NURSES BALL IN PORT CHARLES IN
YEARS.
MISS COE MOVED ON.
>> Sabrina: AND NO ONE TOOK UP
HER MANTLE UNTIL NOW.
BUT WE CAN'T DO IT ALONE.
>> Bree: YOU NEED MONEY.
>> Sabrina: WE NEED LUCY COE,
AND I TRULY BELIEVE THAT SHE
WOULD WANT TO HELP US.
BUT WE WON'T KNOW UNLESS WE ASK.
>> Anna: YOU'RE SAYING THAT
FAISON ACTUALLY SAID SOMEONE
ELSE KNEW HE RUINED HIS PLAN?
WHO?
>> Duke: WELL, THAT'S ALL I GOT
OUT OF HIM AT THE TIME.
ANNA, IT'S BEEN A WHILE, BUT I
KNOW THAT LOOK.
>> Anna: OH, SORRY.
>> Duke: DON'T BE SORRY.
TELL ME, WHAT ARE YOU THINKING?
>> Anna: WELL, I DON'T KNOW WHO
ELSE OTHER THAN ME KNOWS YOU
WELL ENOUGH TO BE ABLE TO GET IN
FAISON'S WAY.
NO.
>> Duke: WHAT?
WHAT IS IT?
>> Anna: NO. IT'S NOT POSSIBLE.
>> Duke: ANNA, NOTHING IS
IMPOSSIBLE.
LOOK AT YOU AND I HERE IN THIS
ROOM.
ANYTHING IS POSSIBLE.
WHO ARE YOU THINKING ABOUT?
>> Anna: IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE
SENSE, THAT'S ALL.
>> Duke: WHO?
>> Anna: ROBIN.
>> Robert: ROBIN! YOU'RE ALI --
STEP AWAY FROM MY DAUGHTER!
OH, BABY. ARE YOU HURT?
YOU ALL RIGHT?
>> Robin: I KNEW YOU'D FIND ME.
I'M OKAY.
>> Robert: I'LL TAKE YOU OUT OF
THIS.
>> Robin: NOW HOW TOUGH DO YOU
FEEL, DR. OBRECHT?
LET ME INTRODUCE YOU TO MY
FATHER -- ROBERT SCORPIO.
>> Robert: I DOUBT THAT THAT'S A
VITAMIN SHOT, SO LEAVE IT THERE,
ALL RIGHT?
>> DR. Obrecht: AS YOU WISH.
>> Robin: DAD --
>> Robert: YEAH.
]
♪
[ snoring ]
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING ZZZQUIL SLEEP-AID.
[ snoring ]
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S NOT FOR COLDS,
IT'S NOT FOR PAIN,
IT'S JUST FOR SLEEP.
[ snoring ]
[ Male Announcer ] BECAUSE
SLEEP IS A BEAUTIFUL THING.
[ birds chirping ]
INTRODUCING ZZZQUIL,
THE NON-HABIT FORMING SLEEP-AID
FROM THE MAKERS OF NYQUIL.
♪
BECAUSE FOUR OUT OF FIVE DOGS
OVER THE AGE OF THREE
DEVELOP GUM DISEASE,
AND TARTAR BUILDUP
IS A CONTRIBUTING FACTOR.
[ Dog ] OR NEW DENTASTIX FRESH.
CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO FIGHT TARTAR
AND NOW WITH ADDED INGREDIENTS
TO FIGHT DOG BREATH, TOO.
as part
of a heart healthy diet.
That's true.
...But you still have to go
to the gym.
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
DISCOVER THE TEMPTING LAYERS
OF FERRERO ROCHER.
A WHOLE HAZELNUT,
SMOOTH CHOCOLATY CREAM
INSIDE A WAFER SHELL,
COVERED IN MILK CHOCOLATE
AND HAZELNUT PIECES.
♪
FERRERO ROCHER.
MAKE YOUR MOMENTS GOLDEN.
WITH LESS CHRONIC
OSTEOARTHRITIS PAIN.
IMAGINE LIVING YOUR LIFE
WITH LESS CHRONIC
LOW BACK PAIN.
IMAGINE YOU, WITH LESS PAIN.
CYMBALTA CAN HELP.
CYMBALTA IS FDA-APPROVED
TO MANAGE CHRONIC
MUSCULOSKELETAL PAIN.
ONE NON-NARCOTIC PILL A DAY,
EVERY DAY,
CAN HELP REDUCE THIS PAIN.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOUR MOOD WORSENS,
YOU HAVE UNUSUAL CHANGES
IN MOOD OR BEHAVIOR
OR THOUGHTS OF SUICIDE.
ANTIDEPRESSANTS
CAN INCREASE THESE
IN CHILDREN, TEENS,
AND YOUNG ADULTS.
CYMBALTA IS NOT APPROVED
FOR CHILDREN UNDER 18.
PEOPLE TAKING MAOIS
OR THIORIDAZINE
OR WITH UNCONTROLLED GLAUCOMA
SHOULD NOT TAKE CYMBALTA.
TAKING IT WITH
NSAID PAIN RELIEVERS, ASPIRIN,
OR BLOOD THINNERS
MAY INCREASE BLEEDING RISK.
SEVERE LIVER PROBLEMS,
SOME FATAL, WERE REPORTED.
SIGNS INCLUDE ABDOMINAL PAIN
AND YELLOWING SKIN OR EYES.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ALL YOUR MEDICINES,
INCLUDING THOSE FOR MIGRAINE
AND WHILE ON CYMBALTA,
CALL RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU HAVE HIGH FEVER,
CONFUSION AND STIFF MUSCLES
OR SERIOUS ALLERGIC
SKIN REACTIONS
LIKE BLISTERS, PEELING RASH,
HIVES, OR MOUTH SORES
TO ADDRESS POSSIBLE
LIFE-THREATENING CONDITIONS.
TALK ABOUT YOUR ALCOHOL USE,
LIVER DISEASE
AND BEFORE YOU REDUCE
OR STOP CYMBALTA.
DIZZINESS OR FAINTING MAY OCCUR
UPON STANDING.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CYMBALTA.
IMAGINE YOU WITH LESS PAIN.
CYMBALTA CAN HELP.
GO TO CYMBALTA.COM
TO LEARN ABOUT
A FREE TRIAL OFFER.
>> MR. FALCONERI?
>> Dante: UH, YES, YES. HI.
>> Lulu: HI.
>> Dante: HEY.
SO, HOW'D IT GO?
>> DR. WESTBOURNE SAID, AND I
QUOTE, "EVERYTHING WENT
SWIMMINGLY."
>> Maxie: MORE FERTILITY HUMOR.
I LIKE HER.
>> SHE'LL BE IN TOUCH LATER TO
GIVE YOU A DETAILED RUNDOWN.
>> Dante: THANK YOU.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
IF YOU DON'T NEED ANYTHING ELSE,
I'M OFF TO DELIVER LULU'S EGGS
TO THE LAB.
>> Dante: I-I THINK WE'RE GOOD.
>> Lulu: WE'RE GREAT.
>> Dante: OKAY.
I THINK I CAN TAKE IT FROM HERE.
>> OKAY.
>> Dante: HEY.
SO, HOW YOU DOING?
>> Lulu: THEY GAVE ME DRUGS.
>> Dante: YEAH, I CAN SEE THAT.
>> Lulu: BUT IT'S GOOD.
EVERYTHING'S OKAY.
YOU WANT TO KNOW WHY?
>> Dante: WHY?
>> Lulu: BECAUSE IT'S GONNA
WORK.
WE'RE GONNA HAVE A BABY.
I CAN FEEL IT IN MY HEART.
I JUST DO.
>> Dante: ME TOO.
[ SMOOCHES ] YEAH, ME TOO.
>> Olivia: SERIOUSLY, WHAT COULD
THIS MEAN, OKAY?
THE -- THE PUPPY THAT I
HALLUCINATED AS DANTE AND LULU'S
BABY IS NOW -- IT'S -- IT'S HERE
STANDING RIGHT IN FRONT OF ME
FOR REAL.
WHAT -- WHAT COULD THIS MEAN?
YOU GUYS GOT ANY IDEAS?
>> Spinelli: NOT AT THE MOMENT,
NO.
>> ELLIE.
>> Ellie: YES?
>> I HAVE MRS. FALCONERI'S EGGS.
>> Ellie: OH. "EGGSELLENT."
GET IT?
>> Spinelli: [ CHUCKLING ] WELL
DONE.
>> Ellie: UH, WELL, IF YOU'LL
EXCUSE ME, I HAVE SOME
FERTILIZING TO DO.
>> Olivia: WAIT! WAIT!
WAIT A SECOND!
THAT -- THAT -- THAT DOG'S NOT
GOING INTO THE LAB WITH YOU, IS
IT?
>> Ellie: NO, OF -- OF COURSE
NOT.
THAT COULD CAUSE ALL MANNER OF
CONTAMINATION.
>> Olivia: OKAY. OKAY.
OKAY, GOOD.
SO PROMISE ME -- PROMISE ME --
THAT NO DOGS OR ANIMAL -- LET'S
JUST SAY NO ANIMALS WITH ANY FUR
OF ANY KIND ARE GONNA GET
ANYWHERE NEAR MY
DAUGHTER-IN-LAW'S EGGS, OKAY?
>> Ellie: I PROMISE.
>> Spinelli: YEAH.
>> Olivia: OKAY.
>> Spinelli: YOU MIGHT WANT TO
RELINQUISH YOUR GRIP OVER THERE.
>> Olivia: I'M SORRY. I'M SORRY.
I'M SORRY.
GO -- GO DO YOUR THING.
GO. GO. FERTILIZE.
>> Ellie: OKAY.
>> Spinelli: YOU KNOW,
THERE'S -- THERE'S NOTHING TO
WORRY ABOUT, THOUGH, ADMITTEDLY,
I'M NOT QUITE SURE OF THE ROOT
OF YOUR CONCERN, ANYWAY.
BUT, UH, ELLIE IS MASTERFUL AT
HER JOB.
>> Olivia: WAIT, WAIT, WAIT!
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
>> Spinelli: WELL, I GOT TO
RETURN ROCCO TO HIS OWNER.
>> Olivia: OH, NO, NO, YOU
DON'T.
THIS -- THIS LITTLE GUY -- HE'S
STAYING WITH ME.
>> Spinelli: I'M SORRY, BUT I'M
RESPONSIBLE.
I HAVE TO GET HIM BACK --
>> Olivia: NO, NO, NO.
THERE'S SOMETHING SHIFTY ABOUT
HIS FACE, YOU KNOW, AND I'M NOT
LETTING HIM OUT OF MY SIGHT
UNTIL I KNOW, FOR ABSOLUTELY
CERTAIN, THAT MY
DAUGHTER-IN-LAW'S EGGS ARE
FERTILIZED WITH DANTE'S SPERM.
>> Felix: COME ON, SABRINA.
SHE'S TOO CAUGHT UP IN THE
TRIPLE P's TO LOOK BEYOND THEM
AND DO ANY GOOD.
>> Sabrina: TRIPLE P's?
>> Felix: PEARLS, PARK AVENUE,
AND POWER PLAY.
>> Sabrina: ISN'T THAT
QUADRUPLE --
>> Felix: YOU GET MY DRIFT.
>> Bree: YOU'RE WRONG.
THE TRUTH?
THESE JEWELS, THIS OUTFIT, THIS
LIFE DIDN'T ALWAYS FIT ME.
I BEGAN MY CAREER IN MUCH
DIFFERENT CIRCUMSTANCES.
>> Sabrina: WHAT DID YOU DO?
>> Bree: I PROVIDED COMFORT TO
MEN.
>> Felix: YOU WERE A HOOKER?
>> Bree: I PREFER "SEX WORKER."
>> Felix: IS THERE A DIFFERENCE?
>> Bree: TO ME.
>> Sabrina: HERE IN NEW YORK?
>> Bree: NEVADA.
THE WOMAN WHO LOOKED AFTER THE
GIRLS LIKE ME --
>> Felix: THE MADAM.
>> Bree: HER NAME WAS RENEE, AND
SHE CARED ABOUT US.
>> Sabrina: EVEN THOUGH SHE MADE
YOU --
>> Bree: NOBODY MADE US DO
ANYTHING.
IT WAS OUR CHOICE TO BE THERE.
IT WAS HER CHOICE TO MAKE SURE
THAT WE STAYED HEALTHY.
"SAFE SEX OR NO SEX," RENEE
ALWAYS SAID.
AND YEARS LATER, I INSISTED UPON
THE SAME.
>> Felix: YOU BECAME A MADAM?
>> Bree: I DID.
NO GIRL OF MINE WAS GONNA GET
SICK -- NOT ON MY WATCH.
SO DON'T SAY I DON'T CARE.
>> Sabrina: IS THIS YOUR WAY OF
SAYING WE CAN SEE MISS COE?
>> Patrick: OKAY.
YEAH.
YOUR PLACEMENT IS IMPECCABLE.
IT'S PERFECT.
>> Emma: DO YOU LIKE IT?
>> Patrick: I LOVE IT.
YOU DID A REALLY GOOD JOB ON
THAT THING.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
YOU WANT TO DO THAT REST?
>> Emma: WELL, CAN WE HANG OUR
STOCKINGS FIRST?
>> Patrick: YEAH.
WE CAN DO THAT.
WE'RE JUST GONNA HAVE TO FIND
THEM.
>> Emma: WILL WE PUT UP MOMMY'S,
TOO?
>> Patrick: WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> Emma: I THINK MOMMY HAS ONE
IN HEAVEN, BUT WE SHOULD PUT IT
UP ANYWAYS, IN CASE SANTA MAKES
A MISTAKE AND BRINGS HER
PRESENTS HERE.
>> Patrick: I THINK THAT'S A
REALLY GOOD IDEA.
WE WOULDN'T WANT HER TO NOT HAVE
ANY PRESENTS, WOULD WE?
THERE'S MOMMY'S, RIGHT THERE.
COME HERE.
>> Duke: I DON'T KNOW WHY I
DIDN'T THINK OF ROBIN.
SHE WAS ALWAYS A BRIGHT GIRL.
SHE'D SEE STRAIGHT THROUGH
FAISON.
>> Anna: THAT'S NOT WHAT I MEAN.
>> Duke: WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
>> Anna: SHE PASSED AWAY, DUKE.
>> Duke: NO.
MY BONNY LITTLE LASS.
OH, ANNA, I'M SO SORRY.
>> Anna: [ SNIFFLES ]
I MEAN, THAT'S -- THAT'S WHAT WE
WERE LED TO BELIEVE.
>> Duke: I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
>> Anna: THERE WAS AN EXPLOSION
AT THE HOSPITAL WHERE SHE
WORKED, AND --
>> Duke: SO SHE DID BECOME A
DOCTOR?
>> Anna: YEAH, YEAH. YEAH.
SHE WAS A REALLY, REALLY GOOD
DOCTOR.
SHE WAS GREAT.
BUT, UM, WE WERE TOLD THAT HER
BODY HAD BURNED, YOU KNOW, AND
WE COULDN'T REALLY SEE IT.
AND SO WE BURIED HER AND TRIED
TO GET ON WITH YOUR LIVES, WHICH
IS IMPOSSIBLE.
IT'S JUST --
SO THEN -- THERE'S THIS UNHINGED
WOMAN WHO DOESN'T REALLY CARE
FOR ME VERY WELL, AND SHE TOLD
ME THAT SHE HAD SEEN ROBIN IN
THIS INSTITUTION IN PORT
CHARLES.
>> Duke: WHY WOULD SHE WANT TO
DO THAT?
>> Anna: BECAUSE SHE WAS PLAYING
WITH MY MIND, YOU SEE?
>> Duke: SO SHE WAS LYING TO
YOU?
>> Anna: YEAH.
WELL, NOW I AM NOT SO SURE,
BECAUSE -- IT TOOK ME ON THIS
TRAIL --
WHICH LED ME RIGHT HERE.
>> Duke: TO SWITZERLAND?
>> Anna: HERE --
TO THIS CLINIC -- TO A PADDED
CELL RIGHT HERE.
>> Duke: YOU'VE BEEN HERE
BEFORE?
>> Anna: YEAH.
>> Duke: BUT YOU DIDN'T FIND
ROBIN?
>> Anna: NO.
IT WAS JUST A YOUNG WOMAN THAT
LOOKED LIKE HER.
I THOUGHT THE WHOLE THING WAS A
MIND GAME.
[ SNIFFLES ]
BUT THE FACT THAT IT LED ME HERE
TO THIS PLACE, TO THIS CLINIC,
WHICH IS FAISON'S BASE --
>> Duke: THAT'S NOT A
COINCIDENCE.
>> Anna: RIGHT?
RIGHT? I'M NOT CRAZY, AM I?
I MEAN, THINK ABOUT IT.
IF HE WANTED ME, MAYBE HE WANTED
ROBIN.
AND HE WAS GONNA GET AN INSTANT
FAMILY.
AND -- SO ROBIN COULD BE HERE.
MAYBE HE BROUGHT HER HERE.
MAYBE SHE'S HERE, AND MAYBE
SHE'S ALIVE.
[ SNIFFLES ]
I MEAN, YOU SAID ANYTHING IS
POSSIBLE.
>> Duke: ANYTHING'S POSSIBLE,
ANNA.
>> Anna: [ SNIFFLES ]
>> Duke: IF ROBIN'S ALIVE --
AND SHE'S HERE --
WE'RE GONNA FIND HER.
WE'RE GONNA FIND HER TOGETHER.
>> Robin: DAD!
DAD, BE CAREFUL!
>> DR. Obrecht: [ GRUNTING ]
>> Robin: DAD!
LET GO!
DAD!
>> DR. Obrecht: [ GRUNTS ]
>> Robin: DAD!!
DAD.
DAD!
DAD, CAN YOU HEAR ME?!
>> Robert: SORRY, ROBIN.
>> Robin: WHAT WAS IN THE
SYRINGE?
WHAT'S IN IT?!
>> DR. Obrecht: NOT THE OUTCOME
YOU ANTICIPATED?
>> Robin: LET ME GO.
LET ME GO!
>> DR. Obrecht: SOMETHING MEANT
FOR YOU.
IT'S TOO LATE, ROBIN.
THERE'S NOTHING MORE YOU CAN DO.
>> Robin: DAD. DAD, LOOK AT ME!
>> DR. Obrecht: ALL THAT'S LEFT
IS TO DEAL WITH YOU.
>> Robin: DADDY!
DADDY.
The saying easy as pie?
I get it now.
Just unroll it,
fill, top,
bake, and present.
That must have
taken you forever!
It was really tough.
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Pie Crust.
Let the Making Begin
INTO JOHN STAMOS.
HONEY! I THINK
I'M GETTING BURNED!
EAT.
♪
TASTES PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
[ men grunting ]
OPEN!
[ Male Announcer ] OIKOS.
POSSIBLY THE BEST YOGURT
IN THE WORLD.
[ men grunting ]
OPEN!
CURÉL ULTRA HEALING LOTION
REPAIRS AND RENEWS DRY SKIN
TWO TIMES BETTER THAN THE
LEADING ADVANCED LOTION.
DEVELOPED WITH
ADVANCED CERAMIDE THERAPY,
IT EVEN HELPS PREVENT
DRY SKIN FROM COMING BACK.
THANK YOU CURÉL.
SEE THE CURE IN CURÉL.
SO I MIX TOGETHER
A PACKET OF HIDDEN VALLEY RANCH,
1 BOX OF SPINACH,
AND 16 OUNCES OF SOUR CREAM,
AND TONIGHT EVERYONE GETS
A TASTE OF SOMETHING SPECIAL...
RANCH SPINACH DIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
HIDDEN VALLEY RANCH. MIX IT UP.
AHH, CLOUDY GLASSES.
YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME OVER!
EASY.
HI. CASCADE KITCHEN COUNSELOR.
LOOK!
OVER TIME, CASCADE COMPLETE PACS
FIGHT FILM BUILDUP TWO TIMES
BETTER THAN FINISH QUANTUM
TO HELP LEAVE GLASSES SPARKLING.
CASCADE. THE CLEAR CHOICE.
SO YOU THINK
SANTA WILL LIKE THESE...
RED AND GREEN M&M'S?
I DON'T KNOW!
I NEVER MET THE GUY!
WHAAAAA!
HE DOES EXIST!
THEY DO EXIST!
UHM... SANTA?
BODY WASHES WITH PAPER
THAT REACTS LIKE SKIN.
IF OTHERS CAN STRIP THIS PAPER,
IMAGINE HOW HARSH
THEY CAN BE TO YOUR SKIN.
OH MY GOSH.
[ Female Announcer ]
Dove IS DIFFERENT.
ITS NEW BREAKTHROUGH FORMULA
CHANGES EVERYTHING.
NEW Dove.
THIS IS CARE.
ITS NEW BREAKTHROUGH FORMULA
CHANGES EVERYTHING.
♪STIR IT, STIR IT,IR IT,
STIR IT UP, STIR IT UP. ♪♪
STIR UP A SMILE,
WITH HERSHEY'S SYRUP.
BUT SINCE I'VE BEEN ON ALLI,
AM I ON THIS ONE?
NOPE.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
I AM ON THIS ONE.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR EVERY 2 POUNDS YOU LOSE
THROUGH DIET AND EXERCISE
ALLI CAN HELP YOU LOSE
ONE MORE
BY BLOCKING SOME OF THE FAT
YOU EAT.
SIMPLE. EFFECTIVE.
BELT-FRIENDLY.
LET'S FIGHT FAT WITH ALLI.
HAVE A HEALTHIER HOLIDAY
AT LETSFIGHTHOLIDAYFAT.COM.
>> Olivia: OKAY.
ENOUGH WITH THE CUTE PUPPY FACE,
YOU.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT YOUR DEAL IS,
BUT IF YOU THINK I'M GONNA LET
YOU MESS WITH MY FAMILY, YOU'RE
EVEN CRAZIER THAN I AM.
GOD, NOW I'M TALKING TO A DOG.
[ SIGHS ]
[ FOOTSTEPS DEPART ]
>> Mac: HEY. YOU'RE STILL HERE.
>> Maxie: YEAH.
I WANTED TO STAY UNTIL I KNEW
EVERYTHING WAS OKAY.
>> Mac: I GUESS THAT MEANS YOU
MADE YOUR DECISION.
>> Maxie: I HAVE.
I HAD A MOMENT OF DOUBT.
THAT'S ALL IT WAS -- JUST A
MOMENT.
>> Mac: WHAT SNAPPED YOU OUT OF
IT?
>> Maxie: MAC, YOU SHOULD SEE
THE WAY HE LOOKS AT HER.
I MEAN, DANTE LOOKS AT LULU LIKE
SHE'S THE ONLY WOMAN ON THE
PLANET.
THEY'RE GONNA MAKE GREAT
PARENTS.
I'M DOING THE RIGHT THING.
>> Mac: OKAY.
>> Maxie: ARE YOU MAD?
>> Mac: MAD? MAD?
SWEETHEART, NO.
[ SMOOCHES ]
I COULDN'T BE MORE PROUD.
>> Spinelli: I COME BEARING GOOD
NEWS.
>> Maxie: WERE YOU IN THE LAB?
>> Spinelli: FERTILIZATION IS A
GO, AS THEY SAY.
WITH ANY LUCK, YOU WILL SOON BE
WITH CHILD.
>> Dante: LOOK AT THAT, LULU.
SHE'S MAKING OUR BABY.
[ SMOOCHES ]
>> Anna: OH, MY GOD!
>> Bree: GOOD LUCK.
>> Sabrina: THANK YOU.
>> Bree: TWO VISITORS FOR YOU.
THEY'RE NOT ON THE BOOKS, BUT I
THINK YOU'RE GONNA WANT TO SEE
THEM.
>> Sabrina: UM, HELLO --
MISS COE.
>> Lucy: YOU CAN CALL ME LUCY.
AI
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
DISNEY-ABC DOMESTIC TELEVISION]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUSE]
Meredith: HELLO.
HI, GUYS. GOOD LUCK.
HELLO, EVERYBODY,
AND WELCOME TO "MILLIONAIRE."
OUR AUDIENCES HERE ARE ALWAYS SO
SUPPORTIVE OF THE CONTESTANTS,
WHICH IS WHY, WHEN WE GET
THE CHANCE, WE LIKE TO GIVE THEM
A LITTLE SOMETHING IN RETURN.
SO ALL THIS WEEK,
IT IS BROADWAY GIVEAWAY WEEK.
EVERY CONTESTANT WILL HAVE
ONE BROADWAY-THEMED QUESTION,
AND IF THEY GET IT RIGHT,
THEY'LL BE GOING
TO "MARY POPPINS"
ALONG WITH AN ENTIRE ROW
FROM THIS AUDIENCE.