(click)
("Little Drummer Boy" playing)
THAT'S IT.
MERRY CHRISTMAS, FELLAS.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
YOU KNOW, I ALWAYS SAY
IT REALLY DOES NOT FEEL
LIKE CHRISTMAS
TILL THE TREE IS UP!
HA HA! LOOK AT THAT.
YOU KNOW THE ONE THING
IT'S MISSIN'?
AND, UH, YOU SEE THIS
A LOT WITH TREES--
IS THE COLOR GREEN.
OH, NOW, CASH, THAT IS
THE GREENEST TREE YOU CAN GET.
IT'S MADE ENTIRELY
OF POST-CONSUMER RECYCLED WASTE.
YOU MEAN LIKE SODA BOTTLES
AND PLASTIC BAGS?
YES, EXACTLY.
BUT MOSTLY DIAPERS.
HEY, GUYS, GEOFFREY AND I--
HO HO!
(door closes)
SWEET HONEY IN THE ROCK.
WHAT'S THAT?
THAT IS A W.P.W.--
A WOOD-LESS PINK WONDER.
YEAH, BUT, MAMA, I WANTED
THE SMELL OF REAL PINE,
LIKE A TRADITIONAL
CHRISTMAS TREE.
OH, HONEY, CHANGE IS GOOD.
YOU KNOW, WHEN I WAS
A GIRL ON THE FARM,
MY FAVORITE TRADITION
WAS WHEN UNCLE CHARLES
CUT OFF THE GOOSE'S HEAD.
AND THEN WHOMEVER
THE HEADLESS TORSO RAN TO
GOT TO PUT THE STAR
ON THE TREE.
DO YOU WANNA GO BACK
TO THAT?
NO.
IT'S JUST THAT
THAT TREE'S A LITTLE MUCH.
IT'S A LITTLE MUCH FOR ME,
AND, YOU KNOW, I'M... LATIN.
COME ON, GUYS.
REBA, REBA, TELL 'EM.
OH. OKAY.
WELL, YOU KNOW HOW THIS IS
OUR FIRST CHRISTMAS
SINCE WE MOVED TO MALIBU.
AY, BORING. COME ON. GET TO
THE MEAT. GET TO THE MEAT.
OH, OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
WELL, I WENT DOWN TO THE CHURCH,
AND YOU KNOW HOW I ALWAYS DID
THE CHRISTMAS SOLO BACK HOME.
WELL, IT TURNS OUT--
OKAY, YOUR MOM
IS GONNA BE SINGING A SOLO
CHRISTMAS EVE AT CHURCH.
REBA, TELL 'EM.
WELL, I HOPE I GET TO.
I STILL HAVE TO AUDITION
AFTER CHURCH ON SUNDAY.
AY, PLEASE. WITH YOUR VOICE,
THAT IS JUST A FORMALITY.
AND I'M TELLING YOU, THIS IS
GONNA BE HUGE FOR HER CAREER.
THE FIRST CHURCH OF MALIBU
IS RED-HOT.
IT IS LISTED AS ONE
OF THE TOP TEN POWER CHURCHES.
YEAH.
THEIR A.A. MEETINGS
ARE THE WHO'S WHO OF HOLLYWOOD.
(laughs) BUT THAT'S NOT WHY
I'M DOING IT.
AY, I KNOW.
IT'S FOR THE CHRISTMAS SPIRIT.
BUT, HEY, IF THIS LAUNCHES
A HUGE SUPERSTAR SINGING CAREER,
THAT IS JUST TINSEL
ON THE BIG GAY TREE.
(laughs)
I'M REALLY HAPPY FOR YOU, MAMA.
WELL, THANK YOU, CASH.
HELLO, HELLO, MY HAPPY
LITTLE HOLIDAY ELVES.
HEY.
(gasps)
OH, MY GOD.
WE HAVE THE SAME TREE.
TREE JINX.
YOU OWE ME AN EGGNOG.
THIS MUST BE KIM.
AH! AND YOU MUST BE
GEOFFREY.
AH. GET A LOAD OF YOU.
LOOK AT YOU.
(gasps) LOVE THE SHOES.
YOU ARE ADORABLE.
I LOVE YOUR HAIR.
OH, MY GOD.
WORKING THAT BABY BUMP.
YOU ARE FABULOUS
AND THEN SOME.
WE SHOULD GO SHOPPING
AND DO BRUNCH.
THEY'RE LIKE THOSE TWINS
FROM "THE SHINING."
OKAY, GUYS, I GOTTA GO TAKE
MY GRANDMA TO THE MALL.
EVERY YEAR SHE INSISTS
ON SITTING ON SANTA'S LAP.
IT'S ALWAYS FUN
UNTIL HE CALLS SECURITY.
BYE, SWEETIE. (kisses)
MWAH.
HEY, REBA.
LOOKS LIKE I'LL BE
SEEING YOU
AT THE SOLO AUDITIONS.
OH, YOU'RE GONNA COME
WATCH ME?
I'M AUDITIONING, TOO,
SILLY.
OOH-HOO-HOO.
THIS IS GETTING GOOD.
I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW YOU SANG.
WELL, I SANG A LITTLE
BACK IN HIGH SCHOOL,
AND I DON'T WANNA BRAG,
BUT LET'S JUST SAY I'M GREAT.
(laughs)
WELL, DON'T YOU THINK THIS IS
GONNA BE A LITTLE WEIRD,
BOTH OF US GOING UP
FOR THE SAME THING?
NO! UNH-UNH. COME ON.
A LITTLE HEALTHY COMPETITION
NEVER HURT ANYBODY,
EVEN IN CHURCH.
RIGHT. THAT'S TRUE.
I MEAN, IF ANYBODY UNDERSTANDS
COMPETITION, IT'S GOD.
THAT SHALT HAVE
NO OTHER GODS BEFORE ME.
SOMEBODY WAS FEELING THREATENED.
(laughs)
(Reba)
♪ WALKIN' WITH MY HEAD HIGH
♪ SOAKIN' UP THE SUNSHINE
♪ LA-LA-LA-LA-LA,
LIFE IS SWEET ♪
WELL, THAT WAS A NICE SERVICE,
WASN'T IT, MAMA?
YOU KNOW, I LIKE THIS CHURCH.
IT'S GOT PLENTY OF GOD,
AND THEY DON'T BEAT YOU
OVER THE HEAD WITH IT.
OH, I BET IT'S GONNA BE
A BEAUTIFUL CHRISTMAS EVE.
OH, YEAH.
OH, YES.
HEY. WAIT UP.
WHAT?
YOU--YOU JUST SAT THERE.
YOU DIDN'T PRAY.
YOU DIDN'T SING.
YOU DIDN'T SING, EITHER.
WELL, I DIDN'T KNOW
THE WORDS,
BUT I STILL MOVED MY MOUTH
AND TRIED TO LOOK JOYFUL.
(clears throat)
MAYBE I'M NOT
THAT INTO CHURCH ANYMORE.
MAYBE I DON'T EVEN
BELIEVE IN GOD.
SHH! GOOD LORD!
YOU'RE IN HIS HOUSE.
OH, IT WAS GOOD.
ARE YOU READY FOR YOUR TRYOUT?
WELL, MAMA,
TO TELL YOU THE TRUTH,
I'M A LITTLE NERVOUS.
WELL, I'VE GOT
JUST THE THING
TO CALM YOUR NERVES--
ONE OF MY... COOKIES.
I DON'T WANT
ONE OF YOUR COOKIES.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO THE OTHER HALF?
WELL, A BETTER QUESTION IS
WHAT HAPPENED TO
THE OTHER ONE AND A HALF?
(laughs)
♪ O COME, LET US ADORE HIM
♪ CHRIST
♪ THE LORD
(mouths words)
THANK YOU.
REBA, THAT WAS TERRIFIC.
I HAVE GOOSE BUMPS.
(laughs)
WELL, YOU KNOW, I HAVE DONE
A FEW CHURCH SOLOS IN MY TIME.
LAST YEAR I GOT TO DO
"THE LITTLE DRUMMER BOY,"
AND THEY'RE STILL
TALKING ABOUT MY...
♪ PA-RUM-PA-PUM-PUMS
(laughs)
YOU KNOW, SHE CAME OUT OF ME
SINGING.
(laughs)
(mouths words)
(speaking inaudibly)
OH, REBA, THAT--
THAT WAS SO GOOD.
I'M ACTUALLY STARTING
TO GET A LITTLE SCARED.
OHH. THANK YOU, KIM.
YOU'LL DO GREAT.
YOU'RE RIGHT. I WILL.
UH, KIM? YOU'RE UP.
OH. OKAY. (laughs)
LIKE WATCHING
A GOPHER AT A GATOR FARM.
MAMA.
I'M SURE SHE'S NOT
AS BAD AS YOU THINK.
(off-key)
♪ O COME, ALL YE FAITHFUL ♪
♪ JOYFUL AND TRIUMPHANT
YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S WORSE.
♪ O COME YE TO BETHLEHEM
(under breath)
WELL, IF YOU'RE GONNA COME,
BRING YOUR EAR PLUGS.
♪ COME AND BEHO-O-OLD HIM
♪ BORN THE KING OF ANGELS
♪ O COME, LET US ADORE HIM
♪ O COME, LET US ADORE HIM ♪
WHY? UH, 'CAUSE HE'S...
(continues off-key)
♪ CHRIST
♪ THE LORD
(microphone stand thuds)
(Kim laughs)
OKAY.
GIVE US A MINUTE, EVERYONE.
KIM, THAT WAS GREAT.
THANK YOU.
IT FELT GREAT, YOU KNOW?
I REALLY LEFT IT
ALL UP THERE ON THE ALTAR.
(laughs) YOU WERE GREAT,
TOO, REBA.
OH, THANK YOU, KIM.
GOOD LUCK.
COME ON.
THANK YOU.
(laughs)
AND JUST REMEMBER,
THERE ARE NO LOSERS.
JUST WINNERS
AND FRIENDS OF WINNERS.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT. THIS WAS
A DIFFICULT DECISION.
BUT THIS YEAR'S
CHRISTMAS SOLO--
"SILENT NIGHT"--
WILL BE SUNG BY KIM.
(gasps)
WELL, HELLFIRE!
WHAT? NO!
(speaks inaudibly)
WHAT?
BUT THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN MUCH
ANYMORE.
THE CREATIVE PROCESS
NEVER STOPS.
AND SONGWRITING IS SO HARD,
BUT I LOVE IT.
THESE DAYS, I GUESS I JUST
DON'T WANT TO MISS A THING.
[ laughs ]
I MISS YOU GUYS.
THAT'S ME.
AND THIS IS MY WINDOWS PHONE.
[ Male Announcer ]
NEW WINDOWS PHONE.
REINVENTED AROUND YOU.
♪
FOR CENTURIES."
THIS LEVIAN COLLECTION
IS AMAZING.
MAYBE IT'S TIME
TO START YOUR OWN.
[ Female Announcer ]
KAY JEWELERS PRESENTS
TODAY'S LEVIAN COLLECTION...
[ gasps ]
FEATURING EXCLUSIVE
LEVIAN CHOCOLATE DIAMONDS.
FROM THE LEVIAN FAMILY -
WHERE THE LATEST IN FASHION
MEETS FINE JEWELRY.
ONE MORE REASON KAY
IS THE NUMBER-ONE JEWELRY STORE
IN AMERICA.
IT'S...
A WORK OF ART?
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
OH, LOOK AT YOU,
DECORATIN' THE TREE--
THE TREE THAT'S SUPPOSED
TO CELEBRATE
THE BIRTH OF A GUY
WHOSE FATHER
YOU DON'T BELIEVE IN.
MAYBE I WOULD BELIEVE IN HIM
IF THERE WAS ANY PROOF.
THERE'S PROOF
ALL AROUND US, JUNE.
THE PROOF IS IN THE OCEANS.
THE PROOF IS IN THE TREE.
THE PROOF IS IN THE PUDDIN'.
OH. (chuckles)
SORRY, CASH. THAT'S NOT PROOF.
THAT'S JUST A LIST.
HEY, WHAT DO YOU THINK?
TOO MUCH?
YEAH, GRANDMA.
THAT'S WHAT'S PUT THE PINK
GARBAGE TREE OVER THE TOP.
(laughs)
REBA?
WHAT'S WRONG WITH YOU?
WHEN ARE YOU GONNA ADMIT
YOU'RE MAD
BECAUSE YOU WERE
ROBBED OF THAT SOLO?
MAMA, I AM NOT MAD.
I'M HAPPY FOR KIM.
IT'S CHRISTMAS.
EVERYTHING'S JIM DANDY.
OKAY. I GOT NEWS.
(door closes)
I GOT BIG NEWS.
WHAT IS IT?
OKAY, I WENT DOWN
TO THE CHURCH,
AND I FOUND OUT THE TRUTH
ABOUT HOW KIM GOT THAT SOLO.
I DON'T WANNA HEAR
ANYTHING NEGATIVE.
EXCUSE ME. WHAT?
IT'S CHRISTMAS--THE SEASON
OF JOY AND ACCEPTANCE,
AND I'M JUST GONNA ACCEPT
THAT I DIDN'T GET THE SOLO.
COME ON. I WANNA HEAR.
TELL ME. TELL ME.
OKAY, OKAY.
OKAY. SO THE WHOLE THING
IS RIGGED.
NO.
AND... (whispering indistinctly)
I DON'T BELIEVE IT!
YOU'VE GOT TO BE
KIDDING ME!
ALL RIGHT! ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT, TELL ME.
OKAY. EVERY YEAR,
KIM AUDITIONS FOR THAT SOLO,
BUT SHE NEVER GETS IT.
BECAUSE WHEN SHE SINGS,
WELL, SHE SOUNDS
LIKE A GARBAGE DISPOSAL
FULL OF NICKELS.
THIS YEAR, HER HUSBAND GAVE
THE CHURCH BUILDING FUND $50,000
BUT ONLY IF KIM GOT THE SOLO.
WELL, BUTTER MY BUTT
AND CALL ME A BISCUIT.
WELL, THAT'S NOT IT, THOUGH.
KIM--SHE DOESN'T EVEN
KNOW ABOUT IT.
THAT'S THE WAY
HER HUSBAND WANTED IT.
WELL, THIS IS
AN INJUSTICE.
WE CAN'T LET IT STAND.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO, REBA?
WELL, NOTHIN'. KIM DIDN'T
KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
HMM.
ACTUALLY, I'M JUST GLAD TO KNOW
IT WASN'T ABOUT MY SINGING.
HMM.
I CAN LIVE WITH THAT.
BUT NOW I'M WORRIED ABOUT KIM.
I HOPE SHE DOESN'T
EMBARRASS HERSELF.
(chuckles)
OKAY, WHAT IS WRONG WITH HER?
I DON'T KNOW.
I TRIED TO RAISE HER MEAN,
BUT IT DIDN'T TAKE.
AH. HELLO,
LITTLE MISS ATHEIST.
(door closes)
YOU WANTED PROOF OF GOD?
WELL, I'VE GOT PROOF. HERE.
A PLANT?
NO. NOT JUST A PLANT, JUNE.
A TINY PLANT.
NOW HOW DOES A TINY PLANT
TURN INTO A BIG PLANT?
THE ANSWER IS A LITTLE THING
BY THE NAME OF "GOD."
BY THE NAME OF "PHOTOSYNTHESIS."
(under breath) PHOTO...
(normal voice) OKAY,
NOW YOU'RE JUST MAKING STUFF UP.
PHOTOSYNTHESIS--YOU KNOW,
CARBON DIOXIDE AND WATER
COMBINED
WITH ELECTROMAGNETIC ENERGY
TO CREATE OXYGEN
AND GLUCOSE?
YOU SHOULD'VE LEARNED
ALL THIS STUFF IN FIFTH GRADE.
HEY, I HAD MONO.
WHAT'S WITH THE PLANT?
JUNE THINKS GOD'S--
JUST SO AWESOME. I MEAN...
LOOK AT THAT PLANT.
THUMBS UP.
OKAY.
(off-key) ♪ DECK THE HALLS
WITH BOUGHS OF HOLLY ♪
♪ FA-LA-LA-LA-LA,
LA-LA-LA-LA-LA-LA ♪
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU,
KIM?
WELL, I WAS OVER AT MY HOUSE
PRACTICING MY SOLO.
AND THEN IT DAWNED ON ME.
I LIVE NEXT DOOR
TO A SEASONED VETERAN.
WHY AM I NOT OVER HERE
ASKING FOR A LITTLE
LAST MINUTE PRIVATE INSTRUCTION?
WELL, THAT'S AN AWFULLY NICE
THING TO SAY.
OH, MY GOSH. OF COURSE.
I MEAN, REBA, COME ON.
YOU'VE BEEN SINGING
FOR YEARS AND YEARS AND YEARS
AND YEARS.
WHAT DO YOU SAY, REBA?
YOU REALLY DO HAVE
SUCH A BEAUTIFUL VOICE.
YOU WANNA GIVE ME
A FEW TIPS?
SURE. "SILENT NIGHT" HAS ALWAYS
BEEN ONE OF MY FAVORITES.
OH, MINE, TOO.
OKAY.
I THINK THE KEY TO SINGING IT
IS COMING INTO THE VOCAL
WITH A SOFT
AND ALMOST REVERENT TONE.
OKAY.
♪ SILENT NIGHT
♪ HOLY NIGHT
MM, NO.
NO.
I REALLY WANNA COME
AT THIS THING LIKE GANGBUSTERS.
YOU KNOW, REALLY GO AFTER IT.
LIKE...
(gravelly voice)
♪ SILENT NIGHT
♪ HOLY NIGHT
OW! GIMME THE HORNS.
KIM, THIS ISN'T
"SEX MACHINE."
IT'S
A TENDER CHRISTMAS SONG.
OKAY, WELL,
LET'S JUST MOVE ON.
HOW ABOUT VOCAL TECHNIQUE?
BECAUSE THERE'S SOME
OF THESE NOTES
THAT JUST GO ON, LIKE,
FOREVER. (laughs)
SO HOW DO I, YOU KNOW,
SPICE THOSE UP?
WELL,
YOU DON'T SPICE 'EM UP.
YOU SUSTAIN THE NOTE
AND ADD A LITTLE VIBRATO.
IT GIVES THE NOTE
RESONANCE AND EXTENSION.
(laughs) OKAY, WELL,
I THINK THE ONLY THING
THAT'LL BE EXTENDING
WILL BE THE PEOPLE LAYING DOWN
IN THE PEWS FOR OUR NAP.
DO YOU WANT HELP WITH THIS
OR NOT?
NO, I DO. I DO.
OF COURSE I DO.
OKAY, SO LISTEN UP,
BECAUSE I'M REALLY GIVING YOU
ALL MY EXPERIENCE ABOUT SINGING.
YEAH.
MAYBE THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
MEANING?
WELL, WITH ALL DUE RESPECT,
REBA--
AND I REALLY DO MEAN THAT,
SERIOUSLY--
IT'S JUST, YOU THINK YOU KNOW
EVERYTHING ABOUT MUSIC,
BUT, YOU KNOW,
YOU DID COME IN SECOND.
I BEG YOUR PARDON.
ACTUALLY, WE DON'T EVEN KNOW
IF IT WAS SECOND,
'CAUSE THERE WERE
FOUR OTHER PEOPLE TRYING OUT,
SO IT COULD HAVE BEEN
THIRD OR FOURTH, EVEN SIXTH.
(chuckles)
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE RIGHT, KIM.
I GUESS I SHOULD'VE DONE
WHAT YOU DID--
GET MY RICH HUSBAND
TO PAY THE CHURCH
A BIG, OL', FAT CHECK
AND BUY ME THAT SOLO.
WHAT?
KIM, I'M--I'M SORRY.
NOTHING.
PLEASE FORGET
EVERYTHING I SAID.
NO. YOU SAID IT.
IS THAT TRUE?
KIM, I AM SO SORRY.
I THINK WE'RE DONE HERE.
(sighs)
[ gasps ]
WILL YOU MARRY ME?
♪
YES!
ATTENTION...
HE WENT TO JARED.
[ applause ]
♪
WHO WANTS A LITTLE CHAMPAGNE?
[ Female Announcer ]
JARED THE GALLERIA OF JEWELRY
HAS FIVE TIMES THE SELECTION
OF ORDINARY JEWELRY STORES,
WITH THOUSANDS
OF LOOSE DIAMONDS
AND HUNDREDS OF SETTINGS
TO CREATE YOUR
OWN, ONE-OF-A-KIND RING.
OH.
PLEASE RETURN YOUR Fiancée TO
HER ORIGINAL UPRIGHT POSITION.
[ Female Announcer ]
THAT'S WHY HE WENT TO JARED.
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Sharable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Get a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
COME ON, KIDS. LET'S GO!
JUNE,
WHY AREN'T YOU DRESSED?
UH... I DON'T FEEL
LIKE GOING.
ARE YOU SICK?
OH, IT'S WORSE THAN SICK, MAMA.
SHE DOESN'T BELIEVE IN GOD.
I'M SORRY.
I HAD TO SAY SOMETHING.
HOW AM I SUPPOSED
TO ENJOY HEAVEN
WHEN YOU'RE IN HELL?
CASH, WHY DON'T YOU WAIT
IN THE CAR FOR ME?
I'LL BE THERE IN A SECOND.
ALL RIGHT.
TREAD CAREFULLY.
SHE KNOWS A LOT ABOUT SCIENCE.
JUNE, IS THAT TRUE?
YOU DON'T BELIEVE IN GOD?
I DON'T KNOW.
HONEY, IT'S OKAY.
YOU CAN TELL ME HOW YOU FEEL.
WELL,
I'VE BEEN THINKING...
AND?
AND MAYBE I DON'T...
BELIEVE IN GOD.
OKAY.
HAVE YOU FELT THIS WAY
FOR A WHILE,
OR DID SOMETHING HAPPEN?
ACTUALLY,
SOMETHING DIDN'T HAPPEN.
(sighs)
WHEN YOU AND DAD WERE GOING
THROUGH YOUR... PROBLEM,
I PRAYED EVERY NIGHT THAT
YOU GUYS WOULD STAY TOGETHER,
BUT YOU DIDN'T,
SO EITHER THERE IS NO GOD,
OR HE JUST DOESN'T CARE.
HARD TO HAVE FAITH
EITHER WAY.
YEAH, IT IS.
YOU'RE NOT MAD?
OH, OF COURSE NOT, HONEY.
BUT I WILL SAY THIS.
I'VE COME TO BELIEVE
THAT FAITH ISN'T SOMETHING
THAT KEEPS BAD THINGS
FROM HAPPENING.
FAITH IS WHAT HELPS US
GET THROUGH BAD THINGS
WHEN THEY DO HAPPEN.
SO? ARE YOU MAKING HER
COME TO CHURCH?
NO. SHE HAS EVERY RIGHT
TO BELIEVE WHAT SHE WANTS.
WHAT?
HUH.
I KNOW.
BY THE WAY,
I DON'T BELIEVE IN CALCULUS.
DO I HAVE TO GO TO SCHOOL?
THIS IS WHAT CHURCH SHOULD BE.
ALL KINDS OF PEOPLE ARE HERE--
BLACK PEOPLE, WHITE PEOPLE,
LATINO, ASIAN...
SINFUL SHOW BUSINESS PEOPLE.
THE WORST PERSON
IN THE WORLD PEOPLE.
OH, GET OFF THE CROSS, REBA.
YOU'RE STEALING FOCUS.
GEOFFREY,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
WHAT? I LOVE CHURCH.
PLUS I WANNA HEAR
WHAT A $50,000 SOLO SOUNDS LIKE.
WELCOME, EVERYONE.
WE'D LIKE TO START
TONIGHT'S SERVICE
WITH A BEAUTIFUL CHRISTMAS SONG.
PLEASE WELCOME KIM WESTLAKE,
WHO WILL BE SINGING
"SILENT NIGHT."
WELL, WHERE IS SHE?
I DON'T KNOW.
UH, WHILE WE WAIT FOR KIM...
I'M GONNA GO SEE
WHAT'S UP WITH KIM.
WE'RE HAVING A PANCAKE BREAKFAST
ON SATURDAY, AND FOR THOSE...
KIM, WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I CAN'T SING. I CAN'T SING.
YES, YOU CAN.
NO, I CAN'T, REBA.
I OPEN MY MOUTH,
AND JUST NOTHING COMES OUT.
JUST LIKE... (squeaks)
SEE?
KIM, IF YOU CAN TALK,
YOU CAN SING.
(garbled voice)
NOW I CAN'T EVEN TALK.
(breathing heavily)
KIM, YOU'VE GOTTA GET
A GRIP.
IT WAS ALL MY FAULT.
I SHOULD HAVE NEVER TOLD YOU
WHAT YOUR HUSBAND DID.
IT WAS VERY PETTY,
AND IT FREAKED YOU OUT.
NOW YOU JUST GOTTA
GET IN THERE.
NO! NO, I'M TOO SCARED,
I MEAN, I CAN'T EVEN REMEMBER
THE OPENING LINE
TO "SILENT NIGHT."
"SILENT... NIGHT."
OKAY,
WHAT'S THE NEXT PART?
"HOLY NIGHT."
WHAT WERE THE FIRST TWO
AGAIN?
OH, GOOD LORD.
SEE, REBA, IT'S NO USE.
YOU WERE RIGHT.
THE ONLY REASON THEY PICKED ME
IS BECAUSE OF LESLIE'S DONATION.
I MEAN, LET'S FACE IT. I TRY OUT
FOR THIS THING EVERY YEAR,
AND EVERY YEAR I ALWAYS FAIL,
AND IT'S BECAUSE
I'M NOT SOME GREAT SINGER.
I'M JUST A TROPHY WIFE,
YOU KNOW?
I MEAN, AT LEAST I WAS.
I KNOW IT SOUNDS
KINDA STUPID.
I GUESS I JUST WANTED TO BE
FRONT AND CENTER FOR ONCE,
YOU KNOW?
AND YOU CAN, TONIGHT.
NO, REBA, I CAN'T.
I CAN'T SING LIKE YOU.
YES, YOU CAN.
(guitar playing, applause)
(Reba's voice) ♪ SILENT NIGHT
♪ HOLY NIGHT
♪ ALL IS CALM
♪ ALL IS BRIGHT
♪ ROUND YON VIRGIN,
MOTHER AND CHILD ♪
♪ HOLY INFANT,
SO TENDER AND MILD ♪
♪ SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE
♪
THAT'S MY GIRL.
THAT'S MY MAMI.
♪ OH, SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE
GIMME THE HORNS!
WELL, THANK YOU.
(man) WHOO!
AND ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL CREATED
A SPECIAL BRAIN TUMOR
TREATMENT JUST FOR ARIANNA.
OUR BOLD, NEW PROCEDURE IS
HELPING TO EXTEND HER LIFE...
AND GIVE HER FAMILY HOPE.
LOOK WHAT I MADE.
BEAUTIFUL...
HUG YOUR CHILD TONIGHT...
GIVE THANKS FOR THE HEALTHY
KIDS IN YOUR LIFE.
AND GIVE TO THOSE WHO ARE
NOT. GO TO ST. JUDE DOT ORG
OR SHOP WHERE EVER YOU SEE
THE ST. JUDE LOGO.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
♪
IT'S FINALLY HERE...
...THE PETSMART
COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS SALE.
SAVE UP TO 50% ON
ALL PETHOLIDAY® PRODUCTS,
DECEMBER 13TH
THROUGH THE 24TH.
AND HELP HOMELESS PETS
WHEN YOU PURCHASE
CHANCE & LUCKY GIFT CARDS!
AT PETSMART®.
GET $100 OFF ANY 4G LTE TABLET
WHEN YOU BUY ANY SMARTPHONE.
AND GET A TABLET DATA PLAN
STARTING AT JUST $10/MO.
NO SHARING REQUIRED.
HURRY INTO A Sprint STORE
OR VISIT sprint.com/tabletoffer
TODAY.
HURRY INTO A Sprint STORE
HEY.
I'M GLAD YOU CAME
TO CHURCH.
HERE. I, UH,
I GOT YOU THIS.
OH. LET ME GUESS.
IS IT A BIBLE?
NO. IT'S A BOOK
ON SCIENCE...
SINCE YOU'RE
INTO THAT STUFF.
THANK YOU, CASH.
YEAH. I KINDA
LOOKED THROUGH IT.
MAN, I MUST HAVE HAD MONO
FOR A LONG TIME.
(laughs)
OH, MAMA,
EVERYTHING SMELLS FANTASTIC.
WELL, THANK YOU, REBA.
COME ON. DINNER'S SERVED.
FOR THOSE OF YOU
WHO DON'T EAT HAM,
THERE ARE SOME TAKEOUT MENUS
ON THE COUNTER.
(laughs)
I HOPE YOU LIKE
MY GRANDMOTHER'S HOMEMADE,
FAMOUS PASTELES.
MMM.
OH, THAT'S SO SWEET.
HOW COME YOU DIDN'T BRING HER?
OH, SHE'S HAVING DRINKS
WITH SANTA...
AT A MOTEL IN THE VALLEY.
SOUNDS LIKE MY KINDA GAL.
(laughs)
WELL, I WOULD JUST LIKE TO SAY
THAT THE BEST CHRISTMAS PRESENT
I COULD EVER HOPE TO RECEIVE
IS TO BE NEIGHBORS
WITH ALL OF YOU.
THAT AND DIAMOND EARRINGS,
BUT IN THAT ORDER.
UM... REBA, THIS IS JUST
A LITTLE SOMETHING FOR YOU.
I GOTTA GO HAVE DINNER
WITH THE IN-LAWS,
BUT I REALLY WANNA SEE YOUR FACE
WHEN YOU OPEN IT.
OH, KIM.
(laughs) OH.
IT'S AN ANGEL
ON A SURFBOARD.
YEAH. THAT'S HOW
WE DO CHRISTMAS IN CALI.
KIM, I LOVE IT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
CASH, GO PUT IT
ON THE TREE FOR ME.
THANKS.
OKAY. WELL, NOW I'D LIKE
TO GIVE A LITTLE SPEECH.
AS YOU ALL KNOW, THIS IS
MY FAVORITE TIME OF THE YEAR.
AND... I WAS A LITTLE WORRIED
WITH ALL THE CHANGES
IN OUR LIVES,
THAT THIS CHRISTMAS
WOULDN'T BE THE SAME.
BUT I GOTTA TELL YA,
EVEN THOUGH I WASN'T
EXPECTING IT,
THIS HAS TURNED OUT
TO BE PRETTY COOL.
AND IT'S BECAUSE OF Y'ALL--
MY FAMILY
AND MY TWO NEW FRIENDS.
AW.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
(Lillie Mae) HEAR, HEAR.
CHEERS.
KIM , YOU CAN'T DRINK.
YOU'RE PREGNANT.
NO. I KNOW, I KNOW.
(sniffs loudly)
OH.
(whispers) THAT'S THE STUFF.
(laughs)
MAMA, YOU, UH...
YOU OUGHT TO SEE THIS.
OH, MY GOSH.
I THINK WE PUT GRANDMA'S TREE
TOO CLOSE TO THE FIREPLACE.
OH. (laughs)
(laughs)
WAIT. AM I THE ONLY ONE
WHO SMELLS DIAPERS?
-- Captions by VITAC --
(man) 'TIS THE SEASON...
GREETINGS. I'M SCOTTY CLAUS.
FOR AN ALL-NEW EPISODE
OF "SHARK TANK"...
I THINK I JUST MET
SANTA CLAUS.
WHERE HOPEFUL ENTREPRENEURS
DREAM OF A CHANCE
TO SECURE AN INVESTMENT
AND GAIN POWERFUL PARTNERS
TO START, GROW, OR SAVE
THEIR BUSINESSES.
I GIVE PEOPLE MEANINGFUL JOBS
DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
IS CHRISTMAS GONNA
COME EARLY?
LOOK, I DON'T--I DON'T WANT
TO BE A GRINCH.
IF THE SHARKS HEAR
A GREAT IDEA,
THEY'RE READY TO INVEST
USING THEIR OWN MONEY.
SO GREEDY ON THIS ONE.
AND THEY'LL FIGHT EACH OTHER
FOR A PIECE OF THE ACTION.
IGNORE EVERYTHING
THEY JUST SAID.
DID YOU REALLY
JUST SAY THAT?
BUT FIRST THE ENTREPRENEURS
MUST CONVINCE A SHARK
TO INVEST THE FULL AMOUNT
THEY'RE ASKING FOR