♪
KELLY: OH, MY GOSH, THAT IS
AMAZING.
[APPLAUSE]
HI.
OH, MY GOSH, IT'S TUESDAY,
DECEMBER 18, 2012.
WELCOME.
DO YOU KNOW THAT GUY?
MICHAEL: I DON'T KNOW HIM, BUT I
HAVE A FEELING I WILL MEET HIM
SOMETIME DURING THE SHOW.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: THAT WAS THE FUNNIEST
THING I EVER
MICHAEL: WE WALKED OUT OF THERE,
YEAH, YEAH, YEAH!
KELLY: I GOT EXCITED.
I WAS LIKE WHO'S COMING UP
BEHIND US?
OH, MY GOD.
MICHAEL: BUT THANK YOU, MAN, I
APPRECIATE THAT.
THAT WAS REALLY ROUSING.
>> COULD HAVE PLAYED SUNDAY,
FIVE-ON-ONE.
KELLY: YEAH, EXACTLY.
MICHAEL: IN MY MIND I BELIEVE I
CAN BUT I DON'T THINK THAT'S
TRUE.
KELLY: I BELIEVE YOU COULD.
I BELIEVE YOU COULD PUT ON A
UNIFORM AND PLAY BRILLIANTLY.
I THINK YOU'RE IN BETTER SHAPE
NOW THAN THEN.
MICHAEL: THAT IS PROBABLY TRUE.
I'M SLACKING THEN.
I LOOK BETTER THAN I DID THEN.
KELLY: I JUST THINK THAT YOU ARE
MORE --
MICHAEL: I FEEL BETTER THAN I
DID.
KELLY: I DON'T WANT TO USE THAT
WORD, OLDER, THE OLDER YOU GET,
THE MORE ATTENTION YOU PAY TO
YOUR BODY.
MICHAEL: I'M OLD.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH THAT?
KELLY: THE OLDER YOU GET, THE
MORE YOU --
MICHAEL: BECAUSE YOU REALIZE
AFTER YOU DID CERTAIN THINGS
THAT YOU DID IN YOUR 20'S,
EVERYTHING HURTS.
YOU'RE LIKE CAN'T DOT THAT
ANYMORE.
AND SPEAKING OF SPORTS, SINCE
WE'RE ON THE TOPIC, THE JETS
PLAYED "MONDAY NIGHT FOOTBALL."
KELLY: OK.
MICHAEL: AND DIDN'T GO TOO WELL.
DIDN'T GO
DIDN'T GO TOO WELL.
KELLY: OH, NO.
MICHAEL: THEY LOST.
AND SANCHEZ JUST DID NOT HAVE A
GREAT GAME.
FIVE INTERCEPTIONS, POUR OR FIVE
INTERCEPTIONS WHICH MEANS THAT
THE JETS ARE OFFICIALLY OUT OF
THE PLAYOFFS.
KELLY: OH.
[APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: I DON'T KNOW IF THEY
WERE SUPPOSED TO CHEER FOR THAT
OR NOT.
WE'LL HOLD UP YOUR HANDS WHEN
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO CLAP.
I DON'T KNOW.
WE'LL HELP YOU OUT.
UT THEY
BUT THEY'RE OFFICIALLY OUT OF
THE PLAYOFFS NOW.
SO IF YOU'RE A JETS FAN, YOUR
SEASON IS OVER.
KELLY: BUT THE GIANTS ARE STILL
IN IT.
MICHAEL: YES.
[APPLAUSE]
WELL, YOU KNOW, THE GIANTS WENT
DOWN TO ATLANTA ON SUNDAY.
THAT WAS FUNNY.
AND I GIVE IT TO THE FALCONS.
THE FALCONS BEAT THEM LIKE THEY
STOLE SOMETHING.
I MEAN, IT WAS BAD.
34-0.
KELLY: WOW.
MICHAEL: ATLANTA LOOKED GREAT.
BUT THE GIANTS LOOKED BAD.
BUT NOW THEY HAVE TO WIN THE
NEXT TWO GAMES TO MAKE THE
PLAYOFFS.
KELLY: THEY HAVE TO.
MICHAEL: THEY HAVE TO.
THEY HAVE NO CHOICE.
THEY HAVE TO PLAY THE RAVENS AND
THE PHILADELPHIA EAGLES.
KELLY: OH.
ARE THE PHILADELPHIA EAGLES
STILL IN --
KELLY: THE PHILADELPHIA EAGLES
ARE NOT IN IT ANYMORE.
THEY'RE OUT OF THE PLAYOFFS, BUT
WHAT BETTER PRESENT TO GIVE YOUR
RIFLES A PRESENT BY SENDING THEM
HOME?
THE GIANTS HAVE TWO HARD GAMES
TO GET IN.
AND THE KNICKS HAVE BEEN REALLY
HARD.
ONE OF THE BEST TEAMS IN THE NBA
BUT LAST NIGHT, THEIR OLD
FRIEND, JEREMY MINUTE CAME INTO
TOWN AND THE ROCKETS BEAT THE
KNICKS BY 13 POINTS.
NO, 12 POINTS.
KELLY: LIN OF THE LIN-SANITY.
HE WAS A KNICK, RIGHT?
MICHAEL: YES.
KELLY: WHEN DID HE NOT BECOME A
KNICK?
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: ARE YOU SERIOUS?
KELLY: NO, I'M SERIOUS.
I DON'T KNOW.
I DON'T KEEP UP WITH JEREMY LIN.
WE DON'T TALK ANYMORE.
MICHAEL: HE'S THE MOST GOOGLED
ATHLETE.
KELLY: I NEVER GOOGLE ATHLETES.
I GOOGLE THINGS LIKE --
MICHAEL: SHOES.
KELLY: RIGHT.
MICHAEL: SHOE.
YEAH, JEREMY LIN IS NOW WITH THE
HOUSTON TEXANS.
AND IT WAS A BIG DEAL WHEN THEY
LET HIM GO OR WHEN HE SIGNED
WITH THE ROCKETS BECAUSE THE
KNICKS DID NOT MATCH THE DEAL
THAT THE ROCKETS GAVE HIM.
KELLY: WOW!
MICHAEL: YEAH.
KELLY: BECAUSE I FEEL LIKE
THE   C
KNICKS CAN MATCH ANY DEAL EVER.
MICHAEL: THEY CAN BUT I GUESS
THEY FEEL IT COULDN'T MAKE IT
FINANCIALLY SO THE ROCKETS WOULD
HAVE TO PAY HIM LIKE $20
MILLION, $30 MILLION, BUT THE
KNICKS SAID HE HASN'T IMPROVEN
ENOUGH.
BIG WIN LAST NIGHT AGAINST OUR
HOMETOWN KNICKS.
KELLY: DID YOU PLAY $20 MILLION,
$30 MILLION A YEAR?
MICHAEL: I'M A MAD FOOTBALL
PLAYER.
GUARANTEED!
KELLY: WHEN YOU PLAY FOOTBALL,
IT'S NOT GUARANTEED?
MICHAEL: NO.
I'M OUT THERE BEATING MYSELF UP
WEEK TO WEEK.
IT'S LIKE A WEEK TO WEEK JOB.
YOU'RE CRYING, TEARS OVER THERE
NOW.
HEY, WEEK TO WEEK.
IT'S WEEK -- NO, FOOTBALL IS NOT
GUARANTEED.
FOOTBALL -- BASKETBALL,
BASEBALL, I KNOW ARE GUARANTEED.
KELLY: SO YOU GUARANTEE LIKE YOU
SIGN ON FOR THE MONEY.
BECAUSE SALARIES ARE ALWAYS TO
ME SEEM SO ENORMOUS.
SO I'VE JUST -- BEAR WITH ME.
I'M NOT -- I DON'T KNOW MUCH
ABOUT SPORTS.
MICHAEL: I'M LISTENING.
KELLY: SO SALARY SEEM ENORMOUS.
GUARANTEED TO ME SEEMS YOU GET
ALL THAT MONEY.
MICHAEL: A-ROD IS HURT RIGHT
NOW.
HE HAS FIVE YEARS, $11 MILLION
LEFT ON HIS DISTRACT.
HE'S GETTING HIS MONEY --
CONTRACT.
HE'S GETTING HIS MONEY.
KELLY: SO UNGUARANTEED MEANS
YOU'RE NOT EARNING A SALARY?
MICHAEL: IF YOU'RE NOT PLAYING
WELL AND THEY COME IN AND GO YOU
KNOW, KELLY, YOU'RE NOT PLAYING
LIKE YOU USED TO.
KELLY: RIGHT.
MICHAEL: GOOD LUCK.
HOLY COW!
MICHAEL: YEAH.
THAT'S HOW IT WORKS.
MICHAEL: YEP.
THAT'S WHY I WAS STRESSED FOR 15
YEARS.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: THAT'S A LOT OF STRESS.
MICHAEL: MOMMA NEEDS SOME SHOES!
KELLY: WOW.
I DID NOT KNOW THAT.
MICHAEL: YEAH.
KELLY: DID YOU GUYS KNOW THAT?
HALF OF YOU KNEW AND HALF OF YOU
DID NOT KNOW.
KELLY: HOW MANY OF YOU ARE
GUARANTEED YOUR SALARY AT WORK?
GO AHEAD, GELMAN.
RAISE YOUR HAND OVER THERE.
RAISE YOUR HAND.
KELLY: WITH WE GUARANTEED OUR
SALARY?
GELMAN: YES, YOU ARE.
MICHAEL: OH, REALLY?
I DON'T HAVE TO FOOL NOW?
I WON'T GET FIRED?
[LAUGHTER]
GELMAN: WE DO HAVE SOME OUTS
HID, IN THERE.
-- HIDDEN IN THERE.
MICHAEL: OH, I BETTER READ MY
CONTRACT.
KELLY: I'VE BEEN AGONIZING ABOUT
WHAT TO GET YOU FOR CHRISTMAS
BECAUSE YOU'RE SO KIND AND SO
LOVELY AND SO GENEROUS I HAVE TO
DO SOMETHING NICE FOR YOU.
AND I SAW THE NEWSPAPER
THAT I SORT OF WANT TO GET YOUR
OPINION THAT I GO OUT AND INVEST
IN THESE STATEMENT PIECES.
MICHAEL: STATEMENT PIECES.
OH, BOY.
KELLY: HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT
LEGGINGS?
MALE LEG
THIS IS WHAT THEY KIND OF --
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: WELL, BEFORE YOU WASTE
YOUR MONEY, I WILL TELL YOU
DON'T WASTE YOUR MONEY ON THAT.
KELLY: OK.
MICHAEL: WEREN'T YOU SAY THAT
LEGGINGS ARE NOT PANTS?
KELLY: NO.
THEY'RE LEGGINGS.
I'M GOING TO GET YOU A BIG BAGGY
SWEATER TO WEAR OVER IT JUST
LIKE WE DID IN THE 1980'S.
MAYBE AN OFF-THE-SHOULDER
NUMBER.
MAYBE A BELT.
MICHAEL: I SAY NO TO THE
MEGGINS.
KELLY: ARE YOU SURE?
I DON'T WANT TO INVEST $20
THAT'S GOING TO SET ME BACK.
MICHAEL: ARE THEY IN STYLE?
KELLY: YES.
MEN HAVE BEEN SEEN WEARING
LEGGINGS.
MICHAEL: FIRST OF ALL, WHEN YOUR
LEGS LOOK LIKE A FLAGPOLE, YOU
MAY BE ABLE TO WEAR THOSE
THINGS.
I ACTUALLY HAVE A MUSCLE ON MY
LEGS.
KELLY: YEAH, YOU DO.
MICHAEL: IMAGINE ME WALKING
ACROSS BROADWAY IN SOMING MINGS.
-- MEGGINGS.
KELLY: ALTHOUGH I BELIEVE THESE
ARE LEGGINGS.
BECAUSE THESE LOOK LIKE LADY
PANS IN THIS AREA.
MICHAEL: THE SKINNY JEANS TOOK A
WHILE FOR ME TO GET IN.
IF HE PULLED THEM ALL THE WAY
UP, I DON'T THINK THEY WOULD BE
LIKE THAT HIGH OVER THE ANKLE.
KELLY: NO, THEY USED TO WEAR
THEM DOWN.
MICHAEL: THEY'RE SO SKINNY.
KELLY: HOW OLD IS HE?
MICHAEL: 18.
KELLY: RIGHT.
MICHAEL: OH, NO, HE'S 20 NOW.
KELLY: YEAH.
SO THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT YOUNG
MEN LIKE -- YOUNG MEN COME IN
TWO SIZES, LIKE VERY SPINLY AND
ROBUST.
BECAUSE LIKE I FEEL LIKE YOUNG
BOYS HAVE LIKE THESE SPINLY
LITTLE LEGS.
ROBUST. I LOVE THE WORD
HEY, EURO BUST.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: BUT MICK JAGGER IS
SOMEBODY THAT CAN WEAR MEGGINGS
WITHOUT WEARING A BLUE SHIRT
OVER TOP.
MICHAEL: AND MILES IS MICK
JAGGER LIKE SPINLY BUT THERE'S
NO REASON FOR MEGGINGS.
SOMETIMES, FELLOWS, I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU'RE BUILT LIKE, DO NOT
PUT ON SOME TIGHTS BECAUSE IF I
SEE YOU, I'M GOING TO TALK ABOUT
YOU RIGHT THERE IN YOUR FACE.
YOU'RE WRONG FOR THIS.
WE CAN'T DO THAT.
KELLY: I HOPE I SAVED THAT GIFT
RECEIPT.
WELL, HERE'S ANOTHER TREND THAT
I WAS GOING TO INVEST IN YOU.
AND I JUST FOUND OUT THAT GELMAN
HAS INVESTED IN THIS TREND FOR
OUR OWN ART MOORE.
SOCKS -- STATEMENT SOCKS.
ANYBODY BUY ANY STATEMENT SOCKS
THIS SEASON, ANYBODY?
NO?
[APPLAUSE]
YES, SOME PEOPLE.
STATEMENT VOX ALL THE RAGE AND
GELMAN, FOR OUR OWN ART MOORE'S
BIRTHDAY, JOINED HIM FOR THE
SOCK OF THE MONTH CLUB.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
GELMAN: I DID, BUT ART LIKES
LOUD SOCKS.
OR BRIGHT, I SUPPOSE.
KELLY: AND YOU'RE ENJOYING THE
SOCK OF THE MONTH SOCKS VERY
MUCH.
MICHAEL: THEY SEND YOU ONE PAIR
OF SOCK A MONTH?
>> IT'S LIKE A COOKIE.
MICHAEL: ONE COOKIE A MONTH
WOULD JUST MAKE ME MAD.
IT'S SOMETHING, I GUESS.
KELLY: ARE THEY LUCKOUS SOCKS?
-- LUXURIOUS SOCKS?
>> THEY FIT.
MICHAEL: THEY FIT YOUR STYLE.
>> HE DID A GOOD JOB.
MICHAEL: A STATEMENT SOCK FOR
ME, I WOULD WEAR IT.
KELLY: YOU WOULD?
SO THAT'S SOMETHING I WON'T HAVE
TO TAKE BACK.
MICHAEL: NO.
LOOK AT GELMAN'S OVER THERE
WRITING, STATEMENT SOCKS,
MICHAEL, STATEMENT SOCK OF THE
MONTH.
DON'T PUT ME IN THAT MONTHLY
CLUB, BUDDY.
GELMAN: IT'S ALREADY IN THE
MAIL, BUDDY.
KELLY: I WAS GOING TO ANNOUNCE
THAT OUR FRIEND, CHANNING TATUM
IS GOING TO BE A DADDY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THE SEXY MAN ALIVE --
[APPLAUSE]
CAN'T BELIEVE HE FOUND SOMEBODY
THAT WOULD DO IT WITH HIM.
YEAH, NO.
SO APPARENTLY HIS WIFE AGREES HE
IS IN FACT THE SEXIEST MAN ALIVE
AND HE'S GOING TO BE THE SEXIEST
DAD ALIVE.
SO GOOD FOR HIM.
[APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: YOU KNOW, HE AND HIS
WIFE JENNA TATUM ARE SO CUTE AND
NICE PEOPLE AND -- WELL,
CONGRATULATIONS TO THEM.
AND THEY OPENED UP A NEW
RESTAURANT IN NEW ORLEANS, BY
THE WAY.
KELLY: THEY DID?
MICHAEL: YEAH, FOR THE SUPER
BOWL, I ALREADY TOLD HIM.
I'M COMING DOWN.
I WANT A STANDING TABLE EVERY
NIGHT ESPECIALLY DURING THAT
TIME.
KELLY: WHAT'S IT CALLED?
DO YOU KNOW THE NAME OF IT?
IT. DONE WANT TO SAY THE NAME
MICHAEL: NO, I'M GUARANTEED LIKE
MY CONTRACT HERE, OK?
[LAUGHTER]
BUT I FORGOT THE NAME OF IT.
KELLY: WE'LL FIND OUT.
MICHAEL: BUT THAT'S GREAT.
CONGRATULATIONS TO THEM.
AND OUR EX-PRESIDENT MR. BILL
CLINTON, THEY SAID MARTIN
SCORSESE'S GOING TO MAKE A BILL
FILM.
YEAH, A DOCUMENTARY ABOUT --
KELLY: ABOUT BILL OR LIKE A BIO
PICK?
MICHAEL: NO, AN AUTHORIZED HBO
DOCUMENTARY.
KELLY: WOW.
MICHAEL: YEAH, I WONDER HOW FAR
ARE THEY GOING TO DIG.
HOW FAR BACK ARE THEY GOING TO
GO NOW?
KELLY: WHAT DON'T WE ALREADY
KNOW?
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: THAT'S TRUE.
KELLY: YOU MEAN THERE'S MORE?
MICHAEL: BUT I THINK I WOULD
WATCH IT.
KELLY: OH, OF COURSE I WOULD.
I LOVE HISTORY IN ALL FORMS,
EVEN RECENT HISTORY.
EVEN HISTORY I CAN STILL
REMEMBER.
I REALLY DO.
MICHAEL: BUT HE'S AN INTERESTING
GUY.
KELLY: HE'S A RHODES SCHOLAR.
MICHAEL: HE'S THE MOST
INTERESTING PERSON I'VE EVER
BEEN AROUND AND IT'S REALLY
AMAZING TO SEE HOW TO TALK TO
YOU ABOUT -- TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT ANYTHING AND TALK TO THEM
ABOUT ANYTHING AND MAKE
EVERYBODY SO CONNECTED AND
ENGAGED.
IT'S REALLY AN INCREDIBLE THING
AND YOU COULD SEE WHY HE WAS THE
PRESIDENT.
I COULD WATCH THAT.
IT COULD BE GOOD.
KELLY: NEWS FLASH, EVERYBODY.
THE NAME OF CHANNING TATUM'S
RESTAURANT IN NEW ORLEANS IS
SAINTS AND SINNERS.
MICHAEL: YES.
KELLY: THE AUDIENCE JUST STARTED
WRITING THAT DOWN.
IT'S CRAZY.
YOU'RE NEVER GETTING IN NOW.
SORRY.
IT'S BOOKED.
MICHAEL: YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S
GOING TO BE?
IT'S GOING TO BE HARD TO GET A
ROOM THERE FOR SUPER BOWL, I
GUARANTEE YOU THAT.
KELLY: CERTAINLY IS.
MICHAEL: AND I KNOW YOU.
YOU DON'T DIET.
YOU JUST EAT RIGHT.
KELLY: YES, I TRY TO EAT RIGHT
ALL THE TIME.
I DON'T LIKE THE PRESSURE OF
HAVING TO LOSE WEIGHT.
SO I TRY NOT TO GAIN IT TO START
WITH.
DOES THAT MAKE SENSE?
MICHAEL: YEAH.
BUT, YOU KNOW, DIETING IT SAYS
CAN ENHANCE YOUR SWEET TOOTH.
FOR ALL YOU DIETERS OUT THERE,
BECAUSE WHEN YOU CHEAT ON YOUR
DIET, THEY SAY THAT SWEETS
TASTES BETTER.
ANYBODY KNOW THAT?
YOU'RE JUST SITTING THERE AND
THAT CAKE IS CALLING YOU.
COME ON, YOU WANT ME.
YEAH, YOU DO.
COME ON.
KELLY: I'M NOT A SWEETS EATER.
I'M A SALTY EEMPLET YOU KNOW THE
POPCORN YOU GAVE US?
SO ALL FOR ME, USUALLY EVERYBODY
GOES CARAMEL CORN ALWAYS GOES
FIRST, FOR ME, I START WITH THE
CHEESE POPCORN FIRST AND THEN I
WORK MY WAY TO THE BUTTER AND
THEN, WHEN I'M DESPERATE, I GO
FOR THE CARAMEL CORN.
MICHAEL: IT'S FUNNY.
I SENT YOU A DIFFERENT TUB OF
POPCORN, I DIDN'T KNOW IF UP
GOING TO EAT ANY POPCORN.
KELLY: IT'S ONE OF MY FAVORITE
SNACKS.
I LOVE IT.
I KNOW THEY SAY YOU CAN HAVE
LIKE FOUR BIG MAX FOR ONE MOVIE
THEATER POPCORN, BUT I'LL TAKE
THE POPCORN.
I STILL FEEL LIKE IT'S A HEALTH
FOOD.
MICHAEL: WELL, GLAD YOU'RE
ENJOYING IT BECAUSE YOU'RE ON
THE POPCORN OF THE MONTH CLUB.
KELLY: WHOO-HOO!
[APPLAUSE]
I LOVE POPCORN.
MICHAEL: OH, BOY.
KELLY: WE HAVE A HUGE SHOW
TODAY.
SETH ROGEN IS HERE FROM THE NEW
FILM "THE GUILTY TRIP."
MICHAEL: AND OUR "THIS
CHRISTMAS" CONTINUES FROM THE
BROADWAY MUSICAL, "ANNIE."
KELLY: THE SUN WILL COME OUT
MICHAEL: YES.
KELLY: DID HE JUST SAY YOU BET
YOUR BOTTOM DOLLAR?
HE DID.
THANK YOU, DADDY WARBUCKS.
MICHAEL: NOW IT'S TIME FOR OUR
FAVORITE "FALL INTO THE HOLIDAYS
TRAVEL TRIVIA."
[APPLAUSE]
♪
[APPLAUSE]KELLY: YOU'RE MY HERO.
THAT BALL WAS COMING STRAIGHT
FOR MY FACE AND YOU JUST REACHED
OUT WITH YOUR FOOTBALL COMMANDS
YOU JUST -- OH.
MICHAEL: YOU KNOW WHAT?
KELLY: WE CAN SEE YOU.
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL: SECURITY!
KELLY: SHE THINKS WE'RE STILL IN
THE TV.
MICHAEL: THAT WAS ONE OF THOSE
OH, I'M GOING TO LET THEM THINK
WE'RE ALL GONE AND HIT THEM IN
THE FACE.
KELLY: TODAY'S TRIVIA DANCER IS
KIMBERLY MOORE FROM GEORGIA.
HEY, KIMBERLY.
[APPLAUSE]
SEE HOW AE IS?
SHE'S GOT HER ANTLERS.
SHE'S GOT HER LEATHER LEGGINGS
AND HER APPROPRIATELY LONG
SHIRT.
[APPLAUSE]
GOOD FOR YOU.
MY DAUGHTER SNEAKS BY ME GOING
WITH THE LEGGINGS AND THE LONG
PANTS.
AND I SAY GO CHANGE.
>> YOU LIKE TO SNEAK ME OUT WITH
THE MEGGINGS.
KELLY: YEP.
ON THE PHONE IS JOHN EVANS, FROM
MANSFIELD, OHIO.
HEY, JOHN.
CALLER: AWW, LOOK AT HIS POOCH.
MICHAEL: WHO IS WITH YOU IN THE
PICTURE?
CALLER: THAT'S MY DOG, SUGAR.
KELLY: I LOVE SUGAR.
AWW, I LOVE SUGAR SO MUCH.
MICHAEL: SO JOHN, WHAT ARE YOU
UP TO TODAY?
CALLER: OH, THEY'RE JUST EATING
ON BREAKFAST.
WE'RE ABOUT TO DO SOME MORE
CHRISTMAS SHOPPING.
KELLY: YOU'RE NOT DONE YET.
WHO DO YOU HAVE TO SHOP FOR?
CALLER: I'VE GOT MY MOM LEFT TO
DO.
YOU GUYS HAVE ANY IDEA?
KELLY: HAVE YOU THOUGHT ABOUT
GIVING HER THE SOCK OF THE MONTH
CLUB?
CALLER:
[LAUGHTER]
NO.
MICHAEL: I'LL SEND HER MY -- HER
MY MEGGINGS.
YOU CAN'T GO WRONG WITH MOM.
JUST SEND HER SOME LOVE.
KELLY: HOW ABOUT A NICE TRIP FOR
HER?
I'LL SPIN THE WHEEL, OK?
CALLER: OK.
[APPLAUSE]
♪
KELLY: HEY, JOHN, DOES YOUR MOM
LIVE IN FLORIDA?
KELLY:
KELLY: THAT'S GOOD.
BECAUSE YOU'RE PLAYING FOR THE
TRADE WINDS ISLAND BEACH RESORT
IN ST. PETE, FLORIDA, INCLUDING
BREAKFAST AND LUNCH DAILY, ONE
SPA TREATMENT PER PERSON,
ROUNDTRIP AFFAIR, AND A PRIZE
VALUED SAT $4300 AND MY
MOTHER-IN-LAW SAYS IT'S RIGHT
DOWN THE STREET FROM HER
APARTMENT.
SO SHE'LL COOK YOU DINNER.
[LAUGHTER]
[APPLAUSE]
Y ONE
GUESS.
GOOD LUCK.
CALLER: OK.
MICHAEL: ON YESTERDAY'S SHOW, WE
TALKED WITH ACTOR PAUL RUDD.
IN WHAT 2007 FILM DID WE SAY
PAUL'S CHARACTER IN HIS CURRENT
FILM ALSO APPEARS?
CALLER: OH.
I MISSED THAT PART.
I DON'T HAVE THE SLIGHTEST IDEA.
I MISSED THAT PART OF IDEA.
-- SHOW.
KELLY: TAKE A GUESS.
YOU HAVE FIVE SECONDS.
CALLER: I DON'T HAVE MY GUESS.
MICHAEL: THE ANSWER WAS "KNOCKED
UP."
CALLER: OH.
MICHAEL: THE MOVIE "KNOCKED
UP."
KELLY: IT'S OK, JOHN, BECAUSE MY
MOTHER-IN-LAW WASN'T WITH GOING
TO BE HOME FOR SEVERAL MONTHS.
[LAUGHTER]
BUT LISTEN, NOW AND A LUCKY
MEMBER OF OUR STUDIO AUDIENCE
WILL EACH RECEIVE A $500 GIFT
CERTIFICATE FROM BED BATH &
BEYOND.
[APPLAUSE]
SO PLEASE PICK A NUMBER BETWEEN
ONE AND 232.
CALLER: UM, 231.
[APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, JOHN, THANK YOU FOR
PLAYING WITH US.
SIR, CONGRATULATIONS.
STAY RIGHT THERE.
NEXT, SETH ROGEN.
[APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: STILL AHEAD ON
"LIVE," OUR COUNTDOWN TO
CHRISTMAS WEEK CONTINUES WITH A
MUSICAL FROM ANN ABOUT.
WE'LL OPEN UP KELLY AND
MICHAEL'S "INBOX."
AND COMING UP NEXT, SETH ROGEN.
[ Female Announcer ]
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
THEY'RE WHOLE GRAIN GOOD...
AND YUMMY GOOD.
REAL FRUIT PIECES.
12 GRAMS OF WHOLE GRAINS
AND A CREAMY
YOGURT FLAVORED COATING.
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
TREAT YOURSELF GOOD.
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY: HEY ON TOMORROW'S SHOW,
IT'S SORT OF A REALLY BIG DEAL.
JOHN TRAVOLTA AND OLIVIA
NEWTON-JOHN WILL BE HERE.
THEY HAVE A NEW CHRISTMAS ALBUM
CALLED "THIS CHRISTMAS."
[APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: AND OUR "THIS
CHRISTMAS" CONTINUES WITH A LOOK
AT THE BEST A.P.S TO GET YOU
THROUGH THE -- APPS TO GET YOU
THROUGH THE HOLIDAYS.
KELLY: LIKE WHAT IS IT?
LIKE AN APP THAT HITS YOU IN THE
HEAD WITH A HAMMER WHEN YOUR
KIDS DRIVE HOME?
GELMAN: TO HELP YOU OUT.
KELLY: WITH GIFTS AND
EVERYTHING?
GELMAN: YEAH.
KELLY: WOW.
MICHAEL: PERFECT.
GELMAN: YOU'VE GOT IT.
TOMORROW.
KELLY: HE'S STARRED IN SOME OF
THE FUNNIEST FILMS IN THE PAST
10 YEARS.
PLEASE WELCOME BACK TO THE SHOW,
SETH ROGEN.
[APPLAUSE]
HI, SETH.
>> HI.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
HELLO, SIR.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY: WELCOME BACK.
WE'RE SO HAPPY TO SEE YOU.
>> THANK YOU.
GLAD TO BE HERE.
THESE CHAIRS MOVE.
I ALMOST JUST FELL REALLY BAD
SITTING.
KELLY: DID YOU?
>> YEAH, I ALMOST LEANED ON AND
FELL.
MICHAEL: I WOULD HAVE HELPED YOU
UP.
KELLY: WE DO THAT TO PEOPLE SO
YOU COULD GIVE US TRUTHFUL
ANSWERS.
>> YEAH.
KELLY: THERE WAS RECENTLY A
"FREAKS AND GEEKS" REUNION FOR
"VANITY FAIR."
>> YES.
I WAS 16 WHEN I DID IT AND IT
WON'T GO AWAY.
IT'S STILL HAPPENING.
KELLY: DON'T YOU THINK IT'S MORE
POPULAR NOW THAN IT IS THEN?
>> YES, I DEFINITELY GET
RECOGNIZED FOR IT NOW AND MORE
PEOPLE WATCHING IT NOW THAT IT'S
ON D.V.D. WHEN I WAS ON 16.
AT THE TIME, I WAS LIKE I'M ON A
TV SHOW AND THEN IT GOT CANCELED
REALLY FAST.
AND NOW, YEAH, 15 YEARS LATER,
PEOPLE WERE LIKE NICE SHOW.
YOU LOOK TERRIBLE IN REAL LIFE.
MICHAEL: BUT YOU DO COMIC-CON
AND ALL THAT?
>> YES, I DO.
I'M A GIANT NERD.
I READ A LOT OF COMIC BOOKS.
I LOST MY VIRGINITY AT AN OLD
AGE.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: THAT'S OK.
>> ALL THAT STUFF.
MICHAEL: I'M SORRY.
IT TOOK ME A MINUTE.
OH, I GOT IT.
I GOT IT.
OH, MAN, THAT'S GOOD.
>> WELL, PEOPLE DON'T ADMIT
THAT.
MICHAEL: OH, BOY.
KELLY: BUT IT DID HAPPEN AND YOU
JUST CELEBRATED YOUR ONE-YEAR
ANNIVERSARY.
>> EXACTLY.
I GOT MARRIED.
YES.
[APPLAUSE]
THANK YOU.
IT'S TRUE.
A LITTLE OVER A YEAR AGO, IT
FINALLY HAPPENED FOR ME.
IT WAS GOOD.
IT WAS SCARY.
NO.
[LAUGHTER]
YEAH, I GOT MARRIED OVER A YEAR
AGO AND WE'RE STILL MARRIED,
WHICH IS PRETTY GOOD.
KELLY: I BELIEVE LIKE THE FIRST
EYE OF MARRIAGE, I MEAN, FROM MY
POINT OF VIEW, THE HARDEST.
DID YOU MIND IT -- FIND IT TO BE
THE HARD SHE'S
>> NO, I FOUND OUT SHE'S BEEN
FULL OF RAGE TO ME THAT I
HAVEN'T ASKED HER TO MARRY HER
EARLIER, THIS YEAR HAS BEEN THE
GREATEST YEAR OF MY LIFE.
I DON'T GET THE SENSE THAT SHE'S
GOING TO STAB ME IN MY SLEEP.
MICHAEL: YOU'RE FUNNY, MAN.
YOUR PROPOSAL STORY THAT YOU
TOLD, YOU PROPOSED TO HER WHEN
YOU SAID SHE WAS TOPLESS, BUT --
>> SHE WAS --
MICHAEL: YOUR FATHER-IN-LAW
DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
>> NO.
I PROPOSED TO HER.
SHE WAS CHANGING.
I GOT THE RING AND I FELT LIKE I
HAD A NUCLEAR BOMB LIKE I HAD TO
GET RID OF IT.
LIKE I'VE GOT UNLOAD THIS THING.
IED A ALL OF THESE ELABORATE
PLANS AND THE SEC I GOT HOME, I
THOUGHT I'M DOING IT AND SHE'S
CHANGING AND SHE'S TOPLESS.
I'M DOING IT RIGHT NOW.
[LAUGHTER]
AND I GUESS SHE DIDN'T TELL MANY
PEOPLE THAT STORY BECAUSE SHE
WASN'T AS PSYCHED ABOUT IT AS I
WAS.
AND THEN I STARTED TELLING IT ON
TALK SHOWS AND MAGAZINES AND
STUFF LIKE THAT AND HER
FATHER-IN-LAW, I GUESS DIDN'T
KNOW AND WASN'T, YOU KNOW,
TICKLED BY IT AS I WAS.
KELLY: YOU MEAN YOUR
FATHER-IN-LAW?
>> MY FATHER-IN-LAW.
BOTH FATHERS-IN-LAW.
I'M NOT GOOD AT THIS.
IS HE MY IN-LAW?
HE'S NOT MY STEP DAD?
KELLY: NO, HE'S YOUR
FATHER-IN-LAW, NOT YOUR STEPDAD.
IF HE WAS YOUR STEPDAD, THAT
WOULD BE REALLY CREEPY.
>> YOU NEVER KNOW.
KELLY: AND YOU'VE ALSO IN
ADDITION TO CELEBRATING YOUR
ONE-YEAR ANNIVERSARY, YOU
DIRECTED YOUR OWN FILM?
>> I DID.
IT COMES OUT THIS SUMMER WITH ME
AND JAMES FRANCO'S IN IT AND
JONAH HILL IS IN IT, AND DANNY
MCBRIDE AND MICHAEL SARAH AND
PAUL RUDD IS A PART OF IT.
EVERY IDIOT I'M IN EVERY MOVIE
IS IN IT.
MICHAEL: SO WE HAVE TO TAKE A
QUICK BREAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'LL FIND
OUT ABOUT HOLLYWOOD'S NEWEST
COUPLE, STREISAND AND ROGEN.
KELLY: OH, MY GOD.
ANNOUNCER: STILL AHEAD ON
"LIVE," A PERFORMANCE FROM THE
BROADWAY MUSICAL "ANNIE."
MICHAEL: WE ARE BACK WITH SETH
ROGEN, STAR OF DEBATE DESK.
-- "THE GUILTY TRIP."
HOLIDAY IS HERE.
HOW IS ZELLEDA DOING?
>> SHE'S GOOD.
SHE'S JEWISH.
KELLY: WAS SHE BORN JEWISH?
>> WE CONVERTED HER TO JEWISH.
KELLY: GOOD FOR HER.
>> MY WIFE MAKES THESE CALENDARS
SHE TORTURES OUR DOG AND DRESS
HER UP.
THAT MIGHT BE ILLEGAL.
SHE DOES NOT LOOK HAPPY IN THAT
PICTURE.
IF SHE COULD TALK, SHE WOULD SAY
"WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS TO ME"
KELLY: SHE'S SO CUTE.
>> SHE'S A VERY CUTE DOG.
VERY CUTE DOG.
KELLY: LET'S TALK ABOUT YOUR NEW
FILM, "THE GUILTY TRIP," WHERE
YOU GO ACROSS THE COUNTRY WITH
BARBRA STREISAND.
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU GET TO SPEND
SO MUCH TIME WITH HER IN A CAR
GOING ACROSS COUNTRY.
>> YEP, WE DID NOT LEAVE MALIBU,
ACTUALLY, WHILE GOING ACROSS
COUNTRY.
KELLY: ARE YOU KIDDING?
>> NO.
BARBRA DOESN'T WANT TO LEAVE
MALIBU.
SHE LOVES IT THERE.
WHEN YOU'RE BARBRA STREISAND,
YOU CAN SAY THINGS OVER THERE.
SHE COULD SAY I WANT TO DRIVE
CROSS-COUNTRY BUT I DON'T WANT
TO LEAVE MALIBU.
THERE'S A SCENE WHERE
DR WE'RE
DRIVING TO GRAND CANYON AND WE
BROUGHT THE GRAND CANYON TO HER.
KELLY: SO IT WAS A SCREEN?
>> YEAH.
AND SHE JUST LIKE THE WHOLE
TIME, WE'RE LIKE IN BARBRA'S
FRONT LAWN.
LITERALLY.
IT'S REMARKABLE.
MICHAEL: DID YOU HAVE ANY
HESITATIONS ABOUT DOING A MOVIE
WITH BARBRA STREISAND?
I MEAN, SUCH A BIG STAR?
>> NO, NOT REALLY.
I HONESTLY JUST -- I USUALLY
JUST MAKE REALLY FILTHY MOVIES.
SO I WASN'T -- I HAD HESITATIONS
ABOUT DOING A MOVIE THAT WASN'T
REALLY DIRTY.
I WASN'T SURE IF I COULD STILL
BE FUNNY.
THAT WAS MY MAJOR FEAR, BUT THE
SCRIPT IS REALLY GOOD AND IT'S A
REALLY SWEET MOVIE AND IT'S
PROBABLY, YEAH, ONE OF THE FIRST
MOVIES I'VE DONE THAT LIKE A LOT
OF PEOPLE WON'T REALLY HATE ME
FOR.
SO YEAH, IT WAS REFRESHING TO
DO, ACTUALLY.
KELLY: AND I KNOW THAT YOUR WIFE
IS A HUGE BARBRA STREISAND FAN.
SO WHEN SHE HEARD YOU WERE
OFFERED THIS FILM, DID YOU SHE
SAY YOU'RE DOING IT?
>> SHE WAS REALLY PSYCHED ABOUT
IT.
SHE'S A HUGE FAN.
SHE'S DRAGGED ME TO SEVERAL OF
BARBRA'S CONCERTS OVER THE
YEARS.
I LOVE IT.
[LAUGHTER]
IT'S NOT MY KIND OF MUSIC.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY.
I LISTEN TO RAP.
BUT YEAH, SHE'S -- NOW MY WIFE
AND BARBRA KNOW EACH OTHER.
SHE'S THRILLED.
MICHAEL: YOU'RE MOTHER AND SON
IN THE FIT.
BUT WERE THERE ANY SIMILARITY
BETWEEN YOUR MOTHER AND YOUR
REAL MOTHER?
>> YEAH, THEY'RE BOTH JEWISH
LADIES.
THAT'S LIKE 98% OF SOMEONE'S
PERSONALITY, I THINK, IN A LOT
OF WAYS.
[LAUGHTER]
SHE PUSHES ME TO EAT A BUNCH OF
STUFF I DON'T WANT AND WHEN I
EAT IT, SHE CRITICIZES ME FOR
EATING TOO MUCH.
IT'S LIKE THAT.
[LAUGHTER]
THAT KIND OF THING.
SHE'S ALSO MESSING WITH MY HAIR,
ALWAYS TOUCHING MY HAIR.
SHE'S A LOT LIKE MY REAL MOTHER.
IT'S LIKE SHE REALLY IS, I'VE
GOT TO SAY.
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY: WE HAVE TO TAKE A
COMMERCIAL BREAK.
BUT WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE
GOING TO TAKE A LOOK AT A SCENE
FROM "THE GUILTY TRIP" WITH SETH
ROGEN AND BARBRA STREISAND WHEN
WE RETURN.
DON'T GO AWAY.
[APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: THIS IS BOB,"LIVE," ]
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
SUCH AS KID ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
KELLY: WE'RE BACK WITH SETH
ROGEN, STAR OF "THE GUILT TRIP."
WOULD YOU WORK WITH BARBRA
STREISAND AGAIN NOW THAT OFF
CHOICE, NOW THAT YOU SAY YOUR
MUSIC IS NOT HER CUP OF TEA?
>> MY MOVIES ARE NOT HER CUP OF
TEA.
I WOULD LOVE TO WORK WITH HER
AGAIN.
YEAH, SHE WAS SUPER COOL.
SHE HAS GREAT STORIES ABOUT --
SHE KNEW LIKE ELVIS.
IT'S CRAZY.
LIKE THE STORIES SHE HAS.
SO YEAH.
[LAUGHTER]
SHE REALLY DID.
THAT'S NOT A JOKE.
KELLY: WHAT DID SHE SAY ABOUT
ELVIS?
CAN YOU RECALL ANYTHING?
>> SHE SAID THAT EVERYONE
THOUGHT HE WAS A HOODLUM BECAUSE
HE HAD GREASY HAIR BUT SHE LIKED
HIM AND THOUGHT HE WAS CUTE AND
TRIED TO PUT HIM IN MOVIE IN A
MOVIE.
KELLY: NO KIDDING?
>> YEAH.
THAT'S BARBRA'S ELVIS STORY.
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: SHE'S -- SHE HAS PRETTY
FINGERNAILS, RIGHT?
>> OH, YEAH.
NOT LIKE MINE.
HERS ARE VERY ATTRACTIVE.
KNOWN FOR THEM.
WOMEN WHO COULD COME TO SET
WOULD GO LET'S GO LOOK AT HER
FINGERNAILS.
MICHAEL: THAT IS A RANDOM
QUESTION.
KELLY: NO, SHE'S KNOWN TO HAVE
VERY BEAUTIFUL COMMANDS
FINGERNAILS.
>> SHE GETS THEM DONE ONCE A
WEEK.
KELLY: ONCE A WEEK.
ONCE A WEEK IS WHAT IT TAKES.
>> THAT'S THE BARBRA REGIMEN.
KELLY: NOW I'M HIDING MY HANDS.
>> I GO TWICE A WEEK.
MICHAEL: DID YOU FIND HER -- WAS
SHE BOSSY?
>> NO.
NOT AT ALL.
SHE'S LIKE -- SHE TECHNICALLY
KNOWS A LOT ABOUT FILMMAKING.
SO SHE WON'T HIDE HER OPINION AS
IF SHE FEELS LIKE THE LIGHTING
CAN BE IMPROVED OR CAMERA ANGLE
COULD BE BETTER.
BUT YEAH, BUT NO, SHE'S NOT
BOSSY AT ALL.
SHE'S LIKE A JEWISH LADY.
[LAUGHTER]
THEY'RE A LITTLE BOSSY, BUT YOU
KNOW.
MICHAEL: WELL, LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT A CLIP AND SEE THE NON-BOSSY
BARBRA STREISAND IN ACTION IN
ROAD TRIP AND ON THIS ONE, YOU
RAISE A TOPIC OF A ROAD TRIP
WITH YOUR MOTHER?
>> YEAH, I'M INVITING HER TO
COME WITH ME.
MICHAEL: PERFECT.
"THE GUILT TRIP."
>> DO YOU WANT TO COME ON A TRIP
WITH ME, MOM?
>> YOU WANT TO DRIVE
CROSS-COUNTRY WITH ME?
>> YEAH.
NO.
IT'S, YOU KNOW, WE WON'T BE
GOING LONG.
IT'S ONLY EIGHT DAYS IN A CAR
TOGETHER.
>> WAIT.
I WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT I'M
HEARING THIS CORRECTLY.
YOU WANT TO SPEND A WEEK IN A
CAR WITH YOUR MOTHER?
>> MORE THAN ANYTHING IN THE
WORLD.
[LAUGHTER]
>> DON'T YOU THINK I MIGHT GET
ON YOUR NERVES A LITTLE BIT?
>> N.
AN WAS JUST A THOUGHT.
AND IF YOU DONE WANT TO DO IT,
THAT'S FINE.
>> NO, AM I SO AWFUL THAT YOU
DON'T WANT TO SPEND TIME IN A
CAR WITH ME?
>> I'M INVITING YOU.
>> I WOULD HAVE TO REROUTE MY
NAIL.
>> YOU HAVE FIVE SECONDS TO TELL
ME WHETHER YOU WANT TO GO OR
NOT.
>> I CAN'T WAIT.
WHAT ARE YOU?
KIDDING ME?
HONEY, THAT'S SO EXCITING.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> OH, MY GOD.
I CAN'T BELIEVE -- I HAVE TO
TOUCH MY ROOTS THOUGH BEFORE I
GO.
WHEN ARE WE GOING TO PACK --
WHAT WITH WE GOING TO PACK?
YOU'VE GOT TO FILL ME IN ON ALL
THE STATES WE'RE GOING TO.
[APPLAUSE]
[LAUGHTER]
KELLY: THAT WAS SO FUNNY.
YOU TWO MAY BE MY NEW FAVORITE
SUPER COUPLE.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH, YES.
SETHRA ROGUESTRAND.
KELLY: IT'S "THE GUILT TRIP" AND
IT OPENS TOMORROW.
GO SEE IT, EVERYBODY.
[APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: NEXT, A PERFORMANCE
FROM "ANNIE."
ANNOUNCER: THE ORBITZ IPHONE APP
IS THE ULTRA FAST WAY TO BOOK
YOUR PERFECT HOTEL.
FIND IT IN THE PERFECT SPOT AND
SAVE UP TO 50% WITH EXCLUSIVE
ORBITZ MOBILE STEALS.
ORBITZ, TAKE VACATION BACK.
FRIDAY ON "LIVE" FROM THE FILM "
ARCH FRAUGE," ACTOR RICHARD
GERE.
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY: HEY, OUR "COUNTDOWN TO
CHRISTMAS WEEK" CONTINUES WITH A
PERFORMANCE TO GET US ALL IN THE
HOLIDAY SPIRIT FROM THE BROADWAY
PRODUCTION OF "ANNIE."
HERE'S LILLA CRAWFORD SINGING A
TRUE CLASSIC, "TOMORROW."
>> OH, POOR BOY, DID THEY HURT
YOU?
THEY'RE AFTER YOU, ABILITY THEY?
WELL, THEY'RE AFTER ME TOO.
BUT DON'T WORRY.
I AIN'T GOING TO LET THEM GET
YOU OR ME.
I'LL TAKE CARE OF YOU.
AND EVERYTHING'S GOING TO BE
FINE.
FOR THE BOTH OF US.
IF NOT TODAY.
WELL ♪
THE SUN WILL COME OUT TOMORROW
BET YOUR BOTTOM DOLLAR THAT
TOMORROW
THERE'LL BE SUN
JUST THINKING ABOUT TOMORROW
CLEARS AWAY THE COBWEBS AND THE
SORROW TILL THERE'S NONE
WHEN I'M STUCK WITH A DAY THAT'S
GRAY AND LONELY, I JUST STICK UP
MY CHIN AND GRIN AND SIGH THE
SUN WILL COME OUT TOMORROW, SO
YOU'VE GOT TO HANG TILL
TOMORROW
COME WHAT MAY
TOMORROW, TOMORROW, I LOVE YOU
TOMORROW, YOU'RE ALWAYS A DAY
AWAY
TOMORROW, TOMORROW, I LOVE YOU,
TOMORROW, YOU'RE ALWAYS A DAY
AWAY ♪
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY: WOW!
LILLA CRAWFORD, EVERYBODY.
THAT WAS TERRIFIC.
>> THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
KELLY: AND WHO'S YOUR FRIEND
HERE?
MICHAEL: THAT WAS GREAT.
>> THANK YOU.
KELLY: WHO PLAYS SANDY?
>> THIS IS SUNNY.
KELLY: SONNY PLAYS SANDY.
SO YOU'RE 11 YEARS OLD FROM LOS
ANGELES, CALIFORNIA CAN.
I'M ASSUMING THAT YOU'VE BEEN
ACTING YOUR WHOLE LIFE?
>> YES, WELL, I -- I MEAN, EVER
SINCE I WAS LITTLE, I WOULD
ALWAYS DANCE AROUND THE HOUSE
SINGING EVER SINCE I EARS YEARS
OLD.
SO I THINK I WAS ALWAYS MEANT TO
DO THIS.
I MEAN, I LOVE IT.
SO WHEN I WAS 4 YEARS OLD, I SAW
MY FIRST BROADWAY SHOW WHICH WAS
"BEAUTY AND THE BEAST" AND AFTER
I SAW THAT, I WAS LIKE THIS IS
WHAT I WANT TO DO FOR THE REST
OF MY LIFE AND I'M LOVING IT SO
FAR.
KELLY: THAT'S SO GREAT.
[APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: AND YOU ALSO IN "BILLY
ELLIOT" AND NOW YOU'RE IN
"ANNIE."
WHAT WERE THE AUDITION PROCESS
LIKE?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, I AUDITIONED
ONCE AND THEN I HAD FIVE
CALLBACKS BUT IT SEEMED LIKE 10
CALLBACKS BECAUSE SOME CALLBACKS
WOULD BE ALMOST A WEEK LONG.
KELLY: OH, MY GOSH.
>> AND WE DID EVERYTHING.
WE DID SINGING.
WE DID DANCING.
WE DID ACTING.
AND WE EVEN WORKED WITH THE DOG
A LITTLE BIT.
KELLY: YOU HAD A SERIOUS FOOT
INJURY VERY RECENTLY IN THE
MIDDLE OF A PERFORMANCE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WELL, YOU KNOW, MY FOOT WAS
STUCK UNDER A SET PIECE WALL
WHILE IT WAS MOVING.
AND SO THAT WAS -- AND THAT WAS
DURING A PERFORMANCE AND IT WAS
CRAZY.
I MEAN, I'M SO LUCKY IT'S NOT
BROKEN, IT'S NOT FRACTURED, IT'S
NOT EVEN SPRAINED.
IT'S JUST A BUNCH OF CUTS AND
BRUISES AND SCRAPES AND SO --
KELLY: BUT YOU'RE OK?
>> YEAH, I'M OK.
MICHAEL: WELL, THAT'S GOODNESS
YOU ARE OK.
>> I'M SO LUCKY.
[APPLAUSE]
MICHAEL: AND LILLA CRAWFORD IS
"ANNIE" AND NOW PLAYING AT THE
PALACE THEATER.
GO CHECK IT OUT.
KELLY: YOU ARE AMAZING.
>> THANK YOU.
KELLY: WE'RE GOING TO OPEN UP
THE "INBOX" WHEN WE COME HOME.
HEY, SONNY.
GOOD JOB.
ANNOUNCER: THURSDAY ON "LIVE"
FROM THE NEW FILM "DJANGO
UNCHAINED," ACTOR SAMUEL L.
JACKSON.
[ Female Announcer ]
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
THEY'RE WHOLE GRAIN GOOD...
AND YUMMY GOOD.
REAL FRUIT PIECES.
12 GRAMS OF WHOLE GRAINS
AND A CREAMY
YOGURT FLAVORED COATING.
QUAKER YOGURT GRANOLA BARS.
TREAT YOURSELF GOOD.
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY: HEY, HERE'S A REMINDER TO
SEND AN E-MAIL TO OUR "INBOX."
MICHAEL: YES, BECAUSE THIS
FRIDAY IS THE DEADLINE TO BE
ENTERED A GREAT PRIZE, A COLGATE
OPTIC WHITE PACK AND AN ALL
SPENCE PAID TRIP TO NEW YORK
WITH V.I.P. TICKETS TO "LIVE."
YEAH.
[APPLAUSE]
AND ON TOP OF THAT, YOU GET A
$1,000 SHOPPING SPREE.
KELLY: WOW.
THAT'S AMAZING PRIZE.
IF YOU WANT TO WIN, JUST GO TO
OUR WEBSITE AND CLICK ON "INBOX"
TO ENTER.
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO WANT TO MISS
THIS OPPORTUNITY BECAUSE IT'S A
GREAT TRIP AND $1,000.
THE WHOLE THING.
MICHAEL: AND THE COLGATE.
NOT BAD.
KELLY: FANTASTIC.
WE'VE GOT A LOT OF "INBOX"
RESPONSES ABOUT LEGGINGS AND
MEGGINGS AND JEGGINGS AND YOU
NAME IT.
CHARLOTTE FROM OHIO SAYS I'M
SORRY, BUT MEN'S LEGGINGS ARE
JUST LOOK LIKE LONG UNDERWEAR TO
ME.
HOWEVER, MICHAEL WOULD STILL
LOOK GOOD IN THEM.
[APPLAUSE]
WE AGREE.
WE SHOULD TRY THEM ON HIM JUST
TO BE SURE.
MICHAEL: YES, THIS WOMAN SAYS HE
WORE HIS LEGGINGS HIS ENTIRE
FOOTBALL CAREER.
[LAUGHTER]
MICHAEL, THOSE WEREN'T PANTS.
KELLY: THOSE WERE NOT LEGGINGS.
THOSE WERE BALLET TIGHTS.
GELMAN: AND THAT WAS WHEN YOU
WERE GUARANTEED.
MICHAEL: YEAH, AND WE WORE
HELMETS TO COVER OUR FACE SO YOU
COULDN'T SEE.
GELMAN: WE WERE ABLE TO BUY SOME
MEGGINGS.
WE MAY BE ABLE TO BUY MICHAEL
SOME MEGGINGS.
KELLY: HOLD ON.
YOU SPENT $24 ON THEM?
GELMAN: YEAH.
MICHAEL: WE'LL SEE.
KELLY: I USED TO AGREE WITH
KELLY THAT LEGGINGS AREN'T PANTS
AND THEN I GOT PREGNANT AND
LEGGINGS ARE JUST TOO
COMFORTABLE.
OK, LISTEN TO ME.
NOW THAT YOU ARE PREGNANT IT IS
PANTS.LLY IMPORTANT TO REALLY
THEY ARE LEGGINGS MEANT TO BE
WORN UNDER SOMETHING.
ANYWAY, ENJOY.
MICHAEL: YEAH, ENJOY, EVERYBODY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: WRITE INTO "LIVE"'S
"INBOX" AND BE ENTERED TO WIN AN
ALL-SPENCE PAID TRIP TO NEW YORK
SPONSORED BY COLGATE OPTIC WHITE
.
LOG ON TO
LIVEKELLYANDMICHAEL.COM FOR THE
DETAILS.
IF YOU WOULD LIKE TO KNOW MORE
ABOUT ANYTHING YOU SEE ON
"LIVE," VISIT
LIVEKELLYANDMICHAEL.COM.
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY: WE'VE GOTTEN AN EXCITING
NEW CONTEST TO ANNOUNCE.
IT'S OUR FAMILY ESCAPE WATCH TO
WIN.
HERE'S ON THE TONY PIGG WITH ALL
THE DETAILS.
ANNOUNCER: IT'S "LIVE"'S FAMILY
ESCAPE WATCH TO WIN.
YEAR GIVING AN EIGHT DAY TRIP TO
LA PLAYA IN NAPLES, FLORIDA.
TWO SPA TREATMENTS PER PERSON,
OCEANFRONT BREAKFAST AND DINING
FOR THE ULTIMATE BEACHFRONT
GETAWAY.
VISIT ON LINE AT LA PLAYA.COM.
WATCH "LIVE! WITH KELLY &
MICHAEL" WEEKDAYS BEGINNING
DECEMBER 24 2012 THROUGH FRIDAY
JANUARY 4, 2013 AND LOOK FOR OUR
FAMILY ESCAPE WATCH TO WIN
QUESTION OF THE DAY WHICH WILL
BE BASED ON SOMETHING SAID
EARLIER ON THE DAY'S SHOW AND
SUBMIT THE CORRECT ANSWER EACH
DAY FOR YOUR CHANCE TO WIN.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE
LIVEKELLYANDMICHAEL.COM TO ENTER
EACH DAY'S ANSWER.
ENTRIES MUST BE RECEIVED BY
MIDNIGHT THAT SAME DAY.
EACH ANSWER COUNTS AS ONE ENTRY.
[APPLAUSE]
KELLY: EXCITING.
WELL, YOU ASKED FOR IT, YOU GOT
IT.
I DON'HEM
GET THEM
HERE SO FAST, BUT WE WRIGGLED
AND WE SQUEEZED MICHAEL STRAHAN
INTO A PAIR OF MEGGINGS.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
[CAPTIONED BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE
--WWW.NCICAP.ORG--]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Announcer: IT'S TUESDAY,
DECEMBER 18th.
COMING UP LIVE ON "THE VIEW"
THEY'RE THE "HOT TOPICS" FROM
TOM CRUISE'S PRESENT TO BARBARA
DISAPPEARED AND LADY GAGA'S
LATEST GETUP AND ANOTHER LOOK AT
VIOLENT MOVIES AND VIDEO GAMES.
"THIS IS 40" WRITER/DIRECTOR
JUDD APATOW IS TELLING YOU IF
DIRECTING HIS WIFE AND KIDS
MAKES THINGS AWKWARD ONCE THEY
GET HOME.