ORRECT RESPONSE WILL START
WITH THE LETTER "M."
Alex: ALISTAIR?
WE'LL START WITH ABBREVIATIONS
FOR $200, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS
RECOMMENDED DAILY AMOUNT?
OR ALLOWANCE. CORRECT.
ABBREVIATIONS FOR $400,
PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS ALL-WHEEL DRIVE?
YES.
$600, PLEASE.
MATT.
WHAT IS UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS,
EL PASO?
RIGHT.
ABBREVIATIONS FOR $800.
[ BEEP ]
AND THAT WOULD BE
GRAND ARMY OF THE REPUBLIC.
MATT, PICK AGAIN.
IATIONS FOR $1,000.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS WOOD-BURNING FURNACE?
NO.
MATT.
WHAT IS WOOD-BURNING FIREPLACE?
FIREPLACE --
THAT'S THE WORD, NOT FURNACE.
STARTS WITH "M$200.
CARLY.
WHAT IS MICROBREW?
GOOD.
STARTS WITH "M," $400.
MATT?
WHAT IS A MOTH?
NO.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS A MANTIS?
NO.
[ BEEP ]
THE OTHER INSECT IS
THE MOSQUITO.
BACK TO YOU, CARLY.
COLORFUL MOVIES, $200.
MATT.
WHAT IS BLACK?
YES.
COLORFUL MOVIES, $400.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS PURPLE?
PURPLE, YES.
COLORFUL MOVIES
FOR $600, PLEASE.
CARLY.
WHAT IS GRAY?
YES.
COLORFUL MOVIES FOR $800.
CARLY?
WHAT IS RED?
YOU GOT IT.
COLORFUL MOVIES, $1,000.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS BLUE?
BLUE, YES.
YOU'RE OUT OF THE HOLE.
STARTS WITH "M" FOR $600,
PLEASE.
JIMMY?
A WORD OR PHRASE THAT QUALIFIES
THE SENSE THER
IS REFERRED TO
BY THIS GRAMMATICAL TERM.
"SCARY" IS ONE FOR BOOKS.
MATT.
WHAT IS A MODIFIER?
MODIFIER --
THAT'S THE "M" WORD.
"M" FOR $800.
CARLY.
WHAT ARE THE MOORS?
YES.
STARTS WITH "M" FOR $1,000.
THEY'RE THE HEAVY WEATHER BOOTS
SEEN HERE.
MATT.
WHAT ARE MUKLUKS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
EUROPEAN RULERS FOR $200.
HANG ON JUST A SECOND.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE OUR FIRST
COMMERCIAL BREAK RIGHT NOW.
COME BACK AND CHAT
WITH THE THREE OF YOU
FOLLOWING THESE MESSAGES.
MATT STEINPREIS IS
FROM WISCONSIN,
AND HE WORKS WITH SOMETHING
THAT IS GAINING
A GREAT DEAL OF ATTENTION
THIS YEAR,
AND IT HAS TO DO WITH
HOW THE UNIVERSE WAS FORMED.
TELL US.
YES, I'M A GRADUATE STUDENT
IN PHYSICS,
AND I WORK
WITH THE LARGE HADRON COLLIDER,
WHICH IS AT CERN,
NEAR GENEVA, SWITZERLAND.
NOW, YOU SAY
LARGE HADRON COLLIDER.
HOW BIG IS IT?
I MEAN, IT'S -- WHAT?
IT'S DOZENS
OF KILOMETERS AROUND.
IT'S QUITE LARGE.
AND DOES EVERYBODY GET
REALLY EXCITED THERE
WHEN SNG HAPPENS?
OH, YES, YES.
E-MAILS CIRCULATING, TALKS,
AND EVERYONE GETS...
SO PHYSICISTS DO GET
EXCITED.
OH, YES.
ALL RIGHT, GOOD.
CARLY GRAMER
OMETHI ORLANDO, FLORIDA.
RELATED TO TWO PRESIDENTS?
YES.
WHICH TWO?
WELL, I'M RELATED
TO THE HARRISONS --
BENJAMIN HARRISON
AND WILLIAM HENRY --
BUT I COULDN'T REALLY GIVE YOU
THE EXACT LINEAGE.
I JUST KNOW THIS
FROM MY MOTHER TELLING US
THE STORY.
SO THE TWO HARRISONS.
TWO HARRISONS, YES.
IT WOULD BE EASY
TO BE RELATED TO THE TWO BUSHES
BECAUSE THE SAME FAMILY
AND CLOSER PROXIMITY.
ALL RIGHT.
ALISTAIR BELL IS
OUR CHAMPION.
NOW, I, ON OCCASION,
TEASE MY WIFE BECAUSE SHE WEARS
COLORFUL SOCKS.
AND I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU DO,
ALSO.
AND YOURS HAVE
SPECIFIC CHARACTERS ON THEM.
I TEND TO WEAR
CARTOON SOCKS.
IT BECAME MY THING,
MY SCHTICK,
AND, YES,
I AM WEARING THEM TODAY.
LIFT IT UP.
LIFT UP, A...
WE HAVE
MR. HAPPY RIGHT HERE.
MR. HAPPY. OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
I HOPE IT BRINGS YOU LUCK.
SO FAR, IT'S WORKED.
MATT, YOU HAVE
COMMAND OF THE BOARD,
AND YOU'RE
IN THE LEAD RIGHT NOW.
SO GO AHEAD.
MAKE A SELECTION.
I'LL
EUROPEAFOR $200.
ANSWER --
ALISTAIR.
WHO ARE FERDINAND AND ISABELLA?
YES.
EUROPEAN RULERS FOR $400,
PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS BELGIUM?
RIGHT.
$600, PLEASE.
MATT.
WHO IS ELIZABETH?
YES.
EUROPEAN RULERS FOR $800.
MATT.
WHO IS LOUIS XVI?
RIGHT.
RS FOR $1,000.
ALISTAIR.
WHO'S QUEEN BEATRIX?
YOU ARE RIGHT.
ROAD SHOW FOR $200, PLEASE.
THIS LONDON THOROUGHFARE
WILL BE FOREVER ICONIC
IN MUSIC HISTORY.
MATT.
WHAT IS ABBEY ROAD?
YOU GOT IT.
ROAD SHOW, $400.
THIS NEW YORK CITY STREET
IS WHERE THE TRANSACTION IS.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS WALL STREET?
YES.
$600, PLEASE.
IT'S THE STREET
WHERE YOU'LL FIND
THE ADDRESS SEEN HERE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS DOWNING STREET?
CORRECT.
$800, PLEASE.
IT'S THE POTENT-POTABLE NAME
OF THIS STREET.
CARLY.
WHAT IS BOURBON STREET?
YOU GOT IT.
ROAD SHOW FOR $1,000
ANSWER THERE --
THE DAILY DOUBLE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
YOU'RE IN A TIE WITH ALISTAIR
FOR SECOND PLACE AT THE MOMENT.
MATT HAS THE LEAD.
UM, $1,200.
ALL RIGHT.
IT'S THE STREET
OF LIGHT SEEN HERE.
WHAT IS THE CHAMPS-ELYSéES?
YES, THAT'S IT.
[ APPLAUSE ]
$4,400.
ANTIQUES FOR $200.
MATT?
WHAT IS 100?
CORRECT.
ANTIQUES FOR $400.
CARLY.
WHAT IS A LAMP?
THAT'S RIGHT.
$600.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT ARE LEGS?
NO.
CARLY OR MATT.
[ BEEP ]
YOU HAD TO GO FURTHER DOWN
TO THE FEET, NOT THE LEG.
THE FEET.
CARLY, BACK TO YOU.
$800.
MATT.
WHAT IS AN ELEPHANT?
NOPE.
CARLY OR ALISTAIR?
[ BEEP ]
WHAT IS A WALRUS.
NOW THE LAST CLUE
FOR $1,000.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS BAKELITE?
THAT'S IT, YES.
AND THAT TAKES YOU
TO $3,600.
YOU'RE STILL IN THIRD PLACE,
AND THAT MEANS, OF COURSE,
YOU'RE GOING FIRST
IN THE DOUBLE JEOPARDY! ROUND
AFTER THIS.
[ APPLAUSE ]
YOU'RE PICKING FIRST
IN DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
AND HERE ARE THE CATEGORIES.
...WORDS THAT ARE
SPELLED THE SAME
BUT PRONOUNCED DIFFERENTLY.
Alex: ALISTAIR?
I SHALL START
WITH COUNTRY OF BIRTH
FOR $400, PLEASE, ALEX.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS ENGLAND?
YES.
COUNTRY OF BIRTH $800,
PLEASE.
ALISTAIR?
WHAT IS AUSTRIA?
GOOD.
$1,200, PLEASE.
[ BEEP ]
BORN IN NORWAY.
ALISTAIR.
$1,600, PLEASE.
[ BEEP ]
MEXICO.
ALISTAIR.
$2,000, PLEASE.
[ BEEP ]
HE WAS BORN IN HUNGARY.
TWO OUT OF FIVE ON THAT,
ALISTAIR.
PICK SOMEWHERE ELSE NOW.
CHEMISTS FOR $400, PLEASE.
MATT.
HEAVY WATER?
WHAT IS HEAVY WATER?
THAT'S RIGHT.
CHEMISTS FOR $800.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS PHTHESIS?
THAT'S IT.
$1,200, PLEASE.
MATT.
WHO IS MENDELEEV?
YES.
CHEMISTS, $1,600.
ALISTAIR?
WHAT IS INSULIN?
YES.
$2,000, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR?
DOW?
HERBERT HENRY DOW --
YES, YOU'RE RIGHT.
HETERONYMS FOR $400, PLEASE.
MATT.
WHAT IS PATE, OR PATé?
CORRECT.
HETERONYMS, $800.
ALISTAIR?
WHAT IS PRIMER, OR PRIMER?
YES.
HETERONYMS FOR $1,200,
PLEASE.
MATT.
WHAT IS WOUND, OR WOUND?
YES.
HETERONYMS, $1,600.
[ BEEP ]
"WHAT IS APPROPRIATE,
OR APPROPRIATE?"
MATT.
ALL RIGHT,
WE'LL FINISH HETERONYMS.
MATT.
WHAT IS A COMBINE?
COMBINE.
YOU MOVE UP TO $9,200.
YOU'RE $800 OFF THE LEAD.
TOON TIME FOR $400.
MATT.
WHO IS SPACELY?
MR. SPACELY.
YOU GOT HIM.
TOON TIME, $800.
[ BEEP ]
AND THAT WOULD BE OPUS.
MATT.TOON TIME, $1,200.
CARLY.
WHO IS BORIS BADENOV?
YES.
TOON TIME FOR $1,600.
[ BEEP ]
HIS NAME IS HADJI.
CARLY.
TOON TIME, $2,000.
MA
WHO IS THE COMEDIAN?
$2,000 MORE AND THE LEAD.
CIVIL WAR LITERATURE FOR $400.
TT.
$2,000 MORE AND THE LEAD.
MATT.
WHAT IS GETTYSBURG?
CORRECT.
LITE, $800.
MATT.
WHAT IS
"THE RED BADGE OF COURAGE"?
YES, THAT'S RIGHT.
LITERATURE, $1,200.
ANSWER THERE --
DAILY DOUBLE.
AND YOU HAVE
A $2,800 LEAD.
[ APPLAUSE ]
UM...
LET'S JUST DO $1,000.
ALL RIGHT.
HERE IS THE CLUE.
WHAT IS "LITTLE WOMEN"?
"LITTLE WOMEN," THAT'S IT.
YES.
DON'T BE UPSET
THAT YOU DIDN'T WAGER MORE.
DON'T SECOND-GUESS
YOURSELF.
LITERATURE, $1,600.
ALISTAIR.
WHO IS SHERMAN?
GOOD.
JOURNALISM FOR $400,
PLEASE.
[ BEEP ]
AND THE COMMENTATOR MOST
ASSOCIATED WITH THE FACTOR --
BILL O'REILLY.
$800, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M CNN CORRESPONDENT
LIZZIE O'LEARY.
U.
ALL RIGHT.
CARLY.
WHAT IS BP?
THAT'S IT.
CIVIL WAR LITERATURE
FOR $2,000.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS SHILOH?
SHILOH. RIGHT.
AND YOU'RE $200
OFF THE LEAD NOW.
JOURNALISM FOR $1,200,
PLEASE.
[ BEEP ]
HIS NAME IS TOM WOLFE.
ALISTAIR.
$1,600, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT.
I'M CHRIS MATTHEWS.
ALISTAIR?
WHAT IS GEORGIA?
GEORGIA IS CORRECT.
AND THE LAST CLUE IS YOURS.
AND IT IS
THE DAILY DOUBLE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
AND AT THE MOMENT,
YOU HAVE $1,400 MORE THAN MATT.
I SHALL WAGER $1,200.
[ Chuckling ] OKAY.
HERE'S THE CLUE.
WHAT IS "FEAR AND LOATHING
IN LAS VEGAS"?
YOU ARE RIGHT,
AND THAT TAKES YOU TO $16,400,
AND IT TAKES US
TO FINAL JEOPARDY!
CATEGORY --
STATES' HIGHEST POINTS.
CLUE IN A MOMENT.
CATEGORY --
STATES' HIGHEST POINTS.
I'VE BEEN A SUPERINTENDEFOR 30Y
DIFFERENT PARK SERVICE UNITS
ACROSS THE UNITED STATES.
THE ONLY TIME I'VE EVER
HAD A BREAK IS WHEN
I WAS ON MATERNITY LEAVE.
I HAVE RETIRED FROM DOING
HING THAT I LOVED.
NOW, I'M GOING TO BE
ABLE TO HAVE THE TIME
TO EXPLORE SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
IT'S LIK ONE THER CHAPTER.
E ANOT
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the political spin.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
membLet's keep Medicare...nts.
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
THIS SOUNDS RATHER EASY,
DOESN'T IT --
STATES' HIGHEST POINTS?
LET'S FIND OUT,
AS WE LOOK AT THE CLUE.
30 SECONDS. GOOD LUCK.
Alex: LET'S SEE --
UTAH, COLORADO, KANSAS -- NO.
THOSE ARE ALL OUT.
LET'S GO TO CARLY.
SHE HAD $6,800.
WHICH STATE
DID SHE SELECT?
"WHAT IS HAWAII?"
MAUNA KEA.
YOU ARE RIGHT.
AND YOU WILL DO WHAT
TO YOUR SCORE?
YOU'LL ADD $1,000.
AND WE'LL MOVE TO YOUR LEFT
TO MATT STEI.
DID HE COME UP
WITH HAWAII?
HE DID, INDEED.
AND HIS WAGER?
[ GASPS ] NOTHING.
SO HE REMAINS
AT $13,800.
HE'S HOPING ALISTAIR
WILL MISS THIS ONE.
WILL ALISTAIR MISS
THIS ONE?
NOPE.
HE'S REMAIN CHAMPION.
HOW MUCH MONEY ADDED TODAY?
WOW! $11,201.
A BIG DAY -- $27,601,
ENJOY THE WEEKEND,
ALISTAIR.
COME BACK AND PLAY AGAIN
ON MONDAY.
AND YOU, TOO,
PLEASE JOIN US THEN.
SO LONG, EVERYONE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
-- Captions by VITAC --
www.vitac.com
HIGH-BURNING STOVE?
Pat: NOPE. STILL TIME.
[ BUZZER ]
FAST-BURNING STOVE?
Pat: NO.
[ BUZZER ]
COAL-BURNING STOVE?
NO.
[ BUZZER ]
V.
CHUCKLES ] YEAH. GEE, I WONDER
WHAT WE'LL BE BURNING NOW.
FOOD-BURNING STOVE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ BUZZER ]
HOOD-BURNING STOVE?
WHAT'S THAT?
HOOD-BURNING STOVE.
NO.
[ BUZZER ]
WOOD-BURNING STOVE.
Pat: YEAH.
YOU GOT IT, BUT TOO LATE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
YEAH, WE PRETTY MUCH
BURNED EVERYTHING IN SIGHT.
WHEEL...
OF...
FORTUNE!
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
PAT SAJAK AND VANNA WHITE.
OUT OF HERE.
THANK YOU, JIM.
IT'S BEEN A FUN WEEK.
IT HAS.
WE'LL TRY TO MAKE IT FUN
TONIGHT, TOO.
OK
HI.
GOOD TO SEE YOU ALL.