THINK I MOVE NEARLY AS MUCH AS
I USED TO, SO I DON'T
HAVE THE NEED
FOR OTHER PILLOWS ANYMORE.
IT'S THE PERFECT PILLOW.
>> BEING MADE IN AMERICA IS
WONDERFUL BUT IT'S MADE RIGHT.
AND TO THE AVERAGE CONSUMER,
YOU'RE LOOKING AT
HELPING YOURSELF TO HELP
THE BODY HELP ITSELF MORE.
THE PILLOW'S A GREAT
PLACE TO START.
>> I'M TONJA WARING AND I AM
SO EXCITED TO INTRODUCE YOU TO
OUR REVOLUTIONARY NEW SLEEP AID
THAT HAS LITERALLY
CHANGED PEOPLE'S LIVES,
INCLUDING MINE.
IT'S MADE RIGHT HERE IN AMERICA,
AND YOU WON'T FIND IT
IN ANY STORE.
BUT FIRST, LET ME ASK YOU
A FEW QUESTIONS.
DO YOU OR SOMEONE YOU CARE
ABOUT WAKE UP MORE TIRED
THAN WHEN YOU WENT TO BED?
DO YOU WAKE UP WITH A HEADACHE,
A STIFF NECK OR THAT TINGLING
FEELING IN YOUR FINGERS?
HOW 'BOUT THIS: DO YOU FIND
YOURSELF TOSSING AND TURNING
ALL NIGHT, STACKING, FOLDING,
RE-SMOOSHING YOUR PILLOWS
OR EVEN FLIPPING IT TO THE COOL
SIDE JUST TO GET COMFORTABLE?
IF YOU'VE ANSWERED YES
TO ANY OF THESE QUESTIONS,
THEN YOU, LIKE MILLIONS OF OTHER
AMERICANS, SIMPLY AREN'T GETTING
A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP.
MY FRIEND AND SLEEP EXPERT,
MICHAEL J. LINDELL,
IS THE FOUNDER AND INVENTOR OF
A REVOLUTIONARY NEW SLEEP AID.
MIKE'S HERE TO SHARE WITH US
WHY GETTING A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP
IS THE SECRET TO
A HAPPY, HEALTHY LIFE.
>> HI, TONJA. >> HI. MIKE.
>> WELL, IT'S NOT ONLY THE
SECRET TO A HAPPY LIFE, IT'S
CRITICAL TO YOUR HEALTH, AND
LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE OUT THERE,
I HAVE USED MY ARMS, FOLDED MY
PILLOWS, GOT MIGRAINES IN THE
MORNING FROM SLEEPING ON POOR
PILLOWS AND WHAT IT IS, WHAT I
FOUND IN MY STUDIES OVER THE
LAST SEVEN YEARS IS THE CERVICAL
NERVES ON EACH SIDE OF YOUR NECK
NEED TO BE HELD STRAIGHT IN
ORDER TO GET THAT DEEP REM SLEEP
THAT WE ALL NEED.
THAT'S OUR HEALING SLEEP.
HEALING IS CRITICAL TO ONE'S
HEALTH AND PILLOWS ARE THE
PROBLEM.
THERE IS NO BIGGER PROBLEM THAN
PILLOWS. >> MIKE, I HEAR WHAT
YOU'RE SAYING.
ACCORDING TO THE NATIONAL SLEEP
FOUNDATION, THE AVERAGE ADULT
PURCHASES 58 PILLOWS OVER THEIR
LIFETIME, THEY OWN SIX DIFFERENT
PILLOWS AT ANY GIVEN TIME-- AND
THIS IS WHAT BLEW ME AWAY--
70% OF US DO NOT LIKE OUR
CURRENT PILLOW WE SLEEP
WITH EVERY NIGHT.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
>> WELL, I JUST HAPPEN TO HAVE
SOME HERE. [LAUGHS]
THESE, THESE PILLOWS, UH, IN
THE LAST 30 YEARS, IN THE 1970s,
PILLOWS KIND OF CHANGED FOREVER
AND WE'VE ALL SLEPT WITH THIS
PILLOW HERE.
THIS PILLOW HERE IS, UH, IT
PUSHES BACK.
YOU KNOW WHEN YOU SLEEP ON YOUR
BACK, YOU FEEL THAT PILLOW.
>> YEAH, YEAH.
>> IT'S LIKE SPRING, IT'S LIKE
PUSHING BACK AT YOU.
>> OH, RIGHT.
>> YOU'RE ON YOUR BACK AND
YOU'RE LIKE THIS WITH A TILTED
NECK, YOU WAKE UP IN THE
MORNING, YOU'VE BENT YOUR
PRECEREBRAL ARTERIES AND
YOU'RE GONNA GET HEADACHES.
THIS IS NO GOOD.
[AUDIENCE LAUGHS]
OKAY, THIS PILLOW HERE, IT
BECOMES A HARD SURFACE.
WE'VE ALL SLEPT IN THAT, WITH
THE CURVE.
THE PROBLEM IS PILLOWS GIVE YOU
SUPPORT HERE AND HERE, NOTHING
WHERE YOUR C1 AND C2 IS--
YOUR AXIS AND YOUR ULNA.
THOSE ARE CRITICAL TO SNORING,
CENTRAL SLEEP APNEA, ALL THESE
DIFFERENT THINGS THAT YOU NEED
SUPPORT IN YOUR NECK.
THIS ONE HERE-- AND YOU ALSO
NEED TO BE KEPT COOL.
THIS PILLOW HERE WILL HEAT UP,
WILL ALSO BECOME A HARD SURFACE
AND IT'S NO GOOD.
[LAUGHTER]
>> WHAT ABOUT THIS ONE?
>> THIS ONE HERE HAS RUINED
AMERICA.
WE'VE ALL SLEPT ON THIS.
THERE'S NO SUPPORT.
THIS HAS DONE MORE FOR BAD
SLEEP DEPRIVATION THAN
ANYTHING ANYWHERE.
AND ANOTHER THING TOO, WHEN YOU
WASH THESE PILLOWS, YOU KNOW
THEY BALL UP IN A WASHER AND
DRYER... THE BIG PILLOW COMPANY
WANTS YOU BUYING MORE AND MORE
PILLOWS AND THEY DON'T CARE
ABOUT YOUR HEALTH.
THEY DON'T CARE ABOUT
OUR SLEEP.
THEY DON'T CARE THAT WE KEEP
BUYING PILLOWS OVER
AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
I JUST WANTED SOME SLEEP AND I
DID SOMETHING ABOUT IT, AND THIS
PILLOW HERE, I CAN'T SAY ENOUGH
BAD THINGS ABOUT, BUT
IT'S TERRIBLE.
>> MIKE, I LOVE YOUR PILLOW.
IT HAS A GREAT WARRANTY.
I LOVE THAT IT'S MADE
IN AMERICA.
>> THE BEST THING YOU'RE GONNA
LIKE ABOUT THIS PILLOW IS I GET
REM SLEEP, THE DEEP-HEALING
SLEEP, THE SLEEP THAT HELPS
ALL YOUR, YOUR HEALTH,
HOW YOU FEEL THE NEXT DAY.
I HAVE A PATENT ON THIS PILLOW,
AND WHAT IT IS, IS ALL THREE
SIZES OF MY FILL ARE IN EVERY
PILLOW.
THIS STUFF WAS WARRANTIED 10
YEARS, IT WON'T GO FLAT.
IT'S THE HEALTHIEST
THING EVER INVENTED.
IT'S GOT... IT'S NON-ALLERGENIC,
IT'S ANTI-MICROBIAL, BUT THE
BEST THING IT DOES... WHEREVER
YOU SET THIS, OKAY, UNTIL YOU
FIRST GET COMFORTABLE ON YOUR
PILLOW AND YOU'RE LIKE THIS AND
YOU GO LIKE THIS AND...
NOW, TONJA, I WANT YOU
TO FEEL THAT.
YOU SEE HOW THAT HOLDS?
>> OH, MY GOSH.
>> THAT WILL NOT MIGRATE.
WHEREVER YOU SET IT, YOU GET
EXACTLY WHAT YOU NEED FOR YOUR
INDIVIDUAL NECK SUPPORT, OKAY?
YOU CAN TRIM THIS ANY WAY
YOU WANT.
YOU CAN MAKE LITTLE BALLOON
ANIMALS OUT OF IT. [LAUGHTER]
IT'S GONNA HOLD. OKAY,
IT TAKES SIX POUNDS OF
PRESSURE TO HOLD THAT
IN POSITION.
YOUR AVERAGE HEAD WEIGHS
12 POUNDS, SO WHEREVER YOU SET
THAT, YOU GET EXACTLY WHAT YOU
NEED FOR YOU AS AN INDIVIDUAL.
IT'S AMAZING, IT WILL
CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
THERE'S NOTHING LIKE IT
ON THE PLANET.
IT'S JUST AMAZING.
NOW, IF YOU'RE ON YOUR BACK...
WE'VE ALL SEEN THAT
CURVE PILLOW.
I THINK WE JUST THREW ONE
AWAY A MINUTE AGO.
OKAY, THAT CURVED PILLOW LIKE
THAT ONLY FITS ONE IN 30 PEOPLE.
REMEMBER, WE TOLD YOU THAT.
IT GIVES YOU SUPPORT HERE AND
HERE, NOTHING HERE.
WELL, YOU COULD BE THAT ONE IN
30, TONJA.
YOU TAKE THE PILLOW, YOU DO
LIKE THIS, YOU TUCK IT,
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
NO MORE SNORING, OKAY?
THE REASON IS YOU'RE
SUPPORTING YOUR C1 AND C2,
YOUR BREATHING IS BETTER.
OTHER COMPANIES HAVE SAID, "OH,
YEAH, WE HAVE THIS AMAZING
CURE FOR SNORING."
THIS WILL REALLY WORK.
FROM THE TESTIMONIALS I HAVE
FROM ALL THE PILLOWS I'VE SOLD,
ABOUT 70% OF THE PEOPLE DON'T
SNORE ANYMORE AT ALL.
[APPLAUSE]
>> WHAT MIKE HASN'T TOLD YOU IS
THAT, ALREADY, HUNDREDS OF
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE HAVE
BENEFITTED FROM SLEEPING
ON MY PILLOW.
>> I GIVE 'EM A 60-DAY
MONEY-BACK GUARANTEE 'CAUSE
PEOPLE, QUITE FRANKLY, ARE TIRED
OF BUYING PILLOWS THAT THEY
CAN'T RETURN AND GET THEIR MONEY
BACK. >> YEAH.
>> AND WE HAVE... OUR CUSTOMER
SERVICE IS THE BEST IN
THE COUNTRY.
WE HAVE AN A+ RATING WITH THE
BETTER BUSINESS BUREAU AND WE
HAVE ZERO COMPLAINTS OUT OF ALL
THE SEVEN YEARS I'VE BEEN IN
BUSINESS WITH THE BETTER
BUSINESS BUREAU.
IT'S THE MOST AMAZING PRODUCT
AND I 100% GUARANTEE IT'LL BE
THE MOST COMFORTABLE PILLOW
YOU'LL EVER OWN.
>> WELL, I CAN HONESTLY SAY THAT
SINCE I'VE BEEN USING MY PILLOW,
IT'S MADE AN AMAZING DIFFERENCE
IN MY LIFE, AND HERE'S YOUR
OPPORTUNITY TO GET YOUR VERY
OWN MY PILLOW AND MAKE THE REST
OF YOUR LIFE THE BEST OF
YOUR LIFE.
>> Announcer: PEOPLE ALL ACROSS
AMERICA ARE TIRED OF TOSSING AND
TURNING ALL NIGHT, SNORING LIKE
A FREIGHT TRAIN AND WAKING UP
WITH ACHES AND PAINS FROM
PILLOWS THAT SIMPLY DON'T WORK.
>> Announcer: INTRODUCING MY
PILLOW, GUARANTEED THE MOST
COMFORTABLE PILLOW YOU'LL EVER
OWN OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
UNLIKE OTHER PILLOWS THAT LACK
SUPPORT, LOSE THEIR SHAPE OR
HEAT UP, MY PILLOW'S PATENTED
THREE-PIECE INTERLOCKING SYSTEM
CREATES A COOLING EFFECT AND
ALLOWS YOU TO EASILY FORM MY
PILLOW TO YOUR UNIQUE SHAPE,
PROVIDING MAXIMUM COMFORT AND
SUPPORT OF THE CERVICAL NERVES
IN YOUR NECK AND SPINE,
RESULTING IN THE MOST RESTFUL,
COMFORTABLE, DEEP-HEALING SLEEP
YOU'VE EVER EXPERIENCED.
MY PILLOW IS MADE RIGHT HERE IN
AMERICA FROM A PATENTED
COMFORT-FIT FILL THAT'S
ANTIMICROBIAL, NON-ALLERGENIC,
MACHINE WASHABLE AND
GUARANTEED FOR 10 YEARS.
THAT'S RIGHT, 10 YEARS!
WE'LL EVEN GIVE YOU 60 RISK-FREE
NIGHTS TO SLEEP ON IT TO ENSURE
YOUR COMPLETE SATISFACTION.
>> TRY THE PILLOW,
YOU'LL LIKE IT.
>> I LOVE SNUGGLING UP TO
BED WITH MY PILLOW.
>> MY PILLOW HAS BEEN A GODSEND
FOR ME AND I LOVE IT. >>
IT'S JUST GREAT FOR ME
AND I LOVE IT.
>> Announcer: OUR TRAINED STAFF
PROFESSIONALS ARE HERE TO SERVE
YOU 24 HOURS A DAY, SO CALL THE
800 NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN NOW OR
VISIT US ONLINE AT MYPILLOW.COM
AND ENTER PROMO CODE "MYPILLOW"
TO SAVE 25% OFF YOUR ENTIRE
PURCHASE WHEN YOU ORDER NOW.
DON'T SPEND ONE MORE SLEEPLESS
NIGHT WITH A PILLOW THAT
SIMPLY DOESN'T WORK.
CALL THE 800 NUMBER ON YOUR
SCREEN NOW OR VISIT OUR WEBSITE
AND GET CUSTOM FIT FOR YOUR
VERY OWN MY PILLOW AND START
EXPERIENCING THE AMAZING
BENEFITS YOU CAN ONLY GET FROM
THE WORLD'S MOST COMFORTABLE
PILLOW, MY PILLOW.
>> WE STARTED WITH ONE OR TWO
AND THEN, ALL OF A SUDDEN, KIDS
REALIZED THAT, THE KIDS... I
THINK KALLI BORROWED MINE FOR
THE FIRST TIME, AND SHE SAID,
"I WANT ONE OF THOSE DAD."
SO I GOT HER ONE OF THE PILLOWS,
AND EVER SINCE THEN,
OUR WHOLE FAMILY HAS 'EM.
>> HEALTHY, NORMAL PEOPLE NEED
TO GO TO BED, STAY ASLEEP AND
WAKE UP FEELING GOOD.
WHEN SOMEBODY'S CHANGING, UM,
ANYTHING IN THEIR LIFESTYLE, UM,
YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
YOU'RE PREPARED TO ADAPT TO
STRESS, AND THAT'S WHAT
SLEEP DOES.
IT PREPARES YOU AND IMPROVES
YOUR ABILITY TO RESPOND TO
STRESS, AND SO, RIGHT OUT OF THE
CHUTE, EASIEST THING I CAN
RECOMMEND IS MY PILLOW.
>> IN ORDER TO GET A GOOD
NIGHT'S SLEEP WE NEED TO BE IN A
POSITION THAT IS COMFORTABLE.
IF OUR BODY IS CONTORTED IN ANY
WAY, WE CAN IMPINGE ON NERVES
THAT WOULD LEAD TO TINGLING,
NUMBNESS, DISCOMFORTS OF
VARIOUS SORT.
IF YOU COULD POSITION YOURSELF
WITH A PILLOW THAT IS
COMFORTABLE, THEN THESE MOTOR
AND SENSORY SIGNALS THAT YOU GET
IN A RESTLESS STATE DON'T OCCUR
AND YOU HAVE A LOT MORE
REM SLEEP.
>> WE'RE HERE WITH SLEEP EXPERT
MICHAEL J. LINDELL, FOUNDER AND
INVENTOR OF A REVOLUTIONARY NEW
SLEEP AID CALLED MY PILLOW.
>> OVER THE LAST SEVEN YEARS,
WHAT I CAME UP WITH IS A THEORY,
AFTER TALKING TO HUNDREDS OF
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE THAT HAVE
THE PILLOW... THERE'S EIGHT
CERVICAL NERVES ON EACH SIDE OF
YOUR NECK, AND WHAT THEY DO...
THEY NEED TO BE IN ALIGNMENT,
OKAY, TO GET-- FOR THE SIGNALS
TO GO TO YOUR BRAIN.
REMEMBER THE OLD-FASHIONED TVs
THAT HAD THE HORIZONTAL HOLE,
YOU KNOW, THE WAVY LINE
WHEN IT WASN'T CLEAR?
WHEN YOU FIRST GET SET AT NIGHT,
YOU FIRST GET COMFORTABLE ON
YOUR PILLOW, YOUR BRAIN SAYS,
"OKAY, I'M COMFORTABLE," 'CAUSE
YOUR CERVICAL NERVES ARE
LINED UP. >> YEAH.
>> WELL, WHAT HAPPENS IS THE AIR
STARTS GOING OUT OF THAT PILLOW
AND THEY'RE BENT, LIKE BENDING A
WATER HOSE, OKAY?
WHEN YOU DO THAT, YOU GO...
[MIMICS GUSHING SOUND]
YOUR SIGNAL'S NOT GOING THROUGH.
SAME WAY WITH YOUR ARTERIES,
YOUR PRECEREBRAL ARTERY AND
YOUR CAROTID ARTERY... THE BLOOD
FLOW TO THE BRAIN NEEDS TO BE,
UM, YOU KNOW, OPEN LIKE A HOSE.
>> IS THAT WHY MY CONCENTRATION
IS SO MUCH BETTER AFTER I
SLEEP ON MY PILLOW?
>> THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT.
>> GOOD SUPPORT, WHICH IS
SOMEHOW THE MIRACLE OF MY
PILLOW, UH, THROUGHOUT THE
NIGHT IS WHAT WE WANT.
IT'S NICE TO FALL ASLEEP, BUT
THEN, AS YOUR PILLOW COLLAPSES,
YOU'RE GONNA WAKE UP AGAIN
'CAUSE YOUR POSITION'S CHANGED.
THE MY PILLOW, IT SEEMS THAT
WE'RE AT A STATE THAT IS
COMFORTABLE AND IT STAYS THE
SAME THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT.
>> WHAT DR. KOLODNY HAS TO SAY
REALLY REINFORCES WHAT YOU'VE
BEEN TELLING US ABOUT MY PILLOW.
>> WHAT IT DOES.... THAT IT CAN
PUT YOU IN A DEEP REM SLEEP,
WHICH IS THE HEALING SLEEP.
IT'S ALSO THE MOST COMFORTABLE
SLEEP.
WHEN YOU GET COMFORTABLE AT
NIGHT, THAT'S WHAT SENDS
YOU INTO THE REM.
THAT'S WHEN YOUR CERVICAL
NERVES, YOUR NECK IS LINED UP.
AND, INTERESTING ENOUGH, WHAT'S
MY THEORY ON THIS-- THIS THEORY
WAS BRAND NEW-- AND IT'S
TRUE, AND IT'S REAL AND
EVERYBODY KNOWS THAT.
NOW, IT'S OUT THERE BECAUSE
YOU'VE ALL DONE THAT WITH YOUR
ARMS, FOLDED YOUR PILLOWS AND
DONE ALL THIS STUFF AND
FLIP-FLOPPED ALL NIGHT
LIKE A GUPPY.
HERE, YOU STAY WITH MY PILLOW.
WHEREVER YOU SET THIS PILLOW,
IT'S GONNA HOLD, EXACTLY FOR
YOU AS AN INDIVIDUAL.
WITH MY PILLOW, BY KEEPING ALL
THOSE THINGS IN YOUR NECK
STRAIGHT, YOU GET THE BEST SLEEP
OF YOUR LIFE EVERY SINGLE
NIGHT AND I GUARANTEE IT.
WE MAKE 'EM RIGHT HERE IN THE
UNITED STATES.
THE REASON WHY I'M STILL IN
BUSINESS IS TO HELP PEOPLE.
THAT'S MY CALLING, THAT'S WHY
I'M HERE AND I WANT EVERYBODY TO
HAVE THE BEST NIGHT'S SLEEP
THEY'VE EVER GOT IN THEIR LIFE.
>> ABSOLUTELY,
ABSOLUTELY! [APPLAUSE]
>> I DISCOVERED THAT HAVING MY
HEAD, NECK AND SPINE PERFECTLY
ALIGNED ALL NIGHT, WHETHER IT'S
ON MY SIDE OR WHETHER,
OCCASIONALLY, I'M ON MY BACK, I
CAN GET A PERFECT CERVICAL
CURVATURE, AND MY ALIGNING THAT
SPINE, THE FOUR CERVICAL NERVES
RUNNING RIGHT THROUGH THE MIDDLE
OF MY NECK GOING EVERYWHERE IN
MY BODY AND REPORTING BACK UP,
EVERYTHING IS IN ALIGNMENT.
IT'S A PHENOMENAL DIFFERENCE IN
THE WAY THAT YOU'RE ABLE
TO SLEEP.
>> I FELL ASLEEP
INSTANTLY... INSTANTLY.
>> I HAVE FOUND THAT I HAVE
MORE ENERGY DURING THE DAY.
I SLEEP BETTER, I'M NOT
RUSTLING AROUND.
MY WIFE USED TO TELL ME THAT I
USED TO FLIP AROUND AND
MOVE ALL OVER THE BED.
SHE HAS NOT SAID THAT SINCE
I'VE HAD THE MY PILLOW.
SO IT'S JUST BEEN, IT'S OVERALL
HAS GIVEN ME A BETTER NIGHT'S
SLEEP, AND AGAIN, THAT'S WHY
THE REST OF MY FAMILY HAS
THE MY PILLOW AS WELL.
>> WITH THOSE OTHER PILLOWS THAT
YOU'RE GETTING AT THE MARKETS,
THEY'RE JUST TRASH, REALLY.
THEY'RE JUST... THEY'RE CHEAP.
AND AFTER YOU WASH THEM, THEY
BUNCH UP, THEY'RE NOT THE
SAME ANYMORE.
WITH MY PILLOW, YOU CAN TOSS IT
INTO THE WASH, YOU CAN AIR DRY
IT, TOSS IT INTO THE DRYER.
IT'S SUCH AN EASY PILLOW TO
TAKE CARE OF AND IT'S GONNA
LAST YOU FOREVER.
>> EARLIER WE TALKED ABOUT THE
IMPORTANCE OF A GOOD NIGHT'S
SLEEP WHICH IS SOMETHING I
CAN REALLY RELATE TO.
I HAVE TO ADMIT, I WAS PRETTY
SKEPTICAL, BUT MICHAEL TOLD ME
IT WOULD REALLY WORK.
AND AFTER ABOUT TWO OR THREE
WEEKS, I NOTICED THAT ALL OF MY
MIGRAINES HAD DISAPPEARED.
AND WHAT I REALLY NOTICED IS
THAT I COULD START GOING OUT
TO THE GYM, I COULD START
EXERCISING MORE, BECAUSE ANY
TIME I TRIED TO DO THAT
BEFORE, I JUST WOULD GET
EXCRUCIATING HEADACHES.
AND SO, UH, ONE OF THE THINGS...
WE TALK ABOUT WASHING AND DRYING
A PILLOW... I'VE WASHED HUNDREDS
OF PILLOWS WHERE THEY END UP IN
THAT CLUMP.
WELL, I PUT IT IN THE WASHER
MACHINE AND WHEN I TOOK IT OUT
OF THE DRYER AND WHEN IT LOOKED
JUST LIKE IT DID THE DAY I
BOUGHT IT, I WAS SOLD.
AND THAT'S WHEN I WANTED TO BUY
'EM FOR MY KIDS BECAUSE MY KIDS
ARE ALWAYS TAKING THEIR PILLOW
IN THE CAR.
THEY'RE TAKING IT TO GRANDPA AND
GRANDMA'S HOUSE, THEY'RE
THROWING IT IN FRONT OF THE TV
AND SO I'D ALWAYS END UP WASHING
THEIR PILLOWS AND I KNEW THAT I
WAS SPENDING MORE MONEY ON GAS
DRIVING BACK AND FORTH TO THE
DEPARTMENT STORE TO BUY
THEM A NEW ONE.
AND THE OTHER THING THAT I
REALLY WANTED AND I KNEW IS
THAT IF THEY REALLY STARTED
GETTING A GOOD NIGHT SLEEP NOW,
KEEPING THEIR CERVICAL NERVES IN
ALIGNMENT AND DOING ALL THAT
STUFF FOR THEIR HEALTH THAT
HOPEFULLY, WHEN THEY GOT TO BE
MY AGE, THEY WOULDN'T HAVE THE
KIND OF PROBLEMS THAT I'VE HAD.
SO IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT FOR ME
THAT MY KIDS SLEEP ON
A GREAT PILLOW.
AND THEY'VE EVEN COMMENTED.
MY DAUGHTER-- I WAS OUT WORKING
ONE DAY-- AND SHE SAID... I WAS
KIND OF TELLING MY PILLOW STORY,
AND SHE SAID, "MOM, I HAD NO
IDEA YOU WERE IN THAT
MUCH PAIN."
AND SHE SAID, YOU KNOW, AND
I JUST KNOW THAT IT'S MADE ME
A MUCH BETTER MOM.
[APPLAUSE]
>> Announcer: PEOPLE ALL ACROSS
AMERICA ARE TIRED OF TOSSING AND
TURNING ALL NIGHT, SNORING LIKE
A FREIGHT TRAIN AND WAKING UP
WITH ACHES AND PAINS FROM
PILLOWS THAT SIMPLY DON'T WORK.
>> Announcer: INTRODUCING MY
PILLOW, GUARANTEED THE MOST
COMFORTABLE PILLOW YOU'LL EVER
OWN OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
UNLIKE OTHER PILLOWS THAT LACK
SUPPORT, LOSE THEIR SHAPE OR
HEAT UP, MY PILLOW'S PATENTED
THREE-PIECE INTERLOCKING SYSTEM
CREATES A COOLING EFFECT AND
ALLOWS YOU TO EASILY FORM MY
PILLOW TO YOUR UNIQUE SHAPE,
PROVIDING MAXIMUM COMFORT AND
SUPPORT OF THE CERVICAL NERVES
IN YOUR NECK AND SPINE,
RESULTING IN THE MOST RESTFUL,
COMFORTABLE, DEEP-HEALING SLEEP
YOU'VE EVER EXPERIENCED.
MY PILLOW IS MADE RIGHT HERE IN
AMERICA FROM A PATENTED
COMFORT-FIT FILL THAT'S
ANTIMICROBIAL, NON-ALLERGENIC,
MACHINE WASHABLE AND
GUARANTEED FOR 10 YEARS.
THAT'S RIGHT, 10 YEARS!
WE'LL EVEN GIVE YOU 60 RISK-FREE
NIGHTS TO SLEEP ON IT TO ENSURE
YOUR COMPLETE SATISFACTION.
>> TRY THE PILLOW,
YOU'LL LIKE IT.
>> I LOVE SNUGGLING UP TO
BED WITH MY PILLOW.
>> MY PILLOW HAS BEEN A GODSEND
FOR ME AND I LOVE IT.
>> IT'S JUST GREAT FOR ME
AND I LOVE IT.
>> Announcer: OUR TRAINED STAFF
PROFESSIONALS ARE HERE TO SERVE
YOU 24 HOURS A DAY, SO CALL THE
800 NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN NOW OR
VISIT US ONLINE AT MYPILLOW.COM
AND ENTER PROMO CODE "MYPILLOW"
TO SAVE 25% OFF YOUR ENTIRE
PURCHASE WHEN YOU ORDER NOW.
DON'T SPEND ONE MORE SLEEPLESS
NIGHT WITH A PILLOW THAT
SIMPLY DOESN'T WORK.
CALL THE 800 NUMBER ON YOUR
SCREEN NOW OR VISIT OUR WEBSITE
AND GET CUSTOM FIT FOR YOUR
VERY OWN MY PILLOW AND START
EXPERIENCING THE AMAZING
BENEFITS YOU CAN ONLY GET FROM
THE WORLD'S MOST COMFORTABLE
PILLOW, MY PILLOW.
>> WE'VE HAD SEVERAL PEOPLE
DRIVE ACROSS THE COUNTRY TODAY
SO THAT THEY COULD BE HERE IN
OUR AUDIENCE SO THAT THEY COULD
SHARE THE IMPACT THAT MY PILLOW
HAS HAD MADE ON THEIR LIVES.
AND ONE OF THE FIRST PEOPLE
THAT I WANT TO INTRODUCE
TO YOU IS ANDY.
ANDY, IF YOU'D BE SO KIND, WE'D
LOVE TO HEAR HOW MY PILLOW HAS
MADE A DIFFERENCE FOR YOU.
>> HI, MIKE. >> HOW YOU DOING,
ANDY? >> GOOD, I MET YOU AT
THE STATE FAIR LAST YEAR.
>> YES, I REMEMBER.
>> AND I DIDN'T EVEN KNOW I WAS
LOOKING FOR A PILLOW AND YOU SAW
ME AND SAID, "I NEED TO TALK
TO YOU."
AND I GOTTA TELL YOU,
THANKS, YOU KNOW?
ITS CHANGED MY LIFE.
IT'S CHANGED THE WAY I SLEEP.
[LAUGHS] I SLEEP, I THINK,
IS THE BIG THING.
>> IT'S A MIRACLE.
WITH YOUR BIG SHOULDERS--
THERE'S A LOT OF PEOPLE ALREADY
LIKE YOU.
YOU HAVE ALL KINDS OF PROBLEMS
BECAUSE OF, YOU KNOW...
>> AND I'M A SIDE SLEEPER, I'VE
ALWAYS BEEN A SIDE SLEEPER.
MY ARM FALLS ALSEEP...
NOT ANYMORE.
>> NOT ANYMORE.
THAT'S AMAZING, YEAH.
THAT'S WHY I LOVE SOME OF
THESE PILLOWS, BECAUSE OF
STORIES LIKE YOURS.
>> I TAKE IT WITH ME
EVERYWHERE. >> RIGHT, RIGHT.
>> IT'S BEEN TO TEXAS
TWICE, ARIZONA...
>> RIGHT.
>> IT DIDN'T GO ON ONE TRIP.
>> ...THAT WENT WELL FOR YOU.
>> AND, WELL, IT DIDN'T
WORK TOO WELL.
THE FIRST NIGHT I WAS DOWN
THERE-- IT'S TWO HOURS AWAY
TO MY WIFE'S FOLKS AND, UH,
IT DIDN'T MAKE IT.
I WOKE UP, YOU KNOW, AFTER AN
HOUR, TWO HOURS, THREE HOURS.
FINALLY, FIVE O'CLOCK IN THE
MORNING, I GOT UP, DROVE BACK UP
TO WHERE WE LIVE, GRABBED THE
PILLOW... >> Tonja: WOW!
>> THERE YOU GO!
>> SO, ON THE SECOND
NIGHT... [APPLAUSE]
THE SECOND NIGHT, I HAD A
GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP.
>> Mike: RIGHT, THAT'S AWESOME.
>> AND THEN, MY WIFE, SHE'D
LIKE TO THANK YOU BECAUSE
I DON'T SNORE.
>> WOW, THAT'S A... [LAUGHS]
YOU'RE BACK IN THE SAME
BEDROOM! >> IT'S GREAT.
>> YOU KNOW, IT JUST GOES TO
SHOW EVEN SOMEONE YOUR SIZE...
WE HELP EVERYBODY, FROM THE
SMALLEST PERSON UP TO THE
BIGGEST, YOU KNOW?
>> IT'S GREAT.
>> THAT'S AN AWESOME STORY.
>> AND WE'RE GONNA SEE YOU
AGAIN AT THE STATE FAIR THIS
YEAR? >> YES, YOU ARE.
I'LL BE THERE MYSELF.
>> THANKS.
>> THANK YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
>> ANDY WAS SO ENTHUSIASTIC
ABOUT SHARING HIS STORY AND
BEING HERE TODAY SO I
CAN SEE WHY.
THANK YOU, ANDY.
AND NEXT WE HAVE JENNIFER.
I'M VERY HAPPY TO HAVE JENNIFER
UP TO SHARE WITH US HOW MY
PILLOW'S MADE A
DIFFERENCE IN HER LIFE.
>> HI! >> Mike: HELLO.
>> Tonja: HELLO, JENNIFER.
>> HOW ARE YOU GUYS?
>> Mike and Tonja: GOOD.
>> GOOD. UM... I JUST AM A
BUSY PERSON ON THE GO.
I HAVE TWO LITTLE GIRLS THAT I
CHASE AFTER AND I HAVE MY OWN
COMPANY, A FLORAL DESIGN
COMPANY, AND I VOLUNTEER
EVERY DAY.
SO WHEN I GO TO BED, I REALLY,
REALLY NEED SLEEP AND I'VE TRIED
PRETTY MUCH EVERY PILLOW OUT
THERE: THE FLAT PILLOWS, THE
FIRM, I TRIED A WATER PILLOW AND
THOSE MEMORY FOAM PILLOWS AND I
ALWAYS WOKE UP WITH A DULL
HEADACHE, JUST...
IT WAS NOT, YOU DON'T HAVE THE
ENERGY AND YOU CAN'T DEAL
WITH CHILDREN WHEN
YOU'RE DEALING WITH THAT.
I SAW MY PILLOW AT ONE OF YOUR
SHOWS AND I THOUGHT, YOU KNOW,
I'D INVESTED ENOUGH MONEY ON
PILLOWS THAT DIDN'T WORK, SO I
THOUGHT I'D JUST TRY IT.
AND THAT NIGHT I HAD THE BEST
NIGHT'S SLEEP OF MY LIFE IN
YEARS AND IT'S... IT'S, I'VE
HAD THE BEST NIGHT'S
SLEEP EVERY NIGHT.
I DON'T TOSS AND TURN ANYMORE, I
DON'T WAKE UP WITH A
DULL HEADACHE.
I JUST REALLY FEEL GOOD
WHEN I WAKE UP.
I HAVE ENERGY AND I
LOVE MY PILLOW.
>> DID YOU BELIEVE IT WHEN YOU
SAW THE SIGN THAT SAID
IT DID ALL THAT?
IT'S TOO GOOD TO BE TRUE!
>> I WAS REALLY SKEPTICAL.
MY HUSBAND IS THE BIGGEST
SKEPTIC EVER.
HE'S LIKE, "YOU WANT TO SPEND
MONEY ON A PILLOW?
GO AHEAD, WE'LL SEE WHAT
HAPPENS," ROLLING HIS EYES.
AND, HONEST, IT WORKED SO WELL.
I LOVE MY PILLOW, LOVE IT.
>> Mike: THANK YOU,
THAT'S AWESOME. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR
MAKING IT. [APPLAUSE]
>> I KNOW, MIKE, THAT THE
60-NIGHT MONEY-BACK GUARANTEE
REALLY MAKES A BIG DIFFERENCE
FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE SKEPTICAL,
WHO KNOW THAT THEY WANT TO TRY A
PILLOW BUT MAYBE THEY'RE AFRAID
BECAUSE THEY HAVE HAD SO MANY IN
THE PAST THAT DIDN'T WORK.
>> RIGHT, AND I'VE SAID, YOU
KNOW, BACK WHEN I INVENTED THIS
SEVEN YEARS AGO, OR EIGHT YEARS
AGO, WHATEVER IT'S BEEN NOW,
THAT WAS THE ONE THING I WANTED
PEOPLE TO NOT HAVE, THAT
SKEPTICISM, SO I GAVE THE... I
BELIEVED IN IT SO MUCH, THAT'S
WHY I GAVE THE 60-DAY MONEY-BACK
GUARANTEE SO THEY'D HAVE NOTHING
TO LOSE AND EVERYTHING TO GAIN.
YOU HAVE EVERYTHING TO GAIN.
YOUR HEALTH IS THE MOST
IMPORTANT THING TO
YOUR LIFE. >> ABSOLUTELY.
>> AND MY PILLOWS ARE MORE
SUPPORTIVE OF YOUR HEALTH.
>> ABSOLUTELY, HANDS DOWN.
WELL, WE HAVE ANOTHER GENTLEMAN
IN OUR AUDIENCE
HIS NAME IS MICHAEL, AND
MICHAEL,THANK YOU FOR BEING
HERE TODAY.
>> WELL, MY PILLOW HELPED A LOT.
A FEW YEARS BACK I HAD A MEDICAL
SCARE-- I HAD A JAW JOINT THAT
WAS GETTING EATEN AWAY BY
A TUMOR.
THE GOOD NEWS IS IT WASN'T
MALIGNANT, IT WAS BENIGN.
THE DOWNSIDE OF THAT IS WHEN
THEY ACTUALLY DO THE SURGERY,
THEY ACTUALLY HAVE TO SEVER THE
MUSCLE THAT NORMALLY FITS OVER
YOUR JAW JOINTS, SO NOW, AT
NIGHT, I'VE FOUND THAT MY
MOUTH WOULD COME OPEN AND
I WOULD START SNORING.
MY WIFE DID NOT LIKE
THAT VERY MUCH.
SO I CAME ACROSS MY PILLOW
AT A COUNTY FAIR, AND I THOUGHT,
NO, I'M NOT GONNA BUY A PILLOW.
AND HE TALKED TO ME, HE SAID,
"LISTEN, IT'S A MONEY-BACK
GUARANTEE, TRY IT OUT.
WHAT DO YOU HAVE TO LOSE?"
THOUGHT, OKAY, THAT'S A PRETTY
GOOD PITCH, LET ME TRY IT.
THAT NIGHT I SLEPT THROUGH THE
NIGHT AND IT REALLY WAS ONE OF
THE FIRST NIGHT'S THAT I CAN
REMEMBER WHERE I DIDN'T TOSS.
IT WAS A NICE, COMFORTABLE
FEELING AND I WOKE UP COOL AND I
WASN'T GETTING HEADACHES.
SO THE PRODUCT DOES WORK.
THANK YOU FOR
MAKING WHAT YOU MADE.
>> AND YOU DON'T SNORE
ANYMORE, YOU SAID?
>> I DON'T SNORE ANYMORE.
>> [LAUGHS] THAT'S AMAZING.
THAT'S WHY I LOVE SELLING THIS
PILLOW, THAT'S A WONDERFUL...
IT'S A MIRACLE PRODUCT,
ISN'T IT?
>> YES, IT IS.
>> DEFINITELY
A LIFE-CHANGER.
>> THANK YOU. [APPLAUSE]
>> WELL, I WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
THOSE GREAT MY PILLOW STORIES
AND FOR JOINING US TODAY.
I KNOW SO MANY OF US ARE
GRATEFUL FOR THE PILLOW THAT
YOU'VE MADE, MIKE.
AND YOU GET THOUSANDS AND
THOUSANDS OF TESTIMONIALS...
>> I'VE GOT ONE HERE.
I GET THESE ALL THE TIME,
YOU'RE RIGHT.
THIS IS FROM... I'VE SENT
PILLOWS OVER TO AFGHANISTAN.
THIS GUY, HE WROTE ME.
HE SAID, "I'M WRITING YOU
BECAUSE I HAVEN'T GOTTEN A GOOD
NIGHT'S SLEEP IN OVER A MONTH.
WE WORK 24-HOUR SHIFTS SO
GETTING OUR CREW REST
IS VERY IMPORTANT.
RIGHT NOW, I'M SLEEPING ON A COT
WITH A BAG FULL OF UNUSED
CLOTHES AS A PILLOW--" WHICH CAN
BE BETTER THAN SOME OF THE
PILLOWS YOU'VE SLEPT ON!
>> SOME OF THOSE WE'VE
SEEN TODAY.
>> WHAT WE DID, WE SENT SOME
PILLOWS AND HERE WAS
THEIR RESPONSE.
"YOUR PILLOWS CAME IN THE MAIL
TWO DAYS AGO, SO I WAS ABLE TO
TEST IT OUT FOR TWO NIGHTS NOW,
AND I CAN'T BEGIN TO TELL YOU
HOW NICE IT IS TO WAKE UP WITH
NO NECK PAIN AND TO BE ABLE TO
GET A GOOD NIGHT'S SLEEP.
I'VE ALREADY TOLD THE REST OF MY
GUYS HOW MUCH OF A DIFFERENCE
YOUR PILLOW IS ALREADY MAKING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH AND
GOD BLESS, CHIEF WARRANT OFFICER
PATRICK DEVLIN, AFGHANISTAN."
AND WHAT WE'VE GOT...
[APPLAUSE]
AND WHAT I'VE DONE SINCE WE
GOT THAT... WE'VE BEEN SENDING
MORE AND MORE OVER THERE TO OUR
TROOPS AND WE'VE ALSO....
IN THE UNITED STATES, JUST THE
MILITARY BASES, TO BE ABLE TO
SELL IN THERE BECAUSE THEY LIKE
OUR PRODUCT AND WE'VE BEEN
OKAYED FOR... ALL THE
WAY TO ALASKA.
AND WE'RE HELPING, YOU KNOW, NOT
ONLY THE EVERYDAY PEOPLE BUT
WE'RE HELPING OUR TROOPS
THROUGH IT AND IT'S
JUST AMAZING.
THIS IS WHY I SELL THE PILLOW.
>> MIKE, YOU JUST HAVE MY UTMOST
RESPECT FOR YOUR COMMITMENT TO
OUR TROOPS, FOR YOUR
COMMITMENT TO THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE, FOR MANUFACTURING HERE
IN THE UNITED STATES, AND JUST
WHAT YOU PROVIDE FOR PEOPLE'S
OVERALL HEALTH.
[APPLAE]
>> I WOULD RECOMMEND IF YOU'RE
TAKING MEDICATIONS TO FALL
ASLEEP AT NIGHT AND COFFEE TO
KEEP YOU AWAKE IN THE DAY THAT
YOU TRY MY PILLOW AND SEE WHAT A
DIFFERENCE IT CAN MAKE IN
YOUR LIFE.
>> MY PILLOW IS ALL I NEED.
I DON'T NEED TWO PILLOWS, UH,
AND I DON'T NEED TO CONSTANTLY
TUCK IT IN THE BACK OF MY NECK
AND SHOULDERS TO BE COMFORTABLE
AS THE NIGHT WEARS ON.
>> I WORK IN A PHYSICAL THERAPY
CLINIC AND WE SEE A LOT OF
PATIENTS WITH STIFF NECKS AND
SORE SHOULDERS AND JUST HAVING
DIFFICULTY SLEEPING.
AND SINCE MY EXPERIENCE WITH MY
PILLOW I RECOMMEND THAT
THEY GIVE IT A TRY.
>> I KNOW THAT MOST OF US NEVER
STOP TO THINK ABOUT THE
TREMENDOUS DIFFERENCE THAT A
PILLOW CAN MAKE TO OUR OVERALL
HEALTH AND WELL BEING.
BUT MY HOPE FOR TODAY IS THAT
YOU'LL TAKE THIS VALUABLE
INFORMATION AND YOU'LL
EXPERIENCE FOR YOURSELF THE
TREMENDOUS DIFFERENCE THAT A MY
PILLOW CAN MAKE IN YOUR
LIFE. [APPLAUSE]
>> Announcer: PEOPLE ALL ACROSS
AMERICA ARE TIRED OF TOSSING AND
TURNING ALL NIGHT, SNORING LIKE
A FREIGHT TRAIN AND WAKING UP
WITH ACHES AND PAINS FROM
PILLOWS THAT SIMPLY DON'T WORK.
>> Announcer: INTRODUCING MY
PILLOW, GUARANTEED THE MOST
COMFORTABLE PILLOW YOU'LL EVER
OWN OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
UNLIKE OTHER PILLOWS THAT LACK
SUPPORT, LOSE THEIR SHAPE OR
HEAT UP, MY PILLOW'S PATENTED
THREE-PIECE INTERLOCKING SYSTEM
CREATES A COOLING EFFECT AND
ALLOWS YOU TO EASILY FORM MY
PILLOW TO YOUR UNIQUE SHAPE,
PROVIDING MAXIMUM COMFORT AND
SUPPORT OF THE CERVICAL NERVES
IN YOUR NECK AND SPINE,
RESULTING IN THE MOST RESTFUL,
COMFORTABLE, DEEP-HEALING SLEEP
YOU'VE EVER EXPERIENCED.
MY PILLOW IS MADE RIGHT HERE IN
AMERICA FROM A PATENTED
COMFORT-FIT FILL THAT'S
ANTIMICROBIAL, NON-ALLERGENIC,
MACHINE WASHABLE AND
GUARANTEED FOR 10 YEARS.
THAT'S RIGHT, 10 YEARS!
WE'LL EVEN GIVE YOU 60 RISK-FREE
NIGHTS TO SLEEP ON IT TO ENSURE
YOUR COMPLETE SATISFACTION.
>> TRY THE PILLOW,
YOU'LL LIKE IT.
>> I LOVE SNUGGLING UP
TO BED WITH MY PILLOW.
>> MY PILLOW HAS BEEN A GODSEND
FOR ME AND I LOVE IT.
>> IT'S JUST GREAT FOR ME
AND I LOVE IT.
>> Announcer: OUR TRAINED STAFF
PROFESSIONALS ARE HERE TO SERVE
YOU 24 HOURS A DAY, SO CALL THE
800 NUMBER ON YOUR SCREEN NOW OR
VISIT US ONLINE AT MYPILLOW.COM
AND ENTER PROMO CODE "MYPILLOW"
TO SAVE 25% OFF YOUR ENTIRE
PURCHASE WHEN YOU ORDER NOW.
DON'T SPEND ONE MORE
SLEEPLESS NIGHT WITH A PILLOW
THAT SIMPLY DOESN'T WORK.
CALL THE 800 NUMBER ON YOUR
SCREEN NOW OR VISIT OUR WEBSITE
AND GET CUSTOM FIT FOR YOUR
VERY OWN MY PILLOW AND START
EXPERIENCING THE AMAZING
BENEFITS YOU CAN ONLY GET FROM
THE WORLD'S MOST COMFORTABLE
PILLOW, MY PILLOW.
>> HEALTHY, NORMAL PEOPLE NEED
TO GO TO BED, STAY ASLEEP AND
WAKE UP FEELING GOOD.
WHEN SOMEBODY'S CHANGING, UM,
ANYTHING IN THEIR LIFESTYLE, YOU
WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT YOU'RE
PREPARED TO ADAPT TO STRESS
AND THAT'S WHAT SLEEP DOES.
IT PREPARES YOU AND IMPROVES
YOUR ABILITY TO RESPOND TO
STRESS AND SO,
RIGHT OUT OF THE CHUTE,
THE EASIEST THING I CAN
RECOMMEND IS MY PILLOW.
YOU WATCHED THIS WHOLE THING
YOU LEARNED ALL ABOUT PILLOWS
ALL YOU NEED TO KNOW IS NO
ZIP ON COVERS LOW THREAD COUNT
PILLOW CASES, ORDER A PILLOW
GET ON WITH YOUR LIFE
AND AS WE ALWAYS SAY
WHEN WE'RE AT SHOWS
YOU KNOW WHAT RING EM UP BECKY
>> YEARS AGO WHEN I SET OUT TO
CREATE A PILLOW FOR MYSELF,
UH, ONCE I MADE THAT AND I
KNEW IT WORKED, I WANTED TO
CREATE THE WORLD'S BEST PILLOW
THAT DID EVERYTHING.
I WANTED TO BE ABLE TO SEE
ANYBODY ON THE STREET AND SAY,
"WHAT WOULD YOU LIKE TO
SEE IN A PILLOW?"
IF THEY SAID, "I WANT
TO WASH IT AND DRY IT," I MADE
MINE FOR WASHER AND DRYER.
IF THEY SAID, "I WANT MINE TO
CONFORM EXACTLY TO ME AS AN
INDIVIDUAL," THAT'S WHAT MY
PILLOW WILL DO.
EVERY THING-- YOU CAN ASK
ANYBODY, ANYWHERE-- WHAT THEY
WANT TO SEE IN A PILLOW,
MY PILLOW HAS IT.
IT STAYS COOL.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO FLIP IT TO
THE COOL SIDE.
IT CONFORMS-- WHEREVER YOU SET
IT, IT HOLDS YOUR NECK IN YOUR
EXACT POSITION FOR YOU SO YOU
GET DEEP SLEEP THAT YOU NEED,
THAT DEEP, HEALING SLEEP
YOU NEED.
IT STAYS COOL, IT'S HEALTHY,
IT'S NON-ALLERGENIC FOR
ANYBODY WITH ALLERGIES.
IT'S ANTIMICROBIAL, WON'T HOLD
FUNGI OR MOLD AND IT LASTS 10
YEARS AND IT WON'T GO FLAT.
PILLOWS ARE MADE TO GO FLAT.
MINE WILL NOT GO FLAT.
YOU CAN THROW IT IN THE WASHER
AND DRYER, IT DOESN'T HURT.
IT STAYS THE SAME FOR 10 YEARS
AND YOU CAN'T BEAT IT.
WE HAVE A 60-DAY
MONEY-BACK GUARANTEE.
THAT RIGHT THERE IS ENOUGH.
YOU HAVE NOTHING TO LOSE.
WE HAVE ALL TRIED EVERY PILLOW
ON THIS PLANET AND THEY
DON'T WORK.
MY PILLOW WILL WORK FOR YOU
AND I GIVE YOU MY PERSONAL
GUARANTEE IT'LL WORK FOR YOU.
IT'LL NOT ONLY WORK FOR YOU,
IT'LL CREATE A MIRACLE
IN YOUR LIFE.
>> Announcer: THE PRECEDING HAS
BEEN A PAID PRESENTATION
BROUGHT TO YOU BY
MY PILLOW INCORPORATED.
>> Announcer: THE FOLLOWING IS
PAID FOR AND FURNISHED BY HAIR
CLUB FOR MEN AND WOMEN.
THIS STATION IS NOT RESPONSIBLE
FOR CLAIMS MADE IN THE FOLLOWING
PROGRAM.
WHEN IT COMES TO HAIR LOSS IN
WOMEN, THE REASONS WHY CAN BE AS
VARIED AS THE WOMEN THEMSELVES,
BUT THERE IS ONE PROVEN HAIR
SOLUTION THAT HAS TAKEN THESE
WOMEN FROM THIS TO THIS IN AS
LITTLE AS SIX WEEKS.
IT'S NOT A WIG, AND IT'S
NOT A WEAVE.
IT'S THEIR OWN HAIR, ONLY
BETTER, THANKS TO THE ONLY
NATIONWIDE COMPANY THAT
SPECIALIZES IN FEMALE HAIR LOSS,
HAIR CLUB FOR WOMEN.
>> IT'S A LIFE CHANGER...
FOREVER.
>> ETERNALLY GRATEFUL
TO HAIR CLUB.
>> BE BALD FOR THE REST OF MY
LIFE OR, YOU KNOW, GO TO HAIR
CLUB AND GET HAIR.
IT'S LIKE, "O.K., PROBABLY I
SHOULD GO TO HAIR CLUB."
>> AND IT HAS BEEN THE MOST
FREEING EXPERIENCE THAT I'VE