SHOWING UP OVER THE OCEAN,
WHERE I THINK THEY ARE GOING
TO STAY MAY GET CLOSE TO THE
COAST.
NAPA 36, 38 FAIRFIELD, 39
SANTA ROSA, 42 CONCORD
LIVERMORE TO MID AND UPPER 40s
COOLER THAN YESTERDAY.
WE WERE IN THE MID 50s THIS
TIME YESTERDAY.
WE'LL BE LUCKY IF WE GET TO
MID 50s THIS AFTERNOON UNDER
PARTLY CLOUDY SKY.
>>> LIGHT NOW, WE LIKE THAT IT
WAY.
HERE'S A LOOK AT EAST SHORE
FREEWAY PAST UNIVERSITY
OVERCROSSING THERE MAKING YOUR
WAY TOWARDS THE MacARTHUR MAZE
LIGHT AND MOVING AT THE LIMIT,
NO DELAYS.
SAME WITH GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE,
NO PROBLEMS STILL YET TO
CONFIGURE LANES SOUTHBOUND
DOWN TO TWO LANES OPENING UP
TO FOUR LANES WHEN THE COMMUTE
GETS UNDERWAY ALL MASS TRANSIT
ON TIME.
DRIVE TIMES TRAVELING FROM
WALNUT CREEK TO CALDECOTT 101
FROM SAN RAFAEL NOVATO TO
SAN RAFAEL HIGHWAY 87 NORTH
TOWARDS 101 NICE DRIVE.
>>> TODAY MORE YOUNG VICTIMS
OF THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
TRAGEDY WILL BE LAID TO REST
OTHER CHILDREN IN THE
DEVASTATED DISTRICT RETURN TO
CLASS FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
FRIDAY'S MASSACRE.
KATIE MARZULLO IS LIVE IN THE
NEWS ROOM ACCOUNT LATEST.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WILL REMAIN
CLOSED STILL A SECURE CRIME
SCENE.
DESKS ARE BEING MOVED TO A
SCHOOL IN A NEARBY TOWN WHERE
STUDENTS WILL RETURN TO CLASS
NO WORD ON WHEN.
6-YEAR-OLD JESSICA WILL BE
BURIED TODAY, SEVERAL WAKES
ARE SCHEDULED.
TWO 6-YEAR-OLD BOYS HAVE
ALREADY BEEN LAID TO REST,
JACK PINTO AND NOAH POSNER.
POLICE ARE TRYING TO GET AS
MUCH INFORMATION AS POSSIBLE
OUT OF A COMPUTER FOUND AT THE
HOME OF ADAM LANZA AND HIS
MOTHER IT WAS WADLY -- IT WAS
BADLY DAMAGED LIKE IT WAS HIT
WITH A HAMMER.
PEOPLE WHO KNEW THE LANZAS ARE
SAYING NANCY KNEW HER SON WAS
TROUBLED AND TOLD PEOPLE HER
SON WOULDN'T LEAVE THE HOUSE
ANY MORE.
>> SHE HOME SCHOOLED HIM AND
EVERYTHING.
I KNEW HE WAS ON MEDICATION
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
>> Reporter: ALSO, AUTHORITIES
HAVE TOLD ABC NEWS THAT THE
WEAPONS USED WERE PURCHASED BY
NANCY BETWEEN 2010 AND 2012.
SHE TOOK ADAM TO A FIRING
RANGE AT LEAST ONCE.
QRNOR OF CONNECTICUT HAS
CALLED FOR A MOMENT OF SILENCE
AND FOR CHURCH BELLS TO RING
THIS COMING FRIDAY MORNING AT
THE EXACT TIME OF THE
SHOOTINGS.
KATIE MARZULLO, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> GOVERNOR MALLOY IS CALLING
FOR HOUSES OF WORSHIP TO RING
THEIR BELLS AT THE SAME HE
WANTS 26 CHIMES FOR THE 26
VICTIMS, ALSO CALLING FOR A
NATIONWIDE MOMENT OF SILENCE
IN FRIDAY AT 6:30, ONE WEEK
AFTER THE SHOOTINGS TOOK
PLACE.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, IN LIGHT
OF THE CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY,
CALIFORNIA TEACHERS PENSION
FUND IS REVIEWING INVESTMENT
WITH A PRIVATE EQUITY FIRM
THAT CONTROLS THE MAKER OF THE
RIFLE USED BY THE NEWTOWN
GUNMAN THE RETIREMENT SYSTEM
HAD 3/4 OF A BILLION DOLLARS
INVESTED WITH THE COMPANY
BUSHMASTER.
OTHERS MAY FOLLOW SUIT.
>>> THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT HAS REIGNITED
NATIONAL DEBATE ON GUN CONTROL,
SALES ARE SOARING BEFORE
CONGRESS PASSES ANY NEW
RESTRICTIONS.
TERRY McSWEENEY WILL HAVE MORE
ON THAT COMING UP IN A LIVE
REPORT IN 30 MINUTES.
>>> ABC7 NEWS WILL CONTINUE TO
COVER THE TRAGEDY.
THE WEB TEAM IS SENDING OUT
UPDATES AS THE STORY DEVELOPS.
>>> SAN FRANCISCO POLICE ARE
HOPING THAT SOMEONE OUT THERE
COULD HELP THEM SOLVE A MURDER
MYSTERY POPULAR HIGH SCHOOL
FOOTBALL PLAYER FROM CONCORD
WAS SHOT TO DEATH OVER THE
WEEKEND.
AMY HOLLYFIELD IS LIVE AT
CONCORD HIGH WITH MORE.
>> Reporter: THEY ARE GOING TO
HAVE A VIGIL FOR HIM FRIDAY
NIGHT ON THE FIELD.
HE WAS ON THE FOOTBALL TEAM.
17-YEAR-OLD MONTREAL BLAKELY
WAS SHOT SUNDAY NIGHT IN THE
BAY VIEW DISTRICT HIS COACH
DESCRIBES HIM AS A GREAT KID
AND TEAMMATE NO WAS
HARDWORKING AND GOT GOOD
GRADES.
PARENTS CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT HE
WAS DOING IN THE BAY VIEW.
>> EVERYBODY THAT HAS ED ABOUT
HIM HAS HAD NOTHING BUT HE'S
-- HUMBLE, QUIET, GOOD GUY,
NICE PERSON.
THIS DOESN'T SEEM TO BE PART
OF THAT FABRIC.
>> Reporter: POLICE SAY THEY
NEED HELP SOLVING THIS CASE.
THEY ARE ASKING ANYONE WITH
INFORMATION TO COME FORWARD
AND TELL THEM WHAT THEY KNOW.
HE WAS IN THE BAY VIEW WITH A
FRIEND.
THEY ARE HOPING SOMEONE KNOWS
OR SAW SOMETHING.
THEY HAVE NO INFORMATION ON
POSSIBLE SUSPECTS OR MOTIVE.
AMY HOLLYFIELD, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> 5:05.
THE MOTHER ACCUSED OF
ABANDONING HER NEWBORN IN
SAN FRANCISCO WILL BE IN COURT
TODAY.
THE 39-YEAR-OLD FACES CHARGES
OF CHILD CRUELTY, A MAN
DISCOVERED THE BOY LAYING ON A
STREET LAST WEDNESDAY POLICE
FOUND MOM NEARBY COVERING IN
BLOOD AND NOT BREATHING
DOCTORS FOUND TRACES OF
COCAINE IN THE NEWBORN'S
SYSTEM.
THE BABY IS BETTER NOW THE TWO
OFFICERS WHO HELPED SAVE HIM
ARE BEING HONORED THEY GOT A
HUG FROM THE CHIEF YESTERDAY,
BOTH RESPONDED TO THE CALL AND
RUSHED THE BABY TO THE
HOSPITAL AFTER LEARNING THE
AMBULANCE WAS STILL 10 MINUTES
AWAY.
ONE OFFICER DROVE WHILE THE
OTHER GAVE THE NEWBORN CPR.
THEY SAY THE INDENT BROUGHT
THEM BOTH TO TEARS.
>>> -- DOG LOVERS IN OAKLAND
ARE SCHEDULED TO FIND OUT IFwsçx
OFFICIALS WAIL PROVE A DOG
PARK ON THE CORNER OF
MacARTHUR AND LAKE SHORE NEAR
LAKE MERRITT THE AREA HAS LONG
BEEN A ING SPOT FOR PICNICS
AND SOCK DER -- GAMES.
2100,000 -- OPPONENTS SAY THIS
AREA IS NOT THE RIGHT
LOCATION.
CITY COUNCIL SCHEDULED TO VOTE
AGAIN TONIGHT.
>>> IN A LANDMARK
SAN FRANCISCO BUILDING SET TO
BE TORN DOWN TODAY IT WAS
BADLY DAMAGED BY FIRE.
OFFICIALS DEEMED THE STRUCTURE
UNSAFE.
THE POOL HOUSE NEXT TO THE ZOO
WAS ONCE A CENTERPIECE.
THE POOL COMPLEX WAS BUILT IN
1925 BUT CLOSED SINCE THE
EARLY 70s.
>>> 5:07.
BUNDLE UP IF YOU ARE HEADED
OUT.
THE RAIN GEAR YOU WON'T NEED
FOR A COUPLE DAYS.
>> LET'S GET DETAILS.
>>> COLD TEMPERATURES NOT
NECESSARILY THE AIR BUT THE
WIND THAT IS BLOWING THAT AIR
AROUND THAT MAKES IT FEEL
COOLER WE HAVE A LITTLE WIND
CHILL THIS MORNING, WINDS OUT
OF THE NORTH, STEERING THE
STORMS OUT OVER THE OCEAN NOW
THAT'S WHERE THEY ARE GOING TO
STAY SIX MILES PER HOUR OR
FASTER IS GOING TO MAKE IT
FEEL COOLER.
WHEN YOU GO OUT AND YOU LOOK
AT TEMPERATURE ON YOUR CAR OR
YOU LOOK HERE AND I SHOW YOU
THE TEMPERATURE SHAVE FIVE OR
SIX DEGREES OFF AND THAT'S
WHAT IT FEELS LIKE OUTSIDE,
LOW TO MID 40s FOR THE BETTER
PART OF THE MORNING HOURS
GOING TO FEEL LIKE MAINLY
UPPER 30s EVERYWHERE THAT'S
HOW YOU SHOULD DRESS SHOWERS
ALONG THE COAST AT NOON MOST
OF US IN MID TO UPPER 40s MORE
SUN THIS AFTERNOON, COOLER
THAN YESTERDAY, UPPER 40s TO
LOW 50s AT 4:00, DROPPING TO
THE LOW TO MID 40s, CLEARING
SKY 7:00, WIDESPREAD FROST
TOMORROW MORNING EXCEPT FOR
THE BEACHES THEN LOW TO MID
50s RAIN RETURNS THURSDAY MORE
OF US WILL GET RAIN AS WE HEAD
INTO THURSDAY NIGHT INTO
FRIDAY WE'LL HAVE WIND ALSO.
>>> GOOD LOOKING RIDE THIS
MORNING.
WE DON'T HAVE MAJOR PROBLEMS
SAN MATEO BRIDGE TAIL LIGHTS
TOWARDS FOSTER CITY FROM
CLAWITER AND INDUSTRIAL
WESTBOUND TOWARDS FASHION
ISLAND AREA AND SAN MATEO NO
DELAYS.
EASTBOUND LOOKING GOOD TOWARDS
HAYWARD.
NAPA SILVERADO TRAIL CAR VS.
GUARDRAIL OUT OF LANES.
HIGHWAY 9 LOSS GUY TESS THAT
ACCIDENT CLEARED.
-- LOS GATOS THAT ACCIDENT
CLEARED.
NORTH 101 FROM 92 TO
SAN FRANCISCO, 680 WALNUT
CREEK TO THE DUBLIN PLEASANTON
INTERCHANGE AND 880 TO 237,
LESS THAN 20 MINUTES.
>>> AN ART PROJECT THAT
COMBINES ROCKET SCIENCE AND
OFF-THE-WALL PHOTOGRAPHY
DESIGNED TO OUT LIVE MANKIND
THAT STORY COMING UP.
>>> EAST BAY SCHOOL HOPES TO
PLANT A DREAM.
MICHAEL FINNEY SHOWS HOW YOU
>>> GOOD MORNING ON THIS
TUESDAY AT 5:12.
IT IS CRYSTAL CLEAR OUT THERE,
IN THE 30s IN THE BAY AREA.
KIND OF A CHILLY START.
MIKE WILL TALK ABOUT HOW LONG
THESE DRY CONDITIONS WILL
CONTINUE.
>>> THE COMPANY THAT UNDER
WROTE FACEBOOK'S TROUBLED
PUBLIC STOCK OFFERING WILL PAY
5 MILLION DOLLARS TO THE STATE
OF MASSACHUSETTS.
MORGAN STANLEY IS ACCUSED OF
DISCLOSING PROJECTED FALL IN
FACEBOOK REVENUE TO CERTAIN
ANALYSTS NOT THE GENERAL
PUBLIC STOCK PLUNGED AFTER THE
NEWS BECAME PUBLIC.
MASSACHUSETTS SUED BECAUSE THE
DROP FORCED STATE OFFICIALS TO
REVISE THEIR EXPECTED REVENUE
ESTIMATES.
>>> ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CONTRA COSTA COUNTY ATTEMPTING
TO WIN A NATIONAL GRANT AND
THEY'VE TURNED TO MICHAEL
FINNEY FOR HELP.
>> Reporter: THIS IS KATHY'S
KINDERGARTEN CLASS AT ALAMO
ELEMENTARY.
THEY ARE EXCITED ABOUT A
GARDEN AND WHAT WILL BE
PLANTED THERE.
>> TOMATOES.
>> Reporter: AMAZING TEACHING
SPACE HERE'S THE REALITY.
HOW DO YOU GET FROM THIS TO
THIS IN THESE TIGHT FINANCIAL
TIMES?
YOU GET CREATIVE.
>> CONTACT 7 ON YOUR SIDE IF
YOU FEEL YOU NEED TO GET THE
WORD OUT.
>> Reporter: ALAMO ELEMENTARY
ISN'T ASKING FOR MONEY THEY
WANT YOUR VOTE AGAIN AND AGAIN
OVER THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS.
>> THIS IS OUR SIMPLE MESSAGE.
WE JUST NEED THE VOTES.
>> Reporter: TEXT 95248 AND
USE CODE 2653, PBF AND YOU
HELP ALAMO ELEMENTARY.
HOW?
BY VOTING IN A CLOROX GRANT
PROGRAM THAT GIVES MONEY TO
SCHOOLS.
>> THE PROGRAM LAUNCHED FOUR
YEARS AGO AND GIVES SCHOOL
PROGRAM IN FINANCIAL NEED THE
OPPORTUNITY TO EARN UP TO
$50,000.
>> Reporter: THERE ARE SEVEN
GRANTS, FOUR GO TO THE SCHOOLS
GATHERING THE MOST VOTES.
WHICH BRINGS US BACK TO MISS
GARRETT'S INCAR BEGAN --
KINDERGARTEN CLASS.
VOTE.
I'M MICHAEL FINNEY, 7 ON YOUR
SIDE.
>>> VOTERS HAVE OFFICIALLY
MADE BARACK OBAMA PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES.
ELECTORAL COLLEGE VOTE THERE'S
IS.
STATE CAPITALS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY CASTED THE FINAL VOTES
OF THE CAMPAIGN YESTERDAY AS
REQUIRED BY THE CONSTITUTION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA 332 VOTES MORE
THAN THE 270 NEEDED TO WIN
THERE WAS CONTROVERSY WHEN A
FEW IN ARIZONA TRIED TO RAISE
DEBUNKED CLAIMS ABOUT THE
PRESIDENT HAVING A FAKE BIRTH
CERTIFICATE.
>>> A GROUP OPPOSED TO CAPITAL
PUNISHMENT SAYS FOUR STATES
CARRIED OUT MORE THAN 75% OF
EXECUTIONS IN THE U.S. THIS
YEAR.
THE DEATH PENALTY INFORMATION
CENTER SAID TEXAS LED THE
NATION WITH 15 EXECUTIONS
FOLLOWED BY ARIZONA,
MISSISSIPPI AND OKLAHOMA.
THE GROUP SAYS ANOTHER 23
STATES HAVE NOT PUT AN INMATE
TO DEATH IN 10 YEARS,
INCLUDING CALIFORNIA.
THE REPORT SAYS MANY STATES
ARE IMPOSING FEWER DEATH
SENTENCES.
>>> NEW SATELLITE CIRCLING THE
EARTH NOW DESIGN TODAY TO
RELAY TV SHOWS AND RADIO
COMMUNICATIONS TO EARTH FOR
THE NEXT 15 YEARS AFTER THAT
IT GETS REAL MISSION THAT
COULD LAST A MILLION TIMES
LONGER.
WHAT DOES THIS ROCKET LAUNCH
FROM KAZAKHSTAN AND THIS BOOK
HAVE IN COMMON?
THEY BOTH CARRY AN ART PROJECT
FROM THE IMAGINATION OF AN
ARTIST.
WE CAUGHT UP WITH HIM IN
MOSCOW A FEW HOURS AFTER HE
WATCHED THE LAUNCH.
>> IT IS HUMLING TO DO WORK ON
A PROJECT LIKE THIS THAT SO
MANY PEOPLE CONTRIBUTED TO AND
SEE IT COME TO LIFE.
>> Reporter: HE GOT HIS PHD IN
GEOGRAPHY AT -- HIS Ph.D IN
GEOGRAPHY AT UC BERKELEY.
THIS DISC ONBOARD THE
SATELLITE CONTAINS HIS LATEST
PROJECT, 100 PHOTOGRAPHS OF
THE MANMADE AND NATURAL
WORLDS.
>> IT WILL OPERATE FOR 15
YEARS, AFTER THAT IT WILL
BOOST UP INTO A HIGHER ORBIT
CALLED THE GRAVEYARD ORBIT.
>> Reporter: THAT IS FAR
ENOUGH OUT THAT SATELLITE AND
IMAGES SHOULD ORBIT FOR
BILLIONS OF YEARS LONG ENOUGH
FOR FUTURE GENERATIONS TO TAKE
A LOOK AND TRY TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT 21st CENTURY HUMANS WERE
ABOUT.
THEY ARE KIND OF LIKE CAVE
PAINTINGS ANCIENT MAN LEFT FOR
US.
>> CAVE PAINTINGS FOR THE
FUTURE.
IF ANYBODY EVER FINDS THESE A
BILLION YEARS FROM NOW IT MAY
LOOK TO TELL THE SAME WAY THAT
CAVE PAINTINGS LOOK TO US.
>> COMING UP AT 6 P.M.,
EXPANDED LOOK AT THE PROJECT
AND MORE ON HOW TREVOR CHOSE
THE PHOTOS ON THE SPACECRAFT
AND IN THE BOOK.
THERE WERE EARLIER RENDERINGS
SENT OUT ENVOY ER, DA VINCI'S
-- OF MAN'S REACH TO HIS
HEIGHT THIS WILL BE A LOT
STKWRAOEUFRPL WE ARE INTRIGUED.
>>> CHANGES, A LOT OF PEOPLE
WANT TO GO SKIING THIS WEEKEND.
>>> WE WILL BE WATCHING IT
WILL BE DIFFICULT.
RIGHT NOW ON THIS TUESDAY
MORNING, LOOKING ON EMERYVILLE
ACROSS THE BAY BRIDGE TOWARDS
SAN FRANCISCO CLEAR THIS
MORNING THAT USUALLY MEANS
ISSUES WITH THE CLEAR WEATHER
OUT THERE BECAUSE IT IS
GETTING COLDER LIVE DOPPLER
RADAR RETURNS OVER THE OCEAN
WHERE MOST OF THE CLOUDS ARE
THIS MORNING.
JUST UPDATED TEMPERATURES
CLOSER TO FROST NAPA 34
COLDEST THERE FAIRFIELD 36,
SANTA ROSA 38, EVERYONE ELSE
IN THE 40s, LOW 40s CONCORD,
40 LIVERMORE, 42, 45 SAN JOSE,
OAKLAND 47, SAN FRANCISCO 46,
THERE'S A LITTLE WIND CHILL
THIS MORNING.
38 WATSONVILLE COOL SPOT LOW
TO MID 40s SANTA CRUZ GILROY,
PARTLY CLOUDY TODAY MOST
SHOWERS OVER THE OCEAN
FREEZING COLD TONIGHT FREEZE
WARNING IN THE NORTH BAY
VALLEYS, FROST ADVISORY FOR
THE BAY SHORELINE, SANTA CLARA
VALLEY AND EAST BAY VALLEYS,
PETS, PLANTS AND PIPES
EVERYWHERE BUT OUR BEACHES
TONIGHT STORMY PATTERN STARTS
THURSDAY.
COLD FRONT FROM YESTERDAY
SWEEPING BY, IN THE COLD AIR
NOW, REINFORCING SHOT OF COLD
AIR WITH TROUGH THAT COMES
DOWN THAT'S GOING TO SPARK
SHOWERS OVER THE OCEAN ALSO
PUSH US INTO THE COLDEST AIR
TONIGHT.
THURSDAY TO FRIDAY, BEHIND
THAT SATURDAY AND SUNDAY'S
STORM GOING TO SCOOP UP MORE
MOISTURE, WEEKEND BIGGEST
CHANCE OF FLOODING AND POWER
OUTAGES.
7:00 TOMORROW MORNING QUIET.
THROUGH THE DAY INCREASE IN
HIGH CLOUDS MAYBE A SPRINKLE
OR TWO IN EXTREME NORTH BAY
DURING THE OVERNIGHT HOURS
BEST CHANCE OF ANY TYPE OF WET
WEATHER IN THE NORTH BAY, 7:00
IN THE MORNING WHERE WE'LL SEE
IT, THIS IS A SLOW MOVING
SYSTEM BY NOON THE RAIN IS
STARTING TO GET INTO THE HEART
OF THE BAY INTO THE AFTERNOON
HOURS GOING TO GET INTO THE
SOUTH BAY LOOK WHERE THE
HEAVIEST RAIN IS, STILL OVER
THE NORTH BAY, YELLOWS AND
ORANGES WHERE IT STAYS FOR THE
BETTER PART THURSDAY NIGHT IT
LOOKS LIKE WE ARE GOING TO
HAVE HEAVIEST RAIN UP THERE
FOR THIS FIRST SYSTEM.
TODAY IN THE LOW TO MID 50s
ANOTHER CHILLY ONE OUTSIDE
EVEN DURING THE AFTERNOON.
FROST AND FREEZE TONIGHT, LOW
TO MID 50s TOMORROW, GET THE
WET WEATHER GEAR THURSDAY
THROUGH SUNDAY, THEN OUT IN
TIME FOR MONDAY.
>>> LIVE SHOT OF THE EAST
SHORE FREEWAY MAKING YOUR WAY
FROM RICHMOND EL CERRITO
THROUGH BERKELEY INTO
EMERYVILLE AND MacARTHUR MAZE
TRAFFIC FLOWING NICELY
UNIVERSITY AVENUE NO DELAYS
GETTING A LITTLE MORE CROWDED
EVERYTHING AT THE LIMIT
FUNNELING INTO THE BAY BRIDGE
TOLL NO PROBLEMS EARLIER
ROADWORK ON UPPER DECK PICKED
UP.
NO PROBLEMS, EVERYTHING AT THE
LIMIT AS YOU MAKE YOUR WAY
THROUGH THE S-CURVE INTO THE
TUNNEL INTO SAN FRANCISCO, NO
DELAYS AT THE TOLL THROUGH
SAN RAFAEL PAST LUCAS VALLEY
ROAD, TRAFFIC LIGHT OUT OF
NOVATO TOWARDS CENTRAL
SAN RAFAEL AND CENTRAL MARIN
NICE LOOK AT SAN JOSE
NORTHBOUND HIGHWAY 87 AT THE
JULIAN EXIT TRAFFIC AT THE
LIMIT AS YOU MAKE YOUR WAY
NORTH TOWARDS 101.
>>> 5:22.
>>> A ROYAL FIRST, THE QUEEN
DID SOMETHING NO MONARCH HAS
EVER DONE.
WHY TOP BRITISH LAWMAKERS WERE
ON THEIR BEST BEHAVIOR.
>>> WHAT HAPPENED WHEN A
DETERMINED LITTLE GIRL TOOK ON
A GIANT TOY COMPANY.
>>> MAJOR TOY COMPANY CHANGING
THE WAY IT MARKETS A PRODUCT.
HASBRO'S EASY BAKE OVEN HAS
BEEN A FAVORITE OF AMERICAN
GIRLS FOR GENERATIONS UNTIL
NOW IT WAS ONLY PINK AND
PURPLE AFTER A 13-YEAR-OLD
GIRL FROM NEW JERSEY STARTED A
PETITION HASBRO AGREED TO MAKE
IT IN MORE NEUTRAL COLORS AND
INCLUDE BOYS ON THE PACKAGING.
SHE SAID HER 4-YEAR-OLD
BROTHER WANTS TO BE A CHEF.
HEAR MORE FROM HER ON
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA" AT 7
A.M..
>> I THINK THAT IS GREAT.
MY KIDS DON'T CARE WHAT COLOR
IT IS, IF THEY LIKE THE TOY
THEY WILL USE IT.
>> YOUR KIDS ARE ENLIGHTENED.
>> BAY AREA KIDS.
>> IF HER KIDS ARE ENLIGHTENED
AND MY KIDS ONLY LIKE TO PLAY
WITH THE BOXES, WHAT DOES THAT
MAKE THEM?
>> I COULD CHARGE YOU $100 FOR
THE HOUR IF WE GO THERE.
>> THEY ARE CREATIVE.
>>> THEY USED TO DO THAT WHEN
THEY WERE YOUNGER THEY DON'T
DO THAT ANY MORE.
LET'S LOOK AT HIGH
TEMPERATURES LOW TO MID 50s
EVERYWHERE COOLER NORTH CLEAR
LAKE AND CLOVERDALE MID TO
UPPER 40s, PARTLY SUNNY,
SHOWERS OVER THE OCEAN COULD
BUMP UP AGAINST BEACHES.
STILL HAVE SNOW IN THE SEE
RATHER RAIN THROUGH THE
GRAPEVINE WILL SLIDE DOWN
TOWARDS SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
THIS AFTERNOON, SHOWERS FROM
EUREKA OVER THE OCEAN TODAY,
39 IN TAHOE THE REST OF US IN
THE 50s, SO CAL MID TO UPPER
60s.
>>> NO FOG AT GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE NO DELAYS, SOUTHBOUND
101 FROM THE WALDO GRADE INTO
SAN FRANCISCO OPENED UP TO
FOUR LANES THINGS ARE MOVING
NICELY.
SAN MATEO BRIDGE TAIL LIGHTS
STARTING TO BUNCH UP A ABOUT
IT, BRAKES ON THE FLAT SECTION
THINGS PICK UP FOSTER CITY
WESTBOUND MacARTHUR MAZE EAST,
SOUTH AND 80 WEST HEADED INTO
THE MacARTHUR MAZE ALL FLOWING
NICELY NO DELAYS AT THE BAY
BRIDGE.
>>> QUEEN ELIZABETH IS MAKING
HISTORY TODAY.
THIS MORNING SHE BECAME THE
FIRST MONARCH IN MORE THAN 100
YEARS TO SIT IN ON A CABINET
MEETING THIS IS NEW VIDEO OF
THE PRIME MINISTER CAMERON
GREETING HER AT THE DOOR.
QUEEN VICTORIA WAS THE LAST
MONARCH TO ATTEND SUCH A
SESSION.
GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS SAY
ELIZABETH PAID A VISIT AS
OBSERVER ONLY, NOT AS A
CONTRIBUTOR IN HONOR OF HER 60
YEARS ON THE THRONE.
>>> GUN DEBATE RAINS ON IN THE
WAKE OF THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
WHAT STATE LAWMAKERS HAVE IN
THE WORKS.
>>> BUG BOMB GONE WRONG.
THE BIG MISTAKE A BAY AREA
HOMEOWNER MADE TRYING TO
FUMIGATE HIS THEME
.
>>> GOOD TUESDAY MORNING.
THANKS FOR JOINING US I'M
KRISTEN SZE.
>>> I'M ERIC THOMAS.
A BIT NIPPY THIS MORNING.
LET'S FIND OUT WHAT THE
FORECAST LOOKS LIKE.
>>> NORTH BAY MID 30s THE REST
OF US IN THE 40s ALL OF US 20s
AND 30s TOMORROW TODAY IS THE
BEGINNING OF THAT COOLING
TREND.
CHANCE OF SCATTERED SHOWERS
ACROSS THE OCEAN PICKED UP BY
LIVE DOPPLER I THINK THEY WILL
STAY OVER THE OCEAN.
36 NAPA, 38 FAIRFIELD, 39
SANTA ROSA, 46 SAN JOSE,
MOUNTAIN VIEW, 48 OAKLAND, 46
SAN FRANCISCO, 42 CONCORD.
LOW TO MID 50s THIS AFTERNOON
WITH PARTLY CLOUDY SKY.
>>> IF YOU ARE LEAVING ANTIOCH
TOWARDS PITTSBURG AND CONCORD,
TRAFFIC SLOWING BUNCHING UP,
TYPICAL WHEN YOU GET TO
HIGHWAY 4 BYPASS.
THINGS PICK UP TOWARDS CONCORD.
OUT OF THE CENTRAL VALLEY NOT
BAD SLOWING UP AND OVER THE
ALTAMONT PASS INTO LIVERMORE.
SILVERADO TRAIL INJURY
ACCIDENT BLOCKING LANES CHP
AND CREWS ARE ON SCENE.
>>> RIGHT NOW MOST CHILDREN IN
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
DISTRICT DEVASTATED BY
FRIDAY'S MASSACRE ARE
RETURNING TO CLASS FOR THE
FIRST TIME.
MORE FUNERALS WILL BE HELD
TODAY AS THE INVESTIGATION
REVEALS NEW DETAILS ON THE
GUNMAN.
KATIE MARZULLO IS LIVE IN THE
NEWSROOM.
>> Reporter: LOCAL POLICE AND
SCHOOL OFFICIALS HAVE BEEN
DISCUSSING HOW AND WHEN TO
INCREASE SECURITY AT SCHOOLS.
STATE POLICE WILL BE ON ALERT
FOR THREATS AND HOAXES.
IT IS BACK-TO-SCHOOL DAY,
EXCEPT OF COURSE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY IT IS STILL A
SECURE CRIME SCENE AND DESKS
AND SUCH ARE BEING MOVED TO A
VACANT SCHOOL IN A NEARBY TOWN
WHERE STUDENTS WILL RETURN TO
CLASS NO WORD ON WHEN THAT
WILL HAPPEN.
AS FOR THE INVESTIGATION
POLICE ARE TRYING TO GET AS
MUCH INFORMATION AS POSSIBLE
OUT OF A DAMAGED COMPUTER
FOUND AT THE HOME OF SHOOTER
ADAM LANZA AND HIS MOTHER
NANCY.
THEY HOPE TO RECOVER SOMETHING
THAT WILL POINT TO A MOTIVE.
THE WEAPONS USED IN FRIDAY'S
RAMPAGE WERE PURCHASED BY
NANCY BETWEEN 2010 AND 12 AND
SHE TOOK ADAM TO A FIRING
RANGE AT LEAST ONCE.
>> EXTREMELY POOR DECISION ON
HER PART.
YOU ARE TALKING ABOUT A SORT
OF EYE PSYCHOLOGICAL SWITCH
THAT I THINK GOT TURNED ON --
ON FOR HIM WITH THE ACCESS OF
THE WEAPONS AND THEN THE READY
AVAILABILITY.
>> Reporter: PEOPLE WHO KNEW
THE LANZAS ARE SAYING NANCY
KNEW HER SON WAS TROUBLED AND
FORMER BABYSITTER SAYS SHE
INSTRUCTED HIM TO NEVER EVEN
TURN HIS BACK ON ADAM.
FOUR FUNERALS ARE SCHEDULED
FOR TODAY THREE STUDENTS AND
ONE TEACHER, TWO -YEAR-OLD
BOYS HAVE ALREADY BEEN LAID TO
REST.
KATIE MARZULLO, ABC7 NEWS --
>>> BAY AREA MAN IN CUSTODY
ACCUSED OF MAKING THREATS
ABOUT THE SHOOTINGS ONLINE.
FAIRFIELD POLICE ARRESTED THE
MAN AT HIS HOME.
FRIDAY HE OFFED COMMENTS THAT
HE SUPPORTED THE SHOOTER IN
SANDY HOOK AND HAD THOUGHTS
ABOUT SOMETHING SIMILAR.
POLICE WILL PURSUE FELONY
CHARGES.
HE HAS NOW POST ADD APOLOGY ON
HIS FACEBOOK PAGE.
>>> GUN SALES ARE UP FOLLOWING
THE SCHOOL SHOOTING.
ALSO CONTROVERSY OVER NEW GUN
STORE OPENING IN THE SOUTH
BAY.
TERRY McSWEENEY IS LIVE IN
LOS GATOS WITH DETAILS.
>> Reporter: THE STORE IS
HAVING ITS GRAND OPENING
SATURDAY AND SOME SAY THAT IS
NOT A GRAND IDEA BECAUSE FOLKS
HERE IN LOS GATOS, SOME SAY
THEY WEREN'T CONSULTED ABOUT
THAT AND FEEL THEY SHOULD HAVE
BEEN.
LOOK AT PICTURES OF THE STORE
OFFICIALLY THIS IS GOING TO BE
A SPORTING GOODS STORE MORE
THAN RIFLES AND GUNS BEING
SOLD.
IT IS DESCRIBED AS A HIGH END
CUSTOM AGAIN SHOP.
HERE'S THE DEBATE.
>> TWO THINGS, -- WE WOULD
LIKE TO KNOW ABOUT THAT
PRODUCT BEFORE IT IS
AVAILABLE.
>> I THINK ANY TIME YOU CAN
BRING BUSINESS TO TOWN IT IS
POSITIVE.
I DON'T THINK THEY ARE GOING
TO BE HANDING OUT GUNS LIKE
CANDY TO CHILDREN SO WHY IS IT
A REAL PROBLEM?
>> Reporter: DEBORAH IS NOT
GOING TO GET HELP FROM CITY
HALL.
THE CODE FROM 1987 SAYS THERE
IS NO REQUIREMENT FOR A
RETAILER TO HAVE ANY KIND OF
HEARINGS IF HE WANTS TO SELL
FIREARMS THAT'S THE WAY THE
LAW IS WRITTEN.
IN SACRAMENTO, A NUMBER OF
LAWMAKERS, INCLUDING SENATOR
YE ARE PUTTING TOGETHER
LEGISLATION THAT WOULD TOUGHEN$
CALIFORNIA'S ALREADY TOUGH GUN
CONTROL LAWS, SOMEBODY SAYING
IF SOMEBODY WANTS TO KILL
SOMEONE OR A THIS OF PEOPLE,
THERE IS A WAY TO DO IT WITH
OR WITHOUT AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
TERRY McSWEENEY, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
IS FELT AS STRONGLY IN THE BAY
AREA MOST FAMILIES DON'T KNOW
THE VICTIMS LOCAL CLERGY
STEPPING UP TO PROVIDE A PLACE
WHERE PEOPLE CAN SHARE THE
HURT AND BEGIN TO HEAL.
CONFUSED AND UPSET BY ÷ KE NEWS
MANY CAME TO THE SERVICE IN
BURLINGAME LAST NIGHT
SEARCHING FOR INSPIRATION TO
HELP THEM COPE.
FOR BETSY THERE'S A CLOSE
CONNECTION TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY THAT'S WHERE SHE
GROUP AND STILL HAS FRIENDS
WHO ARE FIRST RESPONDERS TO
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING.
SHE IS UPSET, BUT ALSO PROUD
OF THE WAY THE TOWN HAS
RESPONDED.
>> THE PEOPLE OF CONNECTICUT,
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN ARE
SHOWING THE WORLD HOW TO LIVE,
HOW TO LOVE AND HOW TO FIGHT
EVIL.
>> THE PASTOR ORGANIZED THE
SERVICE OF REMEMBRANCE,
HEALING AND HOPE TO GIVE
PEOPLE A PLACE TO SHARE TEARS
HE SAYS THAT IS IMPORTANT TO
AVOID BECOMING DISENGAGED OR
CYNICAL ABOUT THE TRAGEDY.
>>> THE POST OFFICE HAS
ESTABLISHED AN ADDRESS YOU CAN
USE TO EXPRESS CONDOLENCES TO
THE PEOPLE OF SANDY HOOK.
YOU CAN SEND LETTERS, CARE
PACKAGES EVEN DRAWINGS FROM
YOUR CHILDREN, P.O. BOX 3700,
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, 06470.
THE ADDRESS ON ABC7NEWS.COM.
STAY WITH ABC7 NEWS FOR
CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
THE ABC7 NEWS WEB TEAM IS
SENDING OUT UPDATES, SIGN UP
AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
>>> EIGHT PEOPLE ARE
RECOVERING AFTER BEING EXPOSED
TO TOXIC CHEMICALS, INCLUDING
PART OF A HAZ-MAT CREW.
EIGHT WERE RUSHED TO THE
HOSPITAL AFTER BEING EXPOSED
TO CHEMICALS FROM A HOUSEHOLD
BUG BOMB AT A TRAILER PARK
NEAR REDWOOD CITY, TWO PEOPLE
SET OFF THE DEVICE INSIDE
THEIR TRAILER BUT DID NOT
LEAVE.
THE COUPLE WITH A NEIGHBOR
BECAME ILL.
WHEN RESPONDERS GOT THERE,
THEY WENT IN WITHOUT REALIZING
THERE WAS TOXIC AIR INSIDE.
ALL EIGHT WERE TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITAL, THEY ARE EXPECTED TO
BE FINE.
>>> SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
SEARCHING AND ASKING FOR THE
PUBLIC'S HELP IN SOLVING THE
MURDER OF A 17-YEAR-OLD
FOOTBALL PLAYER.
MONTREAL BLAKELY PLAYED
OFFENSE AND DEFENSE FOR
CONCORD HIGH AND WAS SENIOR AT
CONCORD HIGH HE WAS SHOT AND
KILLED IN THE BAYVIEW DISTRICT
SATURDAY NIGHT.
SO FAR POLICE HAVE NOT
RELEASED MOTIVE.
>>> SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
SEARCHING FOR TWO MEN WHO SHOT
A CLERK WHILE HOLDING UP A
PHARMACY IN THE MISSION
DISTRICT AT THE AG PHARMACY.
THE TWO MEN ENTERED, PULLED
OUT WEAPONS, TRIED TO HOLD-UP
A WORKER THE EMPLOYEE WAS SHOT
IN THE LEG AND IS EXPECTED TO
SURVIVE.
POLICE LOOKING FOR A GETAWAY
DRIVER.
NO WORD ON WHETHER THE ROBBERS
GOT AWAY WITH ANY LOOT WITH
>>> LIVE DOPPLER FEELING A
LITTLE LONELY.
>> IT IS TAKING A REST AFTER A
BUSY WEEKEND.
>>> YEAH, DEFINITELY, WATCHING
SOME STORMS MAINLY OVER THE
OCEAN, STILL GOING TO KEEP
GUARD AS THE SYSTEM WILL HUG
THE COAST COULD BRING SHOWERS
TO THE COAST, THUNDERSTORMS AS
THE INSTABILITY IS GREATER
OVER THE WARMER OCEAN WATER
THIS MORNING THAN OVER LAND.
A FEW 30s INLAND MAINLY NORTH
BAY VALLEYS MOST OF US LOW TO
MID 40s THROUGH 7:00, SHOWERS
HUG THE COAST BY NOON, MID TO
UPPER 40s.
LOW TO MID 40s DURING THE
EVENING YOU WON'T NEED TO
WORRY ABOUT WET WEATHER, JUST
NEED A HEAVY COAT FROST
EVERYWHERE TOMORROW MORNING
AFTER THAT COLD START LOW TO
MID 50s, WET WEATHER THURSDAY
AND FRIDAY.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
LIT AT THE TOLL PLAZA BAY
BRIDGE -- A FEW CARS BACKED UP
TO PAY CASH, NO PROBLEMS UPPER
DECK INTO SAN FRANCISCO,
EASTBOUND DUMBARTON ROADWORK
UNTIL 6:00 A.M. WILL AFFECT
YOUR DRIVE, YOU CAN SEE YELLOW
TOWARDS THE NEWARK AREA.
PROBLEM IN PALO ALTO NEAR THE
STANFORD SHOPPING CENTER, ON
SAND HILL ROAD BETWEEN
EL CAMINO REAL AND ARBORETUM,
NEAR THE SHOPPING CENTER,
FLOODING ALONG SAND HILL ROAD,
CLOSED BOTH DIRECTIONS CAR HIT
A HYDRANT.
THEY'VE CLOSED OFF THAT
/YYG
DOWNLOAD THIS FREE APP AT THE
APPLE APP STORE AND GOOGLE
PLAY.
>>> BREAKING NEWS FROM
CONCORD.
AG6 CAR SMACKED INTO A STORE IN
THE LAST HOUR.
AMY HOLLYFIELD JOINS US LIVE
WITH A LOOK AT THE DAMAGE.
>> Reporter: WITHIN THE LAST
COUPLE OF MINUTES THEY'VE
BOARDED UP THE DAMAGE, NO WALL
HERE ANY MORE, NO DOLLARS
WINDOW, IT IS GONE.
A CAR SMASHED INTO THIS
GAMESTOP STORE AT 4:00 THIS
MORNING, IN THE CONCORD STRIP
MALL AT IGNACIO BOULEVARD.
THE PERSON IN THE CAR JUMPED
OUT AND STOLE ITEMS AND THEN
RAN AWAY.
THE PEOPLE WHO WORK HERE TELL
US THE ITEMS THEY STOLE CAN BE
TRACED THEY GRABBED PREOWNED
iPHONES, MAYBE THAT COULD HELP
LEAD POLICE TO THESE PEOPLE OR
PERSON.
THE PEOPLE OR PERSON TOOK OFF,
THEY DON'T KNOW FIT WAS ON
FOOT OR THEY HAD A GETAWAY, --
THEY LEFT THE CAR THAT CRASHED
INTO THE WALL, IT HAS BEEN
TOWED NOW WORKERS AND FRIENDS
AND FAMILY MEMBERS ONE OF THE
SHIFT MANAGER FATHER IS HERE
WORKED ONBOARDING THIS UP,
BECAUSE IT IS COLD TO PROTECT
THE STORE.
THEY HAVE EMPLOYEES INSIDE
TRYING TO CLEANUP THE GLASS,
IT IS A MESS IN THERE.
ABOUT 9:00, THE GLASS COMPANY,
THEY HOPE WILL START WORKING
ON A FIX.
POLICE SUSPECTS -- SUSPECT THE
CAR WAS STOLEN, IT HASN'T BEEN
REPORTED STOLEN YET BUT THEY
HAVE THEIR SUSPICIONS.
AMY HOLLYFIELD, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> 5:42.
>>> WASHINGTON MAY BE TAKING A
STEP BACK FROM THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
NEXT, THE OFFER FROM THE
WHITE HOUSE THAT REPUBLICANS
WILL CONSIDER THIS MORNING.
>>> MYSTERY OF A STOLEN
HOLLYWOOD FILM.
WHY APPLICATION AND THE MOVIE
STUDIO ARE
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
Just unroll it,
fill, top,
bake, and present.
That must have
taken you forever!
It was really tough.
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Pie Crust.
Let the Making Begin
>>> THIS MORNING HOUSE SPEAKER
BOEHNER WILL PRESENT THE
WHITE HOUSE'S LATEST OFFER TO
HOUSE REPUBLICANS.
IT WOULD ELIMINATE A TAX CUT
FOR AMERICANS EARNING MORE
THAN $400,000 A YEAR.
IT WOULD CUT 400 BILLION
DOLLARS FROM HEALTH CARE
PROGRAMS AND 200 BILLION
DOLLARS FROM OTHER PROGRAMS
OVER THE NEXT 10 YEARS.
THE OFFER WOULD NOT CHANGE THE
ELIGIBILITY AGE FOR MEDICARE
AND THAT COULD BE A STICKING
POINT IN NEGOTIATIONS.
THE DEAL NEEDS TO BE IN PLACE
BY JANUARY 1st, OR INCREASES
FOR MOST AMERICANS WILL KICK
IN.
>>> INSTAGRAM PHOTOS MAY BE
USED IN ADS WITHOUT YOUR
PERMISSION.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
McDONALD'S WORKERS MAY HAVE TO
CELEBRATE A MIXED -- MISSED
CHRISTMAS THEY MAY BE WORKING.
FAST FOOD CHAIN TO STAY OPEN
TO BUTTE STEALS AFTER
THANKSGIVING TURNED SALES
POSITIVE.
-- NICE HOLIDAY GIFT FOR
DRIVERS, GAS PRICES CONTINUE
TO FALL, AAA SAYS AVERAGE IS
$3.25, A PENNY MORE THAN THIS
TIME LAST YEAR.
IF YOU DON'T WANT YOUR PHOTOS
USED BY ADVERTISERS FOR
MARKETING DON'T USE INSTAGRAM
STARTING NEXT MONTH THE
SERVICE HAS THE GO AHEAD FROM
FACEBOOK TO USE NAMES, TEXT
PHOTOS AND OTHER CONTENT WITH
MARKETING MESSAGES THIS
APPLIES FOR USERS AT YOUNG --
AS YOUNG AS 13.
AT THE NEW YORK STOCK EXCHANGE
I'M JANE KING.
>>> SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
WORKING WITH SECURITY AGENTS
FROM PARAMOUNT STUDIOS TO
RECOVER AN UNRELEASED FILM
STOLEN IN A CAR BURGLARY.
THE THEFT HAPPENED A MONTH AGO
AT A PIER 39 GARAGE A HARD
DRIVE CONTAINING THE FILM WAS
AMONG HUNDREDS OF ITEMS
STOLEN.
SECURITY CAMERAS LED TO THE
ARREST OF SUSPECTS WHILE ITEMS
WERE RECOVER, THE HARD DRIVE
WITH THE FILM IS STILL
MISSING.
LAUGH CAN ONLY SPECULATE AS TO
WHAT HAPPENED TO -- LAW
ENFORCEMENT CAN ONLY SPECULATE
AS TO WHAT HAPPENED TO THE
FILM.
>> IT IS COMMON NOW PEOPLE
CREATE A DV D AND SELL IT ON
THE STREET WITH
>> ONE SOURCE SPECULATED THE
HARD DRIVE COULD HAVE BEEN
TOLD AT A -- COULD HAVE BEEN
SOLD AT A STREET VALUE OF $30.
>> THAT'S WHY CRIME DOESN'T
PAY.
>>> COOLER TEMPERATURES.
LOTS OF TALK, THE WEATHER IS
GOING TO BE CHANGING RAPIDLY
THE NEXT 24 TO 48 HOURS.
5:47, BEAUTIFUL PICTURE OF THE
BREEZES BLOWING THROUGH
DOWNTOWN SAN FRANCISCO, YOU
CAN SEE HOW CLEAR IT IS THAT'S
THE WAY IT IS GOING TO STAY
OVER THE NEXT 24 TO 36 HOURS.
LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD YOU CAN SEE
HOW QUIET IT IS OUT THERE
CLOUDS OVER THE OCEAN, STORMS,
I THINK THAT'S WHERE THEY ARE
GOING TO STAY.
MID TO UPPER 30s NORTH BAY
VALLEYS.
EVERYBODY ELSE LOW TO UPPER
40s, OAKLAND 47, HALF MOON BAY
48.
45 MOUNTAIN VIEW AND SAN JOSE
46 SAN FRANCISCO, 40 CONCORD,
42 LIVERMORE NOW.
MONTEREY BAY LOW TO MID 40s
SANTA CRUZ, GILROY AND SALINAS,
38 WATSONVILLE, 50 MONTEREY.
TODAY PARTLY CLOUDY SHOWERS
MAINLY OVER THE OCEAN PEACING
COLD EVERYWHERE EXCEPT --
FREEZING COLD EVERYWHERE
EXCEPT BEACHES TONIGHT.
FREEZE WARNING IN THE NORTH
BAY VALLEYS, STORMY PATTERN
STARTS THURSDAY YESTERDAY'S
COLD FRONT BRINGING RAIN TO
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA HIGH
ELEVATION SNOW, WE ARE DEEP
INTO THE COLD AIR RIGHT NOW WE
WILL STAY THERE, NOT ONLY
TODAY BUT TONIGHT AND
TOMORROW.
THAT'S WHY OUR COLDEST NIGHT
IS STILL AHEAD OF US.
HERE'S THURSDAY AND FRIDAY'S
STORM, FARTHER BACK HERE'S
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY SAYS STORM
ACTIVE PATTERN ON THE WAY
LOOKS LIKE WE'LL STILL HAVE
GREATER AMOUNTS OF RAIN WITH
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY'S STORM
AND POSSIBILITY OF FLOODING
POWER OUTAGES THEN, STILL
THERE THURSDAY AND FRIDAY,
MORE LIKELY SATURDAY AND
SUNDAY, FROST TOMORROW MORNING,
INCREASING HIGH CLOUDS AS THE
AFTERNOON UNFOLDS.
BEST CHANCE OF SEEING LIGHT
RAIN OVERNIGHT IN THE NORTH
BAY 7:00 THURSDAY MORNING RAIN,
RAIN WILL SLIDE TOWARDS
SAN FRANCISCO AND OAKLAND BY
NOON LEADING EDGE OF STEADIER
RAIN HEAVIER NORTH BAY WHERE
IT GOING TO STAY FOR THE
BETTER PART OF THE AFTERNOON
AND EVENING HOURS.
BY 9:00, 10:00 FINALLY MAKES
EIGHT INTO THE SOUTH BAY
THURSDAY AND SPREAD OVER ALL
-- ALL NEIGHBORHOODS AND
BREEZY FRIDAY, SECONDARY STORM
SATURDAY, SUNDAY WITH A
ONE-TWO PUNCH OF SQUALLY
SITUATIONS.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
TAHOE THERE ARE CHAIN
REQUIREMENTS ON 50 AND 80.
IT IS SNOWING THERE NOW.
SAN JOSE LIGHT, GETTING BUSIER
NORTHBOUND 87 PAST HP PAVILION
AND JULIAN THINGS ARE MOVING
NICELY FROM SAN RAFAEL NORTH
PAST LUCAS VALLEY ROAD FREITAS
PARKWAY TOWARDS NORTH
SAN PEDRO THINGS GOT BUSY IN
THE LAST HALF HOUR, STILL GOOD
TO THE WALDO AND GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE, FOUR LANES FOR YOUR
SOUTHBOUND COMMUTE AND NO
DELAYS THERE.
NAPA, SILVERADO TRAIL AT
HARDMAN INJURY ACCIDENT
BLOCKING LANES, CREWS ON SCENE
CHECKING IN WITH ALL MASS
TRANSIT, ALL RUNNING ON TIME
AT THIS HOUR.
>>> 5:50.
>>> SOUTHWEST HAS A NEW FEE.
WHY YOU WANT TO MAKE SURE YOU
GET TO THE AIRPORT ON TIME.
>>> YOU MIGHT WANT TO DOUBLE
CHECK WHAT IS SITTING UNDER
THE TREE.
WE'LL TELL YOU WHY A POPULAR
TOY IS BEING RECALLED.
>>> IF'S WESTFIELD SHOPPING
CENTER WILL BE OPEN -- WILL BE
OPEN AFTER A SMALL SCARE LAST
NIGHT.
A FIRE BROKE OUT AT A ENTRANCE
ON THE 4th FLOOR.
THE RESTAURANT INSIDE THE MALL
WAS EVACUATED WHILE CREWS PUT
THE FIRE OUT.
INVESTIGATORS ARE STILL TRYING
TO DETERMINE THE EXACT CAUSE
OF THEv0 BLAZE.
>>> PROPONENTS OF NEW WOMEN'S
JAIL IN SANTA CLARA COUNTY
HAVE MORE SUPPORT FOR THEIR
POSITION.
RISING WATER LEVELS FROM LAST
WEEK'S KING TIDES DISRUPTED
OPERATIONS OVER THE WEEKEND.
THAT WOULD BE SAN MATEO COUNTY
FACILITY FOR WOMEN.
HIGH WATER LEVEL MADE ROADS UP
PASSABLE.
FOOD SERVICE AND VISITOR
PRIVILEGES WERE DISRUPTED.
IS -- SAN MATEO COUNTY
OFFICIALS ARGUE THE FACILITY
IS UNSAFE THE SHERIFF'S
DEPARTMENT IS LOBBYING THE
DEPARTMENT OF CORRECTS FOR A
NEW FACILITY.
>> AWAY FROM THE KING TIDES,
OBVIOUSLY.
>>> 5:54.
DON'T HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT THAT
TODAY.
>> A DINING ROOM SET OF
WORRIES.
>>> -- A DIFFERENT SET OF
>>> SCATTERED SHOWERS OVER THE
OCEAN PARTLY SUNNY MORE SUN
THAN YESTERDAY, COOLER LOW TO
MID 50s AROUND THE STATE A
WEALTH OF WATER AROUND
BAKERSFIELD INTO THE GRAPEVINE
SNOW IN THE SIERRA AND HIGHER
ELEVATIONS TO THE NORTH
THUNDERSTORMS TO THE WEST OF
UKIAH NOW OVER THE OCEAN WHERE
I THINK THEY WILL STAY SNOW
AROUND TAHOE 39, YOSEMITE 45.
MID TO UPPER 60s WITH RAIN IN
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
>> TOLL PLAZA, BAY BRIDGE NO
METERING LIGHTS YET, TRAFFIC
BEGINNING TO BUNCH UP FOR CASH
PAYING FOLKS, FAST TRACKERS
AND CARPOOL LANES GETTING BY,
METERING LIGHTS USUALLY
AFTER , BACK TO PALO ALTO,
WITH OUR TRAFFIC APP, SAND
HILL ROAD FLOODED BETWEEN
EL CAMINO REAL AND ARBORETUM,
STANFORD SHOPPING CENTER NO
ESTIMATED TIME OF OPENING, YOU
CAN'T SEE, BUT THIS IS YOUR
WAZE APP, I WANTED TO SHOW YOU
THE AREA WHERE THIS WAS
SHUTDOWN DOWNLOAD THIS APP, IT
IS FREE AT THE APPLE APP STORE
AND GOOGLE PLAY.
>>> 5:56.
RECALL ON FOR POPULAR GROUP OF
TOYS.
TOYS EXPAND WHEN PLACEDQ2R'
WATER.
THE TOYS ARE THE SIZE OF A
MARBLE BUT EXPAND TO 400 TIMES
ORIGINAL SIZE UNDERWATER BIG
TROUBLE IF A KID SWALLOWS ONE
LIQUIDES IN THE BODY CAN MAKE
THEM EXPAND.
A BABY HAD TO HAVE SURGERY TO
REMOVE ONE AFTER INGESTING ONE
OF THE TOYS.
>>> SOUTHWEST NO LONGER GOING
TO ALLOW PASSENGERS WHO MISS
FLIGHTS TO REBOOK FOR FREE.
THE AIRLINE PLANS TO START
CHARGING A NO-SHOW FEE FOR
PASSENGERS WHO DON'T CANCEL
BEFORE MISSING THEIR FLIGHT.
ALSO RAISE FEES TO CHECK A
THIRD BAG FROM $25 TO $75 AND
RAISE THE PRICE OF EARLY
CHECK-IN TO 12:50.
>>> CHRISTMAS -- TOUR OF THE
WHITE HOUSE, U.S. MARINE CORPS
CAPTAIN PROTESTED TO HIS
PARTNER IN WHAT IS BELIEVED TO
BE THE FIRST SAME-SEX
ENGAGEMENT CAUGHT ON CAMERA AT
THE WHITE HOUSE.
PHOTOS SHOW THE CAPTAIN ON
BENDED KNEE.
IT CAME AN INSTANT SENSATION
THOUSANDS OF LIKES ON
FACEBOOK.
>>> BREAKING NEWS FROM CONCORD,
SUSPECT CRASHES THROUGH THE
FRONT OF A STORE HAS PART OF A
DRAMATIC ROBBERY.
>>> PLUS, NEW STUDY REVEALING
THE WORLD'S LARGEST RELIGIONS,
THE ONE GROUP THAT HAS MADE
>>> GOOD-BYES CONTINUE TODAY
FOR THE VICTIMS OF THE TRAGEDY
IN CONNECTICUT.
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>>> THANKS FOR JOINING US I'M
KRISTEN SZE.
>>> I'M ERIC THOMAS THANKS FOR
JOINING US.
IF YOUR CHRISTMAS SHOPPING IS
IN YOUR PLANS TODAY, BUNDLE UP
IT IS CHILLY.
>>> TODAY, TOMORROW AND THEN
THE RAIN ROLLS IN THURSDAY