OUT TO THIS TINY COMMUNITY IN
WAYS BIG, AND SMALL.
A GLIMMER GF NEWS IN THE BAD
COMING OUT OF SANDY HOOK,
CONNECTICUT FOR THREE DAYS.
THERE WERE TWO SURVIVORS NOT
ONE AFTER THE RAMPAGE AT THE
SCHOOL FRIDAY MORNING.
THEY WERE TWO WOMEN, BOTH SHOT
IN THE LOWER EXTREMITIS.
MEANTIME, STATE POLICE SAY
THEY'LL CONTINUE THEIR
INVESTIGATION OF THE TWO CRIME
SCENES, AND TRACE ORIGINS OF
THE GUNS ADAM LANZA KILLED TO
KILL MANY.
THOUGH HE, AND OTHERS ARE
GONE.
>> WE'RE GOING TO DO
EVERYTHING THAT IT TAKES TO
ENSURE THAT WE, UNCOVER EVERY
BIT OFúW4 EVIDENCE, EVERY FACET
OF IT THAT WE CONDUCT AS MANY
INTERVIEW WAS EVERYONE WE NEED
TO DO TO PIN A CLEAR PICTURE.
>> AT THE SAME TIME A PROCESS
OF BURYING THOSE WHO DIED HAS
BEGUN, SERVICES FOR THE FIRST
GRADER JACK PINTO HELD IN
NEWTOWN.
ATTENDED BY PARENTS AND KIDS,
SOME OF THEM, THE 6-YEAR-OLD'S
BEST FRIENDS REMEMBERING HIS
LOVE OF SPORTS.
>> HE WAS JUST ENTHUSIASTIC
ABOUT PLAYING BECAUSE HE LIKES
TO DO ROUGH AND STUFF.
>> NEWTOWN IS FOREVER CHANGED.
MMATE.
BECAUSE THAT IS WHO WE ARE.
RIGHT?
WE'RE HERE FOR THE PINTOS.
>> WHILE THE MOURNERS FILED
OUT OF CHURCH, ACROSS THE
STREET, A GESTURE OF GOODWILL
FROM SOMEONE 3,000 MILES AWAY.
A FAMILY FROM LOS ANGELES
PHONED IN A CREDIT CARD NUMBER
TO THIS STORE, OFFERING TO PAYo!
FOR EVERYONE'S COFFEE, ALL
DAY.
>> SHE JUST WANTED TO OFFER
THE PEOPLE FROM THE TOWN WITH
COFFEE THAT IS HOW SHE CAN DO
IT.
>> IT'S SOMETHING SIMPLE
HELPING PEOPLE OF THE TOWN
PICK UP AND TRY TO MOVE ON.
>> THIS IS TOUCHING.
YOU KNOW.
>> AND ROADS LEADING INTO
SANDY HOOK THIS, IS A LIVE
PICTURE, THE MAIN ROAD THIS,
IS A TINY COMMUNITY.
YOU CAN SEE CARS ARE LINED UP
HERE.
IT'S COLD AND RAINY.
THAT LINE GOES BACK AT LEAST A
MILE.
LET'S SHOW YOU ACROSS THE
STREET HERE, THIS IS A HOME, A
PRIVATE HOME, THEY'VE PUT GOD
BLESS SANDY HOOK, FAITH, HOPE,
LOVE Z THEN, BEYOND THAT, UP
THE STREET, IT'S WHERE THE
SCHOOL S JUST MOMENTS AGO, WE
SAW THREE BIG MOVING VANS
COMING OUT OF THERE JUST A
MOMENT AGO.
THEY CAME OUT OF THERE AND WE
UNDERSTAND THEY'RE TAKING
FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT OUT OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY TO MOVE
TO IT ANOTHER LOCATION SO THE
KIDS CAN RESUME CLASSES,
HOPEFULLY IN THE NEAR FUTURE
THERE, IS ANOTHER SCHOOL SET
UP ABOUT SEVEN MILES FROM HERE,
ABC 7 NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> SCHOOL DISTRICTS THROUGHOUT
THE BAY AREA ARE ADDRESSING
THEIR SECURITY PLANS FOLLOWING
THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
ABC 7 NEWS CHECKED IN WITH ONE
SCHOOL DISTRICT ON THE
PENINSULA.
SHE'S LIVE WITH THE STORY.
LEANNE?lXGJ
>> WELL, CAROLYN, STATE
DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION IS
ASKING ALL SCHOOLS TO
IMMEDIATELY BEGIN REVIEWING
THEIR PLANS, NEAR MILLBRAE WE
SAW WHAT ONE RESPOND -- RESPONSE
PLAN LOOKS LIKE.
MILLBRAE SCHOOL DISTRICT HAS
FOUR ELEMENTARY, ONE MIDDLE
SCHOOL.
THEY HAVE LOCK DOWN DRILLS.
>> HOW DOES THAT GO?
DO YOU GIVE ADVICE?
>> THEY HAVE A PLAN.
WE CAN ALWAYS IMPROVE.
WE MEET AFTERWARDS AND DEBRIEF
WITH THE FIRE DEPARTMENT.
OF COURSE, WITH DRILLS THERE
IS THINGS THAT CAN BE IMPROVED
WHICH IS WHY WE DO THE DRILLS.
>> TEACHERS KNOW TO STAY
INSIDE OF THE CLASSROOM, DRAW
CURTAINS DROP TO THE FLOOR,
LIGHTS OUT NO, TALKING THE
LOCKS WERE CHANGED ABOUT A
YEAR AGO, ALLOWING TEACHERS TO
KEEP INTRUDERS OUT.
NARROW WINDOWS ON THE DOORS
ARE ALSO COVERED.
STILL, THE PRINCIPAL ADMITS
IT'S NEARLY IMPOSSIBLE TO
PREPARE FOR SOMETHING LIKE WE
SNAU NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> WE PREPARE AND DO DRILLS,
SOMETIMES, UNPREDICTABLE
THINGS HAPPEN.
WE HAVE NO CONTROL OVER IT
TODAY, TEACHERS PROVIDED
NEEDED SUPPORT FOR STUDENTS.
OVER THE WEEKEND, THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT ENCOURAGED PARENTS TO
TAKE THE LEAD.
>> SENT OUT E MAILS TALKING
ABOUT BE CAREFUL WHAT KIDS
SEE.
AND BE CAREFUL WHAT YOU SAY TO
THEM, THEY SAID MAKE SURE YOU
LISTEN TO THEM.
DISCUSS WITH THEM.
>> PARENTS TOLD THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT WILL REVIEW SECURITY
MEASURE AUTOS DO THEY NEED TO
BE MORE SECURE?
PARENTS EXPRESSED THAT AND
WE'RE LISTENING.
>> AND THE ISSUE OF SECURITY
WILL BE DISCUSSED BY THE
MILLBRAE SCHOOL BOARD OF
EDUCATION ON JANUARY 14th.
PARENTS ARE ENCOURAGED TO
ATTEND.
OR ENCOURAGED TO ATTEND.
I'M LIVE IN MILLBRAE, ABC 7
NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> THE SHOOTING PROMPTED ONE
CALIFORNIA LAWMAKER TO
REINTRODUCE A PLAN TO ENSURE
SCHOOLS MEET SAFETY STANDARDS,
LAWMAKERS ALOE INDICATED $90
MILLION A YEAR FOR
IMPROVEMENTS BUT MANY
DISTRICTS ARE SPENDING MONEY
ELSEWHERE.
A STATE SENATOR FROM TORRANCE
PLANS TO REINTRODUCE A BILL.
>> TRAGIC Z I JUST WANT TO
MAKE SURE IN CALIFORNIA, WE
TAKE WHATEVER STEPS WE CAN TO
TRY TO MITIGATE OR PREVENT A
FEW TOUR TRAGEDY.
>> HE SAYS THE LACK OF A
SECURITY PLAN IS A PROBLEM FOR
MORE THAN HALF OF CALIFORNIA
SCHOOLS.
IN 2009 HE FOUND 53% OF THE
STATE SCHOOLS DID NOT COMPLY
WITH STATE RULES.
THE CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY ALSO
PROMPTED THIS RESPONSE FROM
STATE EDUCATION OFFICIALS
SAYING CALIFORNIA SCHOOLS HAVE
BEEN ASKED TO IMMEDIATELY
BEGIN REVIEWING THEIR SAFETY
PROCEDURES AND THEY'RE DOING
SO.
THE STATEMENT CONTINUES WE'RE
ALSO PREPARED TO HEED YOUR
CALL FOR A WIDER NATIONAL
CONVERSATION ABOUT SCHOOL
SAFETY.
>> THE POST OFFICE HAS STLISHD
AN OUTLET FOR TO YOU EXPRESS
YOUR CONDOLENCES TO THE PEOPLE
OF SANDY HOOK, SETTING UP AN
ADDRESS TO SEND QLERTS CARE
PACKAGE ASKS DRAWINGS FROM
YOUR KIDS, PERHAPS.Em#Ñ
AND YOU'LL FIND THAT ADDRESS
ON OUR WEB SITE IF YOU DON'T
HAVE A PEN AT THIS MOMENT.
>> THE WEATHER IS BECOMING A
PROBLEM ONCE AGAIN IN NORTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
MUCH OFË(/HE BAY AREA GOT HIT
BY A STEADY RAIN DURING THE
HEIGHT OF THE COMMUTE HOUR.
AND HERE IS A DOWN POUR, ONE
CREW GOT CAUGHT UP IN BEFORE
THE SUN CAME UP TODAY ON THE
SUMMIT IN SANTA CRUZ
MOUNTAINS.
SANDHYA PATEL IS HERE NOW WITH
A LOCK AT LIVE DOPPLER 7.
SANDHYA?
>> IT'S QUIETER TODAY, CHECK
OUT LIVE DOPPLER 7.
WE DO HAVE A FEW SHOWERS BUT
THEY'RE MAINLY AROUND THE
MONTEREY BAY HEADING OUT
TOWARDS MORGAN HILL AND
GILROY.
LIGHT RETURNS, MOST G WET
WEATHER IS OUT OF THE BAY AREA
AND HERE IS WHAT WAS RECEIVE
FLAFTD 24 HOURS, 45/100ths IN
NAPA JUST OVER A THIRD,
43/100ths IN OAKLAND.
TAKE A LOOK AT SAN FRANCISCO.
22/100ths.
SAN JOSE, LESS, ONLY
15/100ths.
7/100ths INétLr LIVERMORE, AND
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS OVER AN
INCH OF RAIN.
AND WE HAVE RAINY DAYS COMING
YOUR WAY GETTING CLOSER TO
HOLIDAYS.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THE POTENTIAL
FOR FROST.
I'LL BE BACK WITH A COMPLETE
FORECAST COMING UP.
>> THANK YOU.
SEE YOU SHORTLY.
POLICE ASKING FOR THE PUBLIC'S
HELP IN SOLVING A MURDER IN
THE BAY VIEW DISTRICT SATURDAY
NIGHT.
THE VICTIM, A 17-YEAR-OLD
FOOTBALL PLAYER, A PROMISING
YOUNG ATHLETE.
HEATHER?
>> DAN, THERE ARE MANY
UNANSWERED QUESTIONS TONIGHT
ABOUT JUST WHAT HAPPENED IN
SAN FRANCISCO.
OVER THE WEEKEND.
AND WHY, A 17-YEAR-OLD
MONTREAL BLAKELY WAS SO FAR
FROM HOME.
HIS CLASSMATES ARE WONDERING
THAT WHILE THEY GRIEVE.
THE 17-YEAR-OLD SENIOR
MONTREAL BLAKE LAYLEE PLAYED
OFFENSE AND DEFENSE FOR THE
MINUTEMEN.
POLICE SAY HE WAS SHOT AND
KILLED IN THE CITY'S BAY VIEW
DISTRICT AROUND 10:00 SATURDAY
NIGHT.
THE SCHOOL HELD A MOMENT OF
SILENCE FOR HIM THIS MORNING.
MANY STUDENTS HEARD YESTERDAY
CAME TO SCHOOL TODAY WEARING
BLACK.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
I -- IT'S VERY TRAGIC.
I HEARD HE WAS A GREAT GUY.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO THINK.
JUST SO SAD.
>> JOE HERNANDEZ'S KIDS ARE
STILL IN MIDDLE SCHOOL.
BUT HE'S AI CONCORD HIGH GRAD,
A BIG FOOTBALL SUPPORTER.
HE CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT BLAKELY
WAS DOING IN THE BAY VIEW.
>> EVERYBODY THAT HAS
COMMENTED ABOUT HIM HAD
INDIVIDUAL, GOOD GUY. NICE
PERSON.
EVERYTHING LIKE THAT.
THIS DOESN'T SEEM TO BE PART
OF THAT FABRIC.
>> A LOT OF PEOPLE ARE POSTING
HIS PICTURESf6F) AND FROM WHATI
HEAR I WAS A GOOD PERSON.
>> PARENTS ARE WEARY OF WHAT
SEEMS LIKE UNRELENTING
VIOLENCE TARGETING YOUNG
PEOPLE.
>> THERE IS NO VALUE ONLY.
THERE JUST SCHBLT TO ME, IT
SEEMS EVERY DAY, YOU READ
ABOUT SOMETHING OR HEAR ABOUT
SOMETHING WHERE TAKING A LIVE
SEEMS TO BE THE MOST IMMEDIATE,
SIMPLE WAY TO ADDRESS A
zp
>> STUDENTS TELL TLUS IS A
VIGIL PLANNED FOR FRIDAY
EVENING ON THE FOOTBALL FIELD.
WE ASKED BOTH SCHOOL DISTRICT
AND SCHOOL FOR COMMENT.
THEY DECLINED N CONCORD ABC 7
NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> COMING UP HERE NEXT A STORY
ONLY ON ABC 7 NEWS A HOLLYWOOD
WHO DONE IT.
POLICE AND VIC LEE HAVE BEEN
PRY TRIING FOR WEEKS TO FIND
OUT WHO STOLE AN UNRELEASED
MOVIE.
>> LATER TONIGHT A CASE OF
VERY BAD TIMING.
A BAY AREA GUN STORE ABOUT TO
OPEN DOORS OVER THE OCCASION
OF THE NEIGHBORS.
>> AND, A BIT LATER A STRIFE A
BIG MOVE FOR SAN FRANCISCO
EXPLORATORIUM.
>>> A FEATURE FILM FROM
PARAMOUNT STUDIOS STOLEN FROM
A CAR IN SAN FRANCISCO, SO FAR,
POLICE HAVE BEEN UNSUCCESS
ENVELOPE LOCATING IT.
SEE ONLY ON ABC 7 NEWS.
>> WE SPOKE TO A MEMBER OF
PARAMOUNT PICTURES SECURITY
TEAM WHO IS HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO TRYING TO LOCATE THE
FILM.
HEAD NO COMMENT BUT SAID HE
WOULD PASS ALONG OUR INQUIRIES
TO THE STUDIO.
NO ONE CALL CALLED US BUT THIS
IS WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THE
THEFT.
THERE ARE A THOUSAND ITEMS
MOSTLY TAKEN FROM CAR BREAK
INS, CELL PHONES LAP TOPS AND
CAMERAS EXPENSIVE DESIGNER
GOODS.
IT'S HERE.
MOST ITEMS STOLEN AT
FISHERMAN'S WHARF IN THE
EMBARCADERO.
POLICE DID NOT FIND ONE VERY
IMPORTANT FEES OF STOLEN
PROPERTY THEY WERE LOOKING
FOR.
>> WE'RE LOOKING FOR SOME
ELECTRONIC DEVICES TAKEN IN AN
FROM THE EVENT THAT ORIGINALLY
CAUSED ALL THIS TO GO INTO
MOTION.
>> THE LIEUTENANT DID NOT TELL
US WHAT IT IS.
BUT A SOURCE WITH KNOWLEDGE OF
THE INVESTIGATION TELLS ABC 7
NEWS, EXTERNAL HARD DRIVE OF A
YET TO BE RELEASED MOVIE FROM
PARAMOUNT STUDIOS STOLEN IN
MID-NOVEMBER ABOUT A WEEK
AFTER SECURITY CAMERAS AT THE
PIER 39 GARAGE CAPTURED IMAGES
OF THE SUSPECTS BREAKING INTO
A CAR AND THEIR GET AWAY CAR'S
LICENSE PLATE.
THAT LED TO THEIR ARREST IN
LATE NOVEMBER.
THE DISCOVERY OF A HUGE HOLE
OF STOLEN GOODS.
POLICE HOPE THE FILM WOULD BE
HERE, OUR SOURCE TELLS US THE
COPY WAS STOLEN AND THE PIER
39 GARAGE BEFORE A -- FROM A
RENTAL CAR LEASED FROM SOMEONE
IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA HERE
WORKING ON THE MOVIE SOUND
TRACK.
THE MAN FILED A REPORT AT THE
POLICE SUBSTATION AT SAN
FRANCISCO INTERNATIONAL
AIRPORT BEFORE HIS FLIGHT
HOME.
POLICE HAVE BEEN WORKING AND
VISITING FLEA MARKETS AND
KNOWN FENCING AREAS AROUND THE
BAY AREA.
TRYING TO FIND THE HARD DRIVE.
ONE CONCERN IS THAT THE
POSSIBILITY THAT THE THIEVES
MAY COPY THE MOVIE.
>> PIRATING IS COMMON NOW.
PEOPLE GO ON AND CREATE A CD
OR DVD, AND SELL IT.
ON THE STREETS.
>> THIS FORMER CHIEF SAYS THE
THIEVES PROBABLY SOLD TO IT A
FENCE.
NOT KNOWING WHAT IS ON THE
HARD DRIVE.
>>.
>> PERSON PURCHASED IT
PROBABLY WIPED IT CLEAN.
IT'S MY SENSE OF WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> OUR SOURCE TELLS US CHANCES
ARE THE FENCE PROBABLY SOLTD
HARD DRIVE FOR GOING STREET
PRICE OF AROUND $30 TO $40.
THIS IS NOT THE FIRST TIME AN
UNRELEASED MOVIE HAS BEEN
STOLEN IN SAN FRANCISCO.
A SIMILAR THEFT HAPPENED YEARS
AGO WITH A MOVIE "TRANCE
FORMERS".
A POLICE FORCE TELLS US
SOMEONE STOLE A COPY THAT HAVE
MOVIE BUT POLICE MANAGED TO
GET THAT FILM BACK TO THE
STUDIO.
>> IN CUPERTINO PARENTS
DEALING WITH EMOTIONS BY THE
NEWTOWN TRAGEDY BUT STRUGGLING
WITH Am PERSONAL, UGLY ATTACK
AT ONE OF THEIR OWN SCHOOLS.
ABC 7 NEWS HAS MORE ON WHAT
HAPPENED THERE, HOW PEOPLE ARE
COPING.
>> FROM PARENTS AT LINCOLN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL THIS, IS
ANYTHING BUT A NORMAL MONDAY.
>> WE FEEL VERY DISTRESSED.
>> THE ANXIETY FROM BOTH A
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT AND
SHAKE YENSEN SENSE OF SECURITY
AT HOME, SCHOOL ADMINISTRATORS
FOUND GRAFFITI BOMB THREATS ON
THURSDAY AGAINST A TEACHER AT
MONTE VISTA HIGH.
THIS DISCOVERY SHUT DOWN THE
CAMPUS AND NEARBY LINCOLN
ELEMENTARY.
>> WE DIDN'T GET INTO DETAILS
OF WHY IT WAS SHUT DOWN.
AND PARENTS SAY IT GAVE THEM A
REASON TO SHIELD YOUNGER
CHILDREN FROM THE EVENTS IN
NEWTOWN.
>> LEADING UP TO OUR YOUNGEST
SO THIS WOULD HAVE BEEN TOO
MUCH FOR HIM.
HE WAS A LITTLE SCARED.
HE THOUGHT THERE WAS A BOMB.
>> THE SHERIFF DEPUTIES WORKED
AROUND THE CLOCK ON FRIDAY TO
MAKE AN ARREST IN THE GRAFFITI
CASE.
BEFORE THAT, PROVIDING A
TEACHER AND FAMILY WITH
PERSONAL PROTECTIONS.
>> STUDENTS SAY TEACHERSoAA!!jD
IN THE BOMB THREAT HERE
RETURNED TO CLASS TODAY.
STUDENTS SAY IT'S IMPORTANT
EVERYONE BE ABLE TO RETURN TO
A ROUTINE.
>> THE PRINCIPAL SAID DON'T
PESTER HIM.
BECAUSE HE JUST WANTS TO FEEL
NORMAL AGAIN.
>> SOME STUDENTS THINK THE
TRAGEDY CAUSES A CONFESSION
FROM THE SUSPECT IN CUPERTINO.
>> AND WE REALIZED THIS COMES
AND GOES.
AND THE 16-YEAR-OLD STUDENT IN
WILL BE PROTECTED IN THE
JUVENILE JUSTICE SYSTEM.
>>ë AND LET'S FOCUS ON THE
WEATHER.
>> YES.
SANDHYA PATEL IS IN TOO YES.
>> WE'LL FREEZE, THEN END UP
NEEDING UMBRELLAS.
WINTER ALMOST HERE, IT'S
EXPECTED.
LET ME SHOW YOU THE WAY IT
LOOKS FROM OUR CAMERA.
WE HAVE MORE RAIN COMING UP.
ACROSS THE BAY THERE, YOU CAN
SEE SAN FRANCISCO, BAY BRIDGE.
WE'RE SEEING CLEARING SKIES,
AND THAT JUST MEANS THAT IT'S
GOING TO BE A CHILLY NIGHT.
WE STILL HAVE A COUPLE SHOWERS
BEING PICKED UP DOWN TOWARDS
SOUTH BAY.
I'M GOING TO TAKE NEW FIRST
DOWN TOWARDS SOUTHERN SAN
JOSE.
WE'RE SEEING SHOWERS HEADING
OFFccuvwú['k
SO STARTING AT 7:00 P.M.
TONIGHT RAIN MOVING OUT.
BAY AREA WILL CLEAR OUT.
SO TEMPERATURES FALL.
TOMORROW, YOU CAN SEE HIT OR
MISS SHOWERS JUST SKIRTS THE
COAST.
YOU CAN SEE A SHOWER OR TWO
WHAT THIS SYSTEM IS GOING TO
PARALLEL THE COASTLINE.
THE CHANCE OF SHOWERS LIMITED
FOR YOUR TUESDAY.
TOMORROW MORNING BUNDLE UP.
IT'S GOING TO GET COLD.
34 DEGREES IN SANTA ROSA.
CHILL WILL BE IN THE AIR.
VALLEJO, CONCORD, UPPER 30s.
LOW 40s AROUND FREMONT AND SAN
JOSE.
SAN FRANCISCO, 45 DEGREES.
INTO AFTERNOON, WILL BE ON THE
COOL SIDE WITH NUMBERS INTO
LOW TO MID-50s,24&kz PARTLY CLOY
sgYY DAYS AND AROUND THE BAY
TEMPERATURES INTO LOW TO
MID-50s SO REMAINING COOLER
THAN AVERAGE.
TAKING A LOOK AT THE
ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST, FOCUS
ON SLIGHT CHANCE OF SHOWERS
TOMORROW, THE CHILL SETTLING
IN WEDNESDAY MORNING, FROSTY
COLD, YOU'LL WANT TO PROTECT
YOUR PLANTS.
COULD SEE FREEZING COLD
CONDITIONS IF THE COMPUTER
MODELS VERIFY.
OF COURSE WILL BE A DRY
WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON, ONLY TO
LEAD UP TO RAIN ON THURSDAY.
WET, WINDY FRIDAY.
THE SYSTEM COMES THROUGH HERE,
TEMPERATURES MID TO UPPER 50s
SO MORE WET WEATHER OVER THE
WEEKEND, SATURDAY, GOING INTO
SUNDAY.
AND BY CHRISTMAS EVE EVEN
CHRISTMAS DAY, LOOKING DRY.
SO GOOD FOR TRAVELING.
GOOD FOR PEOPLE GOING TO
GRANDMA'S.
>> I'M GETTING AI NEW BIKE FOR
CHRISTMAS.
>> YOU WANT TO GO RIDE IT?.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> COMING UP NEXT, ENCOURAGING
SIGNS FROM WASHINGTON WE'RE
NOT GOING OVER THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
>> POSITIVE REACTION NEWS GOT
TODAY ON WALL STREET.
STAY WITH US.
>>> WASHINGTON WILL BE ABLE TO
STEP BACK FROM THE EDGE OF
FISCAL SKPLIF REACH A DEAL TO
AVOID TAX INCREASES AND
SPENDING CUTS.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
RETURNED TO THE WHITE HOUSE
TODAY, WORD IS THAT THE TWO
INCHED TOWARDS A DEAL
FOLLOWING A NEW PROPOSAL FROM
THE PRESIDENT.
THE PLAN INCREASING THE TOP
TAX RATES ON TAX PAYERS
EARNING MORE THAN $400,000 A
YEAR.
>> TONIGHT NEW SIGNS OF
OPTIMISM ON WALL STREET.
DOW ROSE 100 POINTS TODAY,
SNAPPING A THREE DAY LOSING
STREAK.
A AND P GAINED 16 BECAUSE OF
SIGNS ON SOLVING THE DEFICIT
CRISIS.
GOOGLE STOCK WENT UP $18 A
SHARE ON REPORTS AN ANTITRUST
INVESTIGATION COULD END THIS
WEEK WITH NO MAJOR ACTION
REQUIRED.
GOOGLE HAS BEEN ACCUSED OF
GIVING LOWER RANKINGS TO
COMPETITORS MAKING IT HARDER
FOR CUSTOMERS TO FIND THEM,
APPLE SAID IT SOLD MORE THAN
TWO MILLION iPHONE 5S IN THREE
DAYS FOLLOWING IT'S RELEASE IN
CHINA.
THAT IS A A RECORD LAUNCH IN
>> WELL, STILL TO COME HERE
TONIGHT AT 6:00 A NATIONWIDE
CLAM YOER FOR STRONGER GUN
CONTROL LAWS AND A FIREARMS
INSTRUCTOR JOINS TO SAY.
>> THE NEIGHBORS WHO ARE
RAISING A RED FLAG.
>> AND MICHAEL FINNEY HELPS
PLANT A DREAUdsx
A SCHOOL HOPES TO BECOME THE
LITTLE SCHOOL THAT COULD.
STAY WITH
>>> A NEW SURVEY SHOWS GROWING
SUPPORT FOR GUN CONTROL
FOLLOWING THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
ACCORDING A POLL, 54% SUPPORT
STRICTER GUN CONTROL.
71% OPPOSE THE BAN OF HAND
GUNS BUT 52% FAVOR BANNING
SEMI AUTOMATIC WEAPONSnhXV÷ ANDD
IN THE BAY AREA GUN CONTROL
ADVOCATES POINING TO THOSE
NUMBER QUESTIONING UNIVERSAL
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
MORE ON THAT.
AND LAST NIGHT WE HEARD THE
PRESIDENT SAY NO SET OF LAWS
COULD PREVENT A MASS SHOOTING
BUT ADDED THAT COULD NOT BE AN
EXCUSE FOR DOING NOTHING.
TONIGHT THE DEBATE IS GETTING
MORE ATTENTION.
PROTESTORS DEMONSTRATED
OUTSIDE OF THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION IN WASHINGTON,
D.C. THIS MORNING AND A LONG
TIME GUN RIGHTS CONGRESSMAN
TOLD MSNBC IT'S TIME TO DO
SOMETHING.
>> I DON'T KNOW ANYONE THAT
NEEDS 30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP TO
GO HUNTING.
>> SENATOR FEINSTEIN PROMISING
TO REINTRODUCE AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN.
IT WAS IN 1993 MASS MURDER IN
A LAW OFFICE THAT LED TO THAT
LAW.
>> IT'S DARK TIME OF MY LIFE
IN 1993.
MY WIFE WAS KILLED IN 101
CALIFORNIA STREET.
>> STEVEN BECAME A GUN CONTROL
ACTIVIST TESTIFYING BEFORE
CONGRESS, STOOD WITH SENATOR
FEINSTEIN.
AND HE WATCHED 10 YEARS LATER,
CONGRESS LEFTLETT THAT LAW
EXPIRE.
>> AND SENATOR FRIST AT THE
TIME, SENATE MAJORITY LEADER
WAS BOLD ENOUGH TO SATE WAS
THE WILL OF THE PEOPLE TO LET
IT EXPIRE.
AND BOY, I WISH CONGRESS CALL
SENATOR FRIST NOW.
>> FIREARMS INSTRUCTOR SAYS
IT'S NOT THE GUNS OR CLIPS, HE
BLAMES VIOLENCE IN THE MASS
MEDIA AIMED AT CHILDREN.
PARTICULARLY VIOLENT VIDEO
GAMES.
>> THEY'RE PUSHING IT Z KIDS
ARE BEING DESENSE TIESED HE
BLAMES USE OF ANTIDEPRESSANT
DRUGS.
FDA ISSUED WARNINGS SOME DRUGS
COULD LEAD TO INCREASED
THOUGHTS OF SUICIDE AND THIS
MIND ALTERING DRUG AUTOS OUR
CALLS WENT UNANSWERED TODAY.
AT THIS CENTER TO PREVENT GUN
VIOLENCE, THE EXECUTIVE
DIRECTOR SAYS VIOLENT GAMES DO
CARRY A TROUBLING MESSAGE.
>> BLOOD SHED IS ENTERTAINING.
IT'S NOT SOMETHING WE WANT TO
PROMOTE.
>> SAYING BANNING LARGE AMMO
CLIPS AND REQUIRING BACKGROUND
CHECKS ARE PART OF A SOLUTION.
>> WE NEED A NATIONAL LEVEL
BILL THAT REQUIRES A
BACKGROUND CHECK ON EVERY
TRANSFER AND SALE OF A
FIREARM.
>> THOMAS POINTS A SURVEY
SHOWING UNIVERSAL BACKGROUND
CHECKS ARE SUPPORTED BY NEARLY
THREE QUARTERS OF NRA MEMBERS
AND I CAME ACROSS ANOTHER
SURVEY SHOWING GUN OWNERSHIP
IS DROPPING IN THE UNITED
STATES.
BUT GUN SALES ARE INCREASING.
SO FEWER PEOPLE ARE BUYING
MORE GUNS.
>> MARK, THANK YOU.
>> THOUGH IT'S NOT ON
TONIGHT'S AGENDA, LOS GATOS
TOWN COUNCIL BRACE FORWARD AN
EARFUL OF COMMENTS OVER A
CONTROVERSIAL NEW STORE SET TO
OPEN UP THIS WEEKEND.
THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT IS
ONLY INTENSIFYING THIS DEBATE.
FROM OUTSIDE, THE FRESHLY
PAINTED WALLS OF THE LOGO
DON'T TELL YOU MUCH ABOUT WHAT
IS BEING SOLD INSIDE OF THIS
STORE.
BUT NEIGHBORS DO.
>> GUNS KILL THINGS.
THAT IS WHY THE COMMUNITY, WE
WILL LIKE TO KNOW ABOUT THAT
PRODUCT BEFORE IT'S AVAILABLE
ON SHELF AUTOS DEBORAH
WINESTEIN SPOKE US-TO-US IN A
PLAYGROUND FROM WHEN THEY'RE
SET TO OPEN A GUN SHOP.
>> WE FEEL LIKE SCHOOLS AND
THE NEIGHBORHOOD SHOULD BE
NOTIFIED.
>> THE TOWN MANAGER EXPLAINED
WHY THAT WASN'T POSSIBLE.
>> THE SECTION OF THE TOWN
TODAY KOED THAT REGULATES THIS
AREA WAS AMENDMENTED IN 1987.
HE DOESN'T GIVE THE TOWN A
RESTRICTION TO HOLD A PUBLIC
HEARING ON A RETAILER THAT
WANTS TO SELL FIREARMS.
>> IN THE MEANTIME, THE SHOP
PASSED MUSTER WITH POLICE.
>> POLICE DEPARTMENT HAS DONE
TWO REVIEWS OF THEIR
MECHANISMS AND BELIEVES THAT
THEY'RE GOING ABOVE AND BEYOND
WHAT IS REQUIRE BID FEDERAL
LAW.
>> I THINK ANY TIME YOU CAN
BRING BUSINESS TO TOWN IT'S A
POSITIVE THING.
I DON'T THINK THEY'RE GOING
HAND OUT GUNS LIKE CANDY.
>> AND HE ASSURES PARENTS
BUT IN LIGHT OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY, SHE SAYS SHE WISHES
NEIGHBORS HAD BEEN GIVEN MORE
INPUT.
>> CLEARLY AFTER CONNECTICUT
WE CAN SEE THAT FIREARMS ARE
COMMUNITY ISSUE.
>> WHETHER OR NOT THE
NEIGHBORS FIND CAUSE FOR
CELEBRATION, THEY'RE SET TO
CELEBRATE THE GRAND OPENING ON
SATURDAY.
>> FORMER HAWAII SENATOR IS
BEING REMEMBERED AS A
DEDICATED LAWMAKER FORMER THAN
50 YEARS.
HE DIED IN A WASHINGTON, D.C.
HOSPITAL TODAY AT AGE 88.
HE WAS A SOLDIER IN WORLD WAR
II AND FIRST ELECTED TO
CONGRESS IN 1959, THE YEAR
HAWAII BECAME A STATE.
HIS 50 YEARS IN THE SENATE IS
THE LONGEST TENURE IN U.S.
HISTORY.
STAY WITH US.
WE'LL BE BACK.
>>> ALAMO ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
HOPING TO BE THE LITTLE SCHOOL
THAT COULD.
>> THE SCHOOL IS ATTEMPTING TO
WIN A NATION WRAL GRANT AND
THEY TURNED TO MICHAEL FINNEY
FOR HELP.
>> OUR APOLOGIES WE DON'T HAVE
THE AUDIO FOR THAT PIECE.
BUT WE'LL WORK ON THAT AND
HOPE TO BRING IT TO YOU
SHORTLY.
>> AND LET'S PRESS ON.
COMING UP NEXT, A BILLING MOVE
FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO
EXPLORATORIUM.
>> THEY'RE PACKING UP THE PAST,
AS THEY PREPARE FOR THE
FUTURE.
>>> COUNTDOWN IS ON.
TWO AND A HALF WEEKS UNTIL WE
SAY GOODBYE TO THE
EXPLORATORIUM AS WE KNOW IT.
THE MUSEUM WILL REOPEN IN THE
SPRING AT A NEW HOME.
AND TONIGHT, THE STAFF RACES
NOW TO PREPARE FOR THE FUTURE
IT'S STILL HARD TO TELL THESE
ARE THE FINAL DAYS OF THE THIS
PLACE.
EXPLORATORIUM OPENED IN 1969.
A FIRST OF ITS KIND MUSEUM
WITH INTERACTIVE EXHIBITS
MAKING SCIENCE FUN.
A MEMORY WALL SUP NOW WHERE
STAFF AND VISITORS ARE SHARING
THOUGHTS.
ONE VISITOR CAME TO TAKE A
LOOK IS BRIAN MATTHEWS.
>> MADE A BIG IMPRESSION ON
ANY MI CHILDHOOD.
I WANTED TO SAVE IT FOR THE
FUTURE.
>> BRIAN IS AN ENGINEER WITH
AUTO DESK AND AN EXPERT IN
WHAT IS KNOWN AS REALITY
CAPTURE, HE DECIDED HE SHOULD
BE DOING IT HERE.
>> I CALLED UP OUR FRIENDS AND
LIKE ANY OTHER EXPERIMENT THEY
WERE GAME.
>> HE GOT OTHER VOLUNTEERS
WORKING AS FAST AS THEY CAN TO
MAKE A 3 D RECORD OF THE
BUILDING AND EXHIBIT.
THEY'RE USING NEW TECHNOLOGIES
INCLUDING ONE STARTING WITH
PHOTOS FROM A STILL CAMERA.
>> THIS ISk0XcÑ CALLED PHOTO
GRAMITRY.
>> A SOFTWARE PROGRAM PUTS
THEM TOGETHER INTO THIS
INCREDIBLE IMAGE.
>> THAT SOFTWARE CAN ANALYZE
TWO DEMENTIONAL PICTURES AND
MAKE A 3 D MODEL.
>> THEY'RE USING LASER
SCANNERS STARTING IN THE
MACHINE SHOP.
AGAIN, A SOFTWARE PROGRAM
ANALYZING MILLIONS OF DATA
POINTS FROM LASERS COMBINING
THEM.
RESULT IS AN IMAGE SO DETAILED
KOIT BE USED TO CREATE A
REPLICA OF THE SPACE, AND
EVERYTHING IN IT.
THE MAKERS ARE THRILLED TO GET
THIS DATA NOW.
THEY NORT SURE HOW THEY'RE
r WHAT WE'LO
WITH THAT IS WHAT WE'LL DO.
WE'LL HAVE FORTUNATELY, YOU
KNOW, YEARS TO FIGURE THAT
OUT.
>> THEY'RE ALSO SORTING,
CLEANING AND PACKING AND
PUZZLING OVER THE 43 YEARS OF
ACCUMULATED STUFF BEHIND THE
>> THIS ONE IS A SIX FOOT
LENS.
>> FIRST, THEY'LL HAVE TO
FIGURE OUT WHAT THEY HAVE.
NEXT, THEY DECIDE WHAT MAKES
THE CUT.
WHATEVER THEY DO KEEP WILL
COME HERE.
AFTER TWO YEARS OF TOP TO
BOTTOM RENOVATIONS, HUGE
UNDERTAKING THIS WILL BE THE
NEW HOME.
100 ZEBRA FISH AND SPIKEY SEA
YOU ARE CHINZ MAKE THE MOVE
OUT OF A CRAMPED BACK ROOM IN
THE OLD BUILDING INTO THE NEW
HIGH TECH LIFE SCIENCES LAB.
THE YOU ARE CHINZ START
EXPLORING.
YOU CAN SEE THEM MOVING THEIR
ARMS TO CHECK OUT THEIR
SURROUNDINGS.
SEE THEM?
ONE JOB IS PRODUCE MATERIAL
FOR AN EXHIBIT ON
REPRODUCTION.
AND THE MOVE.
IT SEEMS TO HAVE PUT THEM TO
WORK.
>> THEY'RE SPAWNING.
>> YES.
THAT IS ALL SPERM AND EGGS.
>> IT'S EXCITING WORK GOING ON
NOW.
IN THIS LAST FEW MONTHS.
EXPLORATORIUM OPENS THROUGH
JANUARY 2 WHEN ADD MILGS MIGS
WILL BE FREE.
THEY'LL HAVE SMALL EXHIBITS
POPPING UP AROUND SAN
OPENS IN APRIL.
YOU KNOW, I'VE BEEN IN THAT
BUILDING MANY TIMES.
IT'S GOING TO BE IMPRESSIVE IT
WILL BE.
>> AS REFLECTING ON THE HORROR
IN NEWTOWN ASK RENEW GUN
DEBATE ONE ARTIST HAS BEEN
CREATING SCULPTURES MADE OUT
HERE IS DON SANCHEZ.
>> IS THE BELL TOLLING?
IS IT A CALL FOR CHANGE?
>> HAVE YOU TO FIND A WAY TO
TOLERATE EACH OTHER.
>> AND THIS IS GAIN ADD CLAIM
IN ROME IN 2000.
THAT IS A PEACE BELL RINGING
IN AN INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE,
THESE BELLS MADE HAVE GUNS,
RIFLES, WEAPONS HAVE BEEN
MELTED DOWN.
CAST IN BRONZE.
IT'S A STATEMENT ABOUT HOW
THEY AFFECT THE FABRIC OF OUR
SOCIETY.
HE SAYS.
>> AND THE ABUNDANCE OF
WEAPONS THAT COUNTRIES HAVE.
>> IN THIS CASE, WE'VE LEFT
THE BARREL STICKING OUT.
>> I'VE CAST THE BARRELS INTO
IT.
THESE WERE GUN BAIRLZ I PUT
INTO THE PIECE.
>> HE CREATES THESE PIECES
WORKING IN PLAY, WAXED BEFORE
THE BRONZE IS POURED.
SCULPT LG IS INSPIRATION.
>> I FOUND CASTING GAVE ME
MORE FREEDOM TO EXAGGERATE THE
FORMS AND HE CREATES FORMS OF
ENVIRONMENTAL ART.
>> THESE ARE BRANCHES
BRANCHES.
>> THE NEXT SERIES WILL BE
WALKING FIGURES.
SURROUNDED BY LEAF LEAVES AND
OTHER PARTS OF NATURE, IT'S
ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE.
THE FIGURES WILL BE SEVEN FEET
TALL, AND WILL BE IN GALLERIES
AND MUSEUMS.
BUT THIS MAY TAKE TIME.
HE'S ON DEADLINE TO CREATE
WORKS FOR COLLECTORS IN EUROPE
AND SAN FRANCISCO.
>> CALIFORNIA TODAY HONORED 30
SACRIFICE IN THE LINE OF DUTY.
FLAGS FLEW AT HALF STAFF OVER
THE STATE CAPITOL DURING
CEREMONIES INCLUDED CALLING
FAMILY AND FRIENDS FOR FALLEN
OFFICERS.
CALIFORNIA PEACE OFFICER'S
MEMORIAL FOUNDATION USED THIS
TRIBUTE TO URGE CALIFORNIANS
TO BECOME ORGAN DONORS.
FRIENDS AND FAMILY WILL BE
NAMES ARE IN VIAL AUTOS FIRE
OFFICIALS PUT OUT LIST OF HILD
HOLLIDAY DOS AND DON'TS.
DON'T FORGET TO WATER THE
CHRISTMAS TREE.
TODAY THEY LIT A TREE TO SEE
HOW QUICKLY IT COULD BURST
INTO FLAMES.
OFFICIALS HELD A SHOW AND
TELL.
AND CANDLE NEXT TO A DRAPE
TURNED THIS ROOM INTO AN
INFERNO.
ABOUT 400 PEOPLE DIED EACH
YEAR IN THE UNITED STATES
BECAUSE OF HOLIDAY RELATED
FIRE AUTOS TAHOE SKI RESORTS
GETTING READY FOR A WHITE
CHRISTMAS THIS YEAR.
WITH THE FIRST SNOW FALLING
BEFORE THANKSGIVING THE
NATURAL BASE IS BETTER THAN IN
PAST YEARS.
SKI OPERATIONS ABLE TO OPEN
MORE RUNS THIS HOLIDAY SEASON,
AND THEY EXPECT MORE SNOW TO
MAKE THIS ONE OF THE BEST SKI
SEASONS IN A DECADE.
FORECASTERS ARE SAYING TWO
MORE STORMS ARE ON THE WAY.
THAT SHOULD DUMP MORE SNOW ON
TAHOE BEFORE THE WEEKEND.
>> THEY SURE DESERVE IT.
>> LET'S CHECK IN NOW WITH
SANDHYA PATEL.
>> THEY HAVE RECEIVED FROM TWO
TO 12 INCHES OF SNOW.
WITH THIS SYSTEM.
AND STATE WIDE, SNOW PACK
RUNNING 90% OF AVERAGE, THERE
YOU GO.
JUST AN ISOLATED SHOWER, AND
THAT MOVED OFF TO THE EAST OF
SAN JOSE AND HILLS THERE.
AND IT'S ALL WINDING DOWN
TOMORROW, WE'RE GOING TO KEEP
IN SNOW SHOWER POSSIBLE.
WARNING FOR MORNING.
47 IN YOSEMITE.
TAHOE, MORE SNOW COMING.
24 BY AFTERNOON.
LOW 60s WITH RAIN POSSIBILITY
FOR TUESDAY.
HERE IN THE BAY AREA, CARRY
YOUR UMBRELLAS.
IT'S JUST A SLIGHT CHANCE OF
SHOWERS AS THE SYSTEM SKIRTS
THE COAST REMAINING COOL SO A
SWEATER OR JACKET.
MID 40S TO 50s UNDER PARTLY
CLOUDY SKIES.
HERE IS THE ACCU-WEATHER
FORECAST.
FROSTY COLD, WEDNESDAY MORNING
COULD SEE MID TOPYKYó8pm.ñ UPPEs
INTO COLDEST INLAND VALLEYS.
SO MORE SYSTEMS WILL NEED
UMBRELLAS REST OF THE WEEK.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> HON TO LARRY BEIL.
>> OUR MICS COMING ON IN JUST
A MOMENT.
49er LOOK BACK ON A STATEMENT
WIN IN NEW ENGLAND.
WHO EXPECTED THIS?
FROM
>>> GOOD EVENING, SO MUCH FROM
LAST NIGHT'S 49ers WIN IS HARD
TO KNOW WHERE IT STARTS.
WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT THE WORDS
COLLIN CAPPERNICK OUTDUALS?
WHO COULD HAVE ENVISIONED
THIS?
ONLY THE FIFTH START IN
MISERABLE CONDITIONS ON THE
ROAD.
HIS FIFTH START AGAINST THE
TEAM THAT NEVER LOSES AT HOME
IN DECEMBER.
FOUR TOUCHDOWN PASSES THEN
HAVE YOU 49ers FACED WITH
ADVERSITY.
BLOWING A 28 POINT LEAD.
A WIN IN SEATTLE NEXT SUNDAY
WOULD CLENCH THE NFC WEST FOR
THE NINERS.
>> FOR TWO AND A HALF QUARTERS
OF FOOTBALL, WHATEVER WORD YOU
WANT TO USE IT WAS PRETTY DARN
GOOD DEFENSIVELY FOR US.
AND THEN, LAST FIVE MINUTES OF
THE GAME, LAST TWO STOPS, TWO
POINT QUARTER STOPS.
>> I KNOW WE TALK ABOUT THAT A
LOT.
BUT YOU KNOW COME BACK TO GET
THOSE TWO STOPS AT THE END.
>> REALLY MAKES YOU FEEL GOOD.
>> REALLY GOOD.
RAIDERS SNAPPED A SIX-GAME
LOSING STREAK POSTING A SHUT
DOWN IN BEATING CHIEFS.;-9yy
SILL SKPRER BLACK DEFENSE
WHICH STRUGGLED AGAINST GOOD
TEAMS DOMINATED A POOR CHIEFS
SQUAD.
>> TOUGH TO SHUT ANYONE OUT IN
THIS LEAGUE TO BE ABLE TO DO
THAT FIRST TIME IT'S BEEN DONE
IN THIS ORGANIZATION.
IN 10 YEARS.
I THINK THAT WAS CRITICAL FOR
OUR DEFENSE.
IT'S A GOOD CONFIDENCE BUILDER,
WE'VE GOT TO CONTINUE TO BUILD
ON THAT.
>> SPEAKING OF WHICH SAN JOSE
STATE, THEY'RE GOING TO KEEP
BUILDING WITH A NEW FOOTBALL
COACH.
HE REPLACED JIM HARBAUGH SIX
YEARS AGO.
THE 45-YEAR-OLD NATIVE WENT TO
HIGH SCHOOL WITH BELLERMAN
POSTED A RECORD AT THE
UNIVERSITY OF SAN DIEGO.
REPLACING MIKE McENTIRE BUILT
SPARTANS INTO A BOLD TEAM IN
JUST THREE YEARS BEFORE
HEADING TO COLORADO.
>> TO BE A PART OF THIS
PROGRAM, I KNOW THERE HAS BEEN
UPS AND DOWNS OVER THE YEARS
BUT MAYBE I CAN COME IN TO
BRING CONSISTENCY AND KEEP IT
YOU KNOW JUST BUILD OFF WHAT
THE COACH DID HERE, AND KEEP
IT AT A HIGH LEVEL.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO THAT
OPPORTUNITY.
I EMBRACE THAT CHALLENGE.
>> UC DAVIS ANNOUNCED FORMER
CAL RUNNING BACK COORDINATOR
RON GOULD WILL TAKE THE HELM
NEXT SEASON.
A'S SWRIL A NEW FACE NEXT YEAR,
STEVEN DREW REPORTEDLY SIGNED
A DEAL WITH THE RED SOX.
IN 39 GAMES HAD FIVE HOMERS
AND DROVE IN 16.
SIGNING OF A NEW SHORT STOP
FROM JAPAN.
SO WE'LL SFEE THAT IS COMING
UP TOMORROW, THIS SPORTS
REPORT BROUGHT TO YOU BY
MERCEDES-BENZ.
>> FUN GAME.
>> YES.
HE WAS.
>> WHAT A GAME.
>> POSSIBLE.
>> THEY BEAT SEE. NO WORD YET
ON9w JUSTIN SMITH WHO INJURED
HIS ELBOW"u;ñ.
>> CABLE CHANNEL 13, COMING UP,
ENGINEERS TAKE TECHNOLOGY BACK
TO THE BASICS.
THE TOOL HELPING MILLIONS OF
PEOPLE FEEL THEIR FUTURE.
>> THEN AT 11:00 WHY RENEWED
CALLS FOR STRICTER GUN CONTROL
FOLLOWING CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
SHOOTING COULD EXPLAIN A SURGE
IN GUN SALES HERE IN THE BAY
AREA.
IT'S COMING UP AT 9:00 AND
11:00 ON ABC 7 NEWS.
>> WHAT IS THIS EDITION OF ABC
7 NEWS HERE AT 6:00.
>> FROM THE ENTIRE ABC 7 NEWS
TEAM, THANKS FOR JOINING US.
>> WE APPRECIATE YOUR TIME.
HOPE TO SEE YOU AT 9:00 AND
11:00.
BLP
THIS IS "JEOPA
PLEASE WELCOME
TODAY'S CONTESTANTS --
A CLOTHING SALES ASSOCIATE
FROM VALRICO, FLORIDA...
...AN OPERATIONS COORDINATOR
FROM BRISTOL, PENNSYLVANIA...
...AND OUR
RETURNING CHAMPION --
A COMPUTER-CHIP DESIGNER
FROM BERLIN, MASSACHUSETTS...
AND NOW HERE IS
THE HOST OF "JEOPARDY!" --
ALEX TREBEK!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THANK YOU, JOHNNY.
OH, THANK YOU.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
IN EACH APPEARANCE,
OUR CHAMPION, ALISTAIR,
SEEMS TO BE
GETTING BETTER AND BETTER,
A LITTLE MORE COMFORTABLE,
PERHAPS.
SO THAT DOESN'T AUGUR WELL
FOR SUSAN OR THERESA,
BUT THEY WOULDN'T BE HERE
IF THEY HADN'T PASSED
THE "JEOPARDY!" TEST,
LET'S SEE
HOW THIS GAME TURNS OUT.
HERE ARE THE CATEGORIES
FOR THE FIRST ROUND.
HEY, IT'S THAT TIME OF THE YEAR,
ISN'T IT?