GOO GOO.
>> THIS IS THE MOMENT I'VE BEEN
WAITING FOR.
>> Announcer: WHILE MARIO
ANSWERS HIS SWEET TOOTH CRAVING
WITH A HONEY GOLDEN TREAT.
PLUS --
CAN YOU REALLY MAKE A CAKE IN
THE MICROWAVE?
TALK ABOUT EASY BAKE.
EVEN SPECIAL GUEST
SOLEIL MOON FRYE IS SMITTEN WITH
SOME HOLIDAY MITTEN COOKIES.
AND IT ALL STARTS RIGHT NOW, ON
"THE CHEW."
♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> GOOD AFTERNOON, AND WELCOME
TO "THE CHEW."
CHRISTMAS IS JUST EIGHT DAYS
AWAY, AND YOU CAN'T HAVE A
HOLIDAY DINNER WITHOUT DESSERT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
IT'S A WILD CROWD TODAY.
ALL HOUR LONG WE'RE HAVING
OURSELVES A SWEET CHRISTMAS.
AND IF BAKING ISN'T YOUR THING,
WORRY NOT.
LATER IN THE SHOW, WE'RE GONNA
SHOW YOU HOW TO MAKE A DESSERT
IN JUST THREE MINUTES.
FOLKS, THIS IS A SHOW YOU'LL NOT
WANT TO MISS.
NOW, YOU MIGHT BE THINKING TO
YOURSELF, "WHY ON EARTH IS STYLE
GURU CLINTON KELLY WEARING THE
UGLIEST SWEATER I'VE EVER SEEN?
WELL, IT'S NOT JUST ME PEOPLE.
WE'RE HAVING AN UGLY SWEATER
PARTY!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> I'M CERTAIN THAT YOU HAD A
LITTLE "CRAFT CORNER" AT HOME,
AND CONSTRUCTED YOUR SWEATER
YOURSELF.
>> I CAN SWEAR TO YOU THAT I DID
NOT MAKE THIS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> OH, YES YOU DID.
>> -- UGLY, THOUGH.
>> YOU DON'T THINK IT'S THAT
UGLY?
>> UGLY FOR YOU.
>> OH NO, IT'S UGLY.
>> IT'S PRETTY UGLY.
I JUST WISH HE WAS SMOKING A
CIGARETTE.
I THINK THAT WOULD BE FUNNY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> OUT OF YOUR BELLY BUTTON.
>> I LIKE YOU, YOU'RE BATTERY
OPERATED AS ARE YOU.
>> YEAH, I GOT TREATS IN HERE,
TOO.
>> I KEPT THE TAG ON MINE.
>> KEPT THE TAG.
>> BECAUSE --
>> HOW MUCH WAS IT?
>> $375.
>> NO.
>> GET OUT.
>> CAN I JUST SAY --
>> ARE YOU SERIOUS?
>> YOU GUYS KNOW I'M
COMPETITIVE.
>> WE KNOW.
>> IF EVER THERE HAS BEEN A
CHANCE FOR ME TO WIN, THIS WOULD
BE THE DAY.
>> WOW.
[ CHEERS ]
>> WAIT.
WE SHOWED MODERATION ON THE
FRONT.
THERE'S ONLY LIGHTING ON THIS
SIDE.
>> I'M SORRY.
>> WHAT THE HECK IS GOING ON
BACK HERE?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> YOU, LISTEN, THIS BIT HERE.
>> I HAVE AN UGLY ASS.
UGH!
ALSO, BY THE WAY, I CAN'T SIT
DOWN BECAUSE THERE'S BATTERIES
UNDER MY BUTT.
I LITERALLY --
[ LAUGHTER ]
I'M STANDING THIS WHOLE TIME.
I FEEL --
>> I LOVE YOUR HIP.
>> YOU GUYS ARE ALL HYPED UP.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WOW.
>> IT'S A SUGAR SHOW, CLINTON.
SO WHENEVER THERE'S A SUGAR
SHOW, THINGS GO A LITTLE AWRY.
>> LET'S SIMMER DOWN.
LET'S START OFF THE SHOW WITH A
HOLIDAY "HOT PLATE TOPIC."
[ AUDIENCE OOHS ]
ALL RIGHT, I THINK IS A REALLY
GOOD ONE.
OKAY, IF I DO SAY SO MYSELF.
13-YEAR-OLD McKENNA POPE FROM
NEW JERSEY HAS STARTED A
PETITION ASKING THE MAKERS OF
THE EASY BAKE OVEN TO INCLUDE
BOYS ON THE PACKAGING, BECAUSE
McKENNA'S 4-YEAR-OLD BROTHER
GAVIN WANTS AN "EASY BAKE OVEN"
FOR CHRISTMAS BUT HE THINKS THE
GIFT IS TOO GIRLY.
OKAY?
AFTER ALL, THEIR ADS FEATURE
ONLY PINK AND PURPLE COLORS AND
THERE ARE ONLY GIRLS IN THE
COMMERCIALS.
SO, HOW DO WE FEEL ABOUT THIS
CONSIDERING THAT THERE ARE MANY
GREAT CHEFS AND EVEN PASTRY
CHEFS WHO ARE MALES?
WHAT DO WE DO?
>> I LOVE IT.
>> I THINK THIS IS A LEGIT
COMPLAINT.
>> YEAH.
>> I MEAN, YOU KNOW WHEN I WAS
GROWING UP, CHEFS CERTAINLY
WEREN'T ON TV THAT OFTEN AND YOU
DIDN'T KNOW HOW MANY MEN WERE
CHEFS.
YOU KNOW, IN THE CULINARY WORLD
PROBABLY ABOUT 70% OF CHEFS ARE
MEN.
AND THERE'S A LOT OF YOUNG
ASPIRING CHEFS OUT THERE.
SO, I THINK EASY BAKE'S GOTTA
STEP UP.
THEY GOTTA HOT ROD THAT THING
OUT.
MAYBE GIVE THE KIDS A LITTLE
KIT.
>> I THINK A STAINLESS STEEL
MODEL.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> I JUST THINK NON-GENDER
SPECIFIC THINGS PERIOD.
YOU KNOW?
>> I COMPLETELY AGREE WITH YOU.
>> NONE OF THIS BLUE STUFF, NONE
OF THIS CUTE STUFF, NONE OF THIS
G.I. JOES.
I MEAN, THIS IS A NON-GENDER.
>> WHEN YOU SAY NO G.I. JOES,
YOU MARKET TO --
>> WELL -- G.I. JOES.
THEY ARE GIRLS WHO MAY LIKE G.I.
JOES.
>> I AGREE.
THERE SHOULD BE BOYS AND GIRLS
ON PACKAGING FOR THIS STUFF.
>> YEAH.
>> 'CAUSE THIS IS A GREAT WAY TO
SCREW A KID UP LATER IN LIFE.
>> YEAH, EXACTLY.
>> "OH LIKE I THIS, I LIKE TO DO
THINGS THAT ARE CREATIVE.
OH, BUT SOCIETY'S TELLING ME
THAT'S THAT ONLY FOR GIRLS."
>> EXACTLY RIGHT.
>> BUT I ALSO THINK --
I GUESS I DON'T FIND IT WRONG
THAT'S THERE'S BOYS AND GIRLS
VERSIONS OF AN "EASY BAKE OVEN."
I JUST WISH THAT IT WAS MARKETED
TOWARDS BOTH OF THEM.
AND MAYBE THEY COULD, MAYBE
THEY --
WHATEVER THE EASY BAKE OVEN
COMES WITH, IT GIVES THEM THE
ABILITY TO CUSTOMIZE IT TO THEIR
TASTE.
>> HERE WE GO.
>> STAINLESS.
>> YEAH, STAINLESS.
STAINLESS APPLIANCES ARE IN
RIGHT NOW.
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> VERY HOT.
>> GOOD IDEA.
OKAY, STAINLESS.
TAKE THAT, EASY BAKE OVEN!
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, YOU KNOW WHO MAKES
CHRISTMAS SUPER SWEET FOR ME?
RANDY THE REINDEER!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> THE UGLY SWEATER.
>> THE UGLY SWEATER'S WEIGHING
HIM DOWN.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> RANDY, ALMOST BROKE THE PLATE
HE LANDED ON.
>> RANDY, YOU SCARED THE HELL
OUT OF ME, MAN!
>> LIKE, LISTEN IF HE WAS SO --
>> BUT HE LANDED PERFECTLY.
>> -- CUTE AND CUDDLY.
>> AWE.
>> CUTE.
>> HE MATCHES YOU, DAPHNE.
>> I KNOW.
BUT HIS IS WAY CUTER.
>> RANDY, I HAVE A QUESTION FOR
YOU.
>> I'LL TELL YOU, I HAVE GOTTEN
WISER.
I'VE MOVED MY COFFEE TO A
NON-RANDY LANDING ZONE.
GET OUT.
[ BELLS JINGLING ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> UH.
>> MAN, IF I HAD A HEART ATTACK
AND DIED IN THIS SWEATER, IT
WOULD BE A BAD WEEK.
>> IT WOULD BE A TERRIBLE WEEK,
RIGHT?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> IT'D BE GREAT TV, SYMON.
>> KENNY FROM CHARLESTON ASKS --
"I'M DRIVING TWO HOURS AWAY FOR
CHRISTMAS EVE AT MY SISTER'S
PLACE.
I NEED A DELICIOUS DESSERT THAT
TRAVELS WELL.
CAN YOU HELP A BROTHER OUT?"
>> DUDE, I'M YOUR SISTA.
[ LAUGHTER ]
I CAN HELP YOU OUT.
AND I'M A RECOVERING CATERER.
BEEN 1,078 DAYS SINCE MY LAST
JOB, BUT I STILL REMEMBER SOME
TIPS.
FIRST OF ALL, NOTHING FROSTED,
NOTING LAYERED, NOTHING COLD,
NOTHING THAT HAS TO STAY IN ICE.
>> MM-HMM.
>> POUND CAKES, PIES, CRISPS,
BREAD PUDDING.
ANYTHING LIKE THAT, THAT IS NOT
GOING TO SLIDE.
COOKIES THAT, YOU KNOW, PEOPLE
WHO HAVE THE COOKIE EXCHANGE --
STAY AWAY FROM THE COOKIES.
YOU KNOW, STUFF LIKE THAT.
RIGHT?
>> AND NOTHING THAT MATTERS,
REALLY, I GUESS, IF IT'S HOT OR
COLD?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
ABSOLUTELY.
>> DON'T BRING A FROZEN ICE
CREAM CAKE.
>> YEAH, NOTHING THAT HAS TO
STAY FROZEN OR HOT.
>> RIGHT.
BUT YOU COULD MAKE THINGS THAT
YOU'RE MAKING A LITTLE BIT
LATER.
WHAT ARE THOSE THINGS CALLED
AGAIN?
>> STRUFFOLI.
THOSE LITTLE ITALIAN --
>> REALLY MICHAEL, THE PERFECT
ONE TO BRING AROUND.
>> YES.
>> ALL RIGHT, WE HAVE SOME TIME
FOR A LITTLE GAME.
WANNA PLAY "DUDE OR DESSERT?"
[ CHEERS ]
>> Announcer: "DUDE OR DESSERT?"
>> OKAY.
SOME DESSERT NAMES SOUND LIKE
PEOPLE, SOME PEOPLE SOUND LIKE
DESSERTS.
SO, WE'RE GONNA PLAY "DUDE OR
DESSERT?"
ALL RIGHT, I'M GONNA NAME A
NAME.
YOU TELL ME IF IT'S A PERSON OR
A DESSERT.
A DUDE OR A DESSERT.
NORMAN TART --
NORMAN TART.
IS IT A MAN OR A DESSERT?
80% OF YOU SAY MAN IT LOOKS
LIKE.
IT IS A DESSERT.
[ CHEERS ]
THE NORMAN TART IS A VARIATION
OF THE APPLE TART MADE IN
NORMANDY.
THERE IT IS, RIGHT THERE.
FILLED WITH APPLES, SLICED
ALMONDS, AND TOPPED WITH CREAMY
EGG CUSTARD.
ALL RIGHT, NEXT --
THE WILD SAMOANS.
>> OH.
>> ARE THESE CRAZY, SCARY DUDES
OR CRAZY GOOD DESSERT?
UM, ABOUT A 60-40 FAVORITE FOR
DUDES.
>> OH, COME ON.
>> THEY ARE DUDES, OF COURSE.
>> WHAT?
>> NOT TO BE CONFUSED WITH
SAMOAS.
>> WHAT?
>> CAPTAIN LOU ALBANO.
>> THE TAG TEAM DUO OF AFA AND
SIKA --
>> YOU GOT IT RIGHT.
>> RIGHT.
THANKS --
-- WERE CHAMPIONS IN THE '80s.
OKAY.
>> THEY WERE COUSINS WITH JIMMY
"SUPERFLY" SNUKA.
DUDE, JUST IN CASE ANYBODY'S
WONDERING.
>> HOW DO YOU KNOW --
WHO ARE YOU?
>> HOW ABOUT ONE MORE?
I'M GONNA NAME A NAME.
PASCAL LECLAIRE --
IS THAT A CANADIAN DUDE OR A
CANADIAN DESSERT?
UM, MOST OF YOU SAY DUDE.
I'M GONNA SAY 60% OF YOU SAY
DUDE.
THAT IS IN FACT A DUDE.
[ CHEERS ]
HE IS A RETIRED PROFESSIONAL
HOCKEY GOALIE THAT PLAYED FOR
THE OTTAWA SENATORS.
OKAY, THERE HE IS.
HANDSOME FELLOW.
OKAY, WHO'S GOT "THE DISH OF THE
DAY?"
[ CHEERS ]
>> STRUFFOLI!
IT'S COMING UP NEXT, DON'T GO
AWAY!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Announcer: COMING UP --
HONEY-GLAZED FRITTERS,
CHOCOLATE-COATED CLUSTERS,
SUGARY SWEET COOKIES, AND A CAKE
YOU CAN BAKE, IN A MUG?
OH YEAH, WE'RE JUST GETTING
STARTED, WHEN "THE CHEW'S"
"SWEET CHRISTMAS" RETURNS IN A
MOMENT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
HEIR PRO.
BUT SC Johnson
ISN'T JUST A COMPANY.
WE'RE A FAMILY
WHO CARES ABOUT YOURS.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE WORKING
TO SHARE ALL OF OUR INGREDIENTS,
RIGHT DOWN TO THE FRAGRANCES
AND DYES.
SO WITH PRODUCTS LIKE Windex,
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE BRINGING
INTO YOUR HOME.
GOING BEYOND
THE INDUSTRY STANDARD --
THAT'S THE FAMILY STANDARD.
♪
♪ BUT THE FIRE IS
SO DELIGHTFUL ♪
NOTHING MELTS AWAY THE COLD
LIKE A HOT, DELICIOUS BOWL
OF CHICKEN NOODLE SOUP
FROM CAMPBELL'S.
♪ LET IT SNOW, LET IT SNOW
[ Female Announcer ]
Almost nothing can dampen
a baby's mood,
when he wakes up dry
in Pampers.
Unlike other diapers,
Pampers has 3 absorbent layers,
for up to 12 hours
of protection overnight,
and more beautiful mornings.
♪
Pampers. Peaceful Nights.
Playful Days.
♪
ONE SQUARE INCH OF
DELICIOUSLY SMOOTH CHOCOLATE
IN CREAMY MILK...
OR RICH DARK.
INCREDIBLE INDULGENCE.
ONE SQUARE INCH OF BLISS.
HERSHEY'S BLISS.
MAYBMAYBE YOU CAN'T.RE;
WHEN YOU HAVE MIGRAINES
WITH FIFTEEN OR MORE
HEADACHE DAYS A MONTH,
YOU MISS OUT ON YOUR LIFE.
YOU MAY HAVE CHRONIC MIGRAINE.
GO TO MYCHRONICMIGRAINE.COM
TO FIND A HEADACHE
SPECIALIST.
AND DON'T LIVE
A MAYBE LIFE.
BAG MY BUSINESS AND BURY IT
IN THE TRASH ANYMORE.
GOOD, THAT WAS AWFUL.
[ Female Announcer ]
INTRODUCING LITTER GENIE.
EASY LITTER DISPOSAL.
SIMPLY SCOOP, DROP
AND HELP LOCK IN ODORS.
NEW LITTER GENIE.
YOUR WISH GRANTED.
"ARE YOU A COOL MOM?"
I'M GONNA FIND OUT.
[ Female Announcer ]
SWIFFER WETJET'S PADS
ARE BETTER THAN EVER.
NOW THEY HAVE THE SCRUBBING
POWER OF MR. CLEAN MAGIC ERASER
SO YOU DON'T HAVE TO GET DOWN
ON YOUR HANDS AND KNEES
TO SCRUB AWAY TOUGH,
DRIED-ON STAINS.
HEY, DO YOU GUYS THINK I'M
"MOMTACULAR" OR "MOMTROCIOUS"?
♪
[ Female Announcer ] SWIFFER.
NOW WITH
THE SCRUBBING POWER
OF MR. CLEAN
MAGIC ERASER.
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
♪
>> Announcer: AND NOW --
THE MOMENT YOU'VE ALL BEEN
WAITING FOR, IT IS THE "DISH OF
THE DAY."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WELCOME BACK TO "THE CHEW'S"
"SWEET, SWEET CHRISTMAS."
MACAROONS, FRUIT CAKES, SO LAST
YEAR.
IT'S TIME TO AMP UP YOUR HOLIDAY
DESSERT MENU WITH ONE OF MY
FAVORITE SWEET SENSATIONS --
STRUFFOLI.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WHAT EXACTLY IS A STRUFFOLI?
>> WELL, MY LITTLE LOVE, LET ME
TELL YOU WHEN MY HOUSE COOKING
ISN'T COMPLETE WITHOUT A SWEET
STACK OF STRUFFOLI.
ORIGINATING IN NAPLES AND
SYMBOLIZING GOOD LUCK, THESE
LITTLE BITES OF HEAVEN ARE MADE
DAYS BEFORE, OFTEN EXACTLY
12 DAYS, AND GOBBLED UP BY
GUESTS AS THEY COME THROUGH THE
FOYER OR ENTRANCE HALL OF YOUR
HOUSE.
>> OHH.
>> THROUGHOUT THE ENTIRE TWO
WEEKS PROCEEDING CHRISTMAS.
STRUFFOLI, DERIVING FROM THE
TRAGICALLY GREEK WORD
STRANGULOS --
>> YES!
>> -- MEANING ROUND BITE-SIZED
PEOPLE THAT ARE STRANGLED OR
FRITTERS THAT ARE FRIED,
DRENCHED IN HONEY, THEN TOPPED
WITH SPRINKLES OF CANDIED FRUIT.
THEY'RE THEN ARRANGED IN A
WREATH, OR STACKED LIKE A
CHRISTMAS TREE.
IF YOU WANT TO SATISFY SANTA'S
SWEET TOOTH --
I'VE HAD A LITTLE SUGAR -- THEN
LOOK NO FURTHER THAN SIMPLE,
DELICIOUS STRUFFOLI.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> I GOTTA SAY, I LOVE THE MARIO
HISTORY LESSONS.
I LOVE THEM.
>> WELCOME TO THE ITALIAN GREEK
CORNER, WOULDN'T YOU SAY
MR. SYMON?
>> I LOVE THAT.
>> SO, WE'RE GONNA MAKE
STRUFFOLI.
IT'S A LITTLE PASTRY.
IT KIND OF, IN THE END RESEMBLES
A LITTLE BIT OF A KIND OF
CRUNCHY DOUGHNUT.
THE WAY THAT THEY COOK THEM IN
HONEY AFTER THEY'VE BEEN FRIED
SERVES AS A PRESERVATIVE.
SO, YOU'LL SEE HOW THEY BECOME
KIND OF SET AND NOT REALLY ABLE
TO SPOIL.
>> AND THEY REALLY LAST 12 DAYS
OUT ON THE SHELF?
>> AT OUR HOUSE, THEY LAST ABOUT
A WEEK, AND THEN THEY'RE GONE.
OH YEAH, THEY'D LAST 12 DAYS,
THOUGH.
HOW COULD YOU TELL THE
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN A SPOILED OR
OLD STRUFFOLI AND A BRAND NEW
ONE WOULD BE A GOOD QUESTION.
[ LAUGHTER ]
SO, THEY'RE GONNA GET CANNED.
I DON'T KNOW, THEY ALL TASTE
REALLY GOOD TO ME.
SO, I'M GONNA TAKE THREE AND
HALF CUPS OF FLOUR.
AND WE'RE GONNA TAKE THAT --
IF YOU WANNA CRACK THAT WHOLE
EGG IN THERE.
>> YEAH, SURE.
>> WE'RE GONNA TAKE A COUPLE OF
YOLKS.
SIX EGGS --
I'M SORRY, IT'S SIX EGGS AND ONE
YOLK.
LET ME GO BACK INTO THAT GAME.
SO EGG, EGG, EGG, AND YOLK.
RIGHT?
WE'RE GONNA MIX IT UP, DAPH, DO
YOU WANNA ADD --
OOPS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S GETTING A LITTLE SLOPPY
OVER HERE.
THANK GOD I'VE GOT AMAZING
DEXTERITY SKILLS.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A PINCH OF
SALT, A ZEST OF LEMON AND LIME.
I MEAN ZEST OF LEMON AND ORANGE.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A SHOT AND A
HALF OF LIMONCELLO.
>> UH-HUH.
[ CHEERS ]
>> WHICH IS THE SWEET LEMON
LIQUEUR FROM NAPLES AND AMALFI
COAST.
AND YOU BRING IT TOGETHER
RELATIVELY QUICKLY, JUST LIKE A
DOUGH LIKE THAT.
NOW, THIS YOU COULD MAKE THREE
OR FOUR DAYS IN ADVANCE IF YOU
WANTED, BUT IN FACT BECAUSE
THESE SET SO WELL, IT DOESN'T
REALLY MAKE A DIFFERENCE.
WHAT YOU WANNA DO IS AFTER
YOU'RE DONE MIXING THEM FOR
ABOUT THREE OR FOUR MINUTES, LET
IT REST IN THE FRIDGE FOR A FEW
SECONDS SO IT KIND OF SETS UP
LIKE THIS.
>> UM-HMM.
>> THEN --
>> LIKE GNOCCHI.
>> YOU START GOING AT IT JUST
LIKE GNOCCHI.
SO, HERE'S WHAT I'M GONNA DO,
I'M GONNA ROLL THESE INTO
DOWELS.
DAPH, YOU CAN START WITH THE
ONES THAT ALREADY EXIST.
>> OKAY.
>> AND START JUST CUTTING THEM
INTO PIECES ABOUT THAT BIG.
>> OKAY.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> I SAY GOOD.
>> CHEF SYMON, IS THERE ANYTHING
LIKE THIS IN THE GREEK
TRADITION?
LIKE A FRIED DESSERT THAT SITS
AROUND?
THAT'S THE THING, THIS ISN'T
LIKE A BOMBOLONI THAT COULD
ACTUALLY BE MADE IN ADVANCE.
>> YEAH, I'VE NEVER SEEN --
I MEAN, YOU KNOW THERE'S A LOT
OF GREEK FRIED DESSERTS, BUT
I'VE NEVER SEEN ONE THAT WILL
HOLD FOR A COUPLE OF WEEKS.
THE GREEK COOKIE THAT MY MOM
MAKES, IT'S HOLDS, IT'S NOT
FRIED.
BUT KOULOURAKIA IS THE TWISTED
COOKIE WITH THE SESAME SEEDS ON
TOP.
>> RIGHT, RIGHT.
>> AND SHE'LL MAKE THOSE THAT,
YOU KNOW, THEY HOLD FOR A MONTH
AND THEY'RE DELICIOUS.
>> SO, THEY DO HOLD THEN.
>> YOU EAT WITH YOUR COFFEE, BUT
IT'S NOT A FRIED DESSERT.
IT'S A BAKED DESSERT.
>> OH, WELL, YOU SEE THIS?
ABOUT THE SAME TEMPERATURE AS AN
OVEN.
THIS IS 375, 385 SIDE, SO IT'S
ABOUT THE SAME.
>> BUT, CAN YOU BAKE IT?
>> YEAH, OF COURSE.
I DON'T THINK YOU CAN BAKE
THESE.
I THINK THEY WOULD SET UP
REALLY, REALLY HARD.
>> CAN I FRY SOME?
>> YES YOU CAN.
GENTLY, GENTLY, GENTLY.
START DUMPING THEM ALL IN.
YES, GO RIGHT AHEAD.
>> WOO!
>> THAT'S NOT GENTLE.
>> THAT DIDN'T LOOK GENTLE AT
ALL, DAPH, THAT WAS ALMOST LIKE
YOU SPLASHED YOUR LIGHTING
SWITCH.
>> IN MY EAR I'M HEARING THROW
THEM ALL IN.
SO, YOU KNOW.
>> UNLIKE COOKIE, WE DON'T FLICK
THESE OFF OF ANYTHING, WE JUST
CUT THEM INTO STRAIGHT PIECES
LIKE SO.
IS YOUR OIL HOT ENOUGH, DAPH?
>> OH, YOU KNOW, MY SKIN WOULD
SAY YES.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> WELL, YOUR SKIN IS EXACTLY
WHAT I WANNA ASK.
SO NOW WE GET THESE --
>> YEAH, THANK YOU.
>> BE GENTLE.
>> I DIDN'T KNOW --
>> I DON'T WANNA SEE THAT
SWEATER CATCH ON FIRE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> WE HAD A LEGITIMATE QUESTION,
WHICH WAS "IF THIS SWEATER GOT
WET, WOULD I BE ELECTROCUTED?"
>> I WAS VERY CONCERNED.
>> NOT SO WORRIED ABOUT -- DAPH,
DON'T WORRY.
>> OKAY.
>> ALL RIGHT, SO NOW WHAT WE'RE
GONNA DO IS WE'RE GONNA TAKE --
YOU'RE FRYING THOSE.
>> YES.
HOW MANY?
CAN I PUT IN ALL OF THEM?
>> YOU'RE GONNA DO 'EM ALL.
YEAH.
>> OH, HEY, HERE WE GO.
>> SO THEN WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
IS WE'RE GONNA TAKE SOME HONEY,
AND YOU DON'T HAVE TO WORRY
ABOUT THE PITS EVEN GOING IN
THERE BECAUSE YOU'RE FISH THEM
OUT.
WE'RE GONNA HEAT THE HONEY WITH
THE LEMON JUICE SO IT BECOMES
ALMOST A SWEET CITRIC GLAZE THAT
GOES ALL AROUND IT.
AND THEN WE'RE GONNA TOSS AS
SOON AS THEY COME OUT OF THE
FRYER INTO THE HONEY TO COAT
THEM, AND THEN WE'LL DECORATE
THEM IN A WAY THAT WOULD MAKE
GRANDMA FROM NAPLES SO HAPPY.
>> WE LOVE YOU, GRANDMA.
>> SO, WE'RE GONNA KEEP FRYING.
WHEN WE COME BACK, I'LL SHOW YOU
HOW WE GET THESE OUT OF HERE.
WE'LL THEM IN THERE.
HOLD ON, HOLD ON, ALL AT ONCE.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'LL DO IT
ALL TOGETHER.
STAY WITH US.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
>> Announcer: THIS FRIDAY, IT'S
OUR "CHEW" "HOLIDAY SPECTACULAR"
AS CARLA PAYS A VISIT TO RADIO
CITY.
PLUS --
"CLINTON'S CHRISTMAS KARAOKE."
THAT'S FRIDAY, ON "THE CHEW."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
THE WAY IT MOVES.
THE WAY IT CLEANS.
EVERYTHING ABOUT
THE ORAL-B POWER BRUSH
IS SIMPLY REVOLUTIONARY.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES OSCILLATE,
ROTATE
AND EVEN PULSATE
TO GENTLY LOOSEN AND BREAK UP
THAT STICKY PLAQUE
WITH MORE BRUSH MOVEMENTS
THAN MANUAL BRUSHES
AND EVEN
UP TO 50% MORE
THAN LEADING
SONIC TECHNOLOGY BRUSHES
FOR A SUPERIOR CLEAN.
ORAL-B POWER BRUSHES.
GO TO ORALB.COM
FOR THE LATEST OFFERS.
THE RICH DARK CHOCOLATE.
YORK PEPPERMINT PATTIE
GET THE SENSATION.
TO SAY GET WELL
TO YOUR LOVED ONES.
♪
THIS CAME FOR YOU, MOMMY.
[ Female Announcer ]
BUT IT TAKES THE TOUCH
OF KLEENEX® BRAND,
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE,
TO TURN A GESTURE
INTO A COMPLETE GIFT OF CARE.
[ barks ]
SEND YOUR OWN FREE
KLEENEX® CARE PACK...
FULL OF SOOTHING ESSENTIALS
AT KLEENEX.COM.
KLEENEX®.
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE.
AT KLEENEX.COM.
♪
Get her 1/3rd carat
diamond earrings
this week only just $29.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
TOMATO,
OBVIOUSLY.
HAHA. THERE'S MORE
THAN THAT THOUGH,
THERE'S A KICK TO IT.
WAHLALALALALLALA!
SMOOTH, BUT CRISP.
IT'S KIND OF LIKE DRINKING
A FOOD THAT'S A DRINK,
OR A DRINK THAT'S A FOOD,
WOOOOOH!
[ Male Announcer ] TASTE IT
AND DESCRIBE THE INDESCRIBABLE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
I'M HOME.
[ Kids ] HI MOM.
[ Male Announcer ]
OF ALL THE THINGS THAT HAPPEN
ON YOUR SHINY SURFACES,
DISINFECTING
HAS TO BE ONE OF THEM.
CLOROX DISINFECTING WIPES.
KILLS GERMS. DRIES CLEAR.
Your soups are
so awesomely delicious
my husband and I
can't stop eating 'em!
What's...that...
on your head?
Can curlers!
Tomato Basil,
Potato with bacon...
we've got a lot of empty cans.
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
DISCOVER THE TEMPTING LAYERS
OF FERRERO ROCHER.
A WHOLE HAZELNUT,
SMOOTH CHOCOLATY CREAM
INSIDE A WAFER SHELL,
COVERED IN MILK CHOCOLATE
AND HAZELNUT PIECES.
♪
FERRERO ROCHER.
MAKE YOUR MOMENTS GOLDEN.
♪
>> Announcer: WELCOME BACK TO
OUR "SWEET CHRISTMAS" EDITION OF
"THE CHEW."
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WELCOME BACK TO "THE CHEW."
I'M JUST FINISHING UP MY
STRUFFOLI.
I'VE GOT MY HONEY BOILING IN
HERE WITH A LITTLE LEMON JUICE.
>> MMM, THEY'RE SO PRETTY.
>> TAKE THEM OUT JUST LIKE THIS.
AND THIS IS THE STEP THAT MAKES
THEM SOMETHING REMARKABLE, BUT
ALSO PRESERVE THEM.
'CAUSE LITERALLY THEY'D MAKE
THEM 12 DAYS IN ADVANCE, AND
THEY'D SIT THERE TRYING TO
SURVIVE TILL CHRISTMAS EVE AND
NOT VERY SUCCESSFULLY DOING SO.
SO YOU GET THEM ALL THERE.
THEY'RE DANGEROUSLY HOT RIGHT
NOW, AND YOU STIR 'EM AROUND
LIKE THIS.
THERE'S A LITTLE STRUFFOLI CANDY
BAR GOING ON THERE, DAPH.
THAT'S EXCITING.
>> AT THE TOP, WE CAN USE A
SPIDER.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SO NOW, HOLD ON, I'M COMING AT
YOU HOT.
NOW WE TAKE THEM JUST LIKE THAT,
AND OUT OF THERE, GRANDMA WOULD
JUST PILE THEM.
>> OH!
>> OH YEAH.
>> OH, MY GOSH.
ANYONE THAT -- GRANDMA GOT
RIGHT.
>> WATCH OUT.
THEY'RE HOT, THEY'RE HOT!
>> WHOA, WHOA, WHOA --
MOLTEN CANNONBALLS.
>> THEY'VE GONE CRAZY.
NOW, HOLD ON.
NOW, WHAT GRANDMA WOULD DO AT
THIS POINT -- PUT THE SPRINKLES
ON FIRST, DAPH.
>> CANDY TIME?
>> YEAH, ANYTIME.
>> CRAZY TIME?
>> CRAZY.
>> WHOA.
>> AH.
>> BEAUTIFUL.
>> AND THEN THE LEMON, THE
CANDIED LEMON ZEST.
KEEP IN MIND, THIS IS NAPLES OR
AMALFI, THIS IS THE SOUTHERN
PART, OF THE MOST BEAUTIFUL PART
OF ALL TRAPANI.
>> ARE THESE FOR GOOD LUCK?
>> THESE ARE VERY GOOD LUCK.
>> HAVE THEY BROUGHT YOU GOOD
LUCK THIS YEAR?
>> I'VE HAD TREMENDOUS --
WELL, LOOK AT THE SWEATER.
>> I MEAN HELLO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I CERTAINLY HAD BETTER LUCK
THAN YOU AT THE SWEATER
SELECTION.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> THESE ARE FOR ME, GUYS.
SEE YOU LATER.
>> ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, SO PASS THOSE AROUND,
AND TELL ME WHAT YOU GUYS THINK.
YOU CAN ALSO DO THEM IN A BOWL
LIKE THAT.
>> WOW.
>> SAME THING.
THE TRICK OF COURSE BEING,
THAT'S IT'S JUST A CELEBRATION.
YOU HAVE THEM SITTING AROUND,
WHAT YOU DO AT THE END OF THE
DAY BEFORE EVERYONE WENT TO BED,
WOULD BE TO COVER THEM WITH A
LITTLE TOWEL.
YOU WOULD NEVER PUT PLASTIC ON
THEM BECAUSE YOU DIDN'T WANT
WHATEVER MOISTURE WAS IN
THERE -- SOMETIMES SHE'D PUT A
LITTLE ZEST ON THEM.
GO WILD.
MAKE IT RAIN, DAPH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
AND THAT'S AS SIMPLE AS IT GETS,
RIGHT?
I MEAN, THIS IS ITALIAN DESSERT,
IT'S A GREAT WAY TO START.
THESE ARE EQUALLY DELICIOUS AT
BREAKFAST TIME.
>> DELICIOUS.
>> PEOPLE HAVE THEM ANYWAY THEY
WANT.
>> WHO WANTS SOME GOOD LUCK?
[ CHEERS ]
YOU GUYS?
OH, OH, OH, IT'S RAINING, IT'S
RAINING.
>> 15 CENTS FOR A GIANT HANDFUL.
THIS IS A REMARK -- TAKE A
COUPLE, GRAB A COUPLE.
[ CHEERS ]
>> YOU NEED MORE THAN ONE, MORE
THAN ONE.
>> WELL, WHAT'D YOU THINK?
TASTE IT.
HOW IS IT, MY DEAR?
>> SO GOOD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I LOVE THAT.
>> YOU'RE WELCOME.
>> ALL RIGHT, LADIES AND
GENTLEMEN, THAT'S EXACTLY HOW
YOU MAKE STRUFFOLI.
UP NEXT --
CARLA UNCOVERS THE SECRET BEHIND
GOO GOO CLUSTERS.
STAY WITH US.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
>> Announcer: COMING UP --
>> RIGHT HERE WE'RE LOOKING AT
THE NOUGAT FUSING WITH THE
CARAMEL.
>> A MAGICAL MILK AND COOKIES
COMBO THAT SANTA WOULD
DEFINITELY APPROVE OF.
>> THIS IS THE MOMENT I'VE BEEN
WAITING FOR.
>> Announcer: THAT'S NEXT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
[ Rosa ] I'M ROSA
AND I QUIT SMOKING WITH CHANTIX.
WHEN THE DOCTOR TOLD ME
THAT I COULD SMOKE
FOR THE FIRST WEEK...
I'M LIKE...YEAH, OK...
LITTLE DID I KNOW
THAT ONE WEEK LATER
I WASN'T SMOKING.
[ Male Announcer ]
ALONG WITH SUPPORT,
CHANTIX IS PROVEN
TO HELP PEOPLE QUIT SMOKING.
IT REDUCES THE URGE TO SMOKE.
SOME PEOPLE HAD CHANGES
IN BEHAVIOR,
THINKING OR MOOD,
HOSTILITY, AGITATION,
DEPRESSED MOOD AND SUICIDAL
THOUGHTS OR ACTIONS
WHILE TAKING
OR AFTER STOPPING CHANTIX.
IF YOU NOTICE ANY OF THESE
STOP TAKING CHANTIX AND CALL
YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY HISTORY OF DEPRESSION
OR OTHER
MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS,
WHICH COULD GET WORSE
WHILE TAKING CHANTIX.
DON'T TAKE CHANTIX IF
YOU'VE HAD A SERIOUS ALLERGIC
OR SKIN REACTION TO IT.
IF YOU DEVELOP THESE
STOP TAKING CHANTIX
AND SEE YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
AS SOME CAN BE
LIFE-THREATENING.
IF YOU HAVE A HISTORY OF HEART
OR BLOOD VESSEL PROBLEMS,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
NEW OR WORSE SYMPTOMS.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU HAVE SYMPTOMS
OF A HEART ATTACK.
USE CAUTION WHEN DRIVING
OR OPERATING MACHINERY.
COMMON SIDE EFFECTS
INCLUDE NAUSEA,
TROUBLE SLEEPING
AND UNUSUAL DREAMS.
IT HELPS TO HAVE PEOPLE
AROUND YOU...
THEY SAY,
YOU'RE MUCH BIGGER THAN THIS.
AND YOU ARE.
[ Male Announcer ]
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF CHANTIX
IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
YOUR MOUTH HAS BEEN
SNACKING, GIFT STACKING,
NUTCRACKING AND YELLOWING.
BECAUSE IF YOU'RE NOT
WHITENING, YOU'RE YELLOWING.
CREST WHITESTRIPS
REMOVE OVER 10 YEARS OF STAINS,
JUST IN TIME
FOR A WHITE HOLIDAY.
CREST 3D WHITE WHITESTRIPS.
I'd like to thank eating right,
whole grain,
Multigrain Cheerios!
Mom, are those my jeans?
[ Female Announcer ] People
who choose more whole grain
tend to weigh less
than those who don't.
Multigrain Cheerios
>> Announcer: "THE CHEW" WILL
CONTINUE IN A MOMENT, HERE ON
ABC.
♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "THE CHEW'S"
"SWEET CHRISTMAS."
THIS CHRISTMAS, I JUST WANT ONE
THING IN MY STOCKING --
SWEET CHOCOLATY GOO GOO
CLUSTERS.
MADE IN THE --
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
YES!
MADE IN MY HOMETOWN OF
NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE.
NOW TO CELEBRATE THE CANDY'S
100th ANNIVERSARY, I DECIDED TO
TAKE A TRIP BACK HOME TO SEE
JUST HOW THESE SWEET TREATS ARE
MADE.
CHECK IT OUT.
♪
>> THEY'RE CHEWY.
THEY'RE CRUNCHY.
THEY'VE GOT NUTS, CARAMEL, AND
MARSHMALLOW NOUGAT.
AND THEY'RE COVERED IN
CHOCOLATE.
THEY'RE THE GOO GOO CLUSTER, AND
THEY'RE MADE RIGHT HERE IN MY
HOMETOWN OF NASHVILLE,
TENNESSEE.
>> I LOVE THE CHOCOLATE.
I LOVE THE NUTS.
>> GOO GOOS ARE A NASHVILLE
TREASURE, AND THEY ARE
DELICIOUS.
>> IF YOU WANT A PARTY IN YOUR
MOUTH, HAVE A GOO GOO.
>> RIGHT NOW, WE'RE GONNA FIND
OUT EXACTLY HOW IT'S MADE.
♪
HEY, LANCE, HOW ARE YOU?
>> HI CARLA.
THANKS FOR COMING.
>> OH MY GOSH, I AM SO EXCITED
TO BE HERE.
WELL, HOW DO GOO GOO CLUSTERS
GET STARTED?
>> SO, GOO GOO CLUSTERS WERE
INVENTED IN 1912.
IT WAS AMERICA'S FIRST
COMBINATION CONVECTION CANDY
BAR.
>> SO, IT WASN'T SNICKERS, IT
WASN'T BUTTERFINGER --
>> NOPE.
>> -- IT WASN'T TWIX.
IT WAS THE GOO GOO CLUSTER.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
AND IT'S BEEN MADE RIGHT HERE IN
NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE, FOR
100 YEARS.
>> DO YOU KNOW WHAT?
I HAVE BEEN EATING GOO GOOS
PROBABLY HALF THAT TIME.
THAT'S AMAZING.
>> WE THANK YOU FOR YOUR
PATRONAGE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SO, LANCE, WHERE DOES THE NAME
GOO GOO COME FROM?
>> WELL, THEY'RE SO GOOD, YOU
KNOW HOW TO SAY IT FROM BIRTH.
>> GOO GOO.
♪
>> THIS IS OUR ONE AND ONLY
PRODUCTION FACILITY FOR GOO GOO
CLUSTERS.
SO WHEREVER YOU ARE IN THE
WORLD, WHEN YOU'RE EATING A GOO
GOO, IT WAS MADE RIGHT HERE IN
NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE.
>> THAT'S AMAZING.
WELL, I CAN'T WAIT TO GET A
GOOEY ONE OFF THE CONVEYOR BELT.
>> ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GO SHOW YOU HOW THEY'RE
MADE.
♪
RIGHT HERE, WE'RE LOOKING AT THE
NOUGAT FUSING WITH THE CARAMEL.
FROM HERE, THE CARAMEL AND THE
NOUGAT GO THROUGH A COOLING
TUNNEL.
THEN THEY GO INTO THE CORNER,
WHERE THEY HIT THE FOOTER
SPREADER, WHICH SPREADS THEM
APART, AND THEN THEY CUT IN A
LITTLE CORE.
THEN THE CORES GET A COAT IN
CHOCOLATE, THEN THEY GET THE
NUTS, THEN THE REAL MILK
CHOCOLATE ON TOP, INTO THE OTHER
COOLING TUNNEL, AND THEN INTO
THE WRAPPERS, THE BOXES, AND OUT
TO THE STORES.
♪
>> SO LET ME GET THIS STRAIGHT,
IT STARTS WITH SUGAR ON TOP OF
SUGAR --
>> YEAH.
>> -- AND IT ENDS WITH
CHOCOLATE, PEANUTS, AND MORE
CHOCOLATE ON TOP OF THAT.
>> THAT'S CORRECT.
>> I KNEW I LOVED IT FOR A
REASON.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SO HOW MANY ARE MADE IN A DAY?
>> WE CAN MAKE 300,000 IN A DAY.
>> ANY SECRET INGREDIENTS TO IT
THERE?
>> SOUTHERN HOSPITALITY.
>> WELL, I'M GONNA DO WHAT I CAN
TO SPREAD THE WORD.
♪
THIS IS THE MOMENT I'VE BEEN
WAITING FOR.
♪
[ RECORD SCRATCH ]
NOW THIS --
MMM.
-- IS A TRUE TASTE OF
NASHVILLE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
HOW ARE YOU GUYS?
NOW WHAT'S OUR GOO GOO -- WE
ACTUALLY HAVE A HOT CHOCOLATE
THAT IS INSPIRED BY THE GOO GOO.
THE RECIPE IS ON THECHEW.COM.
WE'RE GONNA DRINK UP, AND YOU
DON'T GO AWAY, ALL RIGHT?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
>> Announcer: STILL TO COME --
THE LOVEABLE SOLEIL MOON FRYE
MAKES A SWEET ESCAPE WITH SUGARY
CHOCOLATE COOKIES.
THAT'S NEXT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
THERE'S THE SIGN TO THE BULLPEN.
HERE HE COMES.
YOU WOULDN'T WANT YOUR
DOCTOR DOING YOUR JOB,
THE PITCH!
WHOA!
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING HIS?
ONLY YOUR DOCTOR CAN DETERMINE
IF YOUR PERSISTENT HEARTBURN
IS ACTUALLY SOMETHING
MORE SERIOUS
LIKE ACID REFLUX DISEASE.
OVER TIME, STOMACH
ACID CAN DAMAGE
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
FOR MANY, PRESCRIPTION NEXIUM
NOT ONLY PROVIDES
24-HOUR HEARTBURN RELIEF,
BUT CAN ALSO HELP HEAL
ACID-RELATED EROSIONS IN
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
THERE IS RISK OF BONE FRACTURE
AND LOW MAGNESIUM LEVELS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, ABDOMINAL
PAIN AND DIARRHEA.
CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY IF
YOU HAVE PERSISTENT DIARRHEA.
OTHER SERIOUS STOMACH
CONDITIONS MAY EXIST.
DON'T TAKE NEXIUM IF
YOU TAKE CLOPIDOGREL.
LET YOUR DOCTOR DO HIS JOB.
AND YOU DO YOURS.
ASK IF NEXIUM IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
IF YOU CAN'T AFFORD
YOUR MEDICATION,
ASTRAZENECA MAY BE ABLE TO HELP.
of Green Giant vegetables
it's easy to eat like
a giant...
♪
and feel like a Green Giant.
Ho Ho Ho
♪ Green Giant
Balsamic, Vinegar and Oil,
Authentic Italian Herbs.
Just a few of the
ingredients you'll find in
Hidden Valley's Italians
and Vinaigrettes.
You know Hidden Valley for our
Ranch, but you've never
tasted anything like this.
Since then,
there's been one wedding,
2 kids,
And 43 bottles
of Olay Total Effects.
So in spite of 185 tantrums
378 pre-dawn starts
And a lot of birthdays,
Caroline still looks amazing.
You can challenge
what's possible
Thanks to the trusted
performance of Olay.
60 years, Millions of women,
Real Results.
♪
>> Announcer: WELCOME BACK TO
OUR "SWEET CHRISTMAS" ON "THE
CHEW."
[ APPLAUSE ]
>>> WELCOME BACK TO "THE CHEW'S"
"SWEET CHRISTMAS."
NOW, IN THE '80s THERE WAS NO
ONE ON TV SWEETER THAN
PUNKY BREWSTER.
AND NOW THAT FUN-LOVING WILD
CHILD IS ALL GROWN UP AND CAN
ADD AUTHOR, DIRECTOR AND MOM TO
HER RESUME.
HERE TO MAKE A SWEET CHRISTMAS
COOKIE IS TARGET'S MOMMY
AMBASSADOR SOLEIL MOON FRYE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> HOW ARE YOU?
>> I LOVE YOU, CLINTON!
>> HELLO!
>> HI!
>> YOU'RE SO BEAUTIFUL!
>> THANK YOU.
>> LOVE YOUR UGLY SWEATER!
HELLO!
>> SO FUN.
OF COURSE.
THIS IS LIKE THE FUNNEST
EPISODE IN THE WORLD.
>> I LOVE IT.
[ CHEERS ]
>> YOU GUYS LOOK AMAZING BY THE
WAY!
>> OUR AUDIENCE IS THE BEST,
THEY GET SO DRESSED UP AND THEY
GO 100%.
YOU GUYS, SERIOUSLY --
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> SO NOW, WE ALL KNOW AND LOVE
YOU PUNKY BREWSTER.
I HAVE TO SAY, ROXY KING FROM
"SABRINA THE TEENAGE WITCH"
MIGHT BE BY FAVORITE.
>> AWE, THANK YOU.
>> BUT WHAT WAS IT LIKE GROWING
UP AS A KID ON THE SET?
ESPECIALLY AROUND THE HOLIDAYS?
>> I LOVED IT.
WE PLAYED, WE JUMPED AROUND ON
POGO STICKS AND OUR SCOOTERS,
AND WE WERE ALWAYS ABLE TO BE
KIDS.
IT WAS OUR PLAYGROUND YOU KNOW?
THE LOT AT NBC WAS OUR
PLAYGROUND, SO IT WAS GREAT.
>> RIGHT.
>> SO IT WAS GREAT.
>> LOOKING AT THOSE OLD PHOTOS,
IT'S OBVIOUS THAT MARIO
FASHIONED HIS LOOK AFTER PUNKY
BREWSTER.
>> RIGHT!
>> WHO KNEW?
>> PUNKY WAS AN INSPIRATION.
I FEEL LIKE SHE WAS A STYLE ICON
TO MANY PEOPLE.
>> I AGREE.
>> I THINK SO.
WELL, WE'RE SETTING NEW STYLE
TRENDS TODAY AND YOU ACTUALLY
BROUGHT US A DELICIOUS SWEET
COOKIE RECIPE TO SHARE.
>> OH, IT'S SUCH A YUMMY RECIPE
FROM TARGET.
>> YOU'RE CHOCOLATE MITTENS --
>> YES, I'M SO EXCITED.
WE'RE GONNA DO CHOCOLATE MITTENS
OVER HERE.
>> YUM!
>> WE HAVE CREAM CHEESE, BUTTER,
AND SUGAR OVER HERE.
>> PERFECT.
OKAY.
>> AND WE'RE GONNA ADD OUR
VANILLA.
>> GREAT.
>> RIGHT HERE IN THE EGG.
>> OKAY.
>> AND OUR CHOCOLATE.
I LOVE BAKING WITH THE GIRLS.
BAKING IS BIG IN OUR HOUSEHOLD.
>> TWO DAUGHTERS, RIGHT?
>> TWO DAUGHTERS.
>> HOW OLD ARE THEY?
>> FOUR AND SEVEN.
NOW, OUR HOUSEHOLD IS NOT --
THIS WAS US IN INDIA WHERE WE
EXPERIMENTED WITH LOTS OF FOOD.
I LIKED TELLING PEOPLE TO HAVE
THEM EXPERIMENT EARLY WITH
SPICES.
NOW, OUR HOUSE IS NOT QUITE AS
CLEAN AS THIS SET.
USUALLY THE CHOCOLATE IS ON THE
WALL.
>> OUR SET IS NOT NORMALLY AS
CLEAN AS THIS.
>> WE HAVE THE CHOCOLATE, WE
HAVE A LITTLE SALT OVER HERE.
>> WHAT ABOUT --
>> AND OUR FLOUR.
>> OKAY, HERE WE GO.
>> AND ALL OUR INGREDIENTS OVER
HERE.
>> WHAT ABOUT SOME FOOD
TRADITIONS YOU AND THE GIRLS
HAVE AT HOME?
>> OH, WELL, WE DO THE MYSTERY
TASTE TEST WHERE WE EXPERIMENT
WITH DIFFERENT FOODS.
I'M REALLY A BIG BELIEVER IN
EXPERIMENTING WITH DIFFERENT
FOODS AND GETTING THEM ENGAGED.
I HAVE SO MANY FRIENDS WHO HAVE
A HARD TIME WITH PICKY EATERS.
SO, IT'S REALLY TEACHING THEM
ABOUT FOOD AND THEY LOVE EATING
WITH ME SO WE MAKE IT FUN.
THEY LOVE COOKING WITH ME.
WE PUT OUT SALADS, THEY PICK OUT
THEIR FAVORITE FRUIT TO ADD TO
THE SALAD.
IT MAKES IT UNIQUE.
>> OH, THAT'S NICE.
>> SO, REALLY BAKING TOGETHER,
AND MAKING A MESS, HAVING FUN
AND NOT BEING AFRAID OF THE
CHAOS, YOU KNOW?
>> OR THE UGLY SWEATER.
>> EXACTLY.
>> SO YOU -- WHIPPED IT ALL
TOGETHER, YOU CHILLED IT IN THE
FRIDGE.
>> YEAH.
>> AND THEN WE HAVE OUR CUTE
LITTLE MITTENS, AND YOU CAN GET
ALL THESE GOODIES FROM TARGET.
OF COURSE, I WAS THE MOM THAT
SPENT LIKE HOURS IN AN AISLE AND
NOW GETTING TO BE TARGET'S MOMMY
AMBASSADOR IS SO MUCH FUN
BECAUSE I GET TO SPEND EVEN MORE
HOURS IN THE AISLE.
>> YEAH, TALK ABOUT THAT THOUGH
BECAUSE YOU'RE REALLY BUSY,
YOU'RE A WORKING MOM.
HOW DO YOU MAKE TIME TO SORT OF
ENTERTAIN DURING THE HOLIDAYS
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME AND ENJOY
YOUR KIDS?
>> I INVOLVE THEM.
SO, YESTERDAY WE SPENT ALL DAY
BAKING, WE'RE DOING ALL OF THESE
FUN, HOMEMADE RECIPES AS
GIFTS -- SO REALLY INVOLVING THE
KIDS.
I MEAN, I THINK SO MANY PEOPLE
SPEND TIME IN THE KITCHEN BUT
DON'T REALIZE THAT THE KIDS CAN
BE RIGHT THERE WITH YOU.
AND ALSO, PUTTING IT OUT AT
THEIR LEVEL, SO I REALLY TRY AND
PUT THINGS AT THEIR LEVEL SO
THEY CAN SEE IT, THEY CAN
ENGAGE.
MY GIRLS LOVE SPRINKLES SO WE DO
LOTS OF SPRINKLES AND USUALLY
THEY FLY EVERYWHERE.
BUT ALWAYS INVOLVING THEM IS THE
NUMBER ONE WAY TO TEACH THEM.
>> IF YOU WANT THEM TO TRY
DIFFERENT THINGS, TO GET THEM
INVOLVED IN THE PROCESS IS
THE --
>> ABSOLUTELY!
ISN'T THIS SO CUTE?
WE POKE THIS LITTLE HOLE, OVER
HERE.
AND THEN WE GET A THREAD --
>> AFTER YOU BAKE THEM RIGHT?
>> YES, AFTER YOU BAKE THEM OF
COURSE.
YOU BAKE THEM FIRST, AND THEN
AFTERWARDS WE THREAD THEM.
SO WE HAVE OUR RIBBON, AND THEN
WE CAN PUT OUR RIBBON IN HERE.
>> WHAT GAVE YOU THE IDEA OF
MAKING A MICHIGAN-SHAPED COOKIE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> INSPIRATION, OF COURSE!
BUT HOW CUTE IS THIS?
>> IT'S ADORABLE.
>> SO YOU ADD YOUR LITTLE THREAD
AND THEN LOOK, YOU CAN TIE A
BOW.
TIE THEM TOGETHER AND THEN HOW
CUTE IS THIS AS A LITTLE GIFT?
YOU CAN TIE IT ON.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> SO CUTE.
>> AND THESE BAKE UP REALLY
FAST.
I THINK 375, 8 TO 10 MINUTES.
>> YES, 10 MINUTES IS PERFECT.
YOU CAN GET ALL THESE GOODIES AT
TARGET.
>> ARE THERE DIFFERENT HOLIDAY
SHAPES THEY CAN DO?
>> ALL DIFFERENT SHAPES.
>> OH, BEAUTIFUL.
>> AND, OF COURSE, I LOVE
GETTING CREATIVE.
MY KIDS, WE DO HEARTS, WE DO
STARS, AND A LOT OF TIMES WE
DON'T EVEN USE COOKIE CUTTERS.
WE JUST MAKE OUR OWN.
AND SO, EXPERIMENTING AND HAVING
FUN WITH THEM IS THE NUMBER ONE
KEY TO COOKING IN OUR HOUSEHOLD.
>> HOW ADORABLE IS THAT?
>> LOOK AT HOW MUCH FANCIER
YOURS IS.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> MINE'S THE HAPPY, CHAOS
VERSION OVER HERE.
>> THIS IS YOUR NEW BOOK OUR, IT
CAME OUT LAST YEAR.
WHAT'S IT ALL -- WHAT'S THE DEAL
THERE?
>> "HAPPY CHAOS" IS ALL ABOUT
REALLY ENJOYING THE MOMENTS IN
BETWEEN, AND ENJOYING OUR
PERFECTLY IMPERFECT ADVENTURE.
>> YES!
>> AND THE NEXT BOOK IS ALL
ABOUT ENTERTAINING WITH THE KIDS
AND MAKING IT FUN.
>> I LOVE YOU AS A MOM AND A
MOMMY AMBASSADOR FOR TARGET.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> WHAT'S THE NOISE?
[ BELLS JINGLING ]
>> I THINK IT'S SANTA'S SLEIGH
BELLS RINGING!
I BET HE BROUGHT YOU ALL A GIFT.
EVERYONE IN OUR STUDIO AUDIENCE
IS GETTING A $100 GIFT CARD TO
TARGET AND --
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
-- AND AN ARCHER FARMS SNACK MIX
FOR THE RIDE HOME!
YOU WON'T GO HUNGRY.
THESE ARE SO CUTE.
ADORABLE.
>> THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> YOU GUYS CAN GET THIS RECIPE
ON THECHEW.COM.
UP NEXT, MICHAEL IS MAKING A
SWEET CHRISTMAS TREAT IN THE
MICROWAVE.
YOU DON'T WANNA MISS IT.
♪
>> Announcer: THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON, ORDER YOUR COPY OF "THE
CHEW'S FOOD. LIFE. FUN." BOOK.
OVER 100 MOUTH-WATERING RECIPES
AND TONS OF FABULOUS
ENTERTAINING TIPS.
EVERYTHING YOU NEED TO MAKE YOUR
HOLIDAYS PERFECT.
IT'S ALSO A FANTASTIC GIFT OR
STOCKING-STUFFER.
AVAILABLE ON THECHEW.COM OR
WHEREVER BOOKS ARE SOLD.
MAKE EVERY DAY A HOLIDAY PARTY
IN YOUR KITCHEN.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
[ Michelle ]
WHEN I FIRST DISCOVERED
THAT I HAD SENSITIVE TEETH,
I DIDN'T WANT TO CHANGE
TOOTHPASTES.
I ALREADY HAD A PRODUCT
THAT MADE MY MOUTH FEEL CLEAN.
WHY AM I GOING TO GO
AND CHANGE IT?
THE FIRST THING HE RECOMMENDED
WAS THAT I USE SENSODYNE.
SENSODYNE HELPS
WITH THE SENSITIVITY ISSUES
AND AT THE SAME TIME
IT GIVES YOU THE CLEAN FEELING.
YOUR MOUTH FEELS FRESH.
SENSODYNE SATISFIES THE NEEDS
THAT I WOULD LOOK FOR
IN A TOOTHPASTE.
I DEFINITELY FEEL LIKE
I CAN BE MYSELF NOW.
I DON'T HAVE THE SAME PAIN
I DID.
IT GIVES YOU YOUR LIFE BACK.
he opened up
Jake's very private world.
At first, Jake's family
thought they saved Ziggy,
but his connection with Jake
has been a lifesaver.
For a love this strong,
his family only feeds him Iams.
Compared to other
leading brands,
it has 50% more
animal protein...
...to help keep Ziggy's body
as strong as a love
that reaches further
than anyone's words.
Iams. Keep Love Strong.
SO YOU THINK
SANTA WILL LIKE THESE...
RED AND GREEN M&M'S?
I DON'T KNOW!
I NEVER MET THE GUY!
WHAAAAA!
HE DOES EXIST!
THEY DO EXIST!
UHM... SANTA?
TRUST DURACELL TO POWER
THEIR DONATED TOYS?
DURALOCK POWER PRESERVE.
IT LOCKS IN POWER
FOR UP TO 10 YEARS IN STORAGE.
GUARANTEED.
DURACELL WITH DURALOCK.
TRUSTED EVERYWHERE.
HMM, WE NEED A NEW GAME.
♪
THAT'LL SAVE THE DAY.
SO WILL BOUNTY SELECT-A-SIZE.
IT'S THE SMALLER POWERFUL SHEET.
THE ONLY ONE
WITH TRAP + LOCK TECHNOLOGY.
LOOK! ONE SELECT-A-SIZE SHEET
OF BOUNTY IS 50% MORE ABSORBENT
THAN A FULL SIZE SHEET
OF THE LEADING ORDINARY BRAND.
USE LESS. WITH THE SMALL
BUT POWERFUL PICKER UPPER,
BOUNTY SELECT-A-SIZE.
USE LESS. WITH THE SMALL
BUT POWERFUL PICKER UPPER,
♪
Get her 1/3rd carat
diamond earrings
this week only just $29.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> HEY, EVERYBODY, WELCOME BACK
TO "THE CHEW'S" "SWEET
CHRISTMAS."
NOTHING IS SWEETER THAN MAKING A
GOURMET DESSERT IN LESS THAN
FIVE MINUTES.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> IMPOSSIBLE YOU SAY?
>> IMPOSSIBLE!
>> NO, IT'S POSSIBLE.
AND I'M GONNA PROVE IT BY MAKING
A THREE MINUTE, CHOCOLATE CHIP
CUPCAKE THAT WILL WOW YOU GUYS.
I LOVE MAKING THIS FOR NEPHEWS
BECAUSE IT'S SOMETHING THAT YOU
CAN PUT TOGETHER IN NO TIME AT
ALL AND MAKE EVERYBODY AT THE
PARTY EXTREMELY HAPPY.
CLINTON KELLY, WILL YOU ASSIST
ME IN THIS MISSION?
>> I WOULD LOVE TO BE YOUR MAN
SERVANT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IN THE KITCHEN.
>> I FEEL A LITTLE WEIRD RIGHT
NOW BUT --
>> I APOLOGIZE.
>> IT LOOKS TO ME LIKE SANTA'S
SMOKING!
>> I'M GONNA BACK UP.
>> NO, I'M JUST HAVING A LITTLE
OUT-OF-BODY EXPERIENCE.
>> IT'S ALL RIGHT, CLINTON.
>> I HAD TOO MUCH SUGAR IN ONE
HOUR.
>> WE'LL JUST MAKE SOME OF
THESE, IT'LL GET YOU ALL
STRAIGHTENED BACK OUT.
SO, THIS IS REAL EASY TO MAKE.
WE HAVE FLOUR HERE, I'M GONNA
PUT IN --
>> AM I STIRRING THIS WHILE
YOU'RE DOING IT?
>> YEAH, YOU'RE GONNA HELP.
>> WHISKING IT OR WITH A SPOON?
>> YOU CAN WHISK IT BECAUSE I'M
GONNA ADD THIS OTHER STUFF.
>> SO, YOU KNOW, WHEN I'M
COOKING SAVORY I NEVER REALLY
MEASURE ANYTHING.
WITH BAKING YOU WANNA BE A
LITTLE MORE PRECISE.
>> YES.
>> BECAUSE IT'S NOT AS
WILLY-NILLY.
AND I CAME UP WITH THIS DESSERT
WHEN I WAS GETTING READY FOR
"CHOPPED ALL-STARS" BECAUSE I
WAS WORRIED THAT I HAD TO MAKE A
DESSERT IN LIKE SECONDS, SO I
WAS PRACTICING DIFFERENT
DESSERTS AT HOME AND THIS ONE
WORKS VERY, VERY WELL.
SO THE FLOUR, THE SUGAR -- IT'S
THREE-QUARTERS CUP OF FLOUR, A
CUP OF SUGAR, A GOOD PINCH OF
SALT, AND THEN A LITTLE BIT OF
ORANGE ZEST.
AND BECAUSE THESE ARE SO SWEET,
YOU REALLY NEED THAT SALT IN
THERE.
IT HELPS TO BRING OUT THE FLAVOR
AND ROUND OUT THE WHOLE THING.
I THINK THE BIGGEST MISTAKE
PEOPLE MAKE WITH PASTRIES IS NOT
PUTTING SALT IN THEM.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> ARE YOU FEELING ME CARLA?
>> I'M FEELING YOU.
NOT AS MUCH AS CLINTON, BUT I'M
FEELING YA.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I HAVEN'T TOUCHED ANYTHING.
>> HEY.
>> DANGEROUS.
>> LET ME TELL YOU, THAT SWEATER
AIN'T GONNA WIN YOU ANY POINTS
WITH ME, BUDDY.
>> SORRY.
>> SO JUST LIKE THAT.
AND NOW I HAVE MELTED BUTTER,
KEEP WHISKING, KEEP WHISKING.
DON'T STOP, CLINTON, WHISK!
ALL RIGHT, THIS IS TWO STICKS OF
MELTED BUTTER.
>> WHOA!
>> I JUST MELTED IT IN THE
MICROWAVE AT 30 TO 45 SECONDS
JUST TO KEEP ON IT.
DARK, BITTERSWEET CHOCOLATE.
>> OKAY.
>> ALL RIGHT.
IN GOES THAT, THAT'S ABOUT
1 1/3 CUPS.
WE GOTTA MAKE SURE WE SCRAPE THE
BOWL.
WHISK FASTER, KELLY, FASTER!
ACTUALLY, IT DOESN'T MATTER, I
JUST WANNA SEE YOU WORK A LITTLE
HARDER.
[ LAUGHTER ]
AND NOW, FOUR WHOLE EGGS.
ARE YOU READY?
>> THIS IS SO MUCH HARDER THAN
HERBS, CLINTON.
>> I KNOW USUALLY --
>> ALWAYS COMPLAINING ABOUT THE
HERBS!
AND NOW I PUT YOU TO WORK AND --
ALL RIGHT.
[ SIGH ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> SO HERE'S THE BEAUTIFUL THING
ABOUT THIS, I JUST CALL IT
LITERALLY A CUP CAKE.
BECAUSE IT'S A CAKE THAT WE BAKE
IN A CUP.
AND WE DO IT IN THE MICROWAVE
AND IT ALMOST BECOMES LIKE A
MOLTEN, CHOCOLATE CAKE.
>> MMM.
>> AND I LIKE TO GARNISH IT WITH
THINGS THAT ARE A LITTLE BIT
LIKE TART TO CUT THROUGH IT.
LIKE ANYTHING CITRUSY THAT'S IN
HERE, BOURBON-TYPE CHERRIES --
ALL THAT KIND OF STUFF WORKS
REALLY, REALLY WELL TO CUT
THROUGH.
BUT YOU CAN ALSO SERVE IT WITH
WHIPPED CREAM.
YOU GUYS HAVE HAD FLOURLESS
CHOCOLATE CAKE?
>> YEAH.
>> SURE.
>> YEAH, BUT THERE'S FLOUR IN
THIS ONE.
>> I UNDERSTAND, BUT I'M JUST
TRYING TO EXPLAIN THE
CONSISTENCY, BATALI.
IT'S MORE LIKE A MOLTEN
CHOCOLATE CAKE.
>> I GOT YA.
>> A MOLTEN CHOCOLATE CAKE.
I'M SURE THERE'S SOME BIG
ITALIAN WORD FOR "MOLTEN."
GIVE ME "MOLTEN CHOCOLATE CAKE"
IN ITALIAN, M.B.
>> NO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> CHOCOLATO VESUVIO!
>> YOU ALREADY HAVE A MAN-SLAVE
OVER THERE --
>> ALL RIGHT, SO LOOK.
>> HE'S SAID IT RIGHT.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
>> CHOCOLATO VESUVIETO!
>> CHOCOLATO A LA VESUVIETO!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> SO, HERE IS THE COOLEST THING
ABOUT THIS DESSERT.
YOU CAN HAVE THIS BATTER READY
BEFORE YOUR FRIENDS, FAMILY,
NEPHEWS COME OVER.
AND WHEN THEY'RE COMING OVER,
YOU CAN LOAD THE CUPS AS YOU GO,
AND YOU COULD EVEN DO ONE AT A
TIME, BECAUSE THEY ONLY TAKE
THREE MINUTES ONCE YOU PUT THEM
IN.
OR YOU COULD DO A COUPLE AT A
TIME FOR A COUPLE PEOPLE.
>> DO THEY RISE?
>> THEY RISE A LITTLE BIT AND
THEN THEY FALL.
COULD YOU OPEN UP THE MACHINE?
>> DING!
>> SO, LOOK, WE PUT THESE RIGHT
IN HERE, RIGHT IN THE CENTER.
I AM ON THE HIGHEST SETTING
RIGHT NOW.
CLOSE THE DOOR, THREE MINUTES,
LOOK FOR THE START BUTTON.
BOOM.
AND IN THREE MINUTES, WHEN WE
GET BACK FROM COMMERCIAL, WE ARE
GOING TO HAVE A DELICIOUS,
DESSERT TOPPED WITH TART
CHERRIES AND WHIPPED CREAM.
STICK AROUND.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
DELICIOUS HERSHEY'S CHOCOLATEH,
WITH 30% LESS FAT?
HERSHEY'S SIMPLE
PLEASURES CHOCOLATE.
30% LESS FAT, 100% DELICIOUS.
[ Female Announcer ]
NOW YOUR BEST ACCESSORY
CAN BE YOUR SMILE.
WITH COLGATE OPTIC WHITE
TOOTHPASTE.
IT WHITENS OVER 2 SHADES MORE
THAN A LEADING
WHITENING TOOTHPASTE.
SO WITH COLGATE OPTIC WHITE,
THE ONLY ACCESSORY YOU NEED
TO LOOK FABULOUS
IS YOUR SMILE.
COLGATE OPTIC WHITE.
WHITER TEETH IN 1 WEEK.
NOW TRY NEW COLGATE
OPTIC WHITE MOUTHWASH.
FOR A WHITER SMILE EVEN FASTER,
USE THE WHOLE WHITENING LINE.
WHITER TEETH IN 5 DAYS.
[ ding! ]
LOSING YOUR CHEX MIX TOO EASILY?
TIME TO DEPLOY
THE BORING-POTATO CHIP
DECOY BAG.
THEN NO ONE WILL WANT TO STEAL
THE DELICIOUSNESS.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
ONLY CHEX MIX
IS A BAG OF INTERESTING.
A DELICIOUS NEW WAY TO GET
ESSENTIAL VITAMINS YOU NEED.
JUST BITE
INTO THE TASTY SHELL...
TO A CHEWY VITAMIN CORE
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
NEW CENTRUM FLAVOR BURST.
INTO JOHN STAMOS.
HONEY! I THINK
I'M GETTING BURNED!
EAT.
♪
TASTES PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
[ men grunting ]
OPEN!
[ Male Announcer ] OIKOS.
POSSIBLY THE BEST YOGURT
IN THE WORLD.
♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>>> LOOK AT THAT!
THREE MINUTES.
THEY LOOK DELICIOUS.
YOU COULD SEE HOW THEY KIND OF
LIFTED UP THERE.
I LIKE TO CUT A LITTLE POCKET IN
THEM, AND THEN PUT IN THOSE NICE
BOURBON-SOAKED BERRIES.
BUT AGAIN, YOU COULD TOP THEM
WITH WHATEVER YOU WANT.
OBVIOUSLY, THE BOURBON-SOAKED
BERRIES ARE NOT GOOD FOR THE
KIDDIES, UNLESS YOU WANT THEM TO
SLEEP.
[ LIGHT LAUGHTER ]
A LITTLE BIT OF WHIPPED CREAM ON
TOP.
AND THEN I GO OVER TO MY
FRIENDS.
AND THESE ARE ABOUT 79 CENTS A
SERVING.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
CHECK IT OUT.
>> WOW.
>> IT'S LIKE A SOUFFLE WITHOUT
ALL THE WORKS.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I MEAN, IT'S DENSER THAN A
SOUFFLE, BUT IT'S JUST A REALLY
QUICK, FUN, EASY DESSERT THAT I
THINK THAT YOU COULD MAKE AT THE
LAST MINUTE FOR A HOLIDAY.
OBVIOUSLY, YOU COULD GARNISH IT
WITH DIFFERENT THINGS IF IT'S
FOR CHILDREN OR ADD DIFFERENT
SPICES TO IT.
I MEAN, YOU COULD ADD CINNAMON
TO IT, YOU COULD ADD WHATEVER
YOU WANT TO IT.
MY NEPHEWS LOVE IT AND WE MAKE
IT FOR THEM ALL THE TIME.
>> LOVE IT.
>> REALLY GOOD.
>> THE TEXTURE IS REALLY GOOD,
TOO.
YEAH.
>> HAVE SOME OF THIS.
>> I LIKE IT WITH THE WHIPPED
CREAM ON TOP.
>> AND IF YOU LIKE IT A LITTLE
BIT MORE RUNNY IN THE CENTER
LIKE A MOLTEN CAKE, YOU COULD GO
DOWN TO TWO MINUTES.
>> VERY GOOD.
ALL RIGHT, WELL, WE HAD A GREAT
TIME AT OUR UGLY SWEATER PARTY
TODAY.
IN FACT, I THINK WE SHOULD AWARD
SOME AUDIENCE MEMBERS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
MY CO-HOSTS AND I HAVE DECIDED
THAT WE'RE GOING TO AWARD A
THIRD PLACE, SECOND PLACE, AND A
FIRST PLACE.
THE THIRD PLACE WINNER WILL
RECEIVE A "CHEW" COOKBOOK, BUT
ONE THAT WE'VE BEEN USING AS A
DOOR STOPPER IN THE MEN'S
BATHROOM FOR A WHILE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
AND, THIS UGLY SWEATER TROPHY.
AND THIRD PLACE GOES TO --
YOU IN THE FIREPLACE SWEATER,
THERE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
>> DOMINIQUE.
BRIGANTINE, NEW JERSEY.
>> VERY GOOD.
ARE YOU EXCITED ABOUT THIS
AWARD?
>> I'M REALLY EXCITED.
>> HOW IS THAT FIRE RUNNING?
>> PAD.
>> OH, IT'S AN iPAD.
>> YEAH.
>> IN YOUR SWEATER.
ADORABLE, LOVE IT.
[ LIGHT LAUGHTER ]
ALL RIGHT, GREAT.
THANK YOU, ALL RIGHT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
ALL RIGHT.
>> THAT'S A VERY GOOD IDEA.
>> SECOND PLACE.
SECOND PLACE WILL BE AWARDED A
"CHEW" COOKBOOK THAT HAS BEEN
SIGNED BY OUR EXECUTIVE
PRODUCER, GORDON ELLIOTT, AND NO
ONE ELSE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
AND THIS LOVELY HOLIDAY MANTEL
DECORATIVE PIECE.
OKAY.
SECOND PRIZE WINNER IS --
YOU SIR, IN THE TINSEL SLEEVES
THERE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
>> DON, AND I'M FROM READING,
PENNSYLVANIA.
>> PENNSYLVANIA.
OKAY, DID YOU MAKE THIS SWEATER
YOURSELF?
>> NO, MY PARTNER MADE IT.
>> OH, OKAY.
AND WHERE ARE YOU GOING TO STICK
THAT TROPHY?
>> I'M NOT SURE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> ALL RIGHT.
OKAY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
AND OUR FIRST PLACE WINNER --
THE UGLIEST OR MAYBE JUST THE
MOST AMAZING SWEATER IN THE
ROOM.
YOU WILL WIN THIS.
HALF A MIRROR BALL TROPHY.
[ AUDIENCE OOHS ]
AND A "CHEW" COOKBOOK THAT HAS
BEEN SIGNED BY ALL FIVE OF US.
YOU IN THE CHRISTMAS TREE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
THERE YOU GO!
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME, DARLING?
WHERE ARE YOU FROM?
>> JESSE -- FROM CLEVELAND,
OHIO.
>> CLEVELAND, OHIO!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
CLEVELAND ROCKS.
WELL, CONGRATULATIONS.
NEW WINE GLASS, I LIKE YOUR WAY
OF THINKING.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT, I THINK THAT'S ALL
THE TIME WE HAVE FOR TODAY.
RIGHT?
SO THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING
US.
YOU'RE ALL GORGEOUS IN YOUR OWN
WAY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
YOU CAN GO TO THECHEW.COM FOR
"LAST BITES."
OH, AND DON'T FORGET R.C., OUR
AUDIENCE WARM UP FELLOW IN THE
GINGERBREAD MAN COSTUME.
"CHRISTMAS ACROSS AMERICA"
TOMORROW WHEN SOUTHERN
SWEETHEART, KADEE STRICKLAND
JOINS US.
AND DR. OZ MAKES A HOUSE CALL TO
OUR KITCHEN.
"GENERAL HOSPITAL" IS UP NEXT.
HAVE A GREAT DAY, EVERYBODY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪
>> Sabrina: [ SIGHS ]
SHE IS SO BEAUTIFUL.
>> Felix: THAT'S THE SEXIEST
BITCH.
WE ARE NOT WORTHY.
>> Sabrina: OH, CAN YOU ACTUALLY
BELIEVE THAT WE'RE HERE, IN NEW
YORK, FOR THE HOLIDAYS, IN
CoeCoe COSMETICS HEADQUARTERS?!
>> Felix: BREATHE.
HMM?
>> Sabrina: BREATHING.
BREATHING.
>> Felix: NOW TAKE IT IN --
BECAUSE THIS IS NO TWO-BIT,
BACKWOODS WANNABE, LIKE MELADOR
OR FUSION.
THIS IS THE BIG TIME.
[ CHUCKLES ]
>> Sabrina: WHAT?
>> Felix: I'M JUST THINKING
ABOUT WHAT THE SUCKERS IN PORT
CHARLES ARE UP TO WHILE WE'RE
GETTING OUR WHEEL AND DEAL ON.
>> Sabrina: [ SQUEALS ]
>> Felix: GIVE ME SOME.
UNH. UNH.