AND STOOD OUTSIDE FOR A VIGIL.
I AM KATIE MARZULO.
WE ARE WAITING FOR A NEWS
CONFERENCE AT ANY MOMENT.
AS SOON AS SOMEONE APPROACHES
THAT PODIUM WE WILL GO OUT THERE
LIVE.
AUTHORITIES HOPE TO RELEASE THE
IDENTITIES OF THE VICTIMS THIS
MORNING.
FIRST WE WILL GO TO SANDY HOOK
WI,
CONNECTICUT WITH THE VERY
LATEST.
>> GOOD MORNING.
THIS COMMUNITY IS JUST BEGINNING
THE PROCESS THIS UNIMAGINABLE
HORROR, INNOCENT LIVES LOST AT
SCHOOL.
>> IT ALL STARTED ON A SEEMINGLY
ORDINARY DAY IN A MOST
UNLIKELIEST OF PLACES A SLEEPY
NEW ENGLAND TOWN ONE OF THE
WORST MASS SHOOTINGS IN THIS
NATION'S HISTORY.
>> SANDY HOOKS STEWED SCHOOL.
>> ADAM LANZA SEEN AS A TEENAGER
HEADING TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WEARING A BULLETPROOF VEST AND
ARMED WITH A SEMI AUTOMATIC
ASSAULT RIFLE AND TWO HIGH
POWERED PISTOLS LIKE THESE.
>> EVERYONE WAS SCARED.
A REALLY BIG KID IN MY CLASS I
HAVE NEVER SEEN HIM CRY AND HE
WAS CRYING.
IT WAS SCARY FOR ALL OF US.
>> POLICE SAY LANZA HAD SHOT HIS
MOTHER AT HER HOME AND HE WENT
TO THE SCHOOL KILLED 26 TEAM
MOSTLY CHILDREN AND THEN
HIMSELF.
AFTER THE RAMPAGE ENDED TEACHERS
LED THE STUDENTS SINGLE FILE
FROM THE SCHOOLHOUSE TO A NEARBY
FIRE STATION.
>> WE GOT IN LINES AND WE HAD TO
CLOSE OUR EYES AND WE ALL PUT
OUR HANDS ON OTHER PEOPLE'S
SHOULDERS AND THEN HOUR TEACHER
HOLD THE FIRST PERSON'S HAND AND
SHE LED US OUT.
>> PANFRANTIC PARENTS ARRIVED A
SCHOOL SIMPLY HOPING TO FIND
THEIR CHILDREN ALIVE.
>> HEARTBREAKING.
>> AUTHORITIES ARE STILL
SEARCHING FOR ANSWERS.
>> WE WILL GO BACKWARDS AS FAR
AS WE HAVE TO GO IN THIS
INVESTIGATION.
HOPEFULLY WE WILL STUMBLE ON
ANSWERS.
>> THEY ARE ALSO QUESTIONING
ADAM'S BROTHER RYAN AND FATHER
PETER TO LOOK AT WHAT LED TO THE
SHOOTING SPREE.
RESIDENTS SAY THE HOAR ANOTHER
STILL DOESN'T SEEM REAL.
>> STUD I BE PIN-- SHOULD I BE D
TO SEE IF IT IS REAL.
>> FEELS LIKE A DREAM AND A BAD
DREAM.
>> IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
>> SOME OF THE BODIES HAVE BEEN
REMOVED FROM THE SCHOOL.
THE REST WILL BE REMOVED LATER
TODAY.
WE ARE HEARING REPORTS THAT
CONNECTICUT DOESN'T HAVE ENOUGH
MEDICAL EXAMINERS TO PERFORM
AUTOPSIES AND WILL ASK OTHER
STATES FOR HELP.
REPORTING LIVE IN SANDY HOOK,
NOW BACK TO YOU.
>>> THANK YOU.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE THIS
MORNING ABOUT ADAM LANZA.
HE WAS AN HONOR STUDENT IN HIGH
SCHOOL.
LANZA DID NOT APPEAR IN HIS HIGH
SCHOOL YEARBOOK.
HIS SPOT ON THE PAGE READS
CAMERA SHY.
HIS PARENTS WERE DIVORCED AND
ORDERED TO TAKE A PARENTING
EDUCATION PROGRAM.
HIS FATHER IS VICE PRESIDENT OF
GE CAPITAL.
BOTH PARENTS HAD NUMEROUS
LEGALLY REGISTERED WEAPONS.
IN THE EARLY HOURS OF THE
TRAGEDY POLICE IDENTIFIED ADAM'S
BROTHER RYAN AT THE GUNMAN.
THIS IS HIM BEING HANDCUFFED BY
AUTHORITIES.
LANZA TOLD OFFICERS HE HADN'T
SEEN HIS BROTHER IN RECENT
YEARS.
RYAN IS NOT A SUSPECT AND HE IS
COOPERATING IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
>>> A FEW HOURS FROM NOW A
PRAYER VIGIL IS TAKING PLACE IN
SAN FRANCISCO AT THE AIDS
MEMORIAL GROVE.
VIGILS POPPED OCCUPY ALL OVER
THE COUNTRY INCLUDING THIS ONE
IN MILL VALLEY WHERE ABOUT 20
PEOPLE TURNED OUT TO REMEMBER
THE VICTIMS.
WE HAVE MORE ON ANOTHER VIGIL
HELD LAST NIGHT IN WALNUT CREEK.
>> THIS CAPPED LIGHT VIGIL TAME
KOTH WITHIN A FEW HOURS.
ASHLEY MONTGOMERY WAS XHELED TO
DO SOMETHING AFTER WATCHING NEWS
REPORTS FROM CONNECTICUT THROUGH
OUT THE DAY.
>> SOMETHING LIKE THIS, OUR
HEARTS ARE BROKEN BUT WHEN WE
GATHER HERE LIKE THIS IT SHOWS
OUR SPIRITS AREN'T BROKEN.
>> AMONG THOSE IN THE CROWD WERE
ELEMENTARY AGED SCHOOL STUDENTS.
>> DID YOU HEAR IT THROUGH
FRIENDS OR DID YOU HEAR IT ON
THE PHONE?
>> I HEARD IT FROM MY MOM.
>> HIS MOTHER TELLS ME SHE HAD A
CONVERSATION WITH HIM ABOUT THE
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT WHEN SHE
PICKED HIM UP FOR SCHOOL.
>> I THOUGHT IT WAS IMPORTANT
FOR THEM TO KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
USUALLY I TRY TO SHIELD THEM
FROM EVENTS BUT IT WAS TOO
CLOSE.
>> ANOTHER MOTHER TELLS ME SHE
ALSO SPOKE WITH THE KIDS IN H  P
HOPING TO HELP THEM UNDERSTAND
WHAT OTHERS ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> I CAN ONLY IMAGE THE PARENT
GOING TO SCHOOL HOPING THAT IT
WASN'T MY CHILD IN THAT
CLASSROOM, BUT AT THE SAME TIME
IF IT WASN'T THEN YOU ARE
HORRIFIED BY THE FACT THAT THAT
WAS MY DAUGHTER'S BEST FRIEND IN
THAT CLASSROOM.
>> BILL MILLER IS HEAD OF
INDEPENDENT SCHOOL.
>> I TALKED WITH THEM TODAY AND
SAID, LOOK, THESE WERE OUR
CHILDREN.
THESE AWERE OUR STUDENTS.
THESE ARE MY TEACHERS.
THESE WERE OUR TEACHERS.
THESE ARE OUR COLLEAGUES THAT
FELL.
>> A COUPLE DOZEN PEOPLE TURNED
OUT FOR THIS VIGIL IN WALNUT
CREEK.
THEY LEFT BEHIND A CANDLE, A
CARD AND FLOWERS TO HONOR THOSE
WHO WERE KILLED IN CONNECTICUT
ON FRIDAY.
IN WALNUT CREEK, ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> ANOTHER VIGIL, A VIGIL OF
ONE IN SAN JOSE.
THE MOTHER OF 6-YEAR-OLD SHOWED
THIS PICTURE ON TWITTER.
THE YOUNG BOY LIGHTING A CANDLE.
SOME WHO WERE HIS AGE.
SAN JOSE LOVES SHES CONNECTICUT,
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> THE MASS SHOOTING HAS BEEN
EMOTIONAL FOR PARENTS.
YOU MAY BE WONDERING HOW TO TALK
TO YOUR CHILDREN ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED.
THE DEAN OF PSYCHOLOGY AT SANTA
CLARA UNIVERSITY TELLS ABC NEWS
YOU NOOIRSD TO CONFRONT YOUR OWN
FEELS WHETHER THOSE INCLUDE
FEAR, ANGER OR ANXIETY AND THEN
SPEAK CALMLY TO YOUR CHILD AND
LISTEN INTENTLY AND THE TIME DO
IT IS NOW BEFORE THEY SEE IT
SOMEWHERE ELSE.
>> I WOULD TALK TODAY.
I DON'T THINK IT'S WORTH WAITING
UNTIL THE END OF THE WEEKEND OR
WAITING UNTIL THERE'S A RIGHT
MOMENT.
THE MOMENT IS NOW.
THE KIDS ARE EXPERIENCING THIS.
THEY HAVE TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
DOES THIS REALLY MEAN WHEN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HAS THIS KIND
OF TRAGEDY.
>> DR. SAYS YOU SHOULD REASSURE
YOUR KIDS THEY ARE SAFE AT
SCHOOL BEFORE THEY GO BACK TO
CLASS ON MONDAY.
WE WANT TO TAKE YOU LIVE TO
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
THAT IS WHERE WE ARE WAITING FOR
A NEWS CONFERENCE TO BEGIN AT
ANY MOMENT.
AUTHORITIES MAY RELEASE THE
NAMES OF THE VICTIM THIS IS
MORNING.
SOME OF THE VIC TAMES BODIES ARE
INSIDE THE SCHOOL OTHERS HAVE
BEEN REMOVED.
IT HAS BEEN A SLOW PROCESS
TRYING TO POSITIVELY IDENTIFY
THE CHILDREN AS MOST KIDS DON'T
CARRY IDENTIFICATION.
THERE ARE 27 VICTIMS 20 OF THEM
ARE CHILDREN 7 ADULTS THAT
INCLUDES THE SHOOTER'S MOTHER
NANCY LANZA AND TEACHER VICKY
SOTO.
ANOTHER ADULT VICTIM HAS BEEN
IDENTIFIED 37-YEAR-OLD DONNA
HOCHSPRUNG.
DAMNED LANZA THIS IS A PICTURE
FROM 2005.
THEY ARE INTERVIEWING MEMBERS OF
HIS FAMILY AND FRIENDS THAT
INCLUDES HIS BROTHER AND FATHER
TREEING TO PUT TOGETHER ANY
EXPLANATION FOR THIS TRAGEDY.
WE HAVE MORE COMING UP IN THE
NEWSCAST.
STAY WITH ABC 7 NEWS FOR
CONTINUING COVERAGE.
YOU CAN GET OUR ABC 7 NEWS APP
AND GET THE PUSH OPERATIONS.
WE ARE UPDATING OUR FACEBOOK
PAGE AT FACEBOOK.COM ABC 7 NEWS.
LET'S GET OUR FIRST LOOK AT THE
WEATHER CHECK IN WITH
METEOROLOGIST LISA ARGIN.
>> WE ARE LOOKING FROM OUR ROOF
CAMERA WHERE WE HAVE CHILLY
CONDITIONS NUMBERS IN THE 30s
AND 40s.
AS WE CHECK OUT LIVE DOPPLER 7
THIS IS A SYSTEM OFF TO THE
NORTH.
IT IS PRETTY FAR OFF.
THIS WILL BRING THE LIGHT RAIN
OUR WAY.
41 OAKLAND 47 SAN FRANCISCO 29
FAIRFIELD.
33 LIVERMORE.
IF YOU ARE HEADING OUT
TEMPERATURES IN THE UPPER 20s TO
MID 40s.
OTHERWISE RAIN DEVELOPING THIS
AFTERNOON LOW TO MID 50s.
NUMBERS VERY COOL.
WE WILL SEE THE SHOWERS CONTINUE
INTO THE EVENING HOURS.
WE WILL LET YOU KNOW IF WE HAVE
RAIN FOR THE REST OF THE WEEKEND
AND THE OUTLOOK FOR NEXT WEEK.
>> IT IS 5:09 IN OUR COVERAGE OF
THE DEADLY ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING CONTINUES.
UP NEXT YOU WILL HEAR TWO YOUNG
BROTHERS DESCRIBE THE DAY THAT
WILL CERTAINLY FOREVER CHANGE
THEIR LIVES.
AND WE HAVE MUCH MORE ON THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE WAITING FOR A LIVE NEWS
CONFERENCE OUT OF NEWTOWN WHERE
WE EXPECT THE CHILDREN'S
IDENTITY TO BE REVEALED.
STAY WITH US.
[ Penélope ] I FOUND
THE BEST CAFE IN THE WORLD.
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
>> THEN WE HID BECAUSE EVERYONE
THOUGHT IT WAS AN ANIMAL.
THEN WHEN WE HEARD GUN SHOTS
THAT DIDN'T SOUND LIKE OUR ARMY
GUN SHOTS OR POLICEMAN GUN
SHOTS, WE ALL HID INTO MY
TEACHER'S OFFICE.
IT WAS SCARY.
WE HAD TO HIDE THERE.
WE COULD BE EASILY SHOT BECAUSE
WE WERE REALLY NEAR THAT GUY.
>> THAT GUY COULD HAVE KICKED IN
IN THE DOOR THAT THEY WERE IN.
>> EVERYTHING WAS FINE.
EVERYTHING WAS JUST NORMAL AS A
REGULAR FRIDAY MORNING WOULD BE
TO EVERYONE, AND THEN IT ALL
JUST CHANGED.
IT ALL CHANGED.
>> THEN IT ALL CHANGED.
>> YOUNG BOYS WISE BEYOND THEIR
YEARS.
THAT IS HOW BROTHERS ETHAN AND
SAN PALEY FOURTH GRADE STUDENTS
DESCRIBED THE CHAOS AS SOON AS
SHOTS WERE FIRED.
WE WILL HAVE CONTINUING COVERAGE
OF THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT ON ABC 7 NEWS THIS
MORNING.
THERE WILL BE A SPECIAL EDITION
OF "GOOD MORNING AMERICA"" AT
7:00 A.M.  IT WILL BE BROADCAST
FROM THE SCENE OF THE SHOOTING
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>>> AN INVESTIGATION IS UNDERWAY
AFTER AN OFF DUTY CHP OFFICER
WAS KILLED IN A HEAD ON ACCIDENT
IN FAIRFIELD.
IT HAPPENED BEFORE 6:00 ON
HIGHWAY 12 AT RED TOP ROAD LAST
NIGHT.
THE OFFICER WAS ON HIS PERSONAL
MOTORCYCLE WHEN HE HIT A PICKUP
TRUCK TURNING LEFT IN FRONT OF
HIM.
THE OFFICER WAS THROWN AND HIT
BY A HONDA.
THE UNIDENTIFIED OFFICER WAS
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE.
>> AN 82-YEAR-OLD MAN IS FACING
FELONY CHARGES OF VEHICULAR
MANSLAUGHTER AFTER HE WAS
INVOLVED IN A TERRIFYING CRASH
THAT TOOK THREE LIVES YESTERDAY
ON INTERSTATE 280 IN SAN MATEO
COUNTY.
NICK SMITH HAS THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION.
>> SKY 7 H. D. WAS OVER THE
SCENE MINUTES BEFORE THE CRASH
AT I 280 ON EDGEWOOD ROAD.
THE DREYER PULLED NEXT TO THE
MEDIAN TO FIX A FLAT TIRE.
IT WAS THEN POLICE SAY THIS
BLACK VOLKSWAGON SWERVED INTO
THE CENTER DIVIDE AND CRASHED
INTO THE LEXUS.
>> THERE WERE FOUR PEOPLE TOTAL.
THREE OF THE PEOPLE WERE
PRONOUNCED AT THE SCENE.
>> A 28-YEAR-OLD MAN AND WOMEN.
IT WASN'T IMMEDIATELY CLEAR WHO
WAS IN AND WHAT WAS OUTSIDE OF
THE CAR.
THE EXTENT OF THE DAMAGE AND
FORCE OF THE IMPACT ARE
IMPORTANT CLUES FOR
INVESTIGATORS.
>> LOOKS LIKE SPEED WAS A
FACTOR.
>> ABC 7 NEWS LEARNED THE DRIVER
OF THIS BLACK VOGUES WAGON IS AN
82-YEAR-OLD MAN IN THE AREA.
HE WAS TAKEN TO THE MEDICAL
CENTER FOR NONLIFE THREATENING
INJURIES.
ONCE HE IS RELEASED HE WILL FACE
FELONY CHARGES OF VEHICULAR
MANSLAUGHTER.
THE CRASH CAUSED A BACKUP FOR
MILES.
>> INVESTIGATORS SAY NEITHER
ALCOHOL OR DRUGS APPEAR TO BE A
FACTOR.
IF THEY ARE STILL IN THE
PRELIMINARY STAGES IN THE
INVESTIGATION.
NICK SMITH, ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> LISA ARGIN JOINING US.
IT IS COLD THIS MORNING.
CAN I SAY FREEZING.
>> YOU CAN SAY BELOW FREEZING.
29 IN FAIRFIELD.
WE HAVE FOG AROUND THE BAY AS
WELL.
RIGHT NOW EMERIVILLE
TEMPERATURES ARE CONSIDERABLY
WARMER THAN THE NORTH HILL
VALLEYS.
WE ARE IN THE 40s HERE.
DOESN'T SOUND WARM BUT IT'S ALL
RELATIVE.
WE WILL TALK ABOUT LIGHT RAIN
AND IF IT LASTS THROUGH THE
WEEKEND.
>> TAKING YOU BACK OUT LIVE TO
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT WHERE WE
ARE AWAIT AGNES CONFERENCE THAT
SHOULD BEGIN A-- AWAITING A NEW
CONFERENCE.
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
>> WELCOME BACK EVERYBODY.
WE WANT TO START YOU OFF WITH
WEATHER AT THIS TIME SO YOU KNOW
HOW MUCH YOU NEED TO BUNDLE UP,
WHICH IS MAYBE THERE'S NOT
ENOUGH TO BUNDLE UP.
OO DON'T PUT AWAY THE RAIN GEAR
EITHER.
WE ARE LOOKING AT A PRETTY
UNSETTLED TIME OF IT.
IT IS DRY BUT BOY IS IT COLD.
YOU ARE RIGHT.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT
TEMPERATURES THAT HAVE DROPPED
BELOW FREEZING.
HERE'S A LIVE LOOK OUTSIDE FROM
VULMER PEAK I BELIEVE.
WE ARE LOOKING AT ALL OF THE
TWIJING LIGH -- TWINKLING LIGHT.
RAINSHOWERS OFF TO THE NORTH.
IN LLEYTONVILLE.
THIS IS WHAT IS GOING TO WORK
DOWN INTO THE BAY AREA BY THIS
AFTERNOON.
33 LIVERMORE.
THE WARM SPOT IN SAN FRANCISCO.
WE HAVE FOG FROM NEVADA TO SANTA
ROSA.
GOOD VISIBILITY AROUND THE
COAST.
INCREASING CLOUDS AROUND THE
BAY.
PARTLY CLOUDY SKIES IN THE SOUTH
DAY BAY.
THE RAIN WILL BE DEVELOPING FOR
ALL OF US.
WE ARE TALKING AFTERNOON LIGHT
RAIN LINGERING THROUGH THE
AFTERNOON AND EVENING HOURS AND
A CHANCE OF SHOWERS TOMORROW.
IT WILL TAKE YOU DRTHROUGH IT HR
BY HOUR.
SEVERAL SYSTEMS HEADING OUR WAY.
HERE IS THE FIRST ONE.
WE ARE LOOKING FOR LIGHT RAIN
AMOUNT.
IT IS NOT A BIG RAIN MAKER.
IN FACT OVER THE WEEKEND LIGHT
RAIN BUT THE TEMPERATURES WILL
STAY COOL FOR THE NEXT SEVERAL
DAYS.
THE NEXT WEATHER SYSTEM WILL
BRING US MORE RAIN BUT STILL A
LITTLE COLD OUT THERE.
COLD SYSTEM BRINGING SNOW
SHOWERS PERHAPS UP INTO LAKE
COUNTY.
OTHERWISE RAIN IS OFF THE COAST
BY NOONTIME AND AS WE HEAD
FURTHER INTO THE AFTERNOON AND
EVENING HOURS YOU CAN SEE
SCATTERED SHOWERS 11:00 TONIGHT.
SUNDAY MOST OF THE RAIN UP IN
THE NORTH BAY.
THIS IS 8:00 TOMORROW MORNING.
RO
LOOK AT THE REST OF THE DAY EAST
BAY AND SOUTH BAY NOT MUCH OF AN
ISSUE BUT STAYING RATHER COOL
TAKING YOU THROUGH THE REST OF
SUNDAY.
MONDAY AND MORE RAIN FROM
ANOTHER SYSTEM A MILDER SYSTEM
THAT COULD BUMP UP OUR
TEMPERATURES A LITTLE BIT.
THAT'S A TRADEOFF.
A TENTH TO A THIRD OF AN INCH
TRACE AMOUNTS AROUND SAN JOSE.
YOU SHOULD SEE SUNSHINE 52 SAN
JOSE LOW 50s SAN FRANCISCO.
WE ARE LOOKING AT 49 IN MORGAN
HIL.
53 SELEN,IS.
CLEE
>> FLUID 7 DAY OUTLOOK.
YOU HAVE TO COME BACK AND CHECK
BECAUSE THE TIMING DIFFERENT.
>>> THEY ARE HONORED THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING VICTIMS IN CONNECTICUT.
THIS WAS THE SCENE ON ESPN IN
DENVER WHERE FANS WERE ASKED TO
STAND BEFORE A GRIZZLY'S GAME.
LARRY BEAL BEGINS OUR MORNING
SPORTS WITH THE WARRIORS.
>> GOOD MORNING EVERYBODY.
SPORTS A DIVERSION AFTER WHAT WE
SAW IN CONNECTICUT.
WITH THAT IN MIND WE WILL START
WITH THE WARRIORS TRYING TO KEEP
THEIR PERFECT ROAD TRIP GOING IN
ORLANDO.
MORE THAN THEY HAVE HAD SINCE
1962 BUT THEY DID NOT HAVE IT IN
THIS GAME.
ORLANDO BLOCKED 10 SHOTS DURING
7-13 FOR THE REST OF THE LEAGUE
2-0 FOR THE REST OF THE STATE.
JJ REDIC BEATS THE BUZZER.
DAVID LEE BRINGING IT 24 POINTS
15 REBOUNDS HIS 6TH DOUBLE
DOUBLE IN A ROW.
WARRIORS NEVER CLOSER THAN A 9
POINT DEFICIT.
NELSON MAKING IT LOOK EASY.
99-85 THEY WILL END THE TRIP
TONIGHT IN ATLANTA.
LAKERS TRYING TO SNAP THEIR FOUR
GAME SKID ACROSS THE WIZARDS.
KOBE BRYANT DOING ALL HE CAN TO
WIELD THE LAKERS TO VICTORY.
NICE DISH 12 POINTS FOR HOWARD.
WIZARDS FANS YOU ROOT FOR THE
WIZARDS LIKE ONCE EVERY 10 YEARS
YOU GET A GOOD TEAM.
ALLEY-OOP TO WEBSTER.
HERE COMING DOWN THE LANE,
SOMEBODY GOT A BLOCK OUT.
NOBODY EVER BLOCKS US OUT ANY
MORE.
LASHGS STOPPED THE SKID 102-96.
STILL THEY ARE 10-14.
>> THE DE LA SALLE HIGH SCHOOL
TEAM LOOKS TO WIN THEIR 4TH
CONSECUTIVE TITLE AGAINST SAN
ANTONIO CORONA FROM SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
BOB LATTIS IS TWO WINS SHY OF
400 IN HIS CAREER.
HE IS OPENLY TALKING ABOUT
RETIREMENT.
HE LED THEM FOR 34 YEARS.
IT IS REALLY THE ONE AND ONLY
JOB HE EVER WANTED.
>> I WANTED TO BE A HIGH SCHOOL
TEACHER.
I WANTED TO BE AT THIS SCHOOL.
THAT IS WHEN I WAS 24 YEARS OLD.
NEVER GOT WANDER LUST OR WANTED
TO JUMP A LEVEL OR ANYTHING LIKE
THAT.
IT HAS BEEN VERY REWARDING.
IT HAS BEEN A GOOD CAREER.
I HAVE NO REGRETS WHATSOEVER.
>> HE'S AN AMAZING COACH.
THE 49 YEARS HEAD TO NEW ENGLAND
FOR TOMORROW NIGHT'S SHOW DOWN
AGAINST THE PATRIOTS.
IF THE 9ERS WIN THEY CLINCH A
PLAYOFF SPOT.
DON'T FORGET ABOUT THE BEST
OFFENSIVE WEAPON MR. FRANK GORE.
THEY REACHED THE 1,000 YARD MARK
FOR THE 6TH TIME IN HIS CAREER.
FRANCHISE RECORD IN RUSHING
TOUCHDOWNS WITH 50.
GORE BANGED UP DURING THIS
SEASON BUT HE'S A GUY THAT FINDS
A WAY TO BLOCK OUT THE PAIN.
>> IN FRANK CASE A LOT OF GUY'S
CASE THE LOVE OF THE GAME.
HOW MUCH HE LOVES FOOTBALL, HOW
MUCH HE LIKES PRACTICING AND
PLAYING THIS GAME.
THAT PLAYS A BIG PART IN MAKING
HIM SUCH A DURABLE GUY WEEK
AFTER WEEK.
>> AND RAIDERS HOST THE CHIEFS
SUNDAY.
HE PUTS HIS WBO JUNIOR FEATHER
WEIGHT TITLE AGAINST HOUSTON
AGAINST THE FLEXING JORGE.
THEY ARE GOOD FRIENDS.
DONAR WEIGHED IN AT 121 AND A
HALF.
ARSAY HAD TO TAKE EVERYTHING OFF
TO BARELY MAKE WEIGHT AT 122
POUNDS EVEN.
THAT IS A WRAP ON MORNING
SPORTS.
MIKE SHOEMAN WILL BE HERE WITH
YOUR HIGHLIGHTS AT 5, 6 AND
11:00 P.M.
HAVE A GREAT WEEK EVERYBODY.
>> COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
CONTINUES.
A COMMUNITY IN MOURNING TODAY.
WE JUST LEARNED THE IDENTITIES
OF SOME OF THE YOUNG VICTIMS IN
YESTERDAY'S ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE ARE WAITING FOR THAT
INFORMATION.
WE EXPECT IT THIS MORNING.
PLUS THIS.
>> TO BE ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
THERE ARE BAD GUYS OUT THERE NOW
WE NEED TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD
GUYS.
>> IN ALL OF THE TRAGEDY LIFE
SAVING STORIES, THE TEACHERS WHO
KEPT THE CHILDREN SAFE AND CALM
AS THE GUNMEN OPENED FIRE IN THE
CLASSROOM.
>> I AM LIVE IN GOLDEN GATE PARK
WHERE LATER THIS MORNING A VIGIL
IS SET TO REMEMBER THE VICTIMS
OF THE CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY.
THE PUBLIC IS WELCOME.
I WILL TEL
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
>> WE WILL TAKE YOU LIVE TO
NEWTOWN CONNECTICUT.
AUTHORITIES ARE EXPECTED TO
RELEASE MORE NAMES OF THE
VICTIMS OF THE SHOOTING AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SOME OF THE BODIES ARE STILL
INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
SOME HAVE BEEN REMOVED.
THERE ARE 27 VICTIMS.
20 OF THEM CHILDREN, 7 ADULTS.
ONE OF THE ADD DUPTS BEING THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER'S MOTHER.
SHE WAS FOUND AT HOME NOT AT
SCHOOL.
A COMMUNITY MOURNS ASKING WHY
DID THIS HAPPEN?
>>
>> THE FIRST WORD WAS CHILLING
IT ONLY GOT WORSE.
>> THEY ARE REPORTING MULTIPLE
FATALITIES INVOLVED IN THE
SHOOTING AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> WITH EACH NEW REPORT THE
HORROR DEEPENED.
>> THE NUMBER DEAD CLOSER TO 30
THAN TO 20 SAD EMPLOYS OF THEM
ARE CHILDREN.
>> WE KNOW THE DEATH TOLL IS 27.
20 OF THOSE KILLED ARE AGCHILDR
THE AGES BETWEEN 5 AND 10.
THERE ARE MANY MORE QUESTIONS
BUT THE MOST COMMON ONE IS WHY?
>> IN THESE TIMES OF TROUBLES
AND TREF VEIL WHERE THE
UNTHINKABLE HAPPENS IN OUR VERY
MIDST, OUR FAITH IS TESTED.
>> AS RESIDENTS OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT CAME TO VIGILS
FRIDAY NIGHT OFFICIALS CAME TO
THE SCENE TO PIECE TOGETHER WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> WE CONSIDER THIS TO BE NUMBER
ONE MASS I.
NUMBER TWO IT'S LIKE A BIG
PUZZLE.
WE HAVE TO PUT THE PIECES
TOGETHER TO TRY TO DRAW A
PICTURE AS TO HOW AND WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> AT THE CENTER OF THE PUZZLE
ADAM LANZA IDENTIFIED AS THE
SHOOTER.
HE HAD NO KNOWN CRIMINAL RECORD
BEFORE ENTERING THE SCHOOL
FRIDAY MORNING DRESSED IN FLACK
FATIGUES AND A MILITARY VEST.
HE WAS FOUND DEAD IN A CLASSROOM
BY HIS OWN HAND.
A FORMER CLASSMATE DESCRIBED HIM
AS QUIET.
>> HE WAS ALWAYS A LITTLE BIT
DIFFERENT.
HE MOSTLY STUCK TO HIMSELF.
BUT I DON'T KNOW IF YOU CAN SAY
THAT YOU COULD HAVE PREDICTED
THIS.
>> THE VICTIMS ARE BEING MOURNED
ACROSS THE NATION LIKE AT THIS
CANDLELIGHT VIGIL AT THE U.S.
CAPITOL FRIDAY NIGHT.
NOWHERE IS THE SADNESS MORE
PALPABLE THAN IN THIS SMALL
COMMUNITY.
>> YOU STRUGGLE TO FIND THE
WORDS AS TO WHAT HAPPENED.
>> EVEN AN EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAD TO FIGHT BACK TEARS.
>> THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY
PARENTS IN AMERICA WILL DO WHICH
IS HUG OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE
TIGHTER AND WE WILL TELL THEM
THAT WE LOVE THEM AND WE WILL
REMIND EACH OTHER HOW DEEPLY WE
LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT NOW.
>> ONE OF THE SIX ADULTS KILLED
WAS 47-YEAR-OLD DAWN HOCHSPRUNG
THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL.
SHE WAS KNOWN FOR HER PLAYFUL
PASSION JUST A MONTH AGO SHE
DRESSED UP AS THE SANDY HOOK
BOOK FAIR REWEARING -- FAIRY
WEARING A CROWN AND A DRESS THAT
LIGHTED UP INSPIRING FIRST
GRADERS TO READ.
THE GUNMAN ADAM LANZA AND HIS
BROTHER RYAN AND FATHER.
HE BEGAN SHOOTING HIS MOTHER AT
HIS FAMILY HOME AND LEFT ARMED
WITH TWO HAND GUNS AND A RIFLE.
HE FIRED WITH CHILLING ACCURACY
LEAVING ONLY ONE WOUNDED
SURVIVOR AT THE SCHOOL.
AUTHORITIES BELIEVE HE THEN SHOT
HIMSELF TO DEATH.
ABC NEWS LEARNED BOTH OF HIS
PARENTS LEGALLY OWN A NUMBER OF
GUNS INCLUDING A BUSHMASTER
RIFLE BUT IT'S NOT CLEAR IF ANY
OF THEIR WEAPONS WERE USED IN
THE CRIME.
A SCHOOL BUS DRIVER WHO KNEW
LANZA SAYS IT WAS TOTALLY
UNEXPECTED.
>> NICE KID.
VERY POOL LOI-- POLITE.
SHE RAISED VERY NICE BOYS TO ME.
IT'S A SHOCK TO KNOW THEM AND
REALIZE WHO THEY ARE AND WHAT HE
DID.
>>> WHEN ONE TEACHER HEARD GUN
FIRE SHE RACED TO HERD HER 15
STUDENTS INTO A TINY BATHROOM.
A QUICK THINKING FRANTIC EFFORT
TO SAVE THEIR YOUNG LIVES.
LISTENED TO WHAT HAPPENED.
>> ONE OF MY STUDENTS ON TOP OF
THE TOILET.
I KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN THERE.
I TOLD THEM IT'S GOING TO BE
OKAY.
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ALL RIGHT.
I PULLED A BOOK SHELF BEFORE I
CLOSED THE DOOR IN FRONT OF IT.
WE WERE COMPLETELY BARRICADED
IN.
I WAS SO AFRAID IF HE DID COME
IN HE WOULD HEAR US AND HE WOULD
JUST START SHOOTING THE DOOR.
I SAID WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET AND WE HAVE -- I SAID
THERE ARE BAD GUYS OUT THERE NOW
WE NEED TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD
GUYS.
I AM HEARING THE GUN FIRE IN THE
HALL WAY I AM THINKING IN MY
MIND, I AM THE FIRST CLASSROOM
WHY ISN'T HE COMING?
I AM THINKING WE ARE NEXT.
IN MY MIND I AM THINKING AS A
6-YEAR-OLD, 7-YEAR-OLD WHAT ARE
YOUR THOUGHTS?
I AM THINKING THAT I HAVE TO
ALMOST BE THEIR PARENT.
I HAVE TO TELL THEM.
I SAID I NEED YOU TO KNOW THAT I
LOVE YOU ALL VERY MUCH AND THAT
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE LAST
THING THEY WERE EVER GOING TO
HEAR.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T KNOW IF THAT'S
OKAY.
I WANTED THEM TO KNOW SOMEONE
LOVED THEM AND I WANTED THAT TO
BE ONE OF THE LAST THINGS THEY
HEARD.
NOT THE GUN FIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
>> 20/20 ANCHOR CRISCO MOW
RUSHED TO THE SCHOOL TO MAKE
SURE THEY MADE IT OUT.
T
ONE GIRL TALKS ABOUT THE HEROIC
ACTIONS OF HER TEACHER.
>> WHAT DO YOU REMEMBER?
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WE GOT TO SCHOOL.
WE DID EVERYTHING WE NEEDED TO
AND THEN WE HEARD ALL THIS
RACKET AT OUR CLASSROOM.
WE WERE ALL SCARED.
THEN WE HEARD THEM SAY GO IN
YOUR CUBBIES.
>> EVERYBODY WENT IN THEIR
CUBBIES.
>> DID YOU HEAR ANY MORE BAD
NOISES.
>> YES.
>> WHILE THAT WAS GOING ON YOUR
TEACHER WAS READING YOU BOOKS
AND KEEPING YOU CALM.
>> YEAH.
>> YOU HAVE A GOOD TEACHER DON'T
YOU?
>> UH-HUH.
>> YOU LOVE YOUR TEACHER.
>> DID YOU TEACHER SEEM NERVOUS?
>> NO.
>> SHE KEPT HER CALM AND TOLD
YOU A STORY.
>> UH-HUH.
>> DO YOU REMEMBER WHICH ONE?
>> SHE READ US THE NUT CRACKER
AND ANOTHER BOOK THAT WAS ABOUT
CHRISTMAS.
>> I LOVE THE NUT CRACKER.
DO YOU LOVE IT?
>> YES.
>> I AM AFRAID OF THE MOUSE
KING.
LITTLE SCARY LET'S BE HONEST,
RIGHT?
IT'S NOT JUST ME.
SO YOU ARE IN THERE, HOW DO YOU
LEAVE THE CLASSROOM?
>> WE GOT IN A LINE AND WE HAD
TO CLOSE OUR EYES.
>> YOU HAD TO CLOSE YOUR EYES?
>> YES.
>> WHEN YOU OPENED THEM WHERE
WERE YOU?
>> WE WERE WALKING DOWN TO THE
FIRE STATION.
>> WHAT HAPPENED THERE TODAY
HAPPENED AND IT'S OVER, OKAY?
YOU HAVE TO BE HAPPY THAT YOU
ARE OKAY.
ARE YOU OKAY?
I DIDN'T EVEN CHECK YOU OUT.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
>> YES.
>> WHAT HAPPENED HERE IN THE
FRONT.
DID YOU HAVE TEETH THERE THIS
MORNING WHEN YOU WENT THERE.
>> NO.
>> GOOD.
>> YOU KNOW YOU ARE MISSING ALL
OF THE TEETH IN FRONT.
ARE YOU AWARE.
>> CHRISTMAS LIST MADE?
>> UH-HUH.
>> SENT TO SANTA.
>> HOW LONG IS THE LIST?
>> TWO PIECES OF PAPER.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S A SWEET MOMENT.
THAT WAS CHRIS CUOMO REPORTING.
>> IN THE AREA SMALL GROUPS ARE
CREATING VIGILS TO REMEMBER THE
VICTIMS.
WE ARE LIVE IN GOLDEN GATE PARK
WITH MORE OF ONE THAT WAS
PLANNED FOR THIS MORNING.
>>> KATIE, GOOD MORNING.
WE ARE HERE AT THE AIDS MEMORIAL
DROVE
-- GROVE IN GOLDEN GATE PARK.
WE HAVE VIDEO FROM LAST NIGHT
WHERE IN MILL VALLEY ABOUT 20
PEOPLE GATHERED TO HONOR THOSE
WHO DIED AND TO FIND COMFORT IN
ONE ANOTHER IN THE FACE OF SUCH
BRAZEN VIOLENCE.
PEOPLE OF ALL AGES CONSOLED ONE
ANOTHER AND REMEMBERED THE 27
PEOPLE LOST.
ONE HIGH SCHOOL SOPHOMORE TOLD
US SHE FELT A PERSONAL
CONNECTION TO THE TRAGEDY.
>> I FELT THAT I HAVE A YOUNGER
SISTER AND IT COULD HAVE BEEN
HER.
ANY ONE THAT WOULD HAVE TO GO
THROUGH THAT LOSS IS SO SAD.
AND I HOPE IT NEVER HAPPENS
AGAIN.
I HOPE THAT NO ONE EVER HAS TO
LOSE A FAMILY MEMBER OR THEIR
LIVES TO SOMEONE LIKE THAT.
>> 2 DOZEN HE MOURNERS GATHERED
FOR ANOTHER VIGIL IN WALNUT
CREEK.
THAT'S WHERE PARENTS BROUGHT
THEIR ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AGED
CHILDREN.
TWO MOTHERS WE SPOKE WITH SAID
THEY EXPLAINED WHAT HAPPENED TO
THEIR CHILDREN IN HOPES OF
HAVING THEM UNDERSTAND WHAT
THEIR FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT
ARE GOING THROUGH RIGHT NOW.
HERE IN GOLDEN GATE PARK THE
PUBLIC IS WELCOME FOR A VIGIL
PLANNED AT 8:00 A.M. AT THE AIDS
MEMORIAL GROVE.
LIVE IN GOLDEN GATE PARK ABC 7
NEWS.
>>> TOUGH MORNING.
SCHOOL OFFICIALS ACROSS THE BAY
AREA WERE FIELDING CALLS FROM
PARENTS.
A FEW PARENTS TOOK THEIR KIDS
HOME.
MANY PARENTS SENT A LETTER HOME
TO REASSURE PARENTS THEIR
CHILDREN ARE SAFE AT HOME.
ALLEN WONG HAS MORE FROM
OAKLAND.
>> AS NEWS OF THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT SPREAD SO DID A
SENSE OF INSECURITY IN SCHOOLS
ACROSS THE BAY AREA.
>> IT JUST REMINDED ME TO
APPRECIATE WHAT I HAVE AND TO
DRAW MY LOVED ONES CLOSER.
>> IN OAKLAND CITY POLICE
OFFICERS WERE AVAILABLE FOR ANY
SCHOOL TO OFFER SAFETY ADVICE
AND FOR A SENSE OF REASSURANCE.
>> IT IS TOTALLY WRONG.
THEY ARE NOT ADULTS YET AND THEY
ARE KILLING LITTLE KIDS.
>> THE SCHOOL DISTRICT WILL HAVE
THE FIRST ACTIVE EVER SHOOTER
DRILL NEXT MARCH.
OFFICIALS ARE KEENLY AWARE OF
HOW THIS TRAGEDY MIGHT EFFECT
ITS YOUNGER STUDENTS.
>> WITH YOUNGER CHILDREN IT'S A
FIRE DRILL LIKE EARTHQUAKE DRILL
LIKE MANEUVER WHERE YOU ARE
REASSURING THE CHILDREN AND YOU
ARE MOVING THE CHILDREN AROUND.
>> DISTRICT PSYCHOLOGISTS WERE
COACHING FACULTY MEMBERS HOW TO
SPOT SIGNS OF DISTRESS WITH KIDS
AND HOW TO RESPOND WHEN THEY
COME BACK NEXT WEEK.
>> EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE THIS
THING DOES HAPPEN BUT IT RARELY
HAPPENS AND THERE ARE ADULTS
THERE THEY CAN GO TO WHEN THEY
ARE FEELING AFRAID.
>> IN SAN FRANCISCO IT WAS GUT
CHECK TIME.
SCHOOL OFFICIALS WERE
REEXAMINING SAFETY PLANS THAT
HAVE BEEN IN PLACE SINCE THE
COLUMBINE MASSACRE.
SINCE THEN POLICE SAY THEIR
TACTICS HAVE CHANGED.
>> WE TAKE IMMEDIATE ACTION.
WE KNOW THAT LIVES ARE AT STAKE
AND IF THERE IS AN MEDIACY OUR
OFFICERS ARE TOLD TO GATHER AND
ENGAGE.
>> I AM ALLEN WONG, ABC 7 NEWS.
>>> PRESIDENT OBAMA IS USING HIS
WEEKLY ADDRESS TO ASK ALL
AMERICANS TO KEEP THE VICTIMS OF
VIOLENCE IN MIND.
>> AS A NATION WE HAVE ENDURED
FAR TOO MANY OF THESE TRAGEDIES
IN THE LAST FEW YEARS.
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN,
A SHOPPING MALL IN OREGON, A
HOUSE OF WORSHIP IN WISCONSIN.
MOVIE THEATER IN COLORADO,
COUNTLESS STREET CORNERS IN
PLACES LIKE CHICAGO AND
PHILADELPHIA.
ANY OF THESE NEIGHBORHOODS WOCOD
BE YOU ARE OWN.
WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER AND WE
ARE GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING.
>>> THE PRESIDENT ASKS EACH
AMERICAN TO LEND A HAND TO
FAMILIES IN THEIR OWN
COMMUNITIES WHO HAVE LOST LOVED
ONES TO VIOLENCE.
YOU CAN EXPECT CONDOLENCES ON
OUR FACEBOOK PAGE.
SHARE YOUR THOUGHTS AT
FACEBOOK.COM/ABC 7 NEWS.
YOU CAN ALSO POST THIS BADGE TO
YOUR FACEBOOK WALL A SILENT SHOW
OF SUPPORT FOR EVERYONE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>>> UP NEXT, A NEW CALL FOR GUN
CONTROL AS PEOPLE STRUGGLE WITH
THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
OTHERS ARE ALREADY THINKING
ABOUT HOW TO PREVENT IT FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
THE SCENE IN CONNECTICUT IS ALL
TOO FAMILIAR IN COLUMBINE,
COLORADO.
RESIDENTS ARE REACHING OUT TO
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN.
OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT CONTINUES
IN A MOMENT.
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING CENTRUM FLAVOR
BURST ADULT MULTIVITAMINS...
A DELICIOUS NEW WAY TO GET
ESSENTIAL VITAMINS YOU NEED.
JUST BITE
INTO THE TASTY SHELL...
TO A CHEWY VITAMIN CORE
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
NEW CENTRUM FLAVOR BURST.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
>> GUN CONTROL IS ONCE AGAIN
BEING DEBATED AFTER THE TRAGIC
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
IT'S A CONVERSATION TAKING PLACE
IN THE NATION'S CAPITOL AND
RIGHT HERE AT HOME.
HIRE IS ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER AMA
DATES.
>> PLEASE LAYOUT A PLAN OF
ACTION OF HOW WE MAY ADDRESS
THIS SCOURGE OF GUN VIOLENCE IN
OUR COMMUNITY.
>> THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING GAVE RISE TO THE ANTI
GUN GATHERING OUTSIDE OF THE
WHITE HOUSE.
THEY ARE ALREADY CALLING ON
CONGRESS TO FURTHER RESTRICT
ACCESS TO FIREARMS IN RESPONSE
TO TODAY'S TRAGEDY.
IN CALIFORNIA WE HAVE THE
STRONGEST GUN LAWS IN THE
COUNTRY AS RANKED TO PREVENT GUN
VIOLENCE.
>> IT HAS THE LOWEST MORTALITY
RATES FROM FIREARM DEATHS IN THE
NATION.
>> THEY ARE CONSIDERING
REINTRODUCING A BILL THAT CLOSES
THE LOOPHOLE IN THE STATE
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN.
RECENT POLLS SHOW AMERICANS IN
GENERAL ARE IN FAVOR OF MORE
RESTRICTIONS.
GUN STORE OWNER JOSH DISEASER
SAYS THE CURRENT LAWS ARE FINE.
>> ISOLATED INCIDENTS IT'S
TRAGIC.
WE CAN'T THEY JERK AND THINK
GOES GOING TO CAUSE A PROBLEM.
IF PEOPLE ARE WANTING TO DO
SOMETHING BAD THEY ARE GOING TO
FIGURE OUT A WAY TO DO IT.
>> OTHERS FEEL SOMETHING NEEDS
TO CHANGE.
>> WATCHING THE PREVALENCE OF
GUN VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY, I
JUST CAN'T STAND BY AND WATCH
THAT.
>> MARSHA GETA OF OAKLAND GREW
UP WITH GUNS.
HE ATTEND THIS HAD VIGIL TO
REMEMBER THE LIVES LOST IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> WE NEED TO LOOK INSIDE OF THE
MIRROR AND TAKE A LOOK AT
OURSELVES AMERICA AND REALIZE WE
NEED TO CHANGE A FEW THINGS HOW
WE DEAL WITH GUNS AND THE WAY WE
ISSUE THEM IN SOCIETY AS WELL AS
HOW WE ENCOURAGE VIOLENCE IN OUR
SOCIETY.
>> WE HAVE NOT HEARD ANY
REACTION YET FROM THE GUN
ADVOCACY GROUP THE NATIONAL
RIFLE ASSOCIATION.
THE ORGANIZATION'S FACEBOOK FAJ
WAS UNAVAILABLE FOR MOST OF
YESTERDAY.
>>> ON APRIL 20TH, 1999, THE
NATION WAS HORRIFIED AT
TELEVISION IMAGES OF HIGH SCHOOL
STUDENTS RUNNING FOR THEIR LIVES
AT COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL.
TWO STUDENTS SHOT 12 STUDENTS
AND ONE TEACHER TO DEATH AND
WOUNDED 24 OTHER BROTHERS FAT
FATALLY SHOOTING THEMSELVES.
THE MAN WHO WAS COLUMBINE'S
PRINCIPAL THAT DAY IS STILL
PRINCIPAL TODAY.
>> HERE TO PROVIDE ALL OF THE
SUPPORT THEY NEED.
THE MESSAGE I WOULD LIKE TO SEND
TO THEM IS THEY ARE NOT IN THIS
ALONE.
>> DENVER NOW HAS DETAILED
DIAGRAMS FOR ALL OF THE SCHOOLS
AND HAS TAKEN STEPS TO LIMIT
ACCESS POINTS FOR BETTER
SECURITY.
HE DOESN'T THINK GUN CONTROL OR
TOUGHER LAWS WILL PREVENT MASS
KILLING.
>> MIGHT BE AN UNFORTUNATE
TRUTH.
LISA ARGIN WITH THE FORECAST.
COLD OUTSIDE.
>> IT IS COLD.
WE HAVE RAIN THAT WILL BE
DEVELOPING THROUGH OUT THE DAY
AND THE AFTERNOON.
IF YOU ARE HEAD THE OUT THIS
MORNING WE HAVE TEMPERATURES AS
LOW AS FREEZING.
WITH RAIN DEVELOPING WE HAVE AN
INTERESTING FORECAST.
>> BAY AREA STUDENTS WRITE
LETTERS TO SANTA NOT FOR WHAT
THEY WANT FOR CHRISTMAS.
THESE LETTERS ARE TO HELP MAKE
WISHLIVERMORE.
>> GOOD MORNING EVERYONE.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
WE ARE COMING UP ON 5:50.
IT IS A COLD ONE AND EVER
CHANGING.
>> THAT'S TRUE.
WE HAVE SEVERAL WET WEATHER
SYSTEMS HEADED OUR WAY.
THE FIRST COUPLE ARE PRETTY
WEAK.
MORE OF A NUISANCE RAIN NO ONE
CAN ESCAPE THE COLD AS WE HEAD
ON OUTSIDE RIGHT NOW.
YOU CAN SEE FROM THE ROOF CAMERA
IT IS PRETTY FESTIVE OUT THERE
WITH THE ARROW AND THE LIGHTS.
THE FAIR REBUILDING YOU CAN SEE
IT ALL LIT UP THERE.
WE ARE LOOKING AT CLEAR SKIES
AROUND THE BAY.
THAT HAS DROPPED THE
TEMPERATURES TO BELOW FREEZING
IN SOME PARTS OF THE BAY.
LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD WE ARE
WATCHING A WEAK WEATHER SYSTEM
WELL UP TO THE NORTH.
HERE IT IS.
THIS IS WHAT WILL BE DEVELOPING
LATER ON TODAY.
IT WILL SPREAD LIGHT RAIN OUR
WAY BY MIDDAY IN THE NORTH BAY
AND THE SOUTH BAY SHOULD STAY
CLEAR FOR QUITE SOMETIME.
30s ALONG THE CENTRAL COAST.
32 FOR YOU AS WELL AS SANTA
ROSA.
FAIRFIELD ONLY 30 DEGREES.
WARM SPOT 37.
IT IS AN OVER COAT MORNING WITH
PERHAPS SOME GLOVES.
WE HAVE FOG VISIBILITY LESS THAN
A QUARTER MILE.
BE CAREFUL.
HIGHLIGHTS THEN WE HAVE THE COLD
WEATHER.
CHANCE OF SHOWERS LINGER THROUGH
TOMORROW.
IT LOOKS LIKE THE ON AND OFF
LIGHT RAINSHOWER ACTIVITY THEY
WENT FROM A TENTH TO A THIRD
THROUGH THE WEEKEND.
WE ARE NOT TALKING ABOUT A LOT
OF RAIN.
HERE IS THE SYSTEM.
YOU CAN SEE THE CLOUD COVER AND
BASICALLY IT IS HUNG UP ALONG
THE NORTH COAST.
IT WILL SLOWLY SAG TO THE SOUTH.
COLD AIR.
WITH SOME OF THE VALLEYS COLDER
AIR IS TRAPPED AT THE LOWER
LEVEL.
NOT OUT OF THE QUESTION TO SEE
SOME FLURRIES AROUND LAKE
COUNTY.
HERE IT IS.
YOU WILL NOTICE THE SNOW LEVELS
IN SOME PARTS OF THE BAY AROUND
2,000 FEET WE WILL HAVE SNOW IN
THE FOOTHILLS BUT NOT A LOT OF
MOISTURE WITH THE SYSTEM.
HERE IT IS MIDDAY YOU WILL
NOTICE WE ARE DRY ACROSS MOST OF
THE BAY.
THE PINK INDICATING THE RAIN
SNOW MIX.
THROUGH THE AFTERNOON LIGHT
RAIN.
YOU WILL NOTICE LIGHT RAIN IN
THE NORTH YINIGHT HOURS.
SHOWERS AROUND 8:00 WE ARE STILL
LOOKING AT THE LIGHT PRECIP IN
THE NORTH BAY.
REST OF THE AFTERNOON MAYBE ON
AND OFF SHOWERS BUT TOWARDS
MONDAY WE ARE LOOKING AT ANOTHER
SYSTEM.
LITTLE MEATYER AND WARMER.
A TENTH TO A THIRD OF AN INCH
AND LETTERS AMS ALONG THE COAST
IN SOUTH BAY TODAY.
A WEAK SYSTEM BUT WITH PLENTY OF
COLD AIR 50 HALF-MOON BAY UPPER
40Z FOR THE NORTH BAY, 53 IN   M
CELINE NIS.
A CHANCE OF RAIN ALMOST EVERY
DAY EXCEPT THE MIDDLE OF THE
WEEK.
I HATE TO SAY IT BUT THAT COULD
CHANGE AS THE SYSTEMS SPEED UP
AND THE MODELS GIVE US
CONFLICTING REPORTS.
STAY TUNED.
IT LOOKS SEASONAL.
>> YOU HAVE US AS A CAPTIVE
AUDIENCE.
THANKS.
AS TRAGEDY CONTINUES TO UNFOLD
IN CONNECTICUT IT IS NICE TO BE
REMINDED THERE IS GOOD IN THE
WORLD.
WE WANT TO SHARE A DIFFERENT
STORY OF HOPE AND LOVE TOWARD
OTHERS.
HUNDREDS OF STUDENT IN FREMONT
WROTE LETTERS TO SANTA ASKING
HIM TO GRANT A WISH TO SICK KIDS
AS PART OF THE MAKE A WISH
CAMPAIGN.
LEEANN MOL LHAS THE STORY.
>> THESE ARE ONLY A FEW OF THE
THOUSANDS OF KIDS IN FREMONT WHO
WROTE A WISH ON A PIECE OF
PAPER.
>> I WISHED ABOUT MY FAMILY AND
FRIENDS.
>> THAT MY MOM AND DAD HAVE A
GREAT TIME IN THAE LIFE AND NOT
HAVE TO STRUGGLE WITH IT.
>> FOR ALL OF THE CHILDREN TO
STAY OUT OF THE HOSPITAL AND
FEEL BETTER ABOUT THEMSELVES TO
BE OUT.
>> THEY'RE SECOND GRADE TEACHER
ORGANIZED THE PRODU-- PROJECT.
>> IT COULD BE PEOPLE CLOSE TO
THEM OR CHILDREN FROM MAKE A
WISH.
SOME KIDS WROTE ABOUT WHAT THEY
WISH FOR FOR OBAMA.
>> FOR EACH LETTER MACY'S
DONATED $2 TO MAKE A WISH
FOUNDATION.
THEY GRANT WISHES TO KIDS WITH
LIFE THREATENING MEDICAL
CONDITIONS LIKE SHELBY.
SHE ARRIVED IN A LIMO AND HAD A
SHOPPING SPREE AT MACY'S AT
WALNUT CREEK BEFORE FLYING OFF
IN JANUARY TO MEET JUSTIN
BIEBER.
STUDENTS AND PARENTS MANAGED TO
WRITE 41,000 LETTERS.
>> SOMETIMES WHEN I DO IT MY
HANDS HURT BUT I KEEP DOING IT
BECAUSE I WANT KIDS TO GET OUT
OF THE HOSPITAL.
>> THE MAKE A WISH FOUNDATION
WILL RECEIVE 80,000 DOLLARS
WHICH WILL BE SPENT ON GRANTING
WISHES TO ABOUT 8 SICK CHILDREN.
>> YOU ARE REALLY SICK AND YOU
ARE IN PAIN YOU DON'T HAVE MUCH
TO DO AND KAUNT GO OUT ANYWHERE.
>> WE WANT OUR KIDS TO LEARN TO
PAY IT FORWARD, TO THINK OF
OTHERS FIRST.
AND PLUS WE ARE GETTING THEM TO
WRITE.
>> HE TOLD US HIS BABY SISTER
HAD BEEN SICK.
HE MENTIONED HER IN HIS LETTER.
>> I HOPE SHE GETS BETTER.
>> SHE IS BETTER NOW.
>> THE POWER OF BELIEVING.
IN FLEENT, L--
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
TRUST DURACELL TO POWER
THEIR DONATED TOYS?
DURALOCK POWER PRESERVE.
IT LOCKS IN POWER
FOR UP TO 10 YEARS IN STORAGE.
GUARANTEED.
DURACELL WITH DURALOCK.
TRUSTED EVERYWHERE.
DESCRIBE THE ROOM.
A BIG, OPEN SPACE.
SMELLS REALLY FRESH, MAN.
OH!
[ both laugh ]
FEBREZE? HOW ABOUT THAT?
YEAH.
FEBREZE
ANTI-CLOGGING TECHNOLOGY
KEEPS IT SMELLING FRESH.
FEBREZE. BREATHE HAPPY.
>> AUTHORITIES SAY THEY HAVE
IDENTIFIED ALL OF THE VICTIMS.
20 CHILDREN.
THE SHOOTER NANCY LANZA, THE
SHOOTER AS MOTHER WAS AMONG
THEM.
NANCY MAY HAVE BEEN A VOLUNTEER
OR A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY CONTINUES IN JUST A
MOMENT.
>> GOOD MORNING.
THE CONNECTICUT TOWN OF NEWTOWN
IS MOURNING AFTER ONE OF THE
DEADLIEST SHOOTINGS IN HISTORY.
THESE ARE LIVE PICTURES IN
CONNECTICUT.
VICTIM'S BODYS ARE STILL INSIDE
THE SCHOOL.
AUTHORITIES HAVE IDENTIFIED ALL
OF THEM.
IT'S NOT CLEAR IF THE NAMES WILL
BE GIVEN OUT TODAY.
THERE ARE 27 VICTIMS.
20 OF