EACH CORRECT RESPONSE
WILL BEGIN WITH A LETTER "B"
AND END WITH AR "B."
ALISTAIR, START US.
LET'S START
WITH THE CHRISTMAS SPIRIT
FOR $200, PLEASE, ALEX.
THERESA.
WHAT IS PEPPERMINT?
YES.
CHRISTMAS SPIRIT
FOR $400, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS WHISKEY?
CORRECT.
I'LL GO FOR MATH FUN
FOR $200, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS 12?
YES.
MATH FUN FOR $400,
PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS
"BECAUSE SEVEN ATE NINE"?
CORRECT.
MATH FUN FOR $600,
PLEASE.
HERE'S KELLY
TO HELP YOU OUT.
TAKE A CIRCLE WHOSE DIAMETER IS
ONE FOOT AND MARK THE BOTTOM.
ONCE THE WHEEL
MADE ONE REVOLUTION,
YOU HAVE A MEASUREMENT IN FEET
EQUIVALENT TO THIS RATIO.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS PI?
HAS YES.
MATH FUN FOR $800,
PLEASE.
PI,   ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS 15.
2+5+8, YES.
MATH FUN FOR $1,000,
PLEASE.
ANSWER --
THE DAILY DOUBLE,
AND YOU'RE OFF
TO AN EXCELLENT START.
$2,400 FOR YOU,
ALISTAIR.
SO TEMPTING
TO MAKE IT A TRUE DAILY DOUBLE,
BUT I DON'T THINK SO.
LET'S GO FOR $1,600,
PLEASE.
SEE HOW GOOD YOU ARE
AT RESISTING TEMPTATION.
ALL RIGHT, HERE'S SARAH.
THE VENN DIAGRAM HERE CONTAINS
THREE SETS -- A, B, AND C,
BUT THERE'S ANOTHER SET
THAT INCLUDES
ALL POSSIBLE THINGS
THAT'S CALLED THIS.
WHAT IS THE UNION?
NO.
WHAT IS
THE UNIVERSAL SET? --
NOT THE UNION.
SO YOU LOST SOME MONEY ON THAT,
BUT YOU'RE STILL IN THE LEAD.
AND IT'S EARLY
NOIN THE GAME. GO.
FROM B TO SHINING B
FOR $200, PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS THE BOMB?
FROM B TO SHIN
SUSAYES.
FROM B TO SHINING B
FOR $400, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS A BULB.
CORRECT.
$600, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS A BACK RUB?
GOOD.
$800, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS A BLURB?
BLURB, THAT'S THE WORD.
B FOR $1,000, PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS A BATHTUB?
YES, AND WITH THAT,
YOU MOVE TO $1,200.
AND WE'RE GONNA TAKE
OUR FIRST BREAK RIGHT NOW.
COME BACK SHORTLY,
THOUGH.
[ APPLAUSE ]
NOW, THERESA,
I'M SURE YOU REMEMBER
IN THE COVERAGE OF THE OLYMPICS
THIS PAST YEAR IN LONDON,
THERE WAS ONE SCENE
THAT HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH THE OLYMPICS
THAT INVOLVED
THE LORD MAYOR OF LONDON,
WHO GOT STUCK
ON A ZIP LINE.
THAT GOT PUBLICITY
ALL OVERORLD.
YOU DIDN'T
GET THE PUBLICITY,
BUT THE SAME THING
KIND OF HAPPENED TO YOU.
IT DID. I COULD IDENTIFY
WITH THAT VERY WELL.
MY HUSBAND BURT AND I
WENT TO ST. LUCIA,
DECIDED TO TAKE AN EXCURSION
TO GO ZIP LINING.
ON THE LAST OF 12 ZIP LINES,
WHICH WAS THE HIGHEST
AND THE FASTEST,
THAT'S WHEN
I DECIDED TO GET STUCK,
ABOUT HALFWAY DOWN.
BUT HOW LONG WAS THAT SECTION
AND HOW LONG WERE YOK?
UM...HOW LONG?
YOU KNOW, ETERNITY.
[ LAUGHTER ]
HOW LONG WAS I STUCK?
SEVERAL SECONDS.
U STUCYOU KNOW, I WAS PRETTY PAC
AND PITIFUL,
SO I HAD TO DO WHAT'S CALLED
THE CRAWL OF SHAME,
WHERE ONE OF THE GUIDES
COMES OUT AND GETS YOU
AND PULLS YOU BACK
TO THE PLATFORM.
OKAY, BUT ALL IN ALL, A GOOD EX.
SURE.
YEAH, OKAY.
SUSAN JANN IS FROM BRISTOL,
PENNSYLVANIA.
SHE'S AN OPERATIONS
COORDINATOR
WHO WORKS IN HELPING CUSTOMERS
IN WHAT AR
WHEN PEOPLE ARE TRAVELING
INTERNATIONALLY,
THEY CALL MY CALL CENTER,
AND I HELP THEM OUT.
WHETHER IT BE ASSISTING
WITH AEA?
IN BUENOS AIRES
OR GETTING AN AIR AMBULANCE
OUT OF NAMIBIA.
OKAY, THAT MEANS YOU SPEAK
MORE THAN ONE LANGUAGE.
YES, SIR.
DOCTO
OI SPEAK SPANISH AND PORTUGUESE,
MOREAS WELL AS ENGLISH.
THAT'S GOOD.
[ Chuckling ] YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
ALISTAIR BELL IS OUR CHAMPION,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
HE'S A COMPUTER-CHIP
DESIGNER,
AND HE HAS
A SPECIAL SPHERE OF WORK,
AND THAT INVOLVES
LOOKING FOR BUGS, RIGHT?
I DO, YES.
THAT COSTS US
SEVERAL MILLION DOLLARS,
AND SO IF THERE
ARE ANY BUGS IN IT,
THAT'S GONNA COST THE COMPANY
A LOT OF MONEY.
SO MY JOB IS TO MAKE D
RE
THAT'S GONNA COST THE COMPANY
THAT WE PUT THE THING
TO MANUFACTURING
WITH NO BUGS IN IT AT ALL.
OKAY, GOOD.
LET'S GET BACK TO THIS NOW.
SUSAN GAVE US
THE ARN SUORRECT RESPONSE,
WHICH MEANS
SHE MAKES THE NEXT SELECTION.
GO AHEAD, SUSAN.
CHRISTMAS FOR $600,
PLEASE.
ANSWER.
SUSAN, AGAIN.
WHAT IS EGG NOG.
YES.
LET'S CONTINUE
WITH CHRISTMAS FOR $800, PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS POINSETTIA?
YES.
FINISH THE CATEGORY CHRISTMAS
FOR $1,000.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS GIN?
YEAH,
YOU KNOW YOUR BOOZE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
LET'S TRY MOVIE MISSING LINKS
FOR $200, PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS WOMAN?
GOOD.
LET'S CONTINUE WITH MOVIE
FOR $400, PLEASE.
THERESA.
WHAT IS BLADE?
YES.
LET'S GO AMAKE MY CAR,
$200, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS VOLKSWAGEN?
THHEAD, T.
MAKE MY CAR FOR $400,
PLEASE.
SUSAN.
MOVIE MISSING LINKS
FOR $600.
SUSAN.
WHAT ARE STRANGERS?
CORRECT.
MOVIE FOR $800, PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS...
[ SIGHS ]
OH, TOO MUCH TIME.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS FROST?
FROST, YOU GOT IT.
MISSING LINKS
FOR $1,000, PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS DAWN?
NO.
THERESA.
DARK -- WHAT IS DARK?
WHAT IS DARK?
YES,
WAIT UNTIL DARK.
OKAY. GO AHEAD, MAKE MY CAR,
FOR $600, PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS KIA?
THAT'S IT.
CAR FOR $800.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS ROLLS-ROYCE?
YES.
LET'S FINISH WITH CAR
FOR $1,000.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS TESLA?
GOOD FOR $1,000 MORE.
LET'S START WITH CHILDREN'S
FOR $200.
SUSAN.
WHO IS
THE CAT IN THE HAT?
YES, WITH LESS
THANUTE TO GO.
$400.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS "THE JUNGLE BOOK"?
RIGHT.
$1,000.
[ BEEP ]
AND THAT WOULD BE
MAISY THE MOUSE.
SUSAN.
$800, PLEASE.
THERESA.
WHO IS THUMBELINA?
YES,
AND NOW THE LAST CLUE.
SUSAN.
WHO IS
ENCYCLOPEDIA BROWN?
ANOTHER CORRECT RESPONSE
FROM YOU
TAKES YOU TO $6,600,
GIVES YOU A $3,000 LEAD.
THERESA, YOU GET TIRST
IN DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
WHEN WE COME BACK
AFTER THIS.
[ APPLAUSE ]
AND I THINK YOU'LL ALL RECOGNIZE
THE THEME IN THIS ONE.
FIRST CATEGORY...
Alex: AND, THERESA,
YOU TELL US WHERE WE START.
LET'S START WITH
THE OTHER 45 STATES FOR $400.
THERESA.
WHAT IS A?
NO.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS LOUISIANA?
YES. LOUIS.
THE 45 STATES FOR $800,
PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS NEW MEXICO?
CORRECT.
$1,200, PLEASE.
CHECK OUT
THE GROOVY QUARTERED DESIGN
OF THIS STATE'S FLAG.
THE YELLOW AND BLACK STRIPES
HONOR THE CALVERT FAMILY.
SUSAN.AT IS MARYLAND?
YES, THAT'S THE STATE.
LET'S START
WITH THE STATE OF MY BIRTH --
NEW JERSEY --
FOR $400, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHO ARE
THE MIAMI MARLINS?
THAT'S IT.
NEW JERSEY FOR $800,
PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT ARE DIVOTS?
NO.
THERESA.
WHAT ARE DIMPLES?
DIMPLES NOT DIVOTS.
LET'S DO GEORGE, UHH...
$400, PLEASE.
WHAT ARE DIMPLES?
DIMPLES NOT DIVOTS.
ALISTAIR.
WHO IS GEORGE ORWELL?
OH, YES, THANK YOU.
NEW JERSEY FOR $1,200,
SE.
ANSWER --
THE DAILY DOUBLE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
YOU TRAIL SUSAN
BY AN EVEN $1,400.
I'LL TAKE $1,600, PLEASE.
OKAY, FOR THE LEAD,
HERE IS THE CLUE.
WHO ARE
THE SEATTLE SEAHAWKS?
THAT'S RIGHT. NIKE'S IN OREGON,
NEIGHBORING STATE.
$1,600, PLEASE.
Alex: THE 1912-13
THROWBACK JERSEYS WORN IN 2009
DIDN'T HELP THIS TEAM
ADD TO ITS 24 Y CUPS.
SUSAN.
WHO ARE THE CANADIENS?
MONTREAL CANADIENS,
YES.
LET'S FINISH NEW JERSEY
FOR $2,000STANLE.
[ BEEP ]
AND THAT WOULD BE
THE TORONTO RAPTORS.
SUSAN,
BACK TO YOU NOW.
THE OTHER 45 FOR $1,
600.
SUSAN,
BACK TO YOU NOW.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS WYOMING?
THAT'S THE STATE.
STATES FOR $2,000,
PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS WASHINGTON?
CORRECT.
"MAIN" FOR $400.
WHAT IS PUBLIC DOMAIN?
GOOD.
LET'S TRY MASS
FOR $400.
WHAT IS PUBLIC DOMAIN?
GOOD.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT ARE SACRAMENTS?
RIGHT.
MASS FOR $800, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS
THE "GLORIA IN EXCELSIS"?
YES.
MASS FOR $1,200, PLEASE.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS THE CREED?
CREED, YOU GOT IT.
MASS FOR $1,600,
PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS
IMMACULATE CONCEPTION?
RIGHT.
FINISH MASS FOR $2,000.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS THE COUNCIL OF TRENT?
CORRECT.
"MAIN" FOR $800,
PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS A MAIN
YES.
"MAIN" FOR $1,200.
[ BEEP ]
AND THAT IS A MAINSTAY.
BACK TO YOU, SUSAN.
"MAIN" FOR $1,600.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS THE SPANISH MAIN?
YES.
"MAIN" FOR $2,000,
PLEASE.
THERESA.
WHAT IS THE MAIN LINE?
GOOD, FOR $2,000.
GEORGE, UHH...
$800, PLEASE.
THERESA.
WHO IS GEORGE III.
YES.
GEORGE, UHH...
$1,200, PLEASE.
SUSAN.
WHO IS
GEORGE WASHINGTON CARVER?
YES.
GEORGE, UH...
FOR $1,600.
ANSWER THERE --
THE OTHER DAILY DOUBLE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
AND YOU TRAIL ALISTAIR
BY JUST $600.
$2,0EASE.
OKAY.
HERE'S THE CLUE.
WHO IS MARSHALL?
GEORGE MARSHALL, YES.
[ APPLAUSE ]
SS THAN A MINUTE
TO GO NOW.
GEORGE FOR $2,000.
[ BEEP ]
AND THIS TIME
THE GEORGE IS BOOLE.
SUSAN, BACK TO YOU.
HIPPIE FOR $400.
IT SEEMS LIKE EVERY OTHER
GARMENT IN MRS. HIPPIE'S CLOSET
IS COLORED WITH
THIS KNOTTED-FABRIC TECHNIQUE.
SUSAN.
WHAT IS TIE-DYE?
YEAH.
HIPPIE FOR $800.
ALISTAIR.
WHAT IS WOODSTOCK?
RIGHT.
HIPPIE FOR $1,200,
PLEASE.
MRS. HIPPIE
WEARE SHOES
FROM A COMPANY AROUND
SINCE THE '70s -- THE 1770s.
SUSAN.
WHAT ARE BIRKENSTOCKS?
YES THES
[ BEEP BEEP BEEP ]
AND WITH THAT,
YOU'RE BACK IN THE LEAD
AT $17,800.
ALISTAIR, $15,600.
THERESA, $6,000.
HERE COMES
FINAL JEOPARDY!
WE'LL REVEAL THE CLUE
WHEN WE COME BACK.
YOU KNOW IT CAN BE HARD TO
LBREATHE, AND HOW THAT FEELS.E,
COPD INCLUDES CHRONIC
BRONCHITIS AND EMPHYSEMA.
SPIRIVA HELPS CONTROL
MY COPD SYMPTOMS
BY KEEPING MY AIRWAYS
OPEN FOR 24 HOURS.
PLUS, IT REDUCES COPD FLARE-UPS.
SPIRIVA IS THE ONLY ONCE-DAILY
SPIRIVA HANDIHALER TIOTROPIUM
BROMIDE INHALATION POWDER
DOES NOT REPLACE FAST-ACTING
INHALERS FOR SUDDEN SYMPTOMS.
.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
KIDNEY PROBLEMS, GLAUCOMA,
TROUBLE URINATING, OR
AN ENLARGED PROSTATE.
THESE MAY WORSEN WITH SPIRIVA.
DISCUSS ALL MEDICINES
YOU TAKE, EVEN EYE DROPS.
STOP TAKING SPIRIVA AND SEEK
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
IF YOUR BREATHING
SUDDENLY WORSENS,
YOUR THROAT OR TONGUE
SWELLS, YOU GET HIVES,
VISION CHANGES OR EYE PAIN,
OR PROBLEMS PASSING URINE.
OTHER SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
DRY MOUTH AND CONSTIPATION.
NOTHING CAN REVERSE COPD.
SPIRIVA HELPS ME BREATHE BETTER.
(BLOWING SOUND)
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT SPIRIVA.
WE ARE ABOUT TO FIND OUT.
HERE'S THE CLUE.
ECONDS, PLAYERS.
GOOD LUCK.
Alex: THERESA, LET'S SEE
IF YOU CAME UP WITH IT.
WHAT DID YOU WRITE DOWN?
WHAT IS THE TELEGRAM?
NO, THAT'S INCORRECT.
AND IT'LL COST YOU
HOW MUCH?
OH, IT WON'T COST YOU ANYTHING.
YOU REMAIN AT $6,000.
DOWN TO ALISTAIR BELL NOW.
HE HAD $15,600.
HE WROTE DOWN...
WHAT IS A COTTON GIN?
NOPE.
AND WHAT DID YOU RISK?
[ Chuckling ]
NOTHING ALSO.
INTERESTING WAGERS
OR NON-WAGERS TODAY.
YOU REMAIN AT $15,600.
OVER TO SUSAN JANN.
SHE HAD THE LEAD,
PLAYED WELL.
AND SHE CAME UP WITH,
WHAT IS A TELEGRAPH?
YOU ARE CORRECT.
YOU'RE BE
THE NEW CHAMPION --
WITH HOW MUCH MONEY?
$5,000 MORE.
$22,800 FOR YOU.
WAY TO GO, SUSAN.
[ APPLAUSE ]
YOU HAVE TO
GO GONNAFOR A DAY,
BUT COME BACK
AND PLAY AGAIN TOMORROW.
WE'LL HAVE TWO NEW CHALLENGERS
FOR YOU.
JOIN US THEN. SO LONG.
[ APPLAUSE ]
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
-- Captions by VITAC --
www.vitac.com
OH!
I'M SORRY, PAT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
I -- YOU KNOW,
TWO THOUGHTS --
NUMBER ONE, I'M REAL GLAD
YOU WON ALL THAT MONEY.
NUMBER TWO,
I DIDN'T MIND THAT, ACTUALLY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
WHOO-HOO-HOO!
SORRY, PAT. [ LAUGHS ]
THIS IS AN UGLY TREND
DEVELOPING ON THIS SHOW.
YOU DON'T WIN EXTRA MONEY
FOR PICKING UP THE HOST.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WHEEL...
OF...
FORTUNE!
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
PAT SAJAK AND VANNA WHITE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
HEY, THAT'S US!
HOW YOU DOING?
THANK YOU, JIM.
THANK YOU.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I FEEL BETTER ALREADY.
GO TO THE PUZZLE BOARD,
WILL YOU?
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
HI!
WELL, YOU LOOK
HA BE HERE.
EVERYBODY SHOULD PICK UP
ONE OF THOSE
WHATEVER THEY'RE CALLED,