>> Lucy: REALLY?
I'M SORRY.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE A GOLDEN
DUCK-LEVEL REP.
>> Felix: [ CHUCKLES ]
ACTUALLY, I'M JUST A QUACKER.
>> Lucy: YOU'RE JUST A QUACKER?
WELL, THEN I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHY IN THE WORLD WOULD BREE EVER
LET YOU IN MY OFFICE?
WHO THE HECK ARE YOU?
>> Sabrina: FELIX!
UH, THAT IS, HE'S FELIX DuBOIS,
AND I'M SABRINA SANTIAGO.
WE'RE FROM PORT CHARLES, AND WE
DESPERATELY NEED YOUR HELP.
>> Britt: NO MESSAGE.
ELIZABETH?
>> Elizabeth: YES,
DR. WESTBOURNE?
DO YOU NEED SOMETHING?
>> Britt: IT'S "BRITT," PLEASE.
>> Elizabeth: WHAT'S UP?
>> Britt: I JUST WANTED TO SAY
THANKS FOR THE GOOD WORK DURING
LULU'S EGG EXTRACTION.
>> Elizabeth: I'M GLAD IT WENT
SMOOTHLY.
I KNOW LULU AND DANTE WILL MAKE
EXCELLENT PARENTS, AND THEY HAVE
YOU TO THANK.
>> Britt: IT WAS A TEAM EFFORT.
UM, FOR WHICH I THINK DESERVES A
DRINK, SO WHAT DO YOU SAY?
>> Elizabeth: A DRINK WITH YOU?
>> Ellie: DAMIAN.
>> Spinelli: HI.
>> Ellie: IT'S SO GOOD TO SEE
BOTH OF YOU GUYS.
UH, HOW'S MRS. FALCONERI DOING
AFTER HER PROCEDURE?
>> Maxie: OH, UM, LULU IS A
LITTLE OUT OF IT, BUT DANTE'S
RIGHT BY HER SIDE.
IT'S VERY SWEET.
>> Ellie: OH, I'M GLAD TO HEAR
IT.
>> Spinelli: YEAH, MAXIE WAS
ASKING IF SHE COULD SEE THE
EMBRYOS.
>> Maxie: WELL, WE'RE GONNA BE
SO UP CLOSE AND PERSONAL, I
THOUGHT I MIGHT AS WELL
INTRODUCE MYSELF.
>> Ellie: AH, THAT MIGHT PROVE
TO BE DIFFICULT.
THEY'RE SO SMALL.
IN FACT, THEY'RE MICROSCOPIC.
>> Maxie: THAT'S WHY YOU GUYS
HAVE MICROSCOPES, RIGHT?
>> Ellie: YES, OF COURSE.
BUT UNFORTUNATELY I CAN'T ALLOW
YOU INTO THE LAB.
WE HAVE TO MAINTAIN A COMPLETELY
STERILE ENVIRONMENT.
>> Maxie: I KNEW THAT.
>> Ellie: BUT I CAN ASSURE YOU
THAT I HAVE INSEMINATED
MRS. FALCONERI'S EGGS WITH
MR. FALCONERI'S SPERM, AND THE
EMBRYOS ARE INCUBATING AS WE
SPEAK.
>> Spinelli: WELL, LET ME BE THE
FIRST TO OFFER YOU KUDOS.
>> Ellie: WELL, ALL IN A DAY'S
WORK.
>> Spinelli: IT'S MORE THAN
THAT.
HEY, YOU COULD BE PREGNANT BY
TOMORROW.
[ CHUCKLES ]
>> Britt: YES, WITH ME.
IS THAT SUCH A SHOCKING
SUGGESTION?
>> Elizabeth: WE'VE NEVER
SOCIALIZED, EVER.
>> Britt: WELL, I MEAN, I KNOW
IT DIDN'T INVOLVE CHICK FLICKS
OR SHOE SHOPPING, BUT WE HAVE
HUNG OUT A FEW TIMES.
AND I HAVE THE NIGHT FREE, SINCE
PATRICK SEEMS TO HAVE BLOWN ME
OFF.
>> Patrick: "PLEASE WATCH THIS
ALONE."
ROBIN, WHAT DID YOU DO?
>> Anna: [ GASPS ]
OH, MY GOD!
ROBERT! ROBERT!
ROBERT, STAY WITH ME!
STAY WITH ME, HONEY!
ROBERT!
A FEBREZE EXPERIMENT.
CAN A 30-DAY-OLD
PLUGGABLE FEBREZE
MAKE EVEN THIS OLD CONTAINER
SMELL FRESH?
TAKE A DEEP BREATH.
DESCRIBE THE ROOM
THAT YOU'RE IN.
I THINK JUST LIKE
A BIG, OPEN SPACE.
LIKE I'M HANGING THE SHEETS
ON THE LINE.
AND IT SMELLS
REALLY FRESH, MAN.
LET'S TAKE
YOUR BLINDFOLD OFF.
OH!
[ both laugh ]
SUPER-WEIRD!
OH, IS IT FEBREZE?
YEAH.
OHH, HOW ABOUT THAT?
FEBREZE HAS
ANTI-CLOGGING TECHNOLOGY
THAT KEEPS IT SMELLING FRESH,
EVEN AFTER 30 DAYS.
FEBREZE. BREATHE HAPPY.
♪ME AND YOU...
GHIRARDELLI
SQUARES CHOCOLATE...
♪A LITTLE RENDEZVOUS
SAVOR OUR LUSCIOUS
FILLING COMBINED
WITH OUR SLOW
MELTING CHOCOLATE.
♪THAT LITTLE REWARD FOR
ALL THE THINGS YOU DO.♪
ONLY FROM GHIRARDELLI.
♪ HARK HOW THE BELLS,
SWEET SILVER BELLS ♪
♪ ALL SEEM TO SAY
THROW CARE AWAY ♪
♪ FROM EVERYWHERE,
FILLING THE AIR ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
CHEX PARTY MIX.
EASY 15-MINUTE
HOMEMADE RECIPES
YOU JUST POP IN A MICROWAVE.
LIKE CARAMEL CHOCOLATE
DRIZZLES.
HAPPIER HOLIDAYS.
CHEX PARTY MIX.
OOH-HOO, I CAN'T WAIT TO CLEAN
SOMETHING BESIDES THE SHOWER.
[ Male Announcer ]
Scrubbing Bubbles' FOAM
PENETRATES TOUGH GRIME
AND KILLS 99.9% OF BACTERIA,
SO CLEANING THE WHOLE BATHROOM
IS EASIER.
Scrubbing Bubbles.
[ Female Announcer ]
SC Johnson.
SO I MIX TOGETHER
A PACKET OF HIDDEN VALLEY RANCH,
1 BOX OF SPINACH,
AND 16 OUNCES OF SOUR CREAM,
AND TONIGHT EVERYONE GETS
A TASTE OF SOMETHING SPECIAL...
RANCH SPINACH DIP.
[ Male Announcer ]
HIDDEN VALLEY RANCH. MIX IT UP.
RANCH SPINACH DIP.
SOFT, SWEET COCONUT COVERED
IN RICH, CREAMY CHOCOLATE.
ALMOND JOY AND MOUNDS.
UNWRAP PARADISE.
>> Ellie: I HOPE MAXIE ISN'T
COMING DOWN WITH SOMETHING.
>> Spinelli: I SHOULD PROBABLY
INVESTIGATE THE IMPETUS FOR HER
ABRUPT DEPARTURE.
>> Ellie: RIGHT.
I SHOULD PROBABLY GET BACK TO
INCUBATING.
>> Spinelli: OKAY.
MAXIE, ARE YOU OKAY?
>> Maxie: OH, THIS IS SUPPOSED
TO BE CARTULLO'S FLAGSHIP BAG
FOR THE FALL.
IT'S NOT VERY CONVENIENT.
I CAN'T FIND ANY OF MY STUFF.
>> Spinelli: I DOUBT A
DEFICIENCY WITH YOUR VALISE IS
THE REASON FOR YOUR ABRUPT
DEPARTURE.
>> Maxie: IT'S JUST, UM --
THE LAB.
I CAN'T BE HERE WITHOUT THINKING
ABOUT ROBIN.
IT'S THE LAST PLACE I SAW HER.
>> Spinelli: IT'S A HARD LOSS TO
COPE WITH AT ANY POINT HERE, BUT
I'M SURE IT PROBABLY IS EVEN
MORE KEENLY FELT DURING THE
HOLIDAYS.
>> Maxie: YEAH, AND EVERYBODY
KEEPS SAYING, "YOU SHOULD SPEND
MORE TIME WITH YOUR FAMILY,"
EXCEPT I CAN'T STOP THINKING
ABOUT THE FAMILY THAT I'VE LOST.
>> Spinelli: IS IT POSSIBLE
YOU'RE THINKING ABOUT THE FAMILY
THAT HAS YET TO ARRIVE --
I.E. DANTE AND LULU'S BABY?
>> Maxie: THE BABY'S NOT MY
FAMILY.
>> Spinelli: PERHAPS NOT IN THE
STRICTEST SENSE, BUT IT WILL BE
LIVING INSIDE YOU.
I THINK THAT QUALIFIES AS A
PRETTY CLOSE RELATIONSHIP.
ONE FRAUGHT WITH UNKNOWNS.
I THINK ANYBODY WOULD UNDERSTAND
IF YOU WERE SCARED.
>> Maxie: OKAY, I'M COMPLETELY
FREAKING OUT.
BUT IT'S ONLY BECAUSE I'M NOT IN
CONTROL OF THIS SITUATION.
I'M BASICALLY SIGNING OVER MY
BODY FOR THE NEXT NINE MONTHS.
I ALMOST TOLD LULU AND DANTE
THAT I COULDN'T DO IT.
>> Spinelli: MAXIE, IF YOU FEEL
THAT WAY, THEN YOU SHOULD --
>> Maxie: NO, NO.
THEY'RE EXCITED ABOUT THIS BABY.
THEY HAVE SO MUCH LOVE FOR EACH
OTHER AND THIS CHILD, I COULD
NEVER DISAPPOINT THEM.
I JUST HAVE TO PRETEND THAT I'M
CONFIDENT AND EXCITED --
AND IGNORE OLIVIA'S PREMONITIONS
THAT THIS BABY IS GOING TO BE A
DOG.
>> Spinelli: YEAH, I WOULDN'T
TAKE OLIVIA'S CANINE
CONFABULATIONS --
>> Maxie: IT'S NOT ABOUT THE
DOG.
>> Spinelli: OKAY, THEN WHAT IS
IT?
>> Maxie: I'M WORRIED THAT I'M
DOING THIS FOR THE WRONG REASON.
>> Spinelli: WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHAT COULD BE A WRONG REASON?
>> Maxie: YOU.
>> Elizabeth: I'M GONNA HAVE TO
TAKE A RAIN CHECK ON THAT DRINK.
"CHRISTINA COMES HOME FOR
CHRISTMAS" WAS JUST RELEASED ON
DVD.
>> Britt: THAT MOVIE THAT'S ON
TV 100 TIMES AT CHRISTMAS?
SORRY.
IT'S NEVER BEEN ONE OF MY
FAVORITES.
>> Elizabeth: ACTUALLY, IT'S A
TRADITION IN MY HOUSE.
I THOUGHT I WOULD SURPRISE MY
KIDS WITH IT TONIGHT.
>> Britt: MUST BE NICE TO HAVE
KIDS TO SHARE THE HOLIDAYS.
PATRICK MENTIONED THAT HE AND
HIS DAUGHTER WERE GONNA DECORATE
THEIR TREE TONIGHT, AND I
THOUGHT IT SOUNDED LIKE FUN.
I EVEN OFFERED TO STRING
POPCORN.
BUT HE DIDN'T INVITE ME.
I MEAN, CLEARLY HE'S INTO ME.
I DON'T KNOW WHY HE'S PULLING
BACK NOW.
>> Elizabeth: MAYBE HE WANTED TO
DECORATE HIS TREE WITH JUST HIS
DAUGHTER.
>> Britt: WHAT'S UP WITH YOU?
I MEAN, SINCE I STARTED HERE,
YOU AND I WERE OKAY.
MAYBE WE WEREN'T FRIENDS, BUT WE
WERE CORDIAL.
WE EVEN HAD THAT MOMENT,
REMEMBER, WITH THE NIGHT THE
LUNATIC TRIED TO JUMP OFF THE
ROOF WITH THE BABY.
SO WHAT'S WITH THE COLD
SHOULDER?
>> Elizabeth: I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU MEAN.
>> Britt: SURE YOU DO.
DID YOU DECIDE YOU DON'T LIKE ME
BECAUSE YOU AND SABRINA ARE
JOINED AT THE HIP?
>> Lucy: OH, PORT CHARLES.
IT WAS ALWAYS SUCH A SPECIAL,
SPECIAL PLACE.
BUT I AM AFRAID I HAVE HAD TO
LEAVE IT BEHIND.
[ CHUCKLES ]
>> Sabrina: OH, BUT PORT CHARLES
NEEDS YOU.
>> Lucy: AND WHY IS THAT?
>> Sabrina: FOR A VERY WORTHY
CAUSE.
FROM WHAT I UNDERSTAND, YOU WERE
THE DRIVING FORCE BEHIND THE
NURSES' BALL.
BUT SINCE YOU'VE LEFT, NO ONE'S
PICKED UP YOUR MANTLE.
THERE HASN'T BEEN A NURSES' BALL
IN YEARS.
WE WERE HOPING TO REVIVE THE
TRADITION.
>> Lucy: YOU WERE?
WELL, BRAVO!
BRAVO TO THE TWO OF YOU.
I WANT TO BE THE VERY PERSON YOU
SEND AN INVITATION TO.
>> Sabrina: OH, WELL, WE WOULD
LOVE TO, EXCEPT WE'VE HIT SORT
OF A SNAG.
>> Lucy: A SNAG?
WHAT KIND OF SNAG?
>> Felix: MAJOR.
>> Sabrina: THE HOSPITAL DOESN'T
HAVE ANY MONEY TO FUND THE
NURSES' BALL, SO WE HAVE TO
FINANCE THROUGH PRIVATE
DONATIONS.
WE'RE STILL FAR FROM OUR GOAL,
BUT WE WERE HOPING YOU COULD
HELP US.
>> Lucy: OF -- OF COURSE I CAN.
>> Sabrina: [ LAUGHS ]
>> Robin: HI.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I BET YOU'RE SURPRISED TO SEE
ME.
SO, IT'S CHRISTMAS EVE 2011.
WE HAD THE BEST NIGHT WITH HER.
YOU'RE PROBABLY STANDING THERE
RIGHT NOW, WATCHING HER SLEEP.
AND I WOULD BE THERE RIGHT NEXT
TO YOU, AND WE COULD
CONGRATULATE EACH OTHER ON OUR
AMAZING DAUGHTER.
BUT THERE'S SOMETHING THAT I
HAVE TO TELL YOU, AND I CAN'T
SAY IT TO YOUR FACE.
>> Anna: ROBERT, DO YOU HEAR ME?
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
OH, GOD.
WHO DID THIS TO YOU?
>> Robert: ROBIN! YOU'RE ALI --
STEP AWAY FROM MY DAUGHTER!
OH, BABY. ARE YOU HURT?
[ WEAKLY ] FIND --
>> Anna: WHAT? WHAT?
WHAT IS IT?
>> Robert: FIND -- FIND HER.
>> Anna: "FIND HER"?
WHAT?
>> Robert: [ WHIMPERS ]
FIND HER. FIND HER.
YOU'VE GOT TO FIND HER.
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
I JUST WISH
I COULD KEEP IT THIS WAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW YOU CAN.
WITH THE CREST PRO-HEALTH
CLINICAL LINE.
USED TOGETHER,
THEY HELP KEEP YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
THE TOOTHPASTE
ACTUALLY REDUCES PLAQUE.
AND THE RINSE REACHES ALL AREAS
AND IS CLINICALLY PROVEN TO
HELP PREVENT PLAQUE REGROWTH.
CREST PRO-HEALTH CLINICAL LINE.
TOGETHER, THEY HELP KEEP
YOUR TEETH
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
97% AS CLEAN
AS A DENTAL CLEANING.
Come in now for a 1 carat
diamond heart pendant just
$99.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
BODY WASHES WITH PAPER
THAT REACTS LIKE SKIN.
IF OTHERS CAN STRIP THIS PAPER,
IMAGINE HOW HARSH
THEY CAN BE TO YOUR SKIN.
OH MY GOSH.
[ Female Announcer ]
Dove IS DIFFERENT.
ITS NEW BREAKTHROUGH FORMULA
CHANGES EVERYTHING.
NEW Dove.
THIS IS CARE.
Here's a better idea.
Pillsbury Grands!
Flaky Layers Biscuits
In just 15 minutes
the light delicate layers
add a layer of warmth
to your next dinner.
Pillsbury Grands Biscuits
Let the making begin.
ITS PRETTY NEW SHAPE QUICKLY
FILLS A ROOM WITH FRAGRANCE.
AND A ROOM WITH FRAGRANCE
SETS THE STAGE FOR LIFE.
INTRODUCING THE NEW CANDLE
FROM Glade.
SETS THE STAGE FOR LIFE.
BUT ALL YOU NOTICE IS HER
BEAUTIFUL, HEALTHY SKIN.
JERGENS ULTRA HEALING
MOISTURIZER
MAKES EVEN YOUR DRIEST SKIN
LOOK HEALTHIER, INSTANTLY.
WITH BEAUTIFUL SKIN
FROM JERGENS,
YOU'LL ALWAYS MAKE AN ENTRANCE.
JERGENS®.
THE BEAUTIFUL DIFFERENCE.
SO YOU THINK
SANTA WILL LIKE THESE...
RED AND GREEN M&M'S?
I DON'T KNOW!
I NEVER MET THE GUY!
WHAAAAA!
HE DOES EXIST!
THEY DO EXIST!
UHM... SANTA?
TO SAY GET WELL
TO YOUR LOVED ONES.
♪
THIS CAME FOR YOU, MOMMY.
[ Female Announcer ]
BUT IT TAKES THE TOUCH
OF KLEENEX® BRAND,
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE,
TO TURN A GESTURE
INTO A COMPLETE GIFT OF CARE.
[ barks ]
SEND YOUR OWN FREE
KLEENEX® CARE PACK...
FULL OF SOOTHING ESSENTIALS
AT KLEENEX.COM.
KLEENEX®.
AMERICA'S SOFTEST TISSUE.
>> Robin: REMEMBER THE DEED TO
THE ACRE OF LAND THAT YOU GAVE
ME AND I CRIED AND I TOLD YOU
THAT THEY WERE TEARS OF JOY?
THEY SHOULD HAVE BEEN, BECAUSE
YOU'VE GIVEN ME EVERYTHING THAT
I'VE EVER WANTED -- LOVE AND
COMMITMENT AND A GORGEOUS
DAUGHTER.
YOU GAVE ME A HOME WITH ROOM FOR
MORE CHILDREN AND A GARDEN.
BUT I WASN'T CRYING BECAUSE I
WAS HAPPY.
I WAS CRYING BECAUSE I KNOW THAT
I WILL NEVER SEE THAT HOME, AND
I WILL NEVER HAVE MORE CHILDREN
WITH YOU.
I ALREADY MISS YOU AND EMMA SO
MUCH, I CAN BARELY BREATHE.
MY HIV IS BACK, FOR LACK OF A
BETTER WORD, AND I'VE TRIED ALL
THE PROTOCOLS, AND NOTHING IS
WORKING FOR ME, AND I REALLY
WANTED TO TELL YOU, BUT I DIDN'T
WANT TO RUIN CHRISTMAS FOR YOU
AND EMMA -- OR FOR ME.
I JUST WANTED US TO HAVE ONE
LAST WONDERFUL, PERFECT MEMORY.
[ SIGHS ]
BECAUSE BY NEXT CHRISTMAS --
I WILL BE GONE.
>> Spinelli: YOU VOLUNTEERED TO
BE DANTE AND LULU'S SURROGATE
BECAUSE OF ME?
>> Maxie: I KNOW I SHOULD HAVE
SAID SOMETHING BEFORE, BUT --
NOW THIS IS REAL.
I MEAN, THERE'S REAL EMBRYOS IN
THERE.
AND THEY'RE GONNA PUT THEM
INSIDE OF ME.
IT'S LIKE YOU SAID.
I COULD BE PREGNANT BY TOMORROW.
>> Spinelli: YES. I KNOW.
IT IS A DAUNTING PROSPECT.
>> Maxie: I JUST -- I DON'T WANT
TO MAKE A MISTAKE, SPINELLI.
I NEED TO FIGURE OUT HOW I GOT
HERE.
WHY DID I DECIDE TO DO THIS?
LIKE, WHY WHEN LULU SAID, "I
NEED A SURROGATE," I WAS LIKE,
"HEY! SIGN ME UP!"
>> Spinelli: I'M SURE YOU HAD A
GOOD REASON.
>> Maxie: LULU HAS ACCUSED ME OF
THE ONLY REASON I WANTED TO BE
HER SURROGATE IS BECAUSE OF YOU.
AND THEN MY MOM ASKED ME ABOUT
IT.
AND THEN LULU BROUGHT IT UP
AGAIN.
[ SCOFFS ]
>> Spinelli: DO YOU THINK
THERE'S ANYTHING TO THAT
HYPOTHESIS?
>> Maxie: I KEEP SAYING THAT THE
REAL REASON I'M DOING THIS IS
BECAUSE I WANT TO HELP DANTE AND
LULU HAVE A BABY.
I NEED TO BE A PART OF SOMETHING
IMPORTANT.
>> Spinelli: THAT IS A NOBLE
CAUSE.
>> Maxie: BUT WHAT IF IT'S NOT
SO NOBLE?
OKAY, WHAT IF THE REAL REASON I
WANT TO HELP MY FRIENDS HAVE A
CHILD IS SO THAT I CAN FORGET
THAT I LOVE YOU AND THAT YOU
DON'T LOVE ME BACK?
>> Lucy: DON'T YOU WORRY YOUR
PRETTY LITTLE HEADS, MY
QUACKERS.
CONSIDER THE NURSES' BALL PAID
FOR.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS ASK THE
QUARTERMAINES.
>> Sabrina: QUARTERMAINES?
>> Lucy: WELL, YES, IF YOU'RE
REALLY FROM PORT CHARLES, YOU OF
COURSE -- OF COURSE YOU KNOW THE
Q's.
THEY'RE THE RICHEST, MOST
PROSPEROUS FAMILY IN TOWN.
IN FACT, THEY'RE ACTUALLY
PHILANTHROPIC TO A FAULT.
I KNOW BECAUSE I WAS MARRIED TO
ONE.
>> Sabrina: YOU'RE RIGHT.
THE QUARTERMAINES ARE VERY RICH
AND PHILANTHROPIC, AND THAT'S
WHY I TOOK A MEETING WITH THEM.
UNFORTUNATELY,
TRACY QUARTERMAINE SHOT ME DOWN.
>> Felix: DO YOU KNOW ANYONE
ELSE THAT COULD HELP?
>> Lucy: OF COURSE I DO.
I DO. I DO. LET'S SEE.
OH! I GOT IT.
WHAT ABOUT THAT NEWSPAPER
PUBLISHER, VICTOR LORD'S BASTARD
SON?
WHAT'S HIS NAME?
MEENIE? MEENIE-MO?
MAN --
>> Sabrina: TODD MANNING?
>> Lucy: THAT'S IT. THAT'S IT.
DIDN'T I READ THAT HE MOVED TO
PORT CHARLES EARLIER THIS YEAR?
>> Sabrina: YEAH, HE DID.
UM, BUT, UNFORTUNATELY, HE SHOT
ME DOWN, TOO.
ACTUALLY, HE LAUGHED AT ME.
>> Lucy: HOW RUDE!
OKAY, OKAY.
FORTUNATELY, THAT UPSTART ISN'T
THE ONLY ONE IN PORT CHARLES
WITH DEEP POCKETS.
LET'S THINK.
I KNOW.
SONNY CORINTHOS.
>> Sabrina: UH, YEAH.
WE CONSIDERED SONNY, ACTUALLY.
BUT WE THOUGHT IT WOULDN'T BE
SUCH A GOOD IDEA TO HAVE HIS
NAME ASSOCIATED WITH THE NURSES'
BALL.
>> Lucy: I GET IT.
I GUESS IN RECENT YEARS HIS
REPUTATION HAS, SHALL WE SAY,
"DARKENED SLIGHTLY."
YOU KNOW, IN THE DAY, WAY BACK,
WE KIND OF HEARD RUMORS AND
INNUENDOS, BUT NOW WE JUST SAY,
WELL, HE'S A GANGSTER.
EVERYBODY KNOWS HE'S A GANGSTER.
>> Sabrina: [ CHUCKLES ]
ARE YOU SURE THERE ISN'T ANYONE
ELSE YOU KNOW OF THAT CAN --
>> Lucy: OKAY.
OKAY, DON'T PANIC.
LET ME THINK.
YOU KNOW, I DO TRAVEL IN RATHER
RARIFIED CIRCLES.
UM, OKAY, THERE'S GOT TO BE
SOMEONE WHO CAN HELP US.
SOMEONE VERY, VERY RICH.
THINK, LUCY.
THINK, THINK, THINK, THINK,
THINK, THINK, THINK.
>> Felix: WAIT. MISS COE --
>> Lucy: YEAH?
>> Felix: WHAT ABOUT YOU?
>> Britt: I'VE SEEN THE TWO OF
YOU IN THE BREAK ROOM.
YOU'VE CLEARLY TAKEN HER UNDER
YOUR WING.
>> Elizabeth: SHE'S A STUDENT
NURSE.
>> Britt: YEAH, AND NOT EXACTLY
MY BIGGEST FAN.
>> Elizabeth: OKAY, WE ALL WORK
TOGETHER.
LET'S NOT TURN THIS INTO HIGH
SCHOOL.
>> Britt: YOU TWO ARE THE ONES
GOSSIPING.
LOOK, I'M NOT ASKING FOR YOU TO
TELL ME WHAT SHE WRITES IN HER
DIARY.
ALL I WANT IS FULL DISCLOSURE.
>> Elizabeth: ABOUT WHAT?
>> Britt: ABOUT HOW MUCH SABRINA
HATES ME --
AND LOVES PATRICK.
>> Robin: I'M GONNA HIDE THIS.
HOPEFULLY YOU WON'T FIND IT
UNTIL NEXT CHRISTMAS, 2012, WHEN
YOU'RE GETTING READY.
AND JUST KNOW THAT THERE ISN'T
ANYTHING THAT I WANT MORE THAN
TO BE WITH YOU.
AND I CANNOT STAND THE THOUGHT
OF YOU BEING SAD OR LONELY.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO CUT YOURSELF
OFF FROM THE POSSIBILITY OF
BEING HAPPY AGAIN, BUT I NEED
YOU TO LISTEN TO ME.
YOU HAVE TO STOP THAT RIGHT NOW,
OR YOU'RE GONNA END UP BEING A
BITTER OLD MAN.
AND THAT IS NOT GOOD FOR YOU,
AND THAT IS NOT GOOD FOR OUR
DAUGHTER.
SO I NEED TO ASK YOU SOMETHING,
SOMETHING REALLY BIG --
SOMETHING THAT YOU HAVE TO DO
FOR ME.
>> Anna: OKAY, ROBERT, STAY WITH
US, OKAY?
OBRECHT'S NOT GONNA GET AWAY
WITH THIS.
SHE INJECTED YOU WITH SOMETHING,
OKAY?
>> Robert: [ GRUNTS ]
[ MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY ]
>> Anna: RIGHT.
SAVE YOUR STRENGTH.
WE NEED TO FIND SOMEONE, SOME
HELP.
>> Duke: TRY TO KEEP HIM
CONSCIOUS.
I'LL FIND SOME HELP THAT WE CAN
TRUST.
>> Robert: OH.
SHE HAD --
>> Anna: YES.
>> Robert: SHE HAD HER.
SHE --
>> Anna: WHAT?
IT'S OKAY, ROBERT.
I KNOW. OBRECHT'S INJECTED YOU.
YOU'RE GONNA BE OKAY.
JUST STAY WITH ME, ALL RIGHT?
>> Robert: [ GROANING ]
ANNA?
>> Anna: YES.
>> Robert: SHE HAS --
SHE HA --
[ GROANS ]
>> Anna: ROBERT!
>> Robin: YOU HAVE TO FIND A WAY
TO BE HAPPY.
YOU KNOW EMMA IS -- SHE'S SMALL.
SHE HAS A LONG LIFE AHEAD OF
HER.
I WANT OUR LITTLE GIRL TO GROW
UP IN A HAPPY HOME.
SO I HAVE TO ASK YOU --
TO HONOR MY MEMORY AND THE
MEMORY THAT WE HAVE AS A FAMILY
BY FINDING SOMEONE ELSE TO BE A
FAMILY WITH AGAIN.
AND SO I'M TELLING YOU IT'S OKAY
WITH ME IF YOU MOVE ON --
AND OPEN YOUR HEART TO ANOTHER
WOMAN.
♪
There's a place where the sky is
always blue
and the kids always eat
their vegetables.
Because the salad there is
always served
with the
Original Hidden Valley Ranch.
It's the way Ranch is supposed
to taste.
And try Hidden Valley for
Everything.
It's in the ketchup aisle.
Plus
The perfecting color
of a BB cream
Equal?
Introducing
the newest beauty trend.
Total Effects CC Cream
C for Color. C for Correction.
[ Female Announcer ]
Fight 7 signs of aging
Flawlessly.
CC what's possible.
ONE SQUARE INCH OF
DELICIOUSLY SMOOTH CHOCOLATE
IN CREAMY MILK...
OR RICH DARK.
INCREDIBLE INDULGENCE.
ONE SQUARE INCH OF BLISS.
HERSHEY'S BLISS.
CURÉL ULTRA HEALING LOTION
REPAIRS AND RENEWS DRY SKIN
TWO TIMES BETTER THAN THE
LEADING ADVANCED LOTION.
DEVELOPED WITH
ADVANCED CERAMIDE THERAPY,
IT EVEN HELPS PREVENT
DRY SKIN FROM COMING BACK.
THANK YOU CURÉL.
SEE THE CURE IN CURÉL.
Just unroll it,
fill, top,
bake, and present.
That must have
taken you forever!
It was really tough.
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Pie Crust.
Let the Making Begin
>> Spinelli: YOU DECIDED TO BE A
SURROGATE BECAUSE I CHOSE ELLIE
OVER YOU?
>> Maxie: NO, NO.
I'M HELPING GIVE DANTE AND LULU
A CHILD.
THAT'S THE MOST MEANINGFUL THING
I COULD DO FOR A FRIEND.
ON THE OTHER HAND --
WHEN DID I DECIDE TO DO THIS?
YOU KNOW, RIGHT AFTER YOU CHOSE
ELLIE INSTEAD OF ME.
>> Spinelli: SORRY.
>> Maxie: IT JUST MADE ME WANT
TO DO SOMETHING, LIKE, BIGGER
FOR MYSELF.
I JUST -- I DIDN'T FEEL LIKE I
WAS REALLY IMPORTANT, YOU KNOW.
I DIDN'T FEEL LIKE I MATTERED,
'CAUSE I JUST TOLD YOU I LOVED
YOU WITH ALL MY HEART AND SOUL,
AND THEN YOU SAID YOU DIDN'T
WANT ME.
WHY DID YOU DO THAT?
WAS IT BECAUSE YOU WERE ALREADY
WITH ELLIE?
OR WAS IT BECAUSE OF ME?
YOU JUST KNEW YOU COULDN'T LOVE
ME.
>> Lucy: SO, YOU WANT ME TO
UNDERWRITE THE NURSES' BALL.
>> Sabrina: [ CHUCKLES ]
THAT'S A GREAT IDEA!
>> Felix: WELL, IT'S AN IDEA,
BUT I DON'T KNOW HOW GREAT IT
WAS.
>> Lucy: NO, NO, NO.
IT'S GREAT. IT'S GREAT.
SABRINA'S RIGHT.
IT'S A GREAT IDEA.
AND I WOULD LOVE, LOVE TO FUND
THE NURSES' BALL.
IT'S JUST, UM --
RIGHT AT THE MOMENT, UM, MY
MONEY IS, UM, A BIT TIED UP.
AND -- AND, I MEAN, COME ON.
THE TIME IT TAKES FOR SUCH A
MASSIVE UNDERTAKING, YOU KNOW,
ALL THE COMMITMENT I WOULD HAVE
TO MAKE, I DON'T THINK I COULD
DO THAT.
I MEAN, AFTER ALL, I DO HAVE
THIS GLORIOUS COSMETIC EMPIRE TO
RUN.
>> Sabrina: BUT I KNOW HOW
IMPORTANT RAISING MONEY TO FIGHT
AIDS WAS FOR YOU.
SHOULDN'T THAT TAKE PRIORITY?
>> Lucy: WELL, OF COURSE.
IT'S VERY, VERY IMPORTANT.
>> Sabrina: BUT EVEN MORE SO
THIS YEAR.
ROBIN SCORPIO-DRAKE DIED LAST
SPRING.
>> Lucy: YEAH. I KNOW.
I KNOW.
I WOULD HAVE GIVEN ANYTHING TO
BE AT HER FUNERAL.
SHE -- SHE WAS TRULY AN
INSPIRATION TO ALL OF US.
YOU KNOW, AND I KNEW HER AS A
KID.
I KNEW HER SINCE SHE WAS A
LITTLE GIRL, AND I WAS JUST SO
HAPPY WHEN I FOUND OUT THAT SHE
HAD A FAMILY OF HER OWN.
>> Sabrina: HER HUSBAND IS A
BRILLIANT NEUROSURGEON, AND HE'S
COMMITTED TO KEEPING HER LEGACY
GOING.
ACTUALLY, HE CAN TALK TO YOU
ABOUT IT.
>> Lucy: OH, NO! NO, NO.
THAT'S NOT NECESSARY.
LOOK, I KNOW --
>> Sabrina: NO, IT WON'T BE ANY
TROUBLE AT ALL.
NO, PATRICK -- UH, DR. DRAKE --
HE WILL CONVINCE YOU.
HE WANTS HIS WIFE'S WORK TO
CONTINUE SO THAT HER DEATH WILL
ACTUALLY COUNT FOR SOMETHING.
>> Robin: I DON'T WANT YOU TO BE
ALONE.
YOU'RE AN INCREDIBLE MAN.
YOU HAVE A LOT OF LOVE TO GIVE.
SHE'S OUT THERE.
I MEAN, SHE'S SMART, AND SHE'S
FUNNY, AND --
SHE WILL LOVE YOU.
AND SHE WILL LOVE EMMA AS IF SHE
WERE HER OWN.
SO PLEASE FIND SOMEONE WHO WILL
MAKE YOU A FAMILY AGAIN.
>> Britt: COME ON.
JUST TELL ME THE TRUTH ABOUT
SABRINA.
>> Elizabeth: OKAY.
YES, SABRINA AND I WORK
TOGETHER.
AND WE'RE ON THE SAME COMMITTEE
FOR REVIVING THE NURSES' BALL.
>> Britt: SPEAKING OF, DON'T YOU
FIND IT INTERESTING THAT SHE'S
DECIDED TO MAKE THAT HER PET
PROJECT?
A BENEFIT THAT WAS A MAJOR CAUSE
FOR DR. SCORPIO-DRAKE?
>> Elizabeth: I DON'T KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
>> Britt: I'M TALKING ABOUT
SABRINA MAKING A MOVE ON
PATRICK.
SHE FIGURED THE WAY TO HIS HEART
WAS THROUGH HIS DEAD WIFE.
THAT'S WHY SHE WON'T SHUT UP
ABOUT HER EVERY TIME SHE'S
AROUND HIM.
IT'S NOTHING BUT, "ROBIN, ROBIN,
ROBIN."
>> Elizabeth: YOU WANT THE
TRUTH?
HERE IT IS.
SABRINA WOULD BE BETTER FOR
PATRICK THAN YOU COULD EVER HOPE
TO BE.
>> Robin: I WANT EMMA TO HAVE A
MOTHER FIGURE, AND, QUITE
FRANKLY, YOU NEED A WIFE.
I HAVE TO ADMIT, I HAVE VETTED
SOME CANDIDATES MYSELF THAT ARE
FIT.
NOTHING FORMAL, OF COURSE.
IF YOU THINK IT'S WEIRD WATCHING
THIS, I MEAN, THINK ABOUT HOW
WEIRD IT IS FOR ME TO PICK OUT
MY REPLACEMENT.
ELIZABETH.
YOU'RE ALREADY FRIENDS.
I KNOW THAT SHE CARES ABOUT YOU.
AND SHE WOULD CERTAINLY MAKE AN
INCREDIBLE MOTHER TO EMMA.
I'M SURE THAT THERE ARE WOMEN
LINED UP AROUND THE BLOCK FOR
YOU, SO IF THAT DOESN'T WORK FOR
YOU, FEEL FREE TO PICK ONE OUT
FOR YOURSELF.
BUT JUST KNOW THAT IF YOU PICK
WRONG, I WILL COME BACK TO HAUNT
YOU.
>> Patrick: [ CHUCKLES ]
>> Duke: I GOT A DOCTOR.
>> Anna: WHAT? CAN WE TRUST HIM?
OKAY, WE FOUND HIM ON THE
GROUND.
HE WAS SEMI-CONSCIOUS.
HE'S BEEN INJECTED WITH
SOMETHING.
WHERE'S THAT THING?
>> Duke: WE FOUND THIS IN HIS
CHEST.
>> THIS IS DR. OBRECHT'S WING.
I WILL NEED TO PAGE HER.
>> Anna: NO, WE DON'T!
NO, NO.
SHE'S THE ONE WHO DID THIS TO
HIM.
YOU HAVE TO SAVE HIM.
>> NO, I'M SORRY, WITHOUT
KNOWING WHAT SHE GAVE HIM, I --
>> Duke: HERE, DOES THIS HELP?
>> Anna: WHAT IS THAT?
>> PROPOFOL.
>> Anna: IT'S PROPOFOL?
THAT'S A SEDATIVE, ISN'T IT?
ISN'T THAT LETHAL IN LARGE
DOSES?
ISN'T IT LETHAL?
>> I'M SORRY.
IF SHE GAVE HIM THE ENTIRE VIAL,
I CANNOT HELP.
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS IS BOB,
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
I'd like to thank eating right,
whole grain,
Multigrain Cheerios!
Mom, are those my jeans?
[ Female Announcer ] People
who choose more whole grain
tend to weigh less
than those who don't.
Multigrain Cheerios
FLAVOR, MEET FOOD.
IT'S TIME
FOR SWANSON FLAVOR BOOST.
CONCENTRATED BROTH
IN EASY TO USE PACKETS.
MIX IT INTO SKILLET DISHES,
FOR AN INSTANT DOSE OF...
HELL-O!
[ Female Announcer ]
GET RECIPES AT FLAVORBOOST.COM.
♪
[ Female Announcer ] WITH
ITS RICH, SILKY SMOOTH TASTE
THERE'S MAGIC IN EVERY PIECE
OF DOVE® DARK CHOCOLATE.
♪
WE DON'T LET FREQUENT HEARTBURN
COME BETWEEN US
AND WHAT WE LOVE.
SO IF YOU'RE ONE OF THEM PEOPLE
WHO GETS HEARTBURN
AND THEN TREATS DAY AFTER DAY...
BLOCK THE ACID WITH PRILOSEC OTC
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
[ Male Announcer ]
ONE PILL EACH MORNING.
24 HOURS. ZERO HEARTBURN.
AND DON'T GET HEARTBURN
IN THE FIRST PLACE!
♪
Get her 1/3rd carat
diamond earrings
this week only just $29.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
>> Maxie: NO, NO.
JUST BE HONEST, SPINELLI.
I MEAN, NOW THAT YOU'RE WITH
ELLIE, HAS IT SUDDENLY OCCURRED
TO YOU THAT I'M --
ALL SURFACE AND NOTHING
UNDERNEATH?
I MEAN, YOU -- YOU NEED SOMEONE
WHO CAN KEEP UP WITH YOUR
BRILLIANCE LIKE SHE CAN?
I-I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE [ SIGHS ] ALL THAT LOVE
THAT YOU FELT FOR ME BEFORE, YOU
REALIZED YOU NEVER REALLY FELT
IT AT ALL.
>> Spinelli: MAXIE --
WHEN YOU REVEALED YOUR TRUE
FEELINGS FOR ME --
I COULD HARDLY CONTAIN MY JOY.
I WANTED TO SCREAM, "YES!
OF COURSE I LOVE YOU!"
A-AND YES, I WOULD CHOSE YOU
OVER ELLIE IN AN INSTANT.
>> Maxie: BUT YOU DIDN'T.
YOU CHOSE ELLIE OVER ME.
>> Spinelli: I HAD ALREADY
DECIDED THAT I COULDN'T SPEND
ONE MORE DAY HOPING THAT YOU'D
FALL IN LOVE WITH ME.
DESPITE YOUR -- YOUR GRACE, YOUR
INTELLIGENCE --
AND YOUR INCANDESCENCE, I --
I HAD RESOLVED TO MOVE ON.
I MET ELLIE.
AND SHE WAS OPEN WITH ME IN
REGARDS TO HER FEELINGS, AND I
RETURNED THOSE FEELINGS.
I CAN SEE A FUTURE WITH ELLIE.
BUT I STILL CARE ABOUT YOU.
AND I WILL ALWAYS LOVE YOU.
>> Maxie: SO --
THIS IS ABOUT ELLIE AND --
NOT ME.
>> Spinelli: YOU KNOW, YOU'RE
NOT THE FIRST PERSON TO ASK THAT
IF IT WEREN'T FOR ELLIE, WOULD I
HAVE ACCEPTED YOUR DECLARATION
OF LOVE AND FALLEN INTO YOUR
ARMS, AND --
THE ANSWER IS YES.
IF I HADN'T MET ELLIE, I WOULD
BE WITH YOU.
>> Maxie: BUT YOU DID MEET HER.
>> Spinelli: MAXIE, YOU ARE NOT
STUPID.
YOU'RE NOT SHALLOW.
YOU'RE NOT ANY OF THOSE
CHARACTERISTICS THAT YOU
ASSIGNED YOURSELF.
YOU ARE GENEROUS.
YOU ARE BEAUTIFUL.
AND YOU HAVE A GRACIOUS HEART.
>> Maxie: [ SNIFFLES ]
>> Spinelli: AND YOU DON'T
NEED -- PLEASE BELIEVE ME WHEN I
TELL YOU THAT YOU DON'T NEED TO
BE A SURROGATE TO PROVE THAT
YOU'RE IMPORTANT.
BECAUSE YOU ALREADY ARE.
>> Maxie: THANK YOU FOR
BELIEVING THAT.
>> Spinelli: MAXIE, ARE --
ARE YOU REALLY SURE THAT YOU
WANT TO GO THROUGH WITH THIS
PREGNANCY?
>> Maxie: [ SIGHS ]
>> Sabrina: SO, I JUST LEFT
DR. DRAKE A MESSAGE, AND I-I
JUST KNOW THAT AFTER ONE
CONVERSATION, YOU WILL BE MORE
THAN READY --
>> Lucy: STOP, STOP.
LOOK, I-I DON'T HAVE TO TALK TO
ROBIN'S HUSBAND.
I REMEMBER EVERY SINGLE WORD
ROBIN SAID AT THE NURSES' BALL.
I REMEMBER ALL HER COURAGE WHEN
SHE STOOD UP BEFORE EVERYBODY IN
PORT CHARLES AND SAID, "I AM
HIV-POSITIVE."
SHE SET SUCH AN EXAMPLE HOW TO
LIVE WITH THAT CONDITION WITH
GRACE AND HOW TO LIVE YOUR LIFE
TO THE FULLEST.
SO I-I KNOW, I BELIEVE THE
NURSES' BALL IS SUCH A WORTHY
CAUSE.
>> Sabrina: BUT IF YOU KNOW
THAT, THEN WHY WON'T YOU HELP?
ARE YOU REALLY THAT WRAPPED UP?
ARE YOU REALLY SO BUSY IN THIS
COMPANY?
IS LIPSTICK REALLY THAT MUCH
MORE IMPORTANT?
>> Lucy: NO!
NO. NO.
NO, NO, OF COURSE NOT.
YOU SEE, UM, I'M SORT OF --
I CAN'T --
[ SIGHS ]
I'M BROKE.
>> Felix: BROKE?
HOW CAN YOU BE BROKE?
>> Lucy: HOW CAN I BE BROKE?
WELL, LET ME JUST EXPLAIN SOME
LETTERS TO YOU.
I AM BROKE BECAUSE THE IRS, THE
SEC, THE FDC, THE CIA, THE FBI,
AND SOME SORT OF DEPARTMENT OF
CONSUMER AFFAIRS HAS COMPLETELY
FROZEN MY ASSETS!
>> Sabrina: WHAT? WHY?
WHY WOULD THEY DO THAT?
>> Lucy: WHY?
WELL, BECAUSE THEY'RE CLAIMING
THAT I AM RUNNING A KIND OF
PYRAMID SCHEME.
DO YOU KNOW THEY ARE ACTUALLY
CALLING ME THE BERNIE MADOFF OF
MAKEUP.
>> Sabrina: [ GASPS ]
>> Felix: SO WAIT.
DOES THIS MEAN I WON'T BE A
GOLDEN DUCK?
>> Lucy: NO, NO!
NO, NO, NO, NO.
FELIX, YOU WILL BE A GOLDEN
DUCK.
KEEP THE FAITH.
I WILL CLEAR MY NAME.
BUT, YOU SEE, FOR NOW THE ONLY
CHECKS I'M GONNA BE WRITING ARE
TO MY WHOLE TEAM OF LAWYERS.
EVEN THOUGH I REALLY WOULD LOVE,
LOVE TO FUND THE NURSES' BALL, I
CAN'T.
>> Robin: PLEASE GET ON WITH
YOUR LIVE.
AND JUST KNOW THAT I'M SAYING
ALL OF THIS BECAUSE OF HOW MUCH
I TRULY LOVE YOU.
I ALWAYS WILL.
>> Patrick: [ GROANS ]
>> Britt: YOU'RE KIDDING, RIGHT?
YOU THINK LITTLE SABRINA
SUNSHINE IS BETTER FOR PATRICK
THAN ME?
>> Elizabeth: THAT'S WHAT I
SAID.
>> Britt: THE GIRL PRACTICALLY
MOONS OVER HIM.
YOU THINK THAT'S HOW TO HAVE AN
ADULT RELATIONSHIP, BY
FANTASIZING ABOUT SOMEONE WHO'S
NOT EVEN REMOTELY INTERESTED IN
YOU?
>> Elizabeth: WOW, YOU WANT TO
TALK ABOUT HAVING AN ADULT
RELATIONSHIP?
YOU PURPOSELY DANGLED YOUR HOTEL
KEY UNDER SABRINA'S NOSE JUST TO
MAKE SURE THAT SHE WOULD KNOW
THAT YOU'RE HOOKING UP WITH
PATRICK.
>> Britt: I AM NOT ASHAMED OF MY
PRIVATE LIFE --
UNLIKE SOME PEOPLE.
I DON'T HAVE A REASON TO HIDE.
>> Elizabeth: OH.
IS THAT WHAT YOU DO?
YOU ATTACK PEOPLE WHERE THEY'RE
MOST VULNERABLE.
YOU KNOW SABRINA IS SHY AND
INEXPERIENCED, AND SO YOU ARE
GOING TO MAKE HER FEEL SMALLER
THAN SHE ALREADY DOES.
>> Britt: I CANNOT CONTROL HOW
SABRINA FEELS ABOUT --
>> Elizabeth: YOU TREAT HER LIKE
DIRT.
UNTIL PATRICK SHOWS UP, AND
THEN, OF COURSE, BUTTER WOULDN'T
MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
DON'T THINK YOU'RE FOOLING
ANYONE.
>> Britt: I HAD NO IDEA I WAS
BEING WATCHED SO CLOSELY.
>> Elizabeth: OH, I DON'T HAVE
TO.
YOU'RE TRANSPARENT.
AND IF I CAN SEE RIGHT THROUGH
YOU, SO CAN PATRICK.
>> Britt: PATRICK ENJOYS MY
COMPANY --
MORE EVERY DAY.
>> Elizabeth: BUT HE DIDN'T CALL
YOU TONIGHT, DID HE?
YOU'RE SO CONCERNED HE'S NOT
INTERESTED IN YOU, DID IT EVER
OCCUR TO YOU THAT MAYBE PATRICK
IS HAVING A HARD TIME MOVING ON
BECAUSE THE LOVE OF HIS LIFE WAS
KILLED IN AN ACCIDENT LESS THAN
A YEAR AGO?
NO?
WELL, LET ME TELL YOU THIS.
IT SURE AS HELL OCCURRED TO
SABRINA.
SHE GETS HIM.
SHE UNDERSTANDS THAT HE IS STILL
GRIEVING FOR HIS DEAD WIFE.
>> Anna: YOU DON'T KNOW THIS
MAN.
YOU DON'T KNOW WHAT HE'S
SURVIVED.
HE'S STRONG.
YOU KNOW, YOU HAVE TO SAVE HIM.
>> PERHAPS THERE'S SOMETHING I
CAN TRY.
>> Anna: OKAY, GOOD.
THANK YOU.
ROBERT?
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
LISTEN.
YOU'VE GOT TO LIVE, ALL RIGHT?
BECAUSE GIVING UP AND DYING IS
NOT AN OPTION.
I'M GONNA BE HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA BE HERE, TOO.
I'M NOT GONNA DO THIS ALONE.
>> Elizabeth: I'VE KNOWN PATRICK
A LONG TIME, AND I KNOW THAT HE
WOULD RATHER BE WITH SOMEONE
HONEST AND GENUINE LIKE
SABRINA --
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
-- THAN SPITEFUL AND
BACK-STABBING, LIKE YOU.
>> Britt: HELLO, PATRICK.
>> Patrick: LISTEN, I'M SORRY I
DIDN'T TEXT YOU BACK ABOUT
DECORATING THE TREE.
>> Britt: OH, THAT'S OKAY.
MAYBE ANOTHER NIGHT.
>> Patrick: ACTUALLY, I WAS
THINKING IF IT'S, UM --
WELL, IF IT'S NOT TOO LATE, IF
YOU WANTED TO COME BY FOR A
DRINK.
>> Britt: NO, IT'S NOT TOO LATE.
I CAN COME OVER.
>> Patrick: OKAY, GOOD.
I'M HERE.
SO I'LL SEE YOU IN A BIT.
>> Britt: SEE YOU.
I'M SORRY. YOU WERE SAYING?
[ Mom ] 3 DAYS INTO SCHOOL BREAK
AND THEY'RE ALREADY BORED.
HMM, WE NEED A NEW GAME.
♪
THAT'LL SAVE THE DAY.
SO WILL BOUNTY SELECT-A-SIZE.
IT'S THE SMALLER POWERFUL SHEET.
THE ONLY ONE
WITH TRAP + LOCK TECHNOLOGY.
LOOK! ONE SELECT-A-SIZE SHEET
OF BOUNTY IS 50% MORE ABSORBENT
THAN A FULL SIZE SHEET
OF THE LEADING ORDINARY BRAND.
USE LESS. WITH THE SMALL
BUT POWERFUL PICKER UPPER,
BOUNTY SELECT-A-SIZE.
USE LESS. WITH THE SMALL
BUT POWERFUL PICKER UPPER,
Come in now for a 1 carat
diamond heart pendant just
$99.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
Cheese plate?
Cheese plate...nope.
I made something better.
♪
You used the oven?
BOOM
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the making begin.
A DELICIOUS NEW WAY TO GET
ESSENTIAL VITAMINS YOU NEED.
JUST BITE
INTO THE TASTY SHELL...
TO A CHEWY VITAMIN CORE
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
NEW CENTRUM FLAVOR BURST.
WITH LESS CHRONIC
OSTEOARTHRITIS PAIN.
IMAGINE LIVING YOUR LIFE
WITH LESS CHRONIC
LOW BACK PAIN.
IMAGINE YOU, WITH LESS PAIN.
CYMBALTA CAN HELP.
CYMBALTA IS FDA-APPROVED
TO MANAGE CHRONIC
MUSCULOSKELETAL PAIN.
ONE NON-NARCOTIC PILL A DAY,
EVERY DAY,
CAN HELP REDUCE THIS PAIN.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOUR MOOD WORSENS,
YOU HAVE UNUSUAL CHANGES
IN MOOD OR BEHAVIOR
OR THOUGHTS OF SUICIDE.
ANTIDEPRESSANTS
CAN INCREASE THESE
IN CHILDREN, TEENS,
AND YOUNG ADULTS.
CYMBALTA IS NOT APPROVED
FOR CHILDREN UNDER 18.
PEOPLE TAKING MAOIS
OR THIORIDAZINE
OR WITH UNCONTROLLED GLAUCOMA
SHOULD NOT TAKE CYMBALTA.
TAKING IT WITH
NSAID PAIN RELIEVERS, ASPIRIN,
OR BLOOD THINNERS
MAY INCREASE BLEEDING RISK.
SEVERE LIVER PROBLEMS,
SOME FATAL, WERE REPORTED.
SIGNS INCLUDE ABDOMINAL PAIN
AND YELLOWING SKIN OR EYES.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ALL YOUR MEDICINES,
INCLUDING THOSE FOR MIGRAINE
AND WHILE ON CYMBALTA,
CALL RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU HAVE HIGH FEVER,
CONFUSION AND STIFF MUSCLES
OR SERIOUS ALLERGIC
SKIN REACTIONS
LIKE BLISTERS, PEELING RASH,
HIVES, OR MOUTH SORES
TO ADDRESS POSSIBLE
LIFE-THREATENING CONDITIONS.
TALK ABOUT YOUR ALCOHOL USE,
LIVER DISEASE
AND BEFORE YOU REDUCE
OR STOP CYMBALTA.
DIZZINESS OR FAINTING MAY OCCUR
UPON STANDING.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CYMBALTA.
IMAGINE YOU WITH LESS PAIN.
CYMBALTA CAN HELP.
GO TO CYMBALTA.COM
TO LEARN ABOUT
A FREE TRIAL OFFER.
I NEED ALL THE HELP I CAN GET.
THAT'S WHY I LIKE NUTELLA.
MOM, WHAT'S THE CAPITAL
OF WEST VIRGINIA?
CHARLESTON.
NUTELLA IS A DELICIOUS HAZELNUT
SPREAD MY WHOLE FAMILY LOVES.
MOM, HAVE YOU SEEN MY --
BACKPACK?
NUTELLA GOES GREAT
ON WHOLE-WHEAT TOAST
OR WHOLE-GRAIN WAFFLES.
AND ITS GREAT TASTE
COMES FROM A UNIQUE COMBINATION
OF SIMPLE INGREDIENTS
LIKE HAZELNUTS,
SKIM MILK AND A HINT OF COCOA.
YEAH, BYE.
HAVE YOU SEEN MY --
YES.
AND...THANK YOU.
[ Male Announcer ] NUTELLA.
BREAKFAST NEVER TASTED
THIS GOOD.
>> Maxie: INSTEAD OF YOU BEING
THE FIRST THING I THINK ABOUT
WHEN I WAKE UP AND THE LAST
THING I THINK ABOUT BEFORE I GO
TO SLEEP, I'LL BE THINKING ABOUT
THAT BABY.
SO, YES.
TO ANSWER YOUR QUESTION --
I DO WANT TO DO THIS.
>> Sabrina: WELL, THANK YOU FOR
YOUR TIME, MISS COE.
>> Lucy: WAIT!
WAIT. WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
DON'T -- PLEASE, PLEASE DON'T
GIVE UP HOPE.
YOU CAN'T.
YOU GOT TO KEEP LOOKING FOR
SOMEBODY TO FINANCE THE NURSES'
BALL.
REALLY, AND I'LL BE SENDING ALL
MY LITTLE POSITIVE THOUGHTS
RIGHT OUT TO YOU.
>> Sabrina: IF YOUR ASSETS THAW,
WILL YOU GIVE ME A CALL?
>> Lucy: YEAH.
YOU'LL BE THE FIRST I CALL.
>> Sabrina: OKAY!
WELL, LET ME JUST GIVE YOU MY
NUMBER, THEN.
>> Lucy: OKAY.
HMM.
CoeCoe'S RED VELVET CUPCAKE.
IT WOULD BE PERFECT ON YOUR
BEAUTIFUL SKIN TONE.
>> Felix: SHUT UP!
THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I MADE HER
UP WITH BEFORE HER BREAKFAST
MEETING ABOUT THE NURSES' BALL
WITH THE MAN OF HER DREAMS.
>> Britt: YOUR TREE LOOKS GREAT.
I GUESS YOU AND EMMA FINISHED
THE DECORATING.
>> Patrick: YEAH, WE DID.
I'M SORRY I DIDN'T TEXT YOU
ABOUT THAT.
OH, DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
>> Patrick: IT'S NOT THAT I
DIDN'T WANT TO SEE YOU.
IT WAS JUST, WHEN YOU SAID THAT
THE THREE OF US WOULD DO IT
TOGETHER --
WELL, IT REMINDED ME OF THE
THINGS THAT WE'RE NOT GONNA DO
AS A FAMILY WITH ROBIN ANYMORE
BECAUSE THIS IS OUR FIRST
CHRISTMAS WITHOUT HER.
>> Britt: PATRICK, PLEASE, YOU
DON'T NEED TO EXPLAIN.
I ASSUMED THAT WAS THE REASON.
>> Patrick: THANK YOU FOR
UNDERSTANDING.
>> Britt: HOW COULD I NOT?
I'M JUST GLAD THAT YOU CALLED.
LIKE I SAID, THIS IS MY FAVORITE
TIME OF YEAR, AND IT'S MORE FUN
TO SPEND IT WITH SOMEONE.
I BROUGHT EGGNOG --
>> Patrick: WOW. LOOK AT THAT.
>> Britt: -- AND BOURBON.
>> Patrick: I'M THE HOST.
I'M SUPPOSED TO BE DOING THAT
FOR YOU.
>> Britt: [ CHUCKLES]
I -- OH, I ALSO HAVE A LITTLE
SOMETHING FOR EMMA.
WHERE IS SHE?
>> Patrick: I PUT HER DOWN A
LITTLE BIT AGO.
SHE'S PROBABLY FAST ASLEEP
ALREADY.
>> Britt: OH, THAT'S TOO BAD.
I WAS HOPING MAYBE WE COULD ALL
WATCH THIS.
>> Patrick: WOW.
>> HEY, ELIZABETH.
DID YOU LOSE SOMETHING?
>> Elizabeth: YEAH.
"CHRISTINA COMES HOME FOR
CHRISTMAS."
I BOUGHT A COPY WHEN I PICKED UP
THIS VIDEO GAME FOR CAMERON, AND
THE GAME'S IN THE BAG, BUT THE
MOVIE'S GONE.
>> Patrick: HOW DID YOU GET YOUR
HANDS ON THIS?
"CHRISTINA COMES HOME FOR
CHRISTMAS" -- THIS IS ONE OF MY
FAVORITE MOVIES.
I TRIED TO BUY IT ONLINE, AND
IT'S SOLD OUT.
HOW DID -- YOU HAVE SOME SECRET
CONNECTION OR SOMETHING?
>> Britt: OH, I CAN'T REVEAL MY
SOURCES.
[ BOTH CHUCKLE ]
WELL, WHY DON'T YOU JUST TAKE
MINE?
>> Patrick: NO, NO, NO.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
>> Britt: NO, SERIOUSLY, YOU AND
EMMA CAN WATCH IT TOMORROW.
>> Patrick: TOMORROW.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
THIS IS ONE OF THE BEST
BLACK-AND-WHITE MOVIES HOLLYWOOD
EVER MADE.
THIS CAN'T WAIT TILL TOMORROW.
I THINK WE NEED TO WATCH THIS
TONIGHT.
>> Britt: [ CHUCKLES ]
>> Anna: SO THIS DRUG, IT
COUNTERACTS PROPOFOL?
>> IN THEORY.
BUT I'M AFRAID I CAN'T MAKE ANY
GUARANTEES.
TYOU WOULDN'T WANT YOUR
ADOCTOR DOING YOUR JOB,
HELLO....
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING HERS?
ONLY YOUR DOCTOR CAN DETERMINE
IF YOUR PERSISTENT HEARTBURN IS
ACTUALLY SOMETHING
MORE SERIOUS,
LIKE ACID REFLUX DISEASE.
OVER TIME, STOMACH
ACID CAN DAMAGE
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
FOR MANY, PRESCRIPTION NEXIUM
NOT ONLY PROVIDES
24-HOUR HEARTBURN RELIEF,
BUT CAN ALSO HELP HEAL
ACID-RELATED EROSIONS
IN THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
THERE IS RISK OF BONE FRACTURE
AND LOW MAGNESIUM LEVELS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, ABDOMINAL
PAIN AND DIARRHEA.
CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY IF
YOU HAVE PERSISTENT DIARRHEA.
OTHER SERIOUS STOMACH
CONDITIONS MAY EXIST.
DON'T TAKE NEXIUM IF
YOU TAKE CLOPIDOGREL.
LET YOUR DOCTOR DO HER JOB.
AND YOU DO YOURS.
ASK IF NEXIUM IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
IF YOU CAN'T AFFORD
YOUR MEDICATION,
ASTRAZENECA MAY BE ABLE TO HELP.
Whatever it takes, get to
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
Don't judge me!
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
I DIDN'T WANT TO CHANGE
TOOTHPASTES.
I ALREADY HAD A PRODUCT
THAT MADE MY MOUTH FEEL CLEAN.
WHY AM I GOING TO GO
AND CHANGE IT?
THE FIRST THING HE RECOMMENDED
WAS THAT I USE SENSODYNE.
SENSODYNE HELPS
WITH THE SENSITIVITY ISSUES
AND AT THE SAME TIME
IT GIVES YOU THE CLEAN FEELING.
YOUR MOUTH FEELS FRESH.
SENSODYNE SATISFIES THE NEEDS
THAT I WOULD LOOK FOR
IN A TOOTHPASTE.
I DEFINITELY FEEL LIKE
I CAN BE MYSELF NOW.
I DON'T HAVE THE SAME PAIN
I DID.
IT GIVES YOU YOUR LIFE BACK.
I DON'T HAVE THE SAME PAIN
I DID.
DELICIOUS HERSHEY'S CHOCOLATEH,
WITH 30% LESS FAT?
HERSHEY'S SIMPLE
PLEASURES CHOCOLATE.
30% LESS FAT, 100% DELICIOUS.
♪
Get her 1/3rd carat
diamond earrings
this week only just $29.99.
And save 75 to 80% on
all Fashion Diamonds.
At Kmart.
AHH, CLOUDY GLASSES.
YOU DIDN'T
HAVE TO COME OVER!
EASY.
HI. CASCADE KITCHEN COUNSELOR.
LOOK!
OVER TIME, CASCADE COMPLETE PACS
FIGHT FILM BUILDUP TWO TIMES
BETTER THAN FINISH QUANTUM
TO HELP LEAVE GLASSES SPARKLING.
CASCADE. THE CLEAR CHOICE.
CURÉL ULTRA HEALING LOTION
REPAIRS AND RENEWS DRY SKIN
TWO TIMES BETTER THAN THE
LEADING ADVANCED LOTION.
DEVELOPED WITH
ADVANCED CERAMIDE THERAPY,
IT EVEN HELPS PREVENT
DRY SKIN FROM COMING BACK.
THANK YOU CURÉL.
SEE THE CURE IN CURÉL.
AND WE GOT ONESIES.
SOMETIMES MIRACLES
GET MESSY.
SO WE USE TIDE FREE.
NO PERFUMES OR DYES
FOR HER DELICATE SKIN.
BRAD.
NOT IT. NOT IT.
JUST KIDDING.
THAT'S OUR TIDE.
WHAT'S YOURS?
Aunt Sally's
singing again.
It's a tradition,
honey.
[ singing
Christmas carols ]
mmmm.
[ Female Announcer ]
Make new traditions
with Pillsbury Grands!
Cinnamon Rolls.
FAMILY PARTY IN FIFTEEN.
OK LET'S DO IT!
[ Female Announcer ] IT'S
THE HOLIDAY SALE AT PAYLESS.
GRAB ALL THE STYLES YOU NEED
IN A FLASH
AT FESTIVELY LOW PRICES.
RIGHT NOW AT PAYLESS.
>> Spinelli: ELLIE?
>> Ellie: YEAH.
>> Spinelli: HEY, T-THERE'S
SOMETHING I WANT TO TALK TO YOU
ABOUT.
>> Ellie: I ALREADY KNOW.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO SPELL IT OUT
FOR ME.
BYE, DAMIAN.
>> Elizabeth: HEY!
HOW'D THE MEETING GO?
>> Sabrina: UH, TWO WORDS.
EPIC FAIL.
>> Elizabeth: NO.
>> Sabrina: LUCY COE WAS OUR
LAST HOPE.
WITHOUT HER --
THERE WON'T BE A NURSES' BALL IN
2013.
>> Lucy: IT'S THAT TIME AGAIN.
WELCOME, ONE AND ALL, TO THE
ANNUAL GENERAL HOSPITAL NURSES'
BALL.
[ CROWD CHEERING, WHISTLING ]
ONE -- ONE --
ONE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
[ SIGHS ]
>> Patrick: LISTEN, I'M REALLY
GLAD THAT WE SLOWED THINGS DOWN
A LITTLE BIT.
THAT NIGHT IN THE HOTEL PROBABLY
WOULD HAVE ENDED BADLY.
>> Britt: THAT WAS MY FAULT.
I --
YOU WERE NOT READY.
>> Patrick: I APPRECIATE YOU
UNDERSTANDING.
SO HERE'S TO "CHRISTINA COMES
HOME FOR CHRISTMAS" AND A NEW
START.
>> Britt: I AGREE TO THAT.
>> Patrick: CHEERS.
SO, WHAT ARE WE WAITING FOR?
>> Sabrina: AS MUCH AS I'M
DREADING IT, I HAVE TO GO SEE
PATRICK.
THE LEAST I COULD DO IS DELIVER
THE BAD NEWS IN PERSON.
>> Elizabeth: WAIT.
M-MAYBE YOU SHOULD JUST GO
TOMORROW.
I THINK HE HAS COMPANY TONIGHT.
>> Sabrina: Y-YOU MEAN --
>> Elizabeth: I'M SORRY.
>> Sabrina: [ SCOFFS ]
JUST WHEN I THOUGHT MY DAY
COULDN'T GET ANY WORSE.
>> Patrick: [ CHUCKLES ]
>> Britt: [ CHUCKLES ]
>> Patrick: OKAY.
>> Britt: I THINK YOU NEED ONE.
>> Patrick: [ CHUCKLES ]
MM-HMM.
BETTER?
>> Britt: MUCH BETTER.
>> Patrick: [ CHUCKLES ]
>> Duke: YOU KNOW ROBERT.
HE'S TOO STUBBORN TO DIE.
HE'LL COME THROUGH THIS LIKE
EVERYTHING ELSE, WITH FLYING
COLORS.
>> Anna: I HOPE SO.
HE WAS TRYING TO SAY SOMETHING.
YOU KNOW, BEFORE HE LOST
CONSCIOUSNESS.
HE WAS, LIKE, REALLY FIGHTING TO
SAY SOMETHING.
I KNOW IT WAS IMPORTANT.
ROBERT, WHAT WERE YOU TRYING TO
TELL ME?
>> Robin: WHAT'S GOING ON?
>> DR. Obrecht: SHH!
>> Robin: WHAT AM I DOING HERE?
>> DR. Obrecht: QUIET!
[ DOOR OPENS ]
I' SO SORRY TO DISTURB YOU, BUT
WITH FAISON CAPTURED, I WAS
UNSURE HOW TO PROCEED.
UNDER THE CIRCUMSTANCES, I
THOUGHT IT BEST TO BRING HER TO
YOU.
>> WELL, YOU DID THE RIGHT
THING.
I BELIEVE YOU KNOW THE WAY OUT,
DOCTOR.
>> HOW ARE YOU?
AFTER ALL THIS TROUBLE --
>> Robin: [ SIGHS ]
>> -- YOU WIND UP WITH GOOD OLD
ME.
WHAT DID WE USED TO CALL YOU,
AGAIN?
UH -- "FUN ONE"?
ROBIN -- KIND OF TOO BORING.
DIDN'T WE HAVE A NICKNAME FOR
YOU?
CAN'T REMEMBER. HMM.
OH, WELL.
THERE ARE MORE INTERESTING
QUESTIONS TO PONDER.
LIKE --
WHAT EVER AM I GONNA DO WITH
YOU?
! ! !
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
DISNEY-ABC DOMESTIC TELEVISION]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
Meredith: THANKS, GUYS.
HELLO, AND WELCOME TO
"MILLIONAIRE." IT IS "BROADWAY
GIVEAWAY WEEK," AND AN ENTIRE
ROW IN OUR AUDIENCE IS HOPING
TODAY'S RETURNING CONTESTANT CAN
GET HER BROADWAY QUESTION
CORRECT BECAUSE IF SHE DOES,
THEN THAT ROW WILL BE GOING TO
SEE THE HIT SHOW "MARY POPPINS"
TONIGHT.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ALL OF THOSE HOPES DEPEND ON
HER. FROM NEW YORK CITY, PLEASE
WELCOME KATHRYN SHRADER.