TRADITION NEEDS A MAJOR
HEALTH MAKEOVER.
VICTORIA: WITH THE
FAMILY HISTORY OF HIGH
BLOOD PRESSURE, WE NEED
TO CUT THE CALORIES OF
OUR FRIED CHICKEN
RECIPE.
ALL: PLEASE REHAB OUR
FRIED CHICKEN RECIPE!
DANNY: OUR TWO CHEFS
WILL BATTLE IT OUT TO
SEE WHO CAN REHAB THE
MAJORS' RECIPE AND MAKE
IT MORE NUTRITIOUS.
SPIKE: I'M JUST GOING TO
USE SKINLESS CHICKEN
BREASTS.
CALVIN: I'M GOING TO
GIVE YOU THE CRISPINESS
OF FRIED CHICKEN, BUT
I'M GOING TO BAKE IT FOR
YOU.
DANNY: WITHOUT
SACRIFICING ANY OF THE
FLAVOR.
SPIKE: DOES THAT NOT
LOOK DELICIOUS TO YOU?
CALVIN: WHEN YOU TAKE A
BITE, VOILA.
DANNY: THE MAJORS WILL
COOK THE REHAB RECIPES
IN THEIR OWN KITCHEN.
THEY'LL JUDGE THEM ON
TASTE, HEALTH, AND EASE.
VICTORIA: I LIKE HOW
IT'S CRISPY AND CRUNCHY.
DANNY: WHICH RECIPE WILL
FALL FLAT?
DEVIN JR.: I'M NOT USED
TO HAVING YOGURT IN MY
CHICKEN.
DANNY: WHICH WILL SCORE
BIG?
DEVIN: FOR TASTE, WE
SCORED IT A PERFECT 10.
DANNY: AND WHO WILL WIN
THE TITLE OF RECEIPT
REHAB CHAMPION?
[APPLAUSE]
♪ MUSIC
DANNY: NOW, LET'S MEET
TWO KITCHEN VIRTUOSOS
WHO WILL COMPETE IN THIS
WEEK'S CULINARY
SHOWDOWN.
AT THE GREEN STATION,
IT'S CHEF SPIKE
MENDELSOHN.
AND IN THE YELLO
AND IN THE YELLOW
STATION CHEF CALVIN
HARRIS.
CHEFS, SOME MIGHT CALL
THIS MISSION IMPOSSIBLE.
ARE YOU READY TO SEE
DAD'S FRIED CHICKEN DISH
UP CLOSE?
HERE IT IS.
THIS FRIED CHICKEN IS
FINGER-LICKING GOOD, BUT
IT'S BAD FOR JUST ABOUT
EVERY OTHER PART OF YOUR
BODY.
IT'S JUST GOT A
BUCKETFUL OF CALORIES,
901 PER SERVING, AND 60%RE .
OF THOSE ARE FROM FAT.
DO YOU GUYS THINK YOU
CAN REHAB THIS RECIPE?
CALVIN: ABSOLUTELY.
DANNY: LET'S PUT 60
MINUTES ON THE CLOCK.
ARE YOU READY?
SPIKE: OH, YEAH.
DANNY: ARE YOU STEADY?
CALVIN: YES, SIR.
DANNY: LET'S GET TO
REHABBING.
OUR CHEFS WILL BE JUDGED
IN THREE CATEGORIES.
THE MAJORS FAMILY WILL
JUDGE THE DISHES ON
TASTE AND EASE OF
PREPARATION, PLUS THE
EVERYDAY HEALTH
NUTRITIONIST WILL GIVE
EACH RECIPE A SCORE FOR
HEALTH.
THEY'VE GOT ONE HOUR TO
MAKE FRIED CHICKEN
THAT'S JUST AS
DELICIOUS, BUT MORE
NUTRITIOUS.
SPIKE, SO WHAT'S YOUR
PLAN OF ATTACK HERE?
SPIKE: WITH FRIED
CHICKEN, YOU USUALLY
HAVE DARK MEAT.
DANNY: OKAY.
SPIKE: I'M JUST GOING TO
USE SKINLESS --
DANNY: RIGHT.
SPIKE: -- CHICKEN
BREAST.
DANNY: NO BONE?
SPIKE: NO BONE, NO BONES
AT ALL.
WHAT WE'RE HERE IS WE'RE
JUST BUTTERFLYING THE
CHICKEN A LITTLE BIT.
DANNY: AND BUTTERFLYING
BASICALLY IS JUST
LITERALLY YOU'RE MAKING
IT THINNER.
YOU'RE STRETCHING IT
OUT, RIGHT?
SPIKE: YOU'RE STRETCHING
IT OUT.
DANNY: YEAH.
SPIKE: YOU'RE MAKING IT
THIN SO, FIRST OF ALL,
IT COOKS QUICKER, SO IT
DOESN'T HAVE TO SIT IN
THAT OIL SO LONG AND
ABSORB ALL THAT OIL,
RIGHT?
DANNY: NOW, WHY ARE YOU
PUTTING IT IN A BAG?
SPIKE: WHY AM I PUTTING
IT IN A BAG?
DANNY: WHAT'S GOING ON
HERE?
SPIKE: WELL, I'M GOINGRE.
DANNY: YEAHE BAG
RIGHT HERE.
DANNY: YEAH?
SPIKE: I'M GOING TO TAKE
OUT SOME OF MY ANGER.
DANNY: OH!
SPIKE: THAT'S RIGHT.
DANNY: ANGER MANAGEMENT
CHICKEN STYLE.
LET'S HAVE A LOOK AT
WHAT CALVIN'S DOING.
CALVIN: SO, I'M GOING
WITH CHICKEN BREASTS, AS
WELL AS BONELESS,
SKINLESS THIGH MEAT.
DANNY: SO, WE'RE TAKING
THE SKIN OFF, AND WE'RE
JUST GOING TO GO FOR THE
MEAT.
CALVIN: COMPLETELY OFF,
BABY.
DANNY: RIGHT.
SO, YOU'VE BASICALLY
TENDERIZED IT BY POKING
A FEW LITTLE HOLES IN
IT.
WHAT I NOTICE AROUND
HERE, RIGHT NOW, THERE'S
NO SALT AND PEPPER,
WHICH IS UNUSUAL, WHEN
YOU'RE ADDING FLAVOR TO
SOMETHING.
CALVIN: I AM TRYING TO
REDUCE ALL THE SALT THAT
I POSSIBLY CAN.
WE NEED TO KEEP OUR NICE
ARTERIES CLEAN.
DANNY: SO, IS THAT WHAT
THE LIME JUICE IS DOING
THEN RIGHT NOW FOR YOU?
CALVIN: ABSOLUTELY, IT'S
GOING TO POP UP THE
FLAVOR.
WHEN YOU TAKE A BITE,
VOILA.
DANNY: YOUR BATTER, WHAT
ARE YOU ACTUALLY DOING
HERE?
IS IT -- YOU'VE GOT
WHOLE WHEAT FLOUR.
YOU'VE GOT SOME BREAD
CRUMBS, I SEE.
SPIKE: YEAH, A LITTLE
CORN MEAL.
DANNY: CORN MEAL.
SPIKE: YEAH.
DANNY: THAT'S AS
SOUTHERN AS IT GETS.
SPIKE: YEAH, AND WE'RE
GOING TO PUT SOME LEMON
ZEST IN HERE.
WE'RE GOING TO FLAVOR IT
ALL UP AND MAKE IT
DELICIOUS.
DANNY: CALVIN CHOPPING
AWAY.
YOU ACTUALLY STARTED
MAKING A MARINADE HERE.
CALVIN: I THINK THE
MARINADE IS A WAY TO
REALLY DRAW OUT THE
DANN
DANNY: IS THAT GREEK
YOGURT?
CALVIN: IT IS GREEK
YOGURT.
IT'S GOING TO SERVE AS A
WONDERFUL FLAVOR
CARRIER, A MARINADE.
DOES IS IT ACTUALL IT
DOES IS IT ACTUALLY
MAKES THE CHICKEN MORE
SUCCULENT.
DANNY: NOW, WHAT SPICES
HAVE YOU GOT GOING IN
THERE?
CALVIN: I HAVE A LITTLE
BIT OF CUMIN, A LITTLE
BIT OF ONION POWDER,
CHIPOTLE CHILE POWDER.
DANNY: I LIKED HOW YOU
JUST CIRCULATED ALL THE
JUICE AROUND THE CHICKEN
THERE.
CALVIN: WELL, I'M
MASSAGING IT.
YOU'VE GOT TO MASSAGE
IT.
DANN
CHICKEN.
DANN TO GET THE
FLAVOR IN THERE.
CALVIN: AND THEN HERE'S
THE KEY, JALAPENO.
YOU KNOW, THE BEAUTY OF
USING JALAPENOS --
DANNY: YEAH.
CALVIN: THEY ACTUALLY
HELP YOUR METABOLIC
RATE.
DANNY: SO, WE'RE TRYING
TO MAKE THIS FRIED
CHICKEN HEALTHIER.
CALVIN: ABSOLUTELY.
DANNY: YOU'RE USING OIL
HERE.
SPIKE: YEAH.
DANNY: HOW ARE YOU GOING
TO LOWER THE CHOLESTEROL
OF THIS DISH?
SPIKE: I'M GOING TO TAKE
THE FEAR OUT OF FRYING,
SO I'M GOING TO PAN SEAR
AND THEN BAKE.
DANNY: PAN SEAR AND
BAKE, FEAR OUT OF
FRYING.
SPIKE: YOU'RE NOT
PUTTING THE CHICKEN IN A
HUGE VAT OF OIL.
DANNY: RIGHT.
SPIKE: SUBMERGING IT.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
DANNY: RIGHT.
SPIKE: WHAT YOU WANT TO
DO IS YOU WANT TO FRY
AROUND, LIGHTLY FRY
AROUND, AND YOU DON'T
WANT THE PROTEIN TO
ABSORB ALL THAT OIL.
DANNY: RIGHT.
THESE ARE PANKO BREAD
CRUMBS, RIGHT?
CALVIN: EXACTLY.
DANNY: OKAY, YOU'RE JUST
GOING TO DIP THEM,
RIGHT?
CALVIN: YEAH, ACTUALLY,
I'M JUST GOING TO KIND
OF --
DANNY: THERE'S NO EGG.
CALVIN: YEAH, NO EGG.
YOU'RE GOING TO USE THE
MARINADE TO MAKE IT
STICK, ABSOLUTELY.
I LOVE EGGS -- A LOT OF
CHOLESTEROL, A LOT OF
FAT.
IF I CAN ACTUALLY
ELIMINATE THEM OUT OF
THIS WHOLE PROCESS, I
THINK IT'S A BEAUTIFUL
THING.
DANNY: SO, CALVIN HASN'T
USED ANY EGGS.
SPIKE: NO EGGS.
DANNY: WHY ARE YOU USING
EGGS?
SPIKE: WELL, I'M JUST
GOING TO USE EGG WHITES
INSTEAD OF JUST WHOLE
EGGS, SEE?
DANNY: BECAUSE EGG
WHITES HAVE LESS
CHOLESTEROL, RIGHT?
SPIKE: EXACTLY, IT'S
GOING TO ADD THE SAME
EXACT THING THAT I WANT,
WHICH IS JUST MY TRIPLE
BREADING FOR SEASONING.
DANNY: SPIKE IS DOING
THE TBP, TRIPLE BREADING
PROCEDURE.
JUST GO THROUGH THIS
WITH ME.
SPIKE: ALL RIGHT, SO
WE'RE DOING JUST A
LITTLE BIT OF THE WHEAT
FLOUR AND THEN A LITTLE
BIT OF THE EGG WHITES.
DANNY: EGG WHITES,
RIGHT.
SPIKE: RIGHT, AND THEN A
LITTLE BIT OF THE CORN
MEAL PANKO MIXTURE THAT
WE HAVE.
DANNY: LOOK AT THAT.
SO, THE BATTER IS OUT
FOR CHEF CALVIN, WHILE
CHEF SPIKE IS HOPING TO
HIT A HOME RUN USING HIS
PAN-SEARED STRATEGY.
WHO WILL WIN THIS MAJORS
LEAGUE BATTLE FOR THE
STOMACHS OF OUR SAN
DIEGO CHICKEN LOVERS?
AND HAVE I EXHAUSTED
HOR
IN ONE SENTENCE?
LET'S HOPE SO!
IT'S T
BREAK AND THE BETTER
EATS POP QUIZ.
HERE'S THE BETTER EATS
POP QUIZ QUESTION.
TRUE OR FALSE?
CHOLESTEROL IS ONLY
FOUND IN FOODS OF ANIMAL
ORIGIN, SUCH AS CHICKEN,
FISH, BEEF, MILK,
BUTTER, AND EGGS.
THE ANSWER WHEN WE
RETURN TO RECIPE REHAB.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.
But you'll keep it
to yogurt, right?
'Cause we shouldn't really help
with your love life.
Yoplait. It is so good!
DANNY: WELCOME BACK TO
RECIPE REHAB.
BEFORE THE BREAK, WE
ASKED YOU IF CHOLESTEROL
IS FOUND ONLY IN FOODS
OF ANIMAL ORIGIN, SUCH
AS CHICKEN, FISH, BEEF,
MILK, BUTTER, AND EGGS.
IF YOU ANSWERED TRUE,
YOU'RE RIGHT.
PLANT FOOD DOES NOT
CONTAIN CHOLESTEROL,
WHICH MEANS -- YOU
GUESSED IT -- IF YOU
WANT TO LOWER YOUR
CHOLESTEROL, YOU HAVE TO
EAT MORE VEGETABLES.
WE'VE GOT LOTS MORE
QUIZZES FOR YOU AT
BETTEREATS.COM/RECIPEREHAB,
BUT RIGHT NOW LET'S
GET BACK TO THE KITCHEN.
WE CHALLENGED CHEF SPIKE
AND CHEF CALVIN TO MAKE
OVER THE MAJORS'
FAVORITE FRIED CHICKEN
RECIPE.
CHEF SPIKE HAS REPLACED
DARK MEAT WITH WHITE,
WHILE CHEF CALVIN IS
BANKING ON HIS YOGURT
MARINADE.
WHO WILL WIN THE MAJORS
FAMILY AND THEIR TASTE
BUDS OVER?
WE'RE JUST COMING UP TO
25 MINUTES THERE, GUYS.
SO, WHAT ARE YOU DOING
HERE?
CALVIN: OH, I'M JUST
LINING THE BOTTOM OF THE
PAN WITH A LITTLE BIT OF
ALUMINUM FOIL.
DANNY: OH, SO WE'RE NOT
FRYING THE CHICKEN.
YOU'RE GOING TO BAKE IT?
CALVIN: THIS IS BAKED,
BABY.
DANNY: BIG DIFFERENCE,
BIG DIFFERENCE!
CALVIN: I LOVE FRIED
CHICKEN, BUT I'M GOING
TO GIVE YOU THE
CRISPINESS OF FRIED
CHICKEN, BUT I'M GOING
TO BAKE IT FOR YOU.
I'VE GOT TO CUT A LITTLE
BIT OF THAT FAT OUT OF
THERE.
DANNY: THAT'S REALLY
INTERESTING.
SO, THIS IS GOING TO
TAKE A LITTLE BIT OF
EXTRA TIME THEN, CALVIN.
CALVIN: THESE ARE NICE,
SMALL PIECES OF CHICKEN.
IT WON'T TAKE ANY TIME
AT ALL.
DANNY: SO, WHAT WE'RE
SAYING IS IF IT'S NOT
TOO THICK --
CALVIN: RIGHT.
DANNY: SO, YOU KNOW,
THIN EQUALS SPEED.
CALVIN: RIGHT.
DANNY: THERE WE GO.OU SEE
IF YOU LIKE WHAT YOU SEE
HERE, TODAY, BE SURE TO
CATCH THE FIRST SEASON
OF RECIPE REHAB ON
YOUTUBE.
JUST SEARCH RECIPE
REHAB.
WHAT ARE WE BAKING IT
AT?
CALVIN: WE'RE BAKING IT
AT 350 -- BE IN THERE
20-25 MINUTES.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL THING.
DANNY: RIGHT ON.
HE'S GOING TO BE BAKING,
BUT YOU'RE GOING TO
ACTUALLY BE SEARING.
SPIKE: IT'S A PAN SEAR.
DANNY: PAN SEAR.
NOW, YOUR CHICKEN IS IN.
SO, THIS IS BASICALLY
WE'RE JUST GOING TO SEAR
AWAY.
HALF ON EACH SID MINUTE ANDA
HALF ON EACH SIDE,
PROBABLY.
DANNY: A MINUTE AND A
HALF ON EACH SIDE, SO
WE'RE GOING TO KEEP THE
OIL DOWN.
SPIKE: RIGHT.
DANNY: I LOVE THIS, HOW
IT'S JUST GETTING THIS
GOLDEN BROWN.
SPIKE: DOES THAT NOT
LOOK DELICIOUS TO YOU?
DANNY: YEAH.
SPIKE: SO YOU GET THAT
TEXTURE AND THAT CRUST
THAT YOU WOULD GET FROM
A FRIED CHICKEN, AND
THEN FINISH IT OFF BY
BAKING IT, RIGHT?
DANNY: SO, YOU'RE DOING
A DOUBLE PLAY.
SPIKE: A LITTLE DOUBLE
PLAY, BECAUSE I STILL
WANT TO, I WANT TO ENJOY
WHAT A FRIED CHICKEN IS
ALL ABOUT IS THAT
CRUNCHY KIND OF LAYER OF
-- THIS IS KIND OF LIKE
THE FAKE SKIN.
DANNY: DID YOU HEAR
THIS, CALVIN?
CALVIN: I DID.
SPIKE: HE DID, HE DID.
DANNY: IS YOURS STILL
GOING TO BE, IS YOURS
STILL GOING TO BE, IS
YOURS STILL GOING TO BE
CRISPY?
CALVIN: ABSOLUTELY.
DANNY: HIS IS GOING TO
BE CRISPY, OKAY.
SPIKE: ALL RIGHT, SO
INSTEAD OF USING THAT
GREAT SKIN THAT YOU
WOULD FIND ON THAT
CHICKEN, WE SUBSTITUTE
IT WITH A LITTLE BIT OF
CORN MEAL AND PANKO TO
FORM THAT KIND OF CRUST.
DANNY: SO, YOU'RE MAKING
AN ARTIFICIAL.
SPIKE: ARTIFICIAL KIND
OF SKIN AROUND IT.
DANNY: RIGHT, RIGHT,
RIGHT, RIGHT, RIGHT.
SPIKE: YES, ABSOLUTELY.
DANNY: NOW, WHY ARE YOU
USING THIS WIRE RACK?
I SAW CALVIN DO THAT.
SPIKE: A WIRE RACK IS
GREAT, BECAUSE ALL THE
FAT DRIPPINGS GO TO THE
BOTTOM.
DANNY: AND WE DON'T SIT
IN THE FAT.
SPIKE: THE FAT, EXACTLY.
DANNY: COOL.
NOW, CALVIN, LOOK AT
THAT.
AND THAT'S THE BASE OF
YOUR BARBECUE SAUCE.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT IN
THERE?
I JUST SAW YOU GRATE
SOME ONION.
CALVIN: GRATED SOME
ONION.
DANNY: THAT WENT DOWN
THERE.
YOU SAUTEED THAT
THROUGH?
CALVIN: YES, UNTIL IT'S
TRANSLUCENT.
FINISH WITH A LITTLE
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR, ADD
A LITTLE ORGANIC
KETCHUP, A LITTLE
TABASCO AGAIN, ADD A
LITTLE BIT OF FLAVOR.
NOW, I'VE GOT TO GO GET
MY MAPLE SYRUP.
DANNY: GET ON IT.
MAPLE SYRUP?
OH, OH.
SO, THIS IS YOUR SLAW,
RIGHT?
SPIKE: RIGHT.
DANNY: SO, FRIED CHICKEN
AND COLESLAW JUST GO
TOGETHER LIKE --
SPIKE: EXACTLY.
DANNY: PEAS AND CARROTS.
WHAT HAVE WE GOT IN HERE
RIGHT HERE?
SPIKE: WE'VE GOT A LOT
OF LOVE RIGHT NOW.
WE'VE GOT SOME SHREDDED
CABBAGE.
WE'VE GOT SOME CARROTS.
WE ADDED SOME CORN TO
IT.
AND WHEN I THINK OF
FRIED CHICKEN, I THINK
OF THE SOUTH, AND SO
WE'RE GOING TO ADD A
LITTLE BIT OF RED HOT.
DANNY: OOH.
SPIKE: RIGHT?
JUST A LITTLE BIT,
BECAUSE IT'S HOT.
DANNY: GIVE IT A KICK.
SPIKE: YOU KNOW, WE'RE
JUST GOING TO LIGHTEN
UP.
WE'VE GOT A LIGHT
MAYONNAISE.
DANNY: YOU'RE VERY
FOCUSED ON THE VEGETABLE
COMPONENT OF THIS RIGHT
NOW.
SPIKE: DEFINITELY.
DANNY: THE ONE MINUTE
MARK NOW.
IT'S TIME TO START
PLATING UP.
LOOK AT THAT.
SPIKE'S OUT OF THE OVEN.
STRAIGHTAWAY, CALVIN'S
INTO IT!
THREE, TWO, ONE, TIME'S
UP.
THERE WE GO, GUYS.
LOOK AT THAT.
THE CLOCK'S DOWN -- DONE
A VERY, VERY, VERY GOOD
JOB.
SPIKE: THAT'S RIGHT.
MAJOY: YOU'VE TAKEN THE
MAJORS' FRIED CHICKEN
RECIPE.
YOU'VE MADE IT
HEALTHIER.
DELICIOUS, NUTRITIOUS.
WHAT DID YOU WANT TO GET
FROM THIS, AGAIN?
SPIKE: THE HEALTHIEST
NON-FRIED CHICKEN YOU
COULD EVER GET IN YOUR
WHOLE ENTIRE LIFE.
DANNY: OKAY, BUT YOU
REALLY DID USE A LITTLE
BIT OF FRYING THERE,
OKAY?
SPIKE: NO, A LITTLE
SEARING.
DANNY: OKAY, A LITTLE
SPIKE: WE USED A LITTLE
SEARING.
CALVIN: I THINK HE
ACTUALLY MEANT TO SAY HE
WAS DOING A HEALTHY
FRIED CHICKEN, WHERE I
WAS DOING THE HEALTHY
NON-FRIED CHICKEN.
DANNY: OH, BUT THE TRUE
TEST IS STILL TO COME,
BECAUSE WHEN WE COME
BACK, THE MAJORS FAMILY
WILL COOK THOSE RECIPES.
DEVIN JR.: I'M NOT USED
TO HAVING YOGURT IN MY
CHICKEN.
DANNY: AND THEN THEY'LL
DECIDE WHO'S GOT THE
BETTER EATS.
SHENEKA: ARE YOU READY
TO TASTE?
DAD AND KIDS: YEAH!
DANNY: SO, DON'T GO
ANYWHERE.
WE'LL SEE YOU AFTER THE
BREAK.
[ Woman ] Ring. Ring.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
DANNY: WELCOME BACK TO
RECIPE REHAB, THE SHOW
THAT TAKES AMERICA'S
FAVORITE FAMILY RECIPES
FROM FAT TO FIT.
CHEF SPIKE AND CHEF
CALVIN HAVE WORKED
WONDERS ON THE MAJORS
FAMILY RECIPE.
WE'VE SENT THEM ALL THE
INGREDIENTS THEY NEEDED
TO MAKE BOTH OF THE
REHAB RECIPES.
BEFORE THEY CHOOSE THEIR
FAVORITE, THEY'VE GOT TO
COOK THEM.
SO, LET'S SEE WHAT THEY
DO WITH THEM.
VICTORIA: WHAT IS THIS?
SHENEKA: THAT'S PURPLE
CABBAGE.
DEVIN: THAT'S GREEK
YOGURT.
TYRAH: GREEK YOGURT.
DEVIN: MOMMY LOVES THAT.
DEVIN JR.: CILANTRO.
VICTORIA: WHY IS THERE
CARROTS?
TYSHUN: IN CHICKEN,
SHENEKA: LOW SODIUM
CHICKEN BROTH.
DEVIN JR.: WHY DO WE
NEED CHICKEN BROTH?
DEVIN: ARE WE GOING TO
FRY THE CHICKEN IN
CHICKEN BROTH?
OUT OF THESE TWO RECIPE
BOXES, IM NOT SEEING
ANYTHING THAT COMPARES
TO MY SOUTHERN FRIED
CHICKEN.
SHENEKA: ORGANIC
KETCHUP.
TYRAH: MAPLE SYRUP AND
GREEK YOGURT?
DEVIN JR.: IT SOUNDS
LIKE PANCAKE MIX.
TYRAH: THIS IS NOT AT
ALL SIMILAR TO MY
FATHER'S RECIPE, SO IT'S
STRANGE AND DIFFERENT.
SHENEKA: MAYONNAISE?
VICTORIA: I DO NOT LIKE
MAYONNAISE.
SHENEKA: YEAH, WE KNOW
YOU DON'T.
APPLE CIDER VINEGAR?
LET'S START COOKING,
GUYS.
WHY DON'T THREE OF US
TAKE THE GREEN, AND
THREE OF YOU TAKE THE
YELLOW.
TYRAH: ALL RIGHT.
TYSHUN: ALL RIGHT, LET'S
GO.
DEVIN JR.: LET'S GO.
SHENEKA: ALL RIGHT,
GUYS, LET'S GET COOKING,
LET'S GET COOKING.
WHERE'S OUR CUTTING
BOARD?
A HALF CUP OF WHOLE
WHEAT FLOUR.
VICTORIA: I'M ON IT.
DEVIN: I DON'T KNOW HOW
YOBAKE
CHICKEN, BUT WE'RE GOING
TO FIND OUT.
VICTORIA: THE GREEN
RECIPE IS GOING TO BE
REALLY HEALTHY, BUT I'M
NOT SURE IF IT'S GOING
TO TASTE GOOD, BECAUSE
THE INGREDIENTS THAT
THEY'RE PUTTING IN DON'T
REALLY LOOK THAT GREAT.
OOH, IT'S YELLOW.
SHENEKA: THAT'S
CORNMEAL.
VICTORIA: THAT LOOKS
UNUSUAL.
THAT LOOKS KIND OF
WEIRD, BUT OKAY.
DEVIN JR.: THIS IS
DEFINITELY DIFFERENT
THAN MY DAD'S RECIPE.
THE STEPS ARE THE SAME,
BUT DIFFERENT
INGREDIENTS.
DEVIN: I THINK THAT THE
GREEK YOGURT IS GOING TO
GIVE IT A NICE, SMOOTH,
REFRESHING TASTE, DON'T
YOU?
DEVIN JR.: I'M NOT USED
TO HAVING YOGURT IN MY
CHICKEN.
DEVIN: YEAH, BUT WE HAVE
TO OPEN OUR MINDS, SON.
IT'S NOT GOING TO BE
YOUR DAD'S TRADITIONAL
FRIED CHICKEN.
DEVIN JR.: THIS IS GOING
TO BE SPICY WITH ALL
THAT JALAPENO.
DEVIN: YOU'RE SURE RIGHT
ABOUT THAT, SON.
VICTORIA: TWO
TABLESPOONS?
DAD USES THE WHOLE
BOTTLE.
DEVIN: DUMP IT IN THERE,
SON.
THAT'S OUR MARINADE, AND
THE YOGURT IS GOING TO
GIVE IT A NICE,
SUCCULENT, MOIST,
TENDERIZED FLAVOR.
MASSAGE IT IN THERE,
TYRAH.
DELICIOUS.
TYRAH: IT SMELLS PRETTY
GOOD.
VICTORIA: THE GREEN
RECIPE HAS A LOT OF
VEGETABLES, AND IT NEEDS
TO BE THICK CUT.
IT'S A LOT OF WORK.
BETTEREATS.COM SAYS THAT
RED CABBAGE HAS MORE
ANTI-CANCER CHEMICALS
THAN ANY OTHER
VEGETABLE.
SHENEKA: REALLY?
WOW, THAT'S AN
INTERESTING FACT.
TYRAH: DADDY, YOUR
RECIPE HAS 901 CALORIES,
AND THIS RECIPE ONLY HAS
483 CALORIES.
DEVIN: THIS IS A MUCH
HEALTHIER OPTION.
TYRAH: MUCH HEALTHIER.
SHENEKA: DID YOU KNOW
THAT DADDY'S FRIED
CHICKEN RECIPE HAS 901
CALORIES, AND THE GREEN
BOX RECIPE HAS 345?
VICTORIA: A LOT
HEALTHIER THAN OURS.
SHENEKA: IT SURE IS.
WOW, THAT LOOKS AMAZING.
LOOK AT ALL THOSE
VEGETABLES.
DEVIN: OOH, LOOK IT.
I BET THAT'S GOING TO BE
CRISPY ALREADY.
IT FEELS CRISPY AND
CRUNCHY.
TYRAH: JUST LIKE OURS.
DEVIN: ALMOST JUST LIKE
OURS.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS, OUR
REHAB RECIPE CHICKEN IS
READY.
DEVIN JR.: REALLY?
VICTORIA: WOO!
SHENEKA: LOOK AT THOSE
VEGETABLES.
DEVIN: ALL RIGHT.
SHENEKA: OKAY, GUYS,
THAT WAS A LOT OF FUN
AND A LOT OF WORK.
ARE YOU READY TO TASTE?
DAD AND KIDS: YEAH!
SHENEKA: LET'S START
WITH THE GREEN RECIPE
FIRST.
DEVIN: ALL RIGHT.
SHENEKA: THE GREEN GOES
WITH THE COLE SLAW.
VICTORIA: MMM.
I LIKE HOW IT'S CRISPY
AND CRUNCHY.
SHENEKA: IT'S DELICIOUS.
DEVIN JR.: IT'S
HEALTHIER, AND IT TASTES
AMAZING.
TYSHUN: I WOULD TRY IT
AGAIN.
I WOULD TRY IT LIKE
PROBABLY EVERY WEEK.
TYRAH: I CAN SEE THIS
BEING ONE OF OUR REGULAR
MEALS.
VICTORIA: I LOVE THE
COLE SLAW, EVEN THOUGH
IT HAS MAYONNAISE IN IT,
AND IT HAS LIKE A PINCH
OF SPICINESS.
SHENEKA: IT HAS A NICE
KICK.
VICTORIA: YEAH.
DEVIN: THE GREEN RECIPE
WAS REALLY GOOD, BUT
WAIT UNTIL WE TRY THE
YELLOW CHICKEN RECIPE.
MM.
TYRAH: TASTY.
SHENEKA: I THINK IT'S A
GREAT SUBSTITUTE FOR
FRIED CHICKEN -- THE
SAUCE, THE BARBECUE
SAUCE.
DEVIN: THE YELLOW RECIPE
IS AWESOME, AND THE
BARBECUE SAUCE JUST
TOPPED IT JUST
PERFECTLY.
DEVIN JR.: NOW, I SEE
WHY WE USED THAT MAPLE
SYRUP.
VICTORIA: I STILL DON'T
TASTE ANY YOGURT.
DEVIN: BUT, ACTUALLY,
YOU DO.
DO YOU TASTE THE
TENDERNESS OF THE
CHICKEN?
VICTORIA: MM-HM.
DEVIN: THAT'S BECAUSE WE
MARINATED IT IN GREEK
YOGURT.
SHENEKA: MM, WE DON'T
NEED FRIED CHICKEN AGAIN
-- DEEP FRIED CHICKEN.
DEVIN: WE JUST MIGHT
WANT IT -- SURELY NOT
ME.
VICTORIA: IF WE WANT
FRIED CHICKEN, THEN WE
SHOULD EAT EITHER ONE OF
THESE.
DANNY: THAT LOOKS LIKE
THEY HAD A LOT OF FUN IN
THE KITCHEN.
NOW, WHEN WE COME BACK,
IT'S THE MOMENT OF
TRUTH.
THE MAJORS FAMILY WILL
GIVE THEIR FINAL VERDICT
ON WHICH REHABBED FRIED
CHICKEN RULES THE ROOST.
NOW, DON'T FLY OFF NOW,
OR YOU'LL MISS IT.
HI, I'M PHIL MICKELSON.
I'VE BEEN FORTUNATE TO WIN
ON GOLF'S BIGGEST STAGES.
BUT WHEN JOINT PAIN
AND STIFFNESS
FROM PSORIATIC ARTHRITIS HIT,
EVEN THE SMALLEST THINGS
BECAME DIFFICULT.
I FINALLY UNDERSTOOD WHAT
SERIOUS JOINT PAIN IS LIKE.
I TALKED TO MY RHEUMATOLOGIST
AND HE PRESCRIBED Enbrel.
Enbrel CAN HELP RELIEVE
PAIN, STIFFNESS,
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
BECAUSE Enbrel, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS,
SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS,
LYMPHOMA, OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING Enbrel,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.U HAVE
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON Enbrel, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING, OR PALENESS.
[ Phil ]
GET BACK TO THE THINGS
THAT MATTER MOST.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST
IF Enbrel IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
PRESCRIBED BY RHEUMATOLOGISTS.
...and now...
You!
[ giggles ]
♪ The one and only, Cheerios
DANNY: WELCOME BACK TO
RECIPE REHAB.
IT'S DECISION TIME.EGAN WITS
FAMILY.
THEY LOVE THEIR FRIED
CHICKEN, BUT HATE THE
CALORIES.
CHEF SPIKE AND CHEF
CALVIN DID AN EXCELLENT
JOB AT OVERHAULING THE
MAJORS FAMILY FRIED
CHICKEN.
BUT IN THE FAST-PACED,
HIGH STAKES WORLD OF
REHABBING, THERE CAN
ONLY BE ONE WINNER.
OUR CHEFS WILL BE JUDGED
IN THREE MAJOR
CATEGORIES.
THE MAJORS FAMILY WILL
JUDGE THE DISHES ON
TASTE AND EASE OF
PREPARATION, AND THE
EVERYDAY HEALTH
NUTRITIONIST WILL GIVE
EACH RECIPE A SCORE FOR
HEALTH.
THERE'S 10 POINTS PER
CATEGORY, SO A PERFECT
SCORE IS 30.
ARE YOU READY TO SEE THE
RESULTS?
SPIKE: OH, YEAH.
CALVIN: YES, SIR.
DANNY: OKAY, SO FIRST
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT HOW
YOU DID, CHEF SPIKE.
SPIKE: ALL RIGHT.
DEVIN: THANK YOU, CHEFS,
FOR REHABBING OUR FRIED
CHICKEN RECIPE.
IT WAS WAY TOO HIGH IN
FAT, HAD TOO MANY
CALORIES, AND THE SODIUM
WAS OFF THE CHARTS.
ON THE GREEN RECIPE, FOR
TASTE, WE GIVE IT AN 8
OUT OF 10.
THE CORN MEAL DIDN'T
QUITE SIMULATE THAT
NATURAL FRIED CHICKEN
CRUNCH WE'VE GROWN TO
LOVE SO MUCH.
THE HEALTH SCORE IS A
10.
DANNY: THE EVERYDAY
HEALTH NUTRITIONIST GAVE
YOUR REHABBED FRIED
CHICKEN A SCORE OF 10.
THAT'S THE MAXIMUM
POINTS.
AWESOME, RIGHT?
NOW, THEY ESPECIALLY
LOVED YOUR VEGETABLE
COMPONENT, WHICH IS
BASICALLY YOUR SLAW.
NOW, HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT THAT?
SPIKE: 10 OUT OF 10 ON
NUTRITION, THAT'S WHAT
WE'RE LOOKING FOR.
DEVIN: FOR EASE OF
PREPARAT
AN 8 OUT OF THE 10.
IT WAS JUST A LITTLE TOO
MANY STEPS: CHOPPING,
PRE-FRYING BEFORE
BAKING, ETC.
THE TOTAL SCORE FOR THE
GREEN RECIPE IS 26.
DANNY: SO, CHEF SPIKE,
YOU GOT A TOTAL SCORE OF
26.
NOW, THE FAMILY DIDN'T
REALLY LIKE YOUR TEXTURE
TOO MUCH, BUT I THINK
YOU'VE DONE PRETTY WELL.
SPIKE: YEAH, NOT BAD.
DANNY:E,
GETT
PRETTY GOOD SCORE,
GETTING A 10 FOR HEALTH.
SPIKE: YEAH, THAT'S
OKAY.
DANNY: THAT'S THE MAIN
POINT HERE.
SO, OKAY, CHEF CALVIN,
26 TO BEAT.
THINK YOU'VE DONE IT?
CALVIN: I HOPE SO.
DANNY: OH, GOD, HE'S SO
DRAMATIC.
CALVIN: I HAVE TO TELL
YOU THAT'S A HIGH SCORE.
DANNY: WELL, IT'S TIME
TO HAVE A LOOK AND SEE
WHAT THE MAJORS FAMILY
THOUGHT OF YOUR RECIPE.
DEVIN: ON THE YELLOW
RECIPE FOR TASTE, WE
SCORED IT A PERFECT 10.
THE PANKO CRUMBS DID AN
EXCELLENT JOB OF
SIMULATING THAT FRIED
CHICKEN TASTE.
THE HEALTH SCORE IS A
10.
DANNY: THE EVERYDAY
HEALTH NUTRITIONIST GAVE
YOU A PERFECT 10 OUT OF
10 FOR BRINGING THE
CALORIE COUNT WAY DOWN
AND ALSO BAKING IT
INSTEAD OF DEEP FRYING.
DEVIN: ON THE YELLOW
RECIPE, FOR EASE OF
PREPARATION, WE SCORED
IT A 9 OUT OF 10.
ALL THE MINCIN
ALL THE MINCING AND
CHOPPING PREVENTED IT
FROM BEING A PERFECT 10.
THE TOTAL SCORE FOR THE
YELLOW RECIPE IS 29.
THE YELLOW RECIPE IS THE
WINNER!
[APPLAUSE]
DANNY: WOW.
CALVIN: WOO!
DANNY: CONGRATULATIONS,
CHEF CAL CONGRATULATIONS,
YOU ARE THE RECIPE REHAB
FRIED CHICKEN CHAMPION.
NOW, WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT THAT?
CALVIN: THAT'S VERY
EXCITING.
BEING FROM TEXAS, WE DO
A LOT OF FRIED CHICKEN,
SO BEING ABLE TO BAKE
IT, GIVE IT THE SAME
INTENSE FLAVOR AND
CRISPINESS, VERY HAPPY
ABOUT IT.
DANNY: YOU KNOCKED IT
OUT OF THE PARK.
CALVIN: THANK YOU.
DANNY: AND I THINK YOU
DID A GOOD JOB THERE,
FRIEND, BUT IT WAS THE
TEXTURE THAT WAS ON
THERE.
SPIKE: CAN'T WIN
EVERYTHING.
DANNY: IF YOU'D LIKE TO
TRY EITHER OF THESE
GREAT RECIPES, JUST GO TO
BETTEREATS.COM/RECIPEREHAB.
AND WHILE YOU'RE THERE,
YOU'LL FIND EVEN MORE
REHAB RECIPES, COOKING
TIPS, AND TRICKS.
IT'S ALL AT
BETTEREATS.COM/RECIPEREHAB.
THANKS TO BOTH OUR
CHEFS, THE MAJORS
FAMILY, AND ALL OF YOU
FOR WATCHING.
JOIN US NEXT TIME WHEN
WE CUT THE CALORIES,
FLATTEN THE FAT, AND
REHAB ANOTHER RECIPE FOR
YOU AND YOUR FAMILY.
SEE YOU SOON!
I have high blood pressure.
And when I get a cold I take
Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
deessure.
th high
blood pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
♪ MUSIC
CLAIRE: TODAY ON FOOD
GHT, I'VE GOT
THREE STRESS-FREE
RECIPES FOR HOSTING A
DELICIOUS PARTY NIGHT.
FIRST UP, IT'S MY CREAMY
AND CRUNCHY SMASHED PEA
AND RICOTTA CROSTINI.
NEXT, I'M ON TO MY
BLISTERED CANNELLINI
BEANS AND ROASTED CHERRY
TOMATOES OVER MOZZARELLA
WITH BASIL.
THEN I'VE GOT AN ELEGANT
TWIST ON A GRILLED
CHEESE WITH MY SAUTEED
SWISS CHARD AND
PROSCIUTTO SANDWICH.
FINALLY, MY FRIEND,
PARTY EXPERT WHITNEY
ADAMS, IS STOPPING BY
WITH SOME TIPS FOR A
FLAWLESS PARTY NIGHT.
♪ MUSIC