INTERVIEW.
>> MICK TO YOU.
>> THE ETERNAL ROCK STAR STILL
ELECTRIFYING A CROWD LIKE NO ONE
ELSE ON EARTH.
>>> PLUS, FROM A VERY BAD SANTA
TO A NOT SO SILENT NIGHT, TO A
CHRISTMAS STORY YULETIDE
NIGHTMARE.
WHAT HAPPENS WHEN SAINT NICK
GOES NAUGHTY.
>>> FROM THE GLOBAL RESOURCES OF
ABC NEWS, WITH TERRY MORAN,
CYNTHIA McFADDEN, AND BILL WEIR
IN NEW YORK CITY, THIS IS
"NIGHTLINE," DECEMBER 13th,
2012.
>>> GOOD EVENING, I'M BILL WEIR.
YOU REMEMBER WAY BACK WHEN
REALITY TELEVISION WAS THE WAY
PEOPLE DESCRIBED THE NIGHTLY
NEWS?
THE UNSCRIPTED GENRE HAS
COMPLETELY CHANGED THE LANDSCAPE
INSIDE THE SCREEN YOU'RE
WATCHING RIGHT NOWER BUT HOW HAS
IT ALTERED THE MEANING OF THE
WORD REALITY?
TODAY THE WILDLY POPULAR AUCTION
SHOW "STORAGE WARS" IS UNDER
FIRE FROM AN EX-STAR WHO SAYS
THEY ARE FAKING SOME OF THE BIG
MONEY SHOTS.
ABC'S DAN HARRIS SEPARATES FACT
FROM FICTION.
>> BRING IT ON.
>> 250!
>> SOLD.
>> Reporter: IT IS ONE OF THE
MOST POPULAR REALITY SHOWS ON
TV.
"STORAGE WARS" HAS A SIMPLE
ADDICTIVE CONCEIT.
PEOPLE BID ON THE CONTENTS OF
STORAGE LOCKERS THAT HAVE BEEN
ABANDONED BY THEIR OWNERS.
>> OH, MY GOSH!
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
>> THERE'S A BODY IN THERE.
>> Reporter: INSIDE THEY FIND
EITHER THE WORTHLESS THINGS OF
PEOPLE'S LIVES.
>> WHAT'S THIS?
>> NOT GOOD.
>> Reporter: OR HIDDEN
TREASURES.
>> SILVER SILVERWARE SET.
>> Reporter: ONE OF THE STARS IS
THIS GUY, DAVID HESTER, KNOWN AS
THE MOGUL, A MAN WHO HAS A
SIGNATURE MOTTO WHICH HE HOLLERñ
DURING THE AUCTION.
>> YEP!
>> Reporter: BUT NOW THERE IS
STRIFE IN STORAGE LAND.
>> THIS ONE'S NOT FOR ME.
>> Reporter: THE MOGUL HAS HIRED
A BIG SHOT HOLLYWOOD ATTORNEY
AND FILED A LAWSUIT, ALLEGING
THAT A&E HAS COMMITTED A FRAUD
ON THE PUBLIC.
HESTER SAYS THE PRODUCERS
REGULARLY SALT OR PLANT THE
STORAGE LOCKERS WITH VALUABLE OR
UNUSUAL ITEMS TO CREATE DRAMA
AND SUSPENSE.
>> WOW.
CHECK THESE OUT.
>> Reporter: HE POINTS TO
SPECIFIC EXAMPLES, SUCH AS THIS
STACK OF OLD NEWSPAPERS
ANNOUNCING THE DEATH OF ELVIS
PRESLEY.
AND THIS CAR FOUND UNDER A PILE
OF TRASH.
>> WHOA!
>> IT'S A BMW.
>> Reporter: HESTER SAYS AFTER
HE COMPLAINED, HE WAS FIRED.
A&E, WHICH IS HALF OWNED BY
DISNEY, THE PARENT COMPANY OF
ABC, TOLD US TODAY THEY WILL NOT
COMMENT ON PENDING LAWSUITS, BUT
ONE OF THE SHOW'S PRODUCERS DID
SAY THIS RECENTLY.
>> I CAN HONESTLY TELL YOU THAT
THE STUFF FOUND IN THOSE
CONTAINERS ARE FOUND IN THE
STORAGE CONTAINERS.
>> Reporter: ALTHOUGH HE DID
ADMIT THEY SOMETIMES MOVE ITEMS
FROM ONE STORAGE LOCKER TO
ANOTHER.
THIS IS NOT THE FIRST TIME THE
LEVEL OF REALITY IN REALITY TV
HAS BEEN QUESTIONED.
RECENTLY, A FORMER PARTICIPANT
ON HGTV'S REQUESTS HOUSE
HUNTERS," WHICH FOLLOWS FAMILIES
CHOOSING A NEW HOME, SAID
PRODUCERS KNEW SHE AND HER
HUSBAND HAD ALREADY PURCHASED
THEIR NEW HOME BEFORE THEY TAPED
THE SHOW IN 2006.
>> FINALLY THE PRODUCER SAID
LET'S DO WHATEVER.
SO WE CALLED OUR VERY CLOSEST
AND KINDEST FRIENDS WHO WERE
THAT GENEROUS AND THEY OFFERED
UP THEIR HOUSES FOR US TO TOUR
AS OUR PRETEND DECISION MAKING
HOUSES.
>> Reporter: IN A STATEMENT,
HGTV SAID WE AREN'T SHOWING A
DOCUMENTARY, WE'RE SIMPLY
ENTERTAINING OUR VIEWERS.
>> REALITY TV IS A LITTLE BIT
LIKE SAUSAGE.
YOU MIGHT LOVE THE WAY IT TASTES
BUT YOU DON'T NECESSARILY WANT
TO KNOW HOW IT'S MADE.
>> Reporter: CLEARLY, MOST
VIEWERS KNOW THAT NOT EVERY
FIGHT OR DRUNKEN HOOK UP ON
REALITY TV IS REAL.
BUT WHEN THERE'S A COMPETITION,
THERE IS AN EXPECTATION OF SOME
AUTHENTICITY.
BACK IN THE 1950s, AFTER
REVELATIONS THAT CONTESTANTS ON
POPULAR QUIZ SHOWS WERE SECRETLY
GIVEN THE ANSWERS, CONGRESS HELD
HEARINGS AND MADE IT ILLEGAL TO
RIG QUIZ SHOWS.
>> I DON'T THINK IT'S OUR STYLE.
>> Reporter: NOBODY ALLEGES THE
LEVEL OF MANIPULATION ON TODAY'S
REALITY SHOWS IS ANYWHERE NEAR
THAT, AND LEGAL EXPERTS WE SPOKE
WITH DON'T THINK THE PRODUCERS
OF "STORAGE WARS" ARE IN DANGER
OF ANY CRIMINAL CHARGES.
>> I'M NOT SURE THAT THIS IS
REALLY A CONTEST WITH A PRIZE.
THEY GET TO BUY A LOCKER FULL OF
STUFF AND SOMETIMES THERE MIGHT
BE A JEWEL IN THERE, BUT THAT'S
NOT NECESSARILY A PRIZE FROM THE
SPONSOR.
>> IT'S VERY IMPORTANT FOR THE
PRODUCERS OF THIS PROGRAM TO
HAVE A RELATIONSHIP WITH THE
AUDIENCE THAT MAKES THEM BELIEVE
THAT WHAT THEY'RE SEEING IS
REAL.
AND IF THIS CAN BE ANNIHILATED,
NOT ONLY IN A LEGAL COURT BUT IN
THE COURT OF PUBLIC OPINION, IT
CAN UNDERMINE THE RATINGS
GREATLY.
>> Reporter: WHICH IS WHY AT
LEAST ONE OBSERVER TONIGHT IS
ADVISING THAT A&E THAT WHETHER
THE MOGUL'S ALLEGATIONS ARE TRUE
IMPORTANT.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU, DAN.
COMING UP NEXT, LADIES AND
GENTLEMEN, THE ROLLING STONES.
"NIGHTLINE" HAS THE ONLY
INTERVIEW WHILE THEY'RE ON TOUR
AND WE'LL LEARN HOW THEY MANAGE
TO KEEP THINGS AGAS AFTER 50
YEARS.
CAPTIONS PAID FOR BY ABC, INC.
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the political spin.
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
Let's keep Medicare...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
WHY LET ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
ASK IF YOUR HEART IS HEALTHY
ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA
IF YOU TAKE NITRATES
FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE HEADACHE,
FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION LASTING
MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
>>> "NIGHTLINE" CONTINUES FROM
NEW YORK CITY WITH BILL WEIR.
>> IT HAS BEEN NOTED THAT THE
AVERAGE AGE OF THE ROLLING
STONES IS NOW OLDER THAN THAT OF
THE U.S. SUPREME COURT.
BUT YOU KNOW WHO'S NOT MAKING
THE PREDICTABLE AGE JOKES ON
THIS TOUR?
EVERYONE WHO HAS SEEN THIS TOUR.
BECAUSE MINT, KEITH, CHARLIE,
AND RON STILL ROCK WITH THE BEST
OF THEM, WHILE CALLING THIS LIVE
CHAPTER 50 AND COUNTING IN
DEFIANT REFUSAL TO EVER ROLL TO
AN END.
TONIGHT, TIME IS ON OUR SIDE, AS
"NIGHTLINE" BRINGS YOU THE ONLY
TV INTERVIEW SINCE THEIR GOLDEN
ANNIVERSARY.
THERE'S A SCENE IN THE NEW HBO
DOCUMENTARY "CROSSFIRE
HURRICANE" THAT TAKES US
BACKSTAGE WITH THE STONES IN THE
EARLY '70s.
BACK WHEN MICK JAGGER WOULD
SLITHER INTO A BODY SUIT, SNORT
COKE OFF A SWITCHBLADE, AND THEN
WITH MOLTEN SEXUAL ENERGY
PROCEED TO BLOW THE MINDS OF AN
ARENA PACKED TO THE SWEATY
RAFTERS.
THE LAWS OF BURNT OUT PHYSICS
TELL US THAT THIS LEVEL IS
SUPPOSED TO EITHER SPLIT A BAND
OR KILL ITS STARS YOUNG.
WELL, BEHOLD MICK JAGGER AT AGE
69.
♪
FOR TWO AND A HALF HOURS, HE
SHIMMIES LAPS AROUND THE LIPS
AND TONGUE STAGE, AS BABY
BOOMERS AND THEIR KIDS GET A
CONTACT HIGH FROM ALL THIS
VINTAGE UNCUT ROCK 'N' ROLL.
HOW DO YOU DO IT?
I WAS SORE WATCHING.
>> IT'S JUST WHAT I DO REALLY.
AND THEN AFTER THAT, YOU HAVE A
ROOM FULL OF PEOPLE COME OVER
AND GO CRAZY AND DRINK ALL YOUR
WINE.
>> WE WERE TALKING ABOUT IT.
IF PEOPLE ARE WILLING TO PAY
$500, $600 FOR A SEAT, JUST
THINK WHAT THEY WOULD PAY FOR
MICK JAGGER ELIXIR, OR WHATEVER
IT IS, YOUR FITNESS REGIMEN.
>> I DON'T REALLY HAVE MUCH OF A
FITNESS REGIMEN, TO BE HONEST.
IT'S PRETTY LOW-KEY.
I MEAN, I DO HAVE ONE.
>> KEITH RICHARDS, WHO ALSO
TURNS 69 NEXT WEEK, IS
ADMITTEDLY LESS MOBILE ONSTAGE,
BUT AS HE PROVED DURING LAST
NIGHT'S CONCERT FOR HURRICANE
SANDY RELIEF, THAT GUITAR GIVES
HIM NO LESS POWER TO ANYONE WITH
AN EARDRUM.
WHAT IS IT LIKE TO BE KEITH
RICHARDS AND HIT AN OPENING RIFF
AND SEE IT JUST RIP LIKE
ELECTRICITY THROUGH A ROOM LIKE
THAT?
>> IT IS INDESCRIBABLE.
I WISH YOU COULD ALL BE THERE.
BUT IT'S SOMETHING I CAN'T SHARE
WITH ANYBODY.
MAYBE CHARLIE WATTS AND THE GUYS
IN THE BAND.
THERE'S JUST A MAGIC TO IT.
I'M IN LOVE OF IT, REALLY.
AFTER ALL, WHEN IT COMES DOWN TO
IT, WHAT DO DUO, WHAT ARE WE
GOOD AT, WE TOUCH PEOPLE'S
HEARTS.
>> AND TO THINK THE STONES
NEARLY SPLIT FOR GOOD SEVERAL
TIMES OVER RECENT DECADES.
AS KEITH REVEALED IN HIS RECENT
AUTOBIOGRAPHY "LIFE," HIS
RESENTIMENT FOR JAGGER BEGAN
BUILDING IN THE '80s WHEN THE
SINGER'S EGO SEEMED TO GROW TOO
BIG FOR THE BAND.
I USED TO LOVE TO HANG WITH
MICK, HE WROTE, BUT I HAVEN'T
GONE TO HIS DRESSING ROOM IN 20
YEARS.
SOMETIMES I MISS MY FRIEND.
WHERE THE HELL DID HE GO?
THAT LINE MAKES THE FILM
"CHARLIE IS MY DARLING" ALL THE
MORE POIGNANT.
SHOT IN THE 1965 TOUR, IT SHOWS
THE GLIMMER TWINS WRITING SONGS
AS A TRUE CREATIVE TEAM.
BUT KEITH'S INSULTS OF JAGGER IN
HIS BOOK WERE SO SERING IT TOOK
A REPORTED APOLOGY FROM RICHARDS
BEFORE THIS REUNION COULD EVEN
HAPPEN.
HOW WOULD YOU CHARACTERIZE YOUR
RELATIONSHIP WITH KEITH THESE
DAYS?
>> AT THE MOMENT, IT'S GOOD.
A PRETTY GOOD WORKING
RELATIONSHIP.
WE SEE EACH OTHER, WE GO ONSTAGE
AND WE PLAY TOGETHER AND WE
REHEARSE SIX WEEKS IN PARIS.
IT'S PRETTY GOOD.
♪
>> TWO NEW SONGS.
DID YOU WRITE THOSE TOGETHER?
SEPARATELY?
>> SEPARATELY.
KEITH LIVES IN THE UNITED STATES
AND I LIVE IN EUROPE.
>> ONE OF THE GREAT CLIPS I CAME
ACROSS WAS YOU GUYS NOODLING
TOGETHER.
>> YEAH.
>> HOW MUCH OF THAT IS THE
SECRET SAUCE OF THE STONES,
WHERE YOU TWO NEED TO BE
TOGETHER TO DO THAT?
>> I THINK WE'VE GONE PAST THAT,
REALLY.
>> WE'RE MADE TO DO THIS.
IT'S WHEN WE'RE NOT WORKING
THERE'S A PROBLEM.
OR COULD BE.
BUT OTHERWISE, MICK AND I HAVE
BEEN WORKING TOGETHER THE LAST
FEW MONTHS.
IT'S BEEN A REVELATION REALLY.
>> REALLY?
>> YEAH.
HOW YOU CAN ALL GET ALONG ONCE
YOU'RE IN THE GROOVE AND STUFF
AND HOW MUCH WE ACTUALLY DO FIT
TOGETHER.
IT'S VERY INTERESTING.
>> THERE WAS A TIME EARLIER THIS
YEAR, I THOUGHT -- I DON'T THINK
IT WILL HAPPEN AGAIN.
I DIDN'T MIND.
>> THERE WAS A TIME WHEN IT WAS
IN THE BALANCE WHEN PEOPLE WERE
SAYING OH, IT'S NOT GOING TO
HAPPEN.
IT LOOKED LIKE IT, BUT I NEVER
BELIEVED IT.
>> AND AS THEY HAD STRUGGLED FOR
HARMONY, SOME IN THE BAND HAVE
ALSO TACKLED ADDICTION OVER THE
YEARS, MOST NOTABLY KEITH'S
HARD-WON BATTLES WITH HEROIN.
>> I DON'T DO ANYTHING NO MORE.
I'VE DONE IT ALL.
ONCE YOU'VE DONE IT ALL, WHAT
ARE YOU GOING TO DO, YOU KNOW?
YOU GIVE IT UP AND ENJOY GIVING
IT UP.
THE ONLY THING I HAVEN'T DONE
BEFORE WAS GIVING THINGS UP.
THIS IS ANOTHER TURN.
IT'S WONDERFUL BEING STRAIGHT.
>> HE STILL ENJOYS A DRINK OR
THREE, BUT NOT SO FOR DRUMMER
CHARLIE WATTS.
THE ELDER STONE HAS LONG BEEN A
WELL BEHAVED FAMILY MAN, AND NO
MORE PARTYING UNTIL SUNRISE FOR
GUITARIST RONNIE WOOD.
YOU'VE BEEN SOBER FOR A WHILE.
>> FOR YEARS.
>> THIS IS THE FIRST TOUR,
THOUGH, RIGHT?
TO TEST THAT WILL POWER?
>> YEAH, PROBABLY.
YEAH.
>> HOW'S IT GOING?
>> GOING GREAT.
I HANDLE THINGS MUCH EASIER.
>> HE'S DOING VERY WELL.
IT'S VERY DIFFICULT FOR HIM.
>> GREAT SUPPORT.
>> BUT IT'S A BIG DEAL WHEN YOU
DO IT FOR WEEKS STRAIGHT.
YOU THINK I'M NEVER GOING TO
MAKE THE END OF IT.
>> BUT BY ALL ACCOUNTS, HE DID.
THEY ALL DID, THANKS TO EIGHT
WEEKS OF ALL DAY REHEARSALS TO
PREPARE FOR JUST FIVE SHOWS.
BUT EVEN THOUGH THIS TOUR IS
CALLED 50 AND COUNTING, YOU
CAN'T HELP BUT WONDER WHEN THIS
INCREDIBLE RUN WILL END.
AS YOU CAN SEE IN "CHARLIE IS MY
DARLING", IT'S A QUESTION THAT
GOES BACK TO THE DAYS OF GIRLS
LITERALLY WETTING THEMSELVES IN
THE AISLES AND BOYS STARTING
CONCERT RIOTS.
BACK WHEN IT SEEMED LIKE THE
ROLLING STONES WERE THE MOST
DANGEROUS FORCE IN THE UNIVERSE.
>> WHEN WE FIRST GOT A RECORD,
GIVEN THE CHANCE, WE THOUGHT
WELL, IT'S GOOD -- WE'LL
PROBABLY BE AROUND A YEAR, MAYBE
A YEAR AND A HALF.
THEN IT'S ALL GOING TO BE OVER.
>> FIRST YEAR -- 1965.
CAN YOU KEEP DOING THIS?
I REMEMBER BEING ASKED THAT IN
1965 AND EVERY DECADE I WAS
ASKED IT.
>> YOU ARE NOT A NOSTALGIC GUY.
YOU'RE NOT AN INTROSPECTIVE GUY
AT ALL.
>> NOT REALLY.
I HATE TO PUT UP WITH THIS
50-YEAR THING.
IT WAS SORT OF THRUST UPON YOU.
IT'S SOMETHING TO BE PROUD OF.
BUT I'LL BE GLAD WHEN IT'S OVER.
>> WOULD YOU ALLOW YOURSELF A
MOMENT TO JUST SOAK IN THE
ENORMITY OF WHAT YOU GUYS HAVE
ACCOMPLISHED OVER THESE YEARS
BEFORE WALKING ONSTAGE FOR THIS
ONE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> YEAH, IT'S A PRETTY HUMBLING
THOUGHT WHEN YOU ACTUALLY THINK
ABOUT IT.
AND I DON'T GET HUMBLE OFTEN.
>> ONE MORE SHOT IS WHAT THEY'RE
CALLING THE STONES' 50 AND
COUNTING FINALE.
A LIVE WORLDWIDE PAY-PER-VIEW
EVENT, 9:00 P.M. EASTERN TIME
THIS SATURDAY NIGHT, SPECIAL
GUEST BRUCE SPRINGSTEEN, LADY
GAGA AND THE BLACK KEYS.
>>> NEXT, HOW OLD SAINT NICK IS
GETTING A LITTLE MORE SADISTIC
THESE DAYS.
SORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
I HAVE OBLIGATIONS. CUTE
TOBLIGATIONS, BUT OBLIGATIONS.G.
I NEED TO RETHINK THE
CORE OF MY PORTFOLIO.
WHAT I REALLY NEED IS SLEEP.
INTRODUCING THE ISHARES CORE,
BUILDING BLOCKS FOR THE
HEART OF YOUR PORTFOLIO.
FIND OUT WHY 9 OUT OF 10
LARGE PROFESSIONAL INVESTORS
CHOOSE ISHARES FOR THEIR ETFS.
ISHARES BY BLACKROCK.
CALL 1-800-ISHARES FOR A
PROSPECTUS WHICH INCLUDES
INVESTMENT OBJECTIVES,
RISKS, CHARGES AND EXPENSES.
READ AND CONSIDER
IT CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
RISK INCLUDES POSSIBLE
LOSS OF PRINCIPAL.
>>> HE SEES YOU WHEN YOU'RE
SLEEPING, HE KNOWS WHEN YOU'RE
AWAKE, AND THAT MAY BE
DISTURBING CONSIDERING THE
MODERN SANTA TREND.
HERE'S ABC'S NICK WATT.
>> Reporter: IT'S COLD, SILENT
NIGHT.
THE LATEST IN A LONG LINE OF
MOVIES IN WHICH SANTA WAS BAD.
>> CHRISTMAS EVE IS THE SCARIEST
DAMN NIGHT OF THE YEAR.
>> THE SANTA COSTUME IS RIGHT.
THERE'S TOO MUCH IMBIBING OF THE
CHRISTMAS CHEER.
>> Reporter: FROM "SOUTHPARK."
>> WE MEET AGAIN, JESUS.
>> Reporter: TO "AMERICAN HORROR
STORY."
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY WE BLOW THIS
POP STAND.
>> Reporter: THEY LOVE TO TURN
THE EMBODIMENT OF GOODNESS INTO
EVIL.
>> CHRISTMAS HAS A DARK SIDE,
TOO.
>> IT'S A TRIED AND TESTED
THEATRICAL CHRISTMAS.
>> Reporter: IT'S SCARY LIKE A
CLOWN IS SCARY.
EVIL BEHIND A JOLLY MASK.
IT'S SCARY LIKE THE ORIGINAL
"SILENT NIGHT" IS SCARY, BACK
FROM 1984.
>> IT WAS DEEMED SORT OF
SACRILEGIOUS TO MAKE SANTA THIS
FIGURE.
>> YOU PEOPLE HAVE NOTHING TO BE
PROUD OF, EVEN IF YOU MADE A FEW
BUCKS OFF ALL THE NEGATIVE
PUBLICITY.
YOUR PROFITS TRULY ARE BLOOD
MONEY.
>> Reporter: IT'S FUNNY, LIKE
DAN AYKROYD IN "TRADING PLACES."
AND IT'S FUNNY LIKE A LOCAL NEWS
STORY ABOUT A GRUMPY MALL SANTA
GETTING FIRED IN MAINE.
>> HE DIDN'T EVEN ASK IF SHE WAS
GOOD OR ANY OF THAT.
HE JUST KIND OF SNUBBED HER.
>> Reporter: EVEN THE SANTA WHO
LET ME PULL HIS BEARD AT THE
AMERICANA MALL IN GLENDALE.
THINKS THAT'S FUNNY.
>> THERE'S A LOT OF OLD GRUMPY
SANTAS.
>> Reporter: AND A LOT OF EVIL
BUT OUR SANTA HAS A SERIOUS
POINT TO MAKE.
>> I THINK IT'S AN ABERRATION.
THERE'S NO BAD SANTA.
THERE MAY BE PEOPLE WHO ACT AS
SANTA WHO ARE BAD PEOPLE.
>> BAD SANTA WAS PERHAPS THE
BEST THAT THIS HONOR IS EVER
GOING TO GET.
>> WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
DELICIOUS, KIND OF WORLD
WEARINESS TO HIS SANTA.
>> I'M ON MY [ BLEEP ] LUNCH
BREAK, OKAY?
>> Reporter: DON'T WE ALL AT
TIMES FEEL A LITTLE BIT LIKE
THAT AT THE HOLIDAYS?
I'M NICK WATT FOR "NIGHTLINE."
>> YIKES.
"BAD SANTA 2" WILL BE COMING OUT
IN 2013.
THANK YOU, NICK WATT AND THANK
YOU FOR WATCHING.
WE'LL SEE YOU RIGHT BACK HERE
TOMORROW.
HAVE A GREAT NIGHT.
>> Dicky: UP NEXT ON AN ALL-NEW
"JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE," THIS WEEK,
AN UNNECESSARY CENSORSHIP.
>> I MIGHT [ BLEEP ] YOUR BUM IF
YOU'RE NAUGHTY.
>> Dicky: CARSON DALY.
>> HOW MANY TIMES HAVE YOU BEEN
TO THE WHITE HOUSE SINCE I'VE
HAD MY DAUGHTER?
>> TWICE.
>> YOU CHOOSE THIS COUNTRY OVER
YOUR FRIEND'S DAUGHTER.
>> Dicky: AND ZACHARY KNIGHTON.
AND MUSIC FROM DAN DEACON.