JEFF: HEN, AND WEL'M
JEFF CORWIN, AND WELCOME
TO OCEAN MYSTERIES.
THIS RATHER
OMINOUS-LOOKING GRIN
BELONGS TO NONE OTHER
THAN THE MYSTERIOUS WOLF
EEL.
IT'S A CREATURE THAT
THRIVES IN DEEP, COLD
WATERS OFF OF PLACES
LIKE ALASKA.
AND THIS MIGHTY WOLF EEL
IS A LITTLE TEASER TO
THE ADVENTURE TO COME,
BECAUSE TODAY WE'RE
HEADING TO THE COASTLINE
OF ALASKA, WHERE WE'LL
BE A PART OF AN
INCREDIBLE RESEARCH AND
CONSERVATION PROJECT.
THIS, MY FRIENDS, IS AN
ADVENTURE YOU DON'T WANT
TO MISS.
ALASKA IS OVER 4,000
MILES FROM GEORGIA
AQUARIUM, BUT CERTAINLY
WORTH THE TRIP.
ALASKA IS OUR COUNTRY'S
LARGEST STATE, TWICE THE
SIZE OF TEXAS.
100,000 GLACIERS, HALF
OF ALL GLACIERS ON OUR
PLANET, AND ITS
COASTLINE STRETCHES FOR
NEARLY 34,000 MILES.
BUT FOR ME, THE MOST
INCREDIBLE FEATURE OF
ALASKA IS ITS WILDLIFE,
AND TODAY WE ARE HERE TO
STUDY ONE OF NORTH
AMERICA'S LARGEST MARINE
MAMMALS, THE MIGHTY
STELLER SEA LION.
UNFORTUNATELY, IN RECENT
YEARS, LARGE PORTIONS OF
THE STELLER SEA LION
POPULATION HERE HAVE
DECLINED DRAMATICALLY.
SOME OF ALASKA'S STELLER
SEA LIONS ARE NOW LISTED
AS ENDANGERED, WITH 80%
DECLINED OVER JUST THE
LAST THREE DECADES.
TODAY, SCIENTISTS ARE
RACING TO DETERMINE WHY
THIS SPECIES CONTINUES
TO BE IN TROUBLE.
ALL RIGHT, GUYS, AS YOU
CAN SEE, IT IS A CRISP
AND SOMEWHAT GRAY DAY
HERE OFF OF SEWARD, BUT
THINGS ARE GOING TO PICK
UP, BECAUSE WE'RE
ISLAND WITH A TEAM FROMOROM
THE ALASKA SEALIFE
CENTER T
SEA LIONS.
YOU GUYS READY?
MAN: WE'RE READY.
JEFF: ALL RIGHT, LET'S
DO IT.
TO HELP GATHER
INFORMATION, THE ALASKA
SEALIFE CENTER USES A
NETWORK OF REMOTE VIDEO
CAMERAS THAT CAPTURE SEA
LION BEHAVIOR WITHIN
PRINCE WILLIAM SOUND AND
RESURRECTION BAY.
FOR YEARS, THESE CAMERAS
HAVE PROVIDED VITAL
INFORMATION ABOUT THESE
CREATURES, BUT THIS
MORNING ONE OF THE VIDEO
FEEDS LOCATED ABOVE
GROTTO ISLAND HAS GONE
OFFLINE, SO WE'RE
HEADING OU
OUT
WHY AND TO SEE IF WE CAN
FIX IT.
WE ARE HERE AT THIS
REMOTE ISLAND WITH JOHN
MANISCALCO, WHO WORKS
WITH THE ALASKA SEALIFE
CENTER, AND WE'RE GOING
TO HAVE A MISSION AHEAD
OF US.
WHAT'S THE PLAN?
JOHN: WELL, WE'RE GOING
TO GET OFF THE BOAT
HERE, HIKE UP THESETOCKS, AO
THAT CAMERA AND FIX IT,
IF WE CAN.
GROTTO ISLAND IS A
FAVORITE SPOT FOR MANY
OF THESE STELLER SEA
LIONS AND BIRDS ALIKE.
THIS BROKEN VIDEO CAMERA
IS PERCHED HIGH ABOVE US
WITH A FANTASTIC VIEW OF
THE COVE AND ROCKS
BELOW.
ALL RIGHT, SO HOW DO WE
DO THIS?
JOHN: THERE'S SOME
CRACKS UP TOP.
JEFF: OKAY.
JOHN: AND I PUT MY HAND
IN THOSE CRACKS, PUT MY
RIGHT FOOT ON THIS, AND
HOIST MYSELF ON UP.
JEFF: ALL RIGHT, LET'S
SEE WHAT HAPPENS.
JOHN: ALL RIGHT.
JEFF: WHAT A SPECTACULAR
SPOT.
LOOK AT THIS.
WE HAVE
ERUPTIONS OF GRANITE
THAT JUST STABBED THEIR
WAY UP INTO THIS
POSTCARD-PERFECT BLUESKY.
SKY.
OCCASIONALLY, WE'RE DIVE
BOMBED BY THESE
GREGARIOUS BIRDS.
THEY'RE GLAUCOUS-WINGED
GULLS, CORRECT?
JOHN: THAT'S RIGHT.
JEFF: AND THIS IS THE
NESTING PERIOD, AND
EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE WE
COME ACROSS THESE LITTLE
GEMS, THESE TRUE NATURAL
TREASURES.
IF YOU LOOK RIGHT HERE,
THIS NEST OF THREE EGGS
IS PERHAPS JUST A WEEK
OR SO AWAY FROM
HATCHING, BUT WE'RE HERE
FOR WHAT'S ABOVE JOHN'S
HEAD.
YOU CAN SEE A LITTLE BIT
OF TECHNOLOGY THERE.
AND THAT'S WHAT'S REALLY
GREAT WITH JOHN'S
PROJECT IS HE CAN WORK
IN HIS OFFICE ON THE
MOST MISERABLE ALASKAN
DAY AND JUST FLIP ON HIS
MONITOR, HIS COMPUTER, SCRE,
AND ACTUALLY GET A FLY
ON THE WALL VIEW OF LIFE
AS IT UNFOLDS HERE ON
GROTTO ISLAND.
WHILE JOHN WORKS ON
THIS, I'M GOING TO JUST
CAREFULLY CREEP OVER THE
TOP.
I'M JUST GOING TO GO
THIS WAY, KEEPING A LOW
PROFILE.
I'M GOING TO CHECK OUT
THE COLOSSUS BELOW US.
OH.
THIS IS REALLY COOL.
WE HAVE THE ULTIMATE
BIRD'S EYE VIEW.
BASICALLY, A HAUL OUT
SITE IS A LOCATION
WHERE PINNIPEDS SUCH AS
CALIFORNIA SEA LIONS,
AND SEALS, STELLER SEA
LIONS, THEY PULL
THEMSELVES OUT OF THE
COLD WATER THAT THEY
DEPEND UPON TO TAKE A
REST.
WHAT'S GREAT ABOUT THE
REMOTE
REMOTE SLABS OF GRANITE,
IT PROVIDES THEM WITH A
PLACE TO SOCIALIZE, TO
REST, AND WARM UP THEIR
BODIES.
THEY, OF COURSE, ARE
ARMED WITH BLUBBER UNDER
THEIR THICK SKIN TO
INSULATE THEM.E THERE'S A
LOT E THERE'S A
LOT OF REALLY COOL
SOCIAL DYNAMICS
UNFOLDING HERE.
YOU COULD SEE THAT
THERE'S A REAL PECKING
ORDER WITH WHERE YOU FIT
IN WITH REGARD TO THE
HIERARCHY OF A
HIERARCHY OF A STELLER
SEA LION COMMUNITY.
SOME OF THEM ARE JUST A
FEW YEARS OLD, AND THEN
WE HAVE SOME SUB ADULT
MALES DOWN THERE, AND WE
HAVE SOME BIGGER ONES,
SOME BIGGER BULLS, BUT
THEY'RE CLEARLY LOWER ON
THE TOTEM POLE, BECAUSE
THEY'RE NOT GETTING THE
VALUABLE REAL ESTATE.
THAT BIG GUY HAS FOUGHT
HIS WAY TO THE TOP; AND
BY BEING THERE, HE HAS
ACCESS TO THE FEMALES
THAT ARE READY TO BREED.
THIS IS NOT YOUR EVERY
DAY AT THE OFFICE, ISN'T
IT?
THAT'S WHY I LOVE THIS
JOB.
THE VIDEO FROM THIS
CAMERA WILL HELP
SCIENTISTS BETTER
UNDERSTAND THESE ANIMALS
AND HOPEFULLY PROVIDE
INFORMATION TO DEVELOP A
GOOD STRATEGY TO SAVE
THEM.
AND AFTER A FEW NEW
CABLES AND A LITTLE BIT
OF CLEANING AND FRESH
WIRING, THE VIDEO FEED
IS UP AND RUNNING.
SO, AS YOU CAN SEE, THIS
INCREDIBLY IMPORTANT
PIECE OF EQUIPMENT HAS
BEEN REPAIRED, NO MORE
TECHNICAL DIFFICULTIES.
NO
NOW THE SCIENTISTS CAN
SIT IN FRONT OF THEIR
COMPUTERS; AND LO AND
BEHOLD, THIS INCREDIBLE
STORY WILL CONTINUE TO
UNFOLD.
COMING UP NEXT, OUR
EFFORTS TO REPAIR THE
GROTTO ISLAND CAMERA PAY
OFF BIG TIME, AS WE
WITNESS THE BIRTH OF A
NEW MEMBER OF THIS
STELLER SEA LION
COMMUNITY.
SO, SHE'S PUSHING RIGHT
NOW, AND IT'S REALLY
CLOSE.
JEFF: DON'T GO AWAY.
OCEAN MYSTERIES WILL BE
RIGHT BACK.
WE SET SAIL
ABOARD SeaWorld ONE
TO ENCOUNTER FANTASTICAL
SEA CREATURES AND STUFF,
WHEN SUDDENLY...
SHAMU OF THE SEA RISES AND
THE OCEAN CRASHES OVER THE BOW
WHEN OUR SONAR DETECTED
A TURTLE WORLD.
SO I TOOK CONTROL
AND STEERED US THROUGH IT.
THEN A CURIOUS SEA CREATURE
APPROACHED, AND AS OUR EYES MET
WE WERE TRANSPORTED
TO A SUPER-SECRET
UNDERWATER CAVERN...
SeaWorld?
I THINK THEY LIKED IT.
[ Female Announcer ]
START YOUR ADVENTURES TODAY
AT Seaworld.com
AND FIND SPECIAL OFFERS.
♪
This holiday when Kmart
Shop Your Way members
check out, th
check out, they
can win...
... a trip to
Universal Orlando Resort,
during our 30 Days of
Surgood time.could have a y
Fly with Harry.
Or win lots of other
great prizes.
For more chances to win visit
Shop Your Way .com
Only at Kmart.
TO FLAT SCREENS...NS...
TWIZZLERIZE YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT EVERYDAY
WITH TWIZZLERS,
T RESIST.
THE TWIST YOU CAN'T RESIST.
[ Female Announcer ]
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
RICH DARK CHOCOLATE,
TOASTED OATS.
PERFECT COMBINATIONS OF
NATURE'S DELICIOUS INGREDIENTS,
FROM NATURE VALLEY.
♪
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
NATURE AT ITS MOST DELICIOUS.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
she doesn't
Even though our really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
Who's your mommy now?
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
JEFF: WELCOME BACK TO
OCEAN MYSTERIE
TODAY WE
TODAY WE'RE EXPLORING
THE COASTLINE OF ALASKA
AND UNCOVERING THE
SECRETS OF THE
MYSTERIOUS AND MIGHTY
STELLER SEA LION.
VERY NICE.
GUYS, THIS GIGANTIC
MOUND OF ANCIENT ROCK IS
CHISWELL ISLAND, AND
IT'S A VERY IMPORTANT
SITE FOR THE SURVIVAL OF
STELLER SEAL LIONS.
THIS IS THE PLACE WHERE
THEY BASK, WHERE THEY
BREED, WHERE THEY GIVE
BIRTH, AND THESE MALES,
YOU KNOW, WILL BATTLE TO
KEEP THE COMPETITORS
AWAY; THUS, THEY CONTROL
THIS REGION WHERE THE
FEMALES COME TOGETHER.
WOULD YOU CALL THIS A
HAREM?
IS IT LIKE THAT SORT OF
JOHN: SORT OF.
A HAREM, TECHNICALLY, IS
WHERE A MALE DEFENDS
FEMALES.
THESE MALES DEFEND
TERRITORY, NOT
NECESSARILY FEMALES.
THEY'LL SOMETIMES TRY TO
HERD A FEMALE INTO THEIR
TERRITORY, BUT THEY'RE
NOT TECHNICALLY HAREM
BULLS.
JEFF: THERE HAVE BEEN
SOME CHALLENGES IN
TRYING TO KEEP THIS
POPULATION OF THIS
ENDANGERED SPECIES NICE
AND HEALTHY.
SOME AREAS HAVE
STABILIZED.
COLLAPSED.
THERE'S BEEN SOME GOOD
NEWS; BUT, OVERALL, HOW
IS THIS SPECIES DOING?NK
JOHN: OVERALL, I THINK
THE SPECIES IS DOING
OKAY.
THERE'S STILL SOME MAJOR
CONCERNS FROM HERE
FARTHER WEST, BUT WE'RET OFF
THE WOODS YET, BUT WE'RE
HOPEFUL.
JEFF: KEEPING AN EYE ON
THESE ANIMALS IS
CRITICAL TO UNCOVERING
WHY SOME OF THEIR
POPULATIONS ARE NOW
DECLINING, AND NO PLACE
HAS A BETTER LOOK AT
WILD SEA LIONS THAN THE
ALASKA SEALIFE CENTER.
THIS IS GOING TO BE
AWESOME.
WE'RE ACTUALLY IN THE
REMOTE VIDEO LAB BACK
HERE AT THE ALASKA
SEALIFE CENTER.
WE WERE PHYSICALLY AT
THESE ROCKS, AND YOU
REMEMBER WE WERE OUT
THERE WITH JOHN, AND WE
WERE TWEAKING THAT
CAMERA, AND THAT IMAGE
CAPTURED BY THAT CAMERA
IS SENT TO HERE WITH PAM
AND CARLY, AND WE ARE
WATCHING SOMETHING
REALLY COOL.
WHAT'S HAPPENING HERE,
PAM?
PAM: SHE'S A FEMALE
STELLER SEA LION, AND
SHE IS ABOUT TO GIVE
BIRTH.
JEFF: SO, YOU CAN
ACTUALLY SEE THIS IS THE
BACK END RIGHT HERE, AND
WE'RE ACTUALLY GETTING
SOME CONTRACTIONS.
THE MUSCLES ARE WAXING
AND WANING, AS SHE
PREPARES TO BRING THIS
NEW LITTLE PUP INTO THE
NOW, THI
NOW, THIS IS BECKY,
RIGHT?
PAM: THIS IS BECKY.
JEFF: HOW HAS SHE BEEN
AS A MOTHER?
PAM: BECKY IS AN
EXCELLENT FEMALE.
SHE HAS HAD PUPS OUTWELL ISN
HERE ON CHISWELL ISLAND
SINCE 2004.
SHE'S GIVEN BIRTH IN
EVERY YEAR, AND EVERY
YEAR HER PUP HAS
SURVIVED.
JEFF: YOU CAN SEE TUCKED
UNDER THERE IS ANOTHER
FLIPPER, SO SHE IS
REALLY, REALLY CLOSE.
PAM: BECKY HAS BEEN IN
LABOR PROBABLY A LITTLE
BIT OVERNIGHT, BUT WE
SAW THE INTENSITY OF THE
CONTRACTIONS INCREASE
AROUND 8:00 A.M., AND
THEN WE SAW THE FIRST
EMERGING OF THE FLIPPERS
AROUND 9:08.
JUST BEFORE BIRTH, THE
FEMALES WILL START TO
VOCALIZE AT THEIR REAR
END THERE, AND THE
REASON IS BECAUSE --
JEFF: SHE'LL ACTUALLY
START BARKING AND
VOCALIZING TO THE BACK
END OF THE BIRTH CANAL.
PAM: AND THE REASON FOR
THAT IS AS SOON AS THE
PUP IS BORN, SHE WANTS
TO MAKE A LOT OF
VOCALIZATIONS AT THE PUP
SO THAT THE PUP THEN
LEARNS WHO ITS MOTHER IS
AND VOCALIZES BACK AT
HER SECONDS AFTER BEING
BORN.
JEFF: IT'S AMAZING.
SO, SHE'S PUSHING RIGHT
NOW, AND IT'S REALLY
CLOSE.
JEFF: AND THAT IS HOW A
BRAND NEW BABY PUP IS
BORN.
SO, WHAT IS SHE DOING
THERE?
PAM: WHAT THIS IS, IS
SHE IS GOING TO BE --
SEE HOW SHE'S VOCALIZING
AT THE PUP?
AND THEN SHE'S GOING TO
BE PICKING THE PUP UP
AND SHAKING ANY SORT OF
FLUID OUT OF ITS LUNGS,
AND THEN SHE WILL NUZZLE
THE PUP.
SO, THIS BEHAVIOR IS
CALLED NUZZLING, WHERE
THEIR NOSE-TO-NOSE
CONTACT OCCURS.
JEFF: SO, THAT
VOCALIZATION, THAT
BARKING BEHAVIOR BETWEEN
MOM AND PUP IS REALLY
THE WAY THEY BOND WITH
EACH OTHER AND FIND EACH
OTHER AMONGST THIS GREAT
CHAOS OF STELLER SEA
LIONS.
A HEALTHY, NURSING PUP
CERTAINLY MAKES FOR
GREAT TELEVISION.
THE DATA COLLECTED FROM
THESE CAMERAS CONTINUES
TO BUILD OUR GROWING
UNDERSTANDING OF THESE
MAGNIFICENT CREATURES
AND MAY SOMEDAY UNCOVER
THE SECRETS TO THEIR
CONSERVATION.
WHEN WE RETURN, OUR
STELLER SEA LION
ADVENTURE GETS BIG,
REALLY BIG, WHEN WE MEET
ONE OF THE LARGEST,
STRONGEST, AND MOST
INTIMIDATING SEA LIONS
ON OUR PLANET.
[SEA LION GROWLING]
STAY TUNED AS WEAKESDISCOVES
TO CARE FOR WOODY, NEXT
ON OCEAN MYSTERIES.
For months, I had this deep pain
all over my body.
It just wouldn't go away.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can plan my days
and accomplish more.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
with hand-layered pasta,
tomatoes,
and real mozzarella cheese.
But what makes us even
prouder...
is what our real
dinners can do for your family.
Let's fix dinner.
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
ANNOUNCER: A SPECIAL
OCCASION DESERVES A
SPECIAL PLACE.
AND THAT'S WHY EAST
POINT, GEORGIA IS KNOWN
AS THE DESTINATION FOR
FAMILY REUNIONS.
JUST MINUTES AWAY FROM
THE ATLANTA AIRPORT,
EAST POINT'S SMALL-TOWN
CHARM PROVIDES THE
PERFECT SETTING TO BRING
FAMILIES TOGETHER.
OUR HOTELS AND
RESTAURANTS OFFER
GENEROUS GROUP
DISCOUNTS, EASY ACCESS
TO ATLANTA'S WORLD CLASS
SHOPPING AND
ATTRACTIONS, AND
SEVENTEEN BEAUTIFUL
PARKS EQUAL LOTS OF
FAMILY FUN.
A REUNION IN EAST POINT,
GEORGIA WILL PROVIDE
MEMORIES TO LAST A
LIFETIME.
FIND OUT MORE AT
VISITEASTPOINT.COM.
JEFF: WELCOME BACK TO
OCEAN MY
WHILE SOME WILD
POPULATIONS OF
SEA LIONS ARE PRODUCING
HEALTHY, GROWING PUPSVE STAN
SERIOUS DECLINE.
THE ALASKA SEALIFE
CENTER IS AT THE
FOREFRONT OF RESEARCH
INTO THE BREEDING HABITS
OF THESE AMAZING, YET
MYSTERIOUS CREATURES.
THIS MAMMOTH OF A
STELLER SEA LION I
FAMOUS WOODY LIVING HERE
AT ALASKA SEALIFE
CENTER.
THIS CREATURE WEIGHS
OVER 2,000 POUNDS.
HE SHARES THIS HABITAT
WITH TWO FEMALES, AND
RIGHT NOW IT'S THE
BREEDING SEASON, SO WHAT
THIS TEAM NEEDS TO DO IS
SORT OF GET AN
ASSESSMENT.
IT'S A BIT DICEY,
BECAUSE IN ORDER TO GET
THE FEMALES OUT, THE
COWS OUT, YOU NEED TO
DISTRACT WOODY.
HE'S VERY TERRITORIAL.
HE DOES NOT WANT TO
SHARE THESE FEMALES.
OKAY, SO WOODY'S COMING
IN THE WATER.
AS HE JUMPS IN, HE'S
FOCUSING ON US OVER
HERE.
IN THE MEANTIME, THE
TEAM HERE AT ALASKA
SEALIFE CENTER CAN
SEPARATE THE FEMALES,
BECAUSE THEY NEED TO
ASSESS HOW THEY'RE
DOING, SEE WHERE THEIR
HORMONE LEVELS ARE WITH
REGARD TO THE BREEDING
PROGRESS.
NOW, DISTRACTING WOODY
IS NO EASY TASK.
THIS HUGE MALE IS
EXTREMELY PROTECTIVE OF
HIS TWO FAVORITE LADIES,
AND HE PERCEIVES OUR
EFFORTS TO EXAMINE THEM
AS COMPETITION.
THE SEALIFE CENTER STAFF
CAREFULLY COORDINATES
WITH EACH OTHER TO KEEP
WOODY AT BAY LONG ENOUGH
TO REMOVE THE FEMALES
FROM THE HABITAT.
OKAY, GUYS, SO WE'VE
MOVED FROM THE FRONT OF
THE EXHIBIT TO THE BACK
SIDE.
THIS IS WHERE MOST OF
THE HUSBANDRY AND ANY
VETERINARY WORK TAKES
PLACE ON THESE STELLER
SEA LIONS.
THIS IS CHRISTY.
SO, YOU CAN SEE WHAT
THEY'VE DONE RIGHT HERE.
ACTED ONTEGICALLY, THEY'VE
THE OTHER SIDE AND
BRHERE.NE OF THESE
E
SO, WE HAVE TWO OF THEM.
WE HAVE TWO OF THESE
FEMALE STELLER SEA
LIONS.
THEY'RE GOING TO
ANESTHETIZE THESE
ANIMALS, TAKE A BLOOD
DRAW, AND TO SEE WHERE
THEY ARE AT WITH REGARD
TO THEIR BREEDING CYCLE.
[SEA LION BARKING]
BRETT: AND SO IN ORDER
FOR US TO GET HER READY
FOR A BLOOD DRAW, WE
NEED TO SLOWLY MOVE HER
FLIPPER OUT A LITTLE BIT
AND SPREAD IT.
JEFF: SPREAD IT, JUST
SPREAD OUT THE DIGITS?
BRETT: YEAH, SO YOU CAN
SEE EXACTLY.
JEFF: OKAY.
BRETT: SO YOU CAN SEE
THE WEBBING.
BRETT: FOLLOW ME.
OKAY, THE BACK PORT IS
OPEN.
JEFF: THIS STELLER SEA
LION IS SEDATED, YET IT
REQUIRES A TEAM OF
NEARLY A DOZEN PEOPLE
JUST TO GET HER IN THE
RIGHT POSITION, AND LOOK
AT THE SIZE OF THIS
FLIPPER.
IT'S REALLY INCREDIBLE
TO BE ABLE TO LOOK AT
THE AMAZING DESIGN OF A
STELLER SEA LION
FLIPPER.
YOU CAN SEE THE ACTUAL
NAILS; AND, OF COURSE,
THEY SPREAD OUT, LOTS OF
MEMBRANE IN BETWEEN
THOSE DIGITS FOR
SWIMMING.
HE'S ACTUALLY GOING INTO
AN AREA CALLED THE
SINUS, WHICH IS
BASICALLY A CAVITY.
HE'S PUSHING IT THROUGH
THE SINUS AREA INTO A
VEIN THAT RUNS ALONG THE
SPINE.
BUT THIS TINY LITTLE
SAMPLE CAN OFFER AN
INFINITE AMOUNT OF
INFORMATION.
WE CAN L
STATE OF HER
STATE OF HER HEALTH, THE
NUTRIENT LEVEL OF THE
FOOD SHE'S EATING.
AND RIGHT NOW THE
CRITICAL INFORMATION
THAT WE CAN LEARN FROM
THIS IS, IS SHE A
CANDIDATE FOR PREGNANCY?
OR MAYBE SHE IS
PREGNANT.
ALL THIS STUFF IS VERY
IMPORTANT.
ONCE OUR EXAM IS
COMPLETE, THE SEA LIONGIS MG
AREA TO RECOVER BEFORE
HEADING BACK INTO THE
HABITAT AND REJOIN
WOODY.
BRETT: GOOD GIRL.
NICE JOB.
GO ON.
JEFF: OF COURSE, YOU CAN
SENSE THE ATTITUDE OVER
HERE.
THIS IS THE BREEDING
SEASON.
THIS GUY IS HARDWIRED
WITH ALL THAT
TESTOSTERONE AND ALL
THOSE HORMONES.
HE'S HUNGRY WITH THAT
NEED TO BREED, BECAUSE
WE'RE IN BETWEEN WHAT HE
LOVES, WHICH ARE THESE
FEMALE
WOODY'S SPECIAL LADIES
WILL BE RETURNING TO HIM
SOON; BUT FOR NOW, HE
MAY WANT TO TAKE A COLD
SHOWER.
WHEN WE RETURN, WOODY
CALMS DOWN AND GETS AN
EXAM OF HIS OWN.
OOH.
LISA: YEAH, THAT'S NICE,
ISN'T IT?
JEFF: OH, MY GOD.
AND WE LEARN WHETHER OR
NOT HE'S ABOUT TO BECOME
A NEW FATHER, COMING UP
NEXT ON OCEAN MYSTERIES.
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ ding! ]
LOSING YOUR CHEX MIX TOO EASILY?
TIME TO DEPLOY
THE BORING-POTATO CHIP
DECOY BAG.
THEN NO ONE WILL WANT TO STEAL
THE DELICIOUSNESS.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
ONLY CHEX MIX
IS A BAG OF INTERESTING.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
TO FLAT SCREENS...NS...
TWIZZLERIZE YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT EVERYDAY
WITH TWIZZLERS,
THE TWIST YOU CAN'T RESIST.
JEFF: OOH.
LISA: YEAH, THAT'S NICE,
ISN'T IT?
JEFF: OH, MY GOD.
WOODY SMELLS LIKE A
SMOKER.
SO, WE'RE BACK HERE AT
THE ALASKA SEALIFE
CENTER A FEW MONTHS
LATER, AND WOODY HAS
DRAMATICALLY CHANGED.
FIRST OF ALL, HE'S A
LITTLE BIT MORE MELLOW.
WHEN WE WERE HERE LAST
TIME, WOODY WAS REALLY
FOCUSED ON BREEDING.
HE WAS IN WHAT WE CALL
SEASON, WHICH MEANT HE
WAS VERY IRRITABLE.
HE'D ALSO PUT ON A LOT
OF WEIGHT, AND NOW HE'S
LOST A LOT OF WEIGHT.
HE'S LOST HOW MANY
POUNDS?
LISA: WELL, HE'S LOST
OVER 200 KILOS, SO OVER
400, ABOUT 450 POUNDS.
JEFF: YEAH, SO HE'S
LOST, HE'S LOST HUNDREDS
AND HUNDREDS OF POUNDS.
LISA: GOOD.
JEFF: OOH, AND NOW THAT
HE'S COMING OUT OF THE
BREEDING SEASON, THIS IS
A CHANCE FOR THE TEAM
HERE AT THE ALASKA
SEALIFE CENTER TO GIVE
HIM A GOOD HEALTHESESSMENT E
HE'S DOING GOOD.
LISA: GOOD JOB.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
[SEA LION GROWLING]
JEFF: TO BEGIN THE EXAM,
WOODY HAS BEEN TRAINED
TO MOVE INTO A SPECIAL
HOLDING AREA FOR HIS
SAFETY AND FOR OURS.
LISA: GOOD BOY!
JEFF: WATCH WHEN WOODY
SLIDES OVER.
IT'S LIKE A TIDAL WAVE.
LISA: GOOD -- CAGE.
THAT'S IT, BUDDY.
YOU'RE OKAY, YEAH, OPEN.
JEFF: SO, WHEN YOU HAVE
HIM OPEN HIS MOUTH LIKE
THAT, WHAT ARE YOU
LOOKING FOR?
LISA: ANYTHING, YOU
KNOW, ANYTHING THAT
COULD INDICATE AN INJURY
OR PROBLEMS WITH HIS
ORAL HYGIENE.
JEFF: WHAT'S WITH THAT
DARK TARTAR, LIKE, ON
HIS TEETH?
LISA: IT'S JUST, IT'S
VERY NORMAL IN SEA
LIONS.
IT'S PRETTY MUCH THEIR
SALIVA IS VERY DARK, AS
WELL, AND IT JUST STAINS
THEIR TEETH LIKE THAT.
JEFF: AND THIS IS AN
ANIMAL THAT CAN DIVE
VERY DEEP, IF IT NEEDS
TO.
LISA: YES, THEY'RE GOING
TO DIVE TO WHERE THEY
CAN FIND FOOD.
SO, IF THEY HAVE TO GO,
YOU KNOW, 100 FEET TO
200 FEET, THEY'RE GOING
TO GO WHERE THERE'S
FOOD.
THEY CAN SEE VERY WELL,
ACTUALLY.
SEE A LOT CAN
SEE A LOT BETTER THAN A
LOT OF PEOPLE GIVE THEM
CREDIT FOR.
BUT, I MEAN, YOU CAN SEE
HOW HE ROTATES THEM
AROUND AND LOOKS ALL
OVER.
JEFF: INCREDIBLY CUTE.
LISA: YEAH.
JEFF: AND SO WE KNOW ON
THE OUTSIDE HE'S DOING
GREAT.
ON THE INSIDE, HE'S
DOING GREAT.
THE GREAT MYSTERY IS
HA
SUCCESSFUL
SUCCESSFUL IN ACTUALLY
SIRING ANOTHER
GENERATION OF STELLER
SEA LION.
LISA: WE ACTUALLY DID
SEE COPULATION WITH THE
FEMALES.
SO, WE'RE OPTIMISTIC
THAT, YOU KNOW, WE MAY
HAVE A SUCCESSFUL
PREGNANCY, BUT WE WILL
NOT KNOW UNTIL
POTENTIALLY THE FIRST OF
THE YEAR.
JEFF: AND THAT'S A
MYSTERY WE HOPE TO SOLVE
IN THE NOT SO DISTANT
FUTURE.EEPING CLOSE
WE'LL BE KEEPING CLOSE
TABS ON WOODY IN THE
BREEDING PROGRAM HERE AT
THE ALASKA SEALIFE
CENTER.
THEIR RESEARCH IS
PROVIDING VITAL CLUES
INTO THE HEALTH OF THE
ALASKA STELLER SEA LION
POPULATION; AND WITH
CONTINUED WORK, THE
CONSERVATION MYSTERIES
OF THIS INCREDIBLE
SPECIES MAY ONE DAY BE
ANSWERED.
WELL, GUYS, THAT
ADVENTURE WAS ABSOLUTELY
UNFORGETTABLE.
TO BE OUT THERE IN THOSE
WATERS EXPLORING THE
MYSTERIOUS WORLD OF THE
STELLER SEA LIONS,
AMAZING.
SO, UNTIL WE MEET AGAIN,
I LOOK FORWARD TO SEEING
YOU ONLY ON OCEAN
MYSTERIES.
ANNOUNCER: CLOSED
CAPTIONING AND OTHER
PROMOTIONAL
CONSIDERATION PROVIDED
BY --
[ Female Announcer ]
What would you call
an ordinary breakfast pastry
that's been wrapped
in a flaky crust
stuffed with a gooey center
toasted up all golden brown
then given a delicious design?
A toaster strudel.
Pillsbury Toaster Strudel.
So Delicious...So Fun.
And when I get a cold I take
Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
JEFF: THE FIRST THING
THAT REALLY TOOK ME BY
SURPRISE WHEN I FIRST
SAW WOODY WAS HOW FAST
HE WAS.
I MEAN, THIS GUY WAS
WEIGHING 2,200 POUNDS,
AND HE FLIES OUT OF THE
WATER WITH A TSUNAMI OF
A WAKE IN HIS PATH, AND
IT'S JUST YOU WOULDN'T
HAVE A CHANCE.
LISA: NO, NO, HE IS --
JEFF: HIS BREATH IS LIKE
THE OPPOSITE OF FEBREZE.
AND SO WHAT DO WE DO
FIRST?
♪ MUSIC
- PERHAPS THE GREATEST
POWER COUPLE
OF ALL TIME
WAS ROME'S JULIUS CAESAR
AND EGYPT'S CLEOPATRA.
YOU'LL NEVER GUESS
WHAT THEY BUILT
ON THAT ISLAND HERE IN CYPRUS.
JOIN US ON BORN TO EXPLORE
AS WE TRY TO SOLVE
A LONG LOST SECRET