GRIEVING.
>> OH, I'M SO SORRY.
>>> AND THE PEOPLE ON THE FRONT
LINES HELPING THEM THROUGH.
"WORLD NEWS" BEGINS NOW.
>>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "WORLD NEWS"
WITH DAVID MUIR.
"TRAGEDY AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL."
>>> GOOD EVENING TONIGHT ON THIS
SATURDAY EVENING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, AGAIN THIS EVENING,
A SMALL TOWN IN A SMALL
NORTHEASTERN STATE, BUT THE
KILLING THAT HAPPENED HERE IS
BREAKING HEARTS FROM ONE CORNER
OF THIS VAST COUNTRY TO ANOTHER.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, 26 CHRISTMAS
TREES PLACED TODAY ON THE ROAD
TO THE SCHOOL, ONE FOR EVERY
VICTIM WHO DIED THERE.
IN TEXAS TODAY, HIGH SCHOOLERS
COMING TOGETHER TO SING IN
HONORED OF THOSE LOST.
IN OREGON, HUNDREDS GATHERING
FOR A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL.
IN WHAT HAS BECOME A NATIONAL
DAY OF GRIEF.
BUT OF COURSE THAT GRIEF FELT
NOWHERE MORE THAN RIGHT HERE IN
NEWTOWN, WHERE YOU'RE LOOKING AT
MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL, OUTSIDE OF
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
PEOPLE COMING TOGETHER THERE
THIS EVENING TO TRY TO
UNDERSTAND WHAT HAPPENED.
AND TRY TO COMFORT ONE ANOTHER.
OUR ABC NEWS TEAM HERE ON THE
GROUND COVERING IT ALL AND THIS
EVENING FOR THE FIRST TIME,
WE'RE LEARNING THE NAMES, SEEING
SOME OF THE FACES OF THE YOUNG
VICTIMS, ALL OF THEM FIRST
GRADERS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER REPORTING A
SHORT TIME AGO, MANY OF THEM
WERE SHOT AT CLOSE RANGE.
AND THIS EVENING, WE BEGIN WITH
A FATHER WHO LOST HIS LITTLE
GIRL.
AS YOU DRIVE THROUGH THIS
COMMUNITY, THE SIGNS OF GRIEF
ARE INESCAPABLE.
ON THE SIDE OF TO ROAD, WE LOVE
YOU SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
TONIGHT, WE'RE HEARING A
FATHER'S ANGUISH.
ROBBIE PARKER LOST HIS DAUGHTER
EMILIE.
SHE WAS 6.
>> TEACHING HER HOW TO READ,
DANCE AND THE SIMPLE JOYCE OF
LIFE.
HER LAUGH WAS INFECTIOUS.
>> Reporter: THIS EVENING A
HORRIFIC PORTRAIT OF JUST WHO
THE GUNMAN TARGETED.
IN ONE CLASSROOM, EVERY STUDENT
BUT ONE SHOT AND KILLED.
15 FIRST GRADERS IN THAT ONE
ROOM ALONE LOST IN INSTANT.
IN ANOTHER CLASSROOM FIVE OF THE
VICTIMS WERE CHILDREN.
WE KNOW THAT A LITTLE BOY WHO
HAD A TWIN SISTER, HE DIED.
HIS TWIN IN ANOTHER CLASSROOM
HIDING IN A BATHROOM WITH HER
TEACHER SURVIVED.
WE KNOW THAT THE SCHOOL
PRINCIPAL IS AMONG THE DEAD.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, MARRIED, A
MOTHER HERSELF.
NOW IT'S BELIEVED AS THE HORROR
UNFOLDED,
SHE MAY HAVE TURNED ON THE P.A.
SYSTEM SO THAT TEACHERS COULD BE
WARNED OF THE DANGER COMING.
MARY SHERLACH, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
A FAMILY IN A STATEMENT TONIGHT,
FE
SAID THAT SHE FELT SHE WAS DOING
GOD'S WORK.
ANOTHER TEACHER, VICTORIA SOTO,
27, HER FAMILY SAID THAT HER
BODY WAS FOUND IN A POSITION
SHIELDING SOME OF HER
FIRST-GRADE STUDENTS.
SHE HURRIED MOST OF THEM INTO A
CLOSET BEFORE THE GUNMAN
ARRIVED.
ANA MARQUEZ-GREENE WAS 7.
HER FATHER SAYING THEY'RE
STRUGGLING TO WORK THROUGH THIS
NIGHTMARE.
JESSE WHITE, -- LEWIS,
JUST 6, HIS FATHER WAS HEADED TO
SCHOOL TO WATCH HIM MAKE A
GINGERBREAD HOUSE.
>>> AND TONIGHT, FOR THE FIRST
TIME, WE HEAR FROM ONE OF THE
FIRST RESPONDERS, INSIDE THAT
FIRE HALL WHERE PARENTS WERE
TOLD TO PICK UP THEIR STUDENTS.
WE MET THIS COUNSELOR.
>> IT WAS LIKE WATCHING
SOMETHING THAT WASN'T REAL.
>> SHE WATCHED AS IT DAWNED ON
THE PARENTS.
TELLING ME THEY ALL KNEW THE
ANSWER IN THAT ROOM, AND YET
THEY KEPT WAITING.
>> BEING THERE, YOU KNOW, SEEING
THE INDIVIDUALS, WERE GOING INTO
THAT ROOM TO PICK UP THEIR KIDS.
AND THEN, SEEING THEM LEAVE SO
DISTRAUGHT, FROM A POSITION
YOU'RE TRYING TO HELP.
>> SHE SAID SOME NEEDED HUGS,
OTHER SIMPLY NEEDED SOMEONE TO
HOLD THEIR HAND.
>> I THINK JUST BEING THERE.
>> AND FOR YOU, WHAT WAS THE
HARDEST PART ABOUT LAST NIGHT
GOING HOME?
>> THAT I WAS GOING HOME.
I WAS GOING HOME TO A FAMILY AND
LOVED ONES.
AND TAKING THAT WITH ME, THOSE
FAMILIES WERE GOING HOME AND
SOMEBODY DIDN'T GO HOME WITH
THEM.
>> SO BRAVE TO SHARE HER STORY
WITH US TODAY.
>>> AND AS THIS LIST IS REVEALED
LATE TODAY OF THE VICTIMS.
SOME OF THE YOUNGEST NAMES AND
FACES.
WE HAVE LEARNED THAT A MEMBER OF
OUR OWN ABC FAMILY HAS LEARNED
THAT SHE'S LOST ONE OF HER OWN
RELATIVES.
WE'RE PRAYING FOR ALL OF THE
FAMILIES HERE TONIGHT.
>>> OF COURSE, WHAT'S HAPPENED
HERE DEFIES UNDERSTANDING.
THIS EVENING WE DO KNOW MORE
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED AS IT
UNFOLDED YESTERDAY, HOW THIS
GUNMAN BLAZED HIS WAY INTO THAT
SCHOOL AND ABC'S DAN HARRIS HAS
THE LATEST.
HE REPORTS NOW FROM ACROSS TOWN
AT THE FIRE STATION.
DAN, GOOD EVENING.
>> Reporter: DAVID, GOOD EVENING
TO YOU.
AS YOU KNOW WELL HAVING COVERED
THIS STORY SINCE THE MOMENT IT
BROKE, THERE HAVE BEEN SO MANY
CONTRADICTORY AND FALSE REPORTS
ABOUT EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED
INSIDE THAT SCHOOL, BUT TONIGHT,
FINALLY, WE'RE GET A FULLER
PICTURE OF THOSE FIRST, FRANTIC
MOMENTS.
AT AROUND 9:30 A.M., THE SUSPECT
ARMED TO THE TEETH AND COATED IN
KEVLAR FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL BY BREAKING THE GLASS
HERE AT THE FRONT ENTRANCE.
THE CHARDS STILL VISIBLE EVEN
FROM THE AIR TODAY.
>> UNITS RESPONDING TO SANDY
HOOK SCHOOL.
THE FRONT GLASS HAS BEEN BROKEN
OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
THEY'RE UNSURE WHY.
>> I CAN TELL YOU IT WAS
BELIEVED HE WAS NOT VOLUNTARILY
LET INTO THE SCHOOL AT ALL, THAT
HE FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: LANZA HAD JUST
DRIVEN THE FIVE MILES FROM THE
HOME OF HIS MOTHER, NANCY LANZA,
WHO HE HAD MURDERED.
ONCE INSIDE THE SCHOOL THE
RAMPAGE APPEARS TO HAVE BEGUN
HERE NEAR THE OFFICE AREA.
AMONG HIS FIRST VICTIMS,
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
AND THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST MARY
SHERLACH.
>> THE PRINCIPAL OF THE SCHOOL
WAS RUNNING TOWARD THE SHOOTER
IN ORDER TO PROTECT HER
STUDENTS, AS WAS THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
>> OKAY, ALL UNITS, THE
INDIVIDUAL THAT I HAVE ON THE
PHONE CONTINUING TO HEAR WHAT HE
BELIEVES TO BE GUNSHOTS.
>> Reporter: THEN LANZA
PROCEEDED DEEP INTO THE SCHOOL
WHERE HE KILLED THOSE
20 FIRST-GRADERS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYING
TODAY, THAT ALL OF THE CHILDREN
THAT HE SAW WERE HIT MULTIPLE
TIMES.
>> THIS PROBABLY IS THE WORST
THAT I HAVE SEEN OR THE WORST
THAT I KNOW OF ANY OF MY
COLLEAGUES HAVE SEEN.
>> Reporter: POLICE SAY THE
FIRST 911 CALL CAME WITHIN
MINUTES OF LANZA'S ARRIVAL.
>> ONE OF THE TEACHERS HELPED
PEOPLE GET OUT OF A WINDOW.
>> Reporter: FIVE TO TEN MINUTES
AFTER THAT, LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS WERE ON THE SCENE,
ENTERING THE SCHOOL, EVACUATING
THE STUDENTS AND STAFF AND
SEARCHING THE ROOMS UNTIL THEY
FOUND LANZA DEAD, APPARENTLY BY
HIS OWN HAND.
AND POLICE TOLD US TODAY THE
ENTIRE DISASTER WAS OVER WITHIN,
QUOTE, MERE MINUTES.
SO LITTLE TIME, DAVID, AND
INCALCULABLE DAMAGE.
>> ALL OF THOSE YOUNG LIVES LOST
SO QUICKLY.
DAN HARRIS HAS BEEN HERE SINCE
THE BEGINNING.
DAN, THANK YOU.
>>> OF COURSE THE QUESTION THAT
WE HAVE BEEN ASKING HERE, WHAT
WOULD DRIVE ANYONE TO TARGET
CHILDREN SO YOUNG, SO HELPLESS?
TONIGHT, WE'RE LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THE CONNECTION BETWEEN THE
GUNMAN, THE SCHOOL AND HIS
FAMILY.
HIS RELATIONSHIP WITH HIS
MOTHER.
HERE'S OUR CHIEF INVESTIGATIVE
CORRESPONDENT, BRIAN ROSS.
>> Reporter: THE CONNECTION
BETWEEN ADAM LANZA AND SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, GOES
BACK TO WHEN HE WAS A STUDENT.
HIS MOTHER, NANCY, WORKED AS A
TEACHER'S AIDE THERE.
ACCORDING TO ADAM'S AUNT.
>> I KNOW THAT SHE HAD ISSUES
WITH SCHOOL.
SHE EVENTUALLY WOUND UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT, IN WHAT CAPACITY, I'M
NOT CERTAIN.
IF IT WAS BEHAVIOR OR LEARNING
DISABILITIES.
>> Reporter: AMONG THOSE KILLED
ON FRIDAY, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, MARY SHERLACH, WHO
WORKED WITH TROUBLED STUDENTS
AT SANDY HOOK
SINCE 1994, WHICH WOULD INCLUDE
THE TIME THAT ADAM WAS A STUDENT
THERE.
>> AS FAR ANYTHING REALLY WRONG
WITH HIM, NOBODY EVER SAID
ANYTHING.
>> Reporter: AS A FULLER PICTURE
OF ADAM LANZA
BEGAN TO EMERGE, INCLUDING HIS
MEMBERSHIP IN THE HIGH SCHOOL
TECH CLUB, FORMER CLASSMATES
TOLD ABC NEWS THAT HE WAS A
SMART BUT SOCIALLY AWKWARD
STUDENT.
>> HE ALWAYS CARRIED A
BRIEFCASE.
>> Reporter: ANOTHER FORMER
CLASSMATE TOLD DAVID MUIR THAT
ADAM WAS A LONER.
>> ALMOST VERY TIMID.
VERY NERVOUS.
IF SOMEONE TALKED TO HIM HE
WOULD BE VERY SURPRISED.
>> Reporter: ADAM'S PARENTS,
PETER AND NANCY, WENT THROUGH AN
UNCONTESTED DIVORCE THREE YEARS
AGO, AND ADAM'S AUNT ALSO SAID
TODAY THAT NANCY HAD PURCHASED A
NUMBER OF GUNS BECAUSE SHE WAS
LIVING ALONE.
>> AND FOR SELF-DEFENSE, NO
OTHER REASON.
>> Reporter: POLICE SAY HIS
MOTHER'S HIGH-POWERED GUNS WERE
THE GUNS USED BY ADAM TO KILL
HIS MOTHER AND THOSE HE
MASSACRED AT THE SCHOOL.
IN A STATEMENT LATE TONIGHT,
LANZA'S FATHER PETER SAID, OUR
HEARTS GO OUT TO THOSE WHO LOST
LOVED ONES.
>>> THE DEVELOPMENTS COMING SO
QUICKLY.
BRIAN ROSS ALL ON THEM.
THANK YOU.
>>> AS YOU HEARD THERE, THE
SHOOTER USED A HIGH-POWERED
ASSAULT RIFLE TO KILL SO MANY.
ABC'S PIERRE THOMAS TO TELL US
HOW POWERFUL THESE WEAPONS ARE.
AND JUST HOW EASY THEY ARE TO
GET IN THIS COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: EXTREMELY POWERFUL.
THE ASSAULT RIFLE USED IN THIS
TYPE OF SHOOTING TYPICALLY
CARRIES ABOUT 30 ROUNDS OR SO.
BUT IT COULD CARRY UP TO 100
ROUNDS OR MORE.
IT CAN FIRE A BARRAGE OF BULLETS
IN SECONDS.
THAT'S WHY THOSE CHILDREN WERE
KILLED SO QUICKLY.
THEY'RE EASY TO BUY.
YOU CAN GO TO A LOCAL GUN STORE
AND BUY THESE GUNS WITHIN
MINUTES AFTER A BACKGROUND
CHECK.
>> I KNOW YOU'RE GOING TO STAY
ON THE SCENE AND REPORT IN THE
COMING DAYS.
PIERRE THOMAS WITH US HERE
TONIGHT, THANK YOU.
>>> TONIGHT THIS EVENING,
ANOTHER CHILD'S EYE VIEW, WE
HEAR FROM THE CHILDREN INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL, AND THIS EVENING
IT'S 9-YEAR-OLD ETHAN AND
9-YEAR-OLD BEN, TWINS BROTHERS,
WHO WERE IN DIFFERENT PARTS OF
THE SCHOOL WHEN THE SHOTS RANG
OUT.
>> EVERYONE THOUGHT THAT IT WAS
AN ANIMAL.
WHEN WE HEARD GUNSHOTS, WE ALL
HUDDLED INTO MY TEACHER'S
OFFICE.
EVERYBODY WAS QUIET.
WHEN THE POLICEMAN CAME IN TO
GET US, HE TOLD US TO CLOSE OUR
EYES AND DO THIS.
>> AND RUN.
>> AND JUST GO OUT.
>> WHEN I WENT TO THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT, WHEN I DIDN'T SEE
ETHAN, I WAS LIKE, OH, MY GOD,
WHAT HAPPENED TO MY BROTHER?
IS HE OKAY?
AND THEN, WHEN I FINALLY FOUND
ETHAN, I WAS VERY, VERY RELIEVED
AND WE STUCK TOGETHER.
>> AS YOU CAN SEE THERE FROM
THEIR STORY, THEY PUT THEIR
HANDS ON THEIR SHOULDERS.
THEIR TEACHERS AND SCHOOL STAFF
DID ALL OF THE RIGHT THINGS
HERE.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS
RATED AS ONE OF THE BEST SCHOOLS
IN THE COUNTRY.
IT LEADS TO THE QUESTION IF IT
CAN HAPPEN HERE, WHAT CAN IT BE
DONE TO STOP IT FROM HAPPENING
AT THIS SCHOOL AND EVERY OTHER
SCHOOL ACROSS THE COUNTRY?
>> Reporter: THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL
DISTRICT DECIDED TO SPEND
10 TIMES MORE ON SECURITY
TRAINING FOR STAFF THIS YEAR
ACCORDING TO BUDGET DOCUMENTS.
MEASURES THAT DID NOT PREVENT AN
UNTHINKABLE ATTACK, BUT TRAINING
THAT MAY HAVE LIMITED THE
DAMAGE.
>> WE PRACTICED IT, AND THEY
KNEW WHAT TO DO, AND YOU JUST
THINK ABOUT PROTECTING THE KIDS,
AND JUST DOING THE RIGHT THING.
>> Reporter: CLERK
MARY ANN JACOB SAYS SHE HAD BEEN
DRILLED TO SEND THE KIDS IN THE
LIBRARY TO A BACK CLOSET BETWEEN
BOOKSHELVES, AN EMERGENCY PLAN
DEVELOPED IN ADVANCE.
>> YOU HAVE TO HAVE A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF FIRE DRILLS A YEAR,
AND A CERTAIN AMOUNT OF
EVACUATION DRILLS, AND A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF LOCKDOWN DRILLS, SO
THE KIDS KNOW THE ROUTINE, AND
THE TEACHERS KNOW THE ROUTINE,
AND EVERYONE HAS A SPOT IN THE
ROOM WHERE THEY ARE SUPPOSED TO
GO.
>> Reporter: NEW TO THE PLAN
THIS YEAR AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY A LETTER TO PARENTS
TELLING THEM NO MORE OPEN
CAMPUS, EVEN FOR THEM.
INSTALLATION OF A SECURITY
CAMERA ABOVE THE FRONT ENTRY
DOOR.
PICTURE I.D. IF YOU ARE NOT
RECOGNIZED.
SECURITY MEASURES RECOMMENDED
FOR ALL SCHOOLS AND USED
NATIONWIDE AS THE GOLD STANDARD
IN SAFETY.
>> SOUNDS AS THOUGH THE SCHOOL
HAD SECURITY MEASURES AT THE
DOOR, THAT THEY HAD STAFF WHO WE
WERE TRAINED WITH LOCK-DOWN
PROCEDURES, AND IN SOME CASES,
STAFF WHO STEPPED IN FRONT OF A
BULLET PERHAPS TO PROTECT A
CHILD'S LIFE.
WE CAN DO OUR BEST TO PREVENT
INCIDENTS, WE HAVE TO DO OUR
BEST TO BE PREPARED TO MANAGE
THOSE INCIDENTS.
UNFORTUNATELY, TRAGEDIES STILL
OCCUR.
>> SAFETY EXPERTS TELL US THAT
THIS IS NOT THE WEEK FOR PARENTS
TO BE FRIGHTENED FOR SENDING
THEIR KIDS BACK TO SCHOOL.
EVERY SCHOOL IN THE COUNTRY WILL
BE LOOKING AT THEIR SECURITY
PLANS THIS WEEK.
IT'S THE FUTURE THEY NEED TO
WORRY ABOUT.
DAVID?
>> THIS IS THE TIME WHEN
STUDENTS, THOSE LITTLE CHILDREN
JUST COUNT DOWN TO CHRISTMAS.
JIM AVILA TONIGHT ON THE SAFETY
ISSUE.
JIM, THANK YOU.
>>> THERE'S STILL MUCH MORE
AHEAD ON "WORLD NEWS" --
IN THE MIDST OF PROFOUND SADNESS
AND GRIEF,
THE REMARKABLE STORY BEHIND AN
AMAZING PRINCIPAL WE TOLD YOU
ABOUT EARLIER IN THE BROADCAST.
IT WAS JUST NOT HER SIGNAL TO
OTHER TEACHERS, SHE LEFT
A MESSAGE
TO THIS COMMUNITY AS A WHOLE.
HER EXTRAORDINARY STORY AFTER
THIS BREAK TONIGHT.
CHECK OUT
MY NEW TREADMILL APP.
PRETTY SWEET, HUH?
CUTE.
BUT DON'T YOU HAVE ANY APPS
ON YOUR PHONE
THAT CAN MAKE YOUR LIFE
EASIER?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
AT Quicken Loans, WE'LL PROVIDE
YOU WITH MYQL MOBILE.
THIS AMAZINGLY USEFUL APP
ALLOWS YOU
TO TAKE PICTURES
OF YOUR MORTGAGE DOCUMENTS
USING AN iPhone
OR Android SMART PHONE...
SO YOU CAN EASILY
SEND THEM TO US.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS Engineered to Amaze.
OOH, LA-LA!
BUT I'M STILL STUBBED UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus Liquid Gels
SPEEDS RELIEF
TO YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A DECONGESTANT
FOR YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
I'VE BEEN FORTUNATE TO WIN
ON GOLF'S BIGGEST STAGES.
BUT WHEN JOINT PAIN
AND STIFFNESS
FROM PSORIATIC ARTHRITIS HIT,
EVEN THE SMALLEST THINGS
BECAME DIFFICULT.
I FINALLY UNDERSTOOD WHAT
SERIOUS JOINT PAIN IS LIKE.
I TALKED TO MY RHEUMATOLOGIST
AND HE PRESCRIBED Enbrel.
Enbrel CAN HELP RELIEVE
PAIN, STIFFNESS,
AND STOP JOINT DAMAGE.
BECAUSE Enbrel, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS,
SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS
INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS,
LYMPHOMA, OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING Enbrel,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START Enbrel IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON Enbrel, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING, OR PALENESS.
[ Phil ]
GET BACK TO THE THINGS
THAT MATTER MOST.
ASK YOUR RHEUMATOLOGIST
IF Enbrel IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
[ Doctor ]
Enbrel, THE NUMBER ONE
BIOLOG MEDICINE
PRESCRIBED BY RHEUMATOLOGISTS.
>>> A COMMUNITY IN MOURNING
TONIGHT.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT AN IMAGE OF
SANDY HOOK, CONNECTICUT, THE
FIREFIGHTERS HERE HANGING BLACK
BUNTING FROM THEIR FIRE TRUCKS
TODAY.
THE TOWN IN SHOCK AFTER
YESTERDAY'S ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
MAASACRE.
>>> WE WELCOME YOU BACK NOW TO
THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF "WORLD
NEWS."
THIS EVENING AS THIS COMMUNITY
COMES TO GRIP WITH AN
UNFATHOMABLE TRAGEDY WE'RE
LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE HEROES.
IN THE LINE OF FIRE.
IN THE HEAT OF VIOLENCE SAVED SO
MANY OF THOSE CHILDREN.
HERE'S ABC'S AMY ROBACH TONIGHT.
>> Reporter: FOR THE LAST TWO
YEARS, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, INFUSED
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WITH HER OWN SPECIAL MAGIC.
A MODERN PRINCIPAL.
SHE TWEET AND ORGANIZED HAPPY
HOURS FOR THE TEACHERS TO SHARE
THE BEST iPAD APPS FOR THE
CLASSROOMS.
THIS A PHOTO SHE SHARED ON
TWITTER.
ON THE FIRST DAY OF SCHOOL --
WELCOMING OUR KINDERS THIS
MORNING.
74 NEW OPPORTUNITIES TO INSPIRE
LIFE LONG LEARNING.
SHE INTRODUCED THIS SANDY HOOK
BOOK FAIRY, KEEPING BOOK IN OUR
HEARTS AND ON OUR MINDS, SHE
TWEETED.
AND WITH HER LOVE OF LEARNING,
SHE LED A GROUP OF REMARKABLE
TEACHERS WHO WERE THERE FOR
THEIR STUDENTS,
TEACHERS LIKE KAITLIN ROIG, HOW
SHE QUICKLY HID ALL OF HER FIRST
GRADE STUDENTS IN A BATHROOM.
>> I NEED YOU TO KNOW THAT I
LOVE YOU ALL VERY MUCH AND THAT
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY, BECAUSE I
THOUGHT THAT WAS GOING TO BE THE
LAST THING THEY EVER HEARD, I
THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
>> Reporter: SHE TAUGHT HER
TEACHERS TO DO IN A EMERGENCY.
THAT TRAINING BROUGHT THIRD
GRADER HOPE SAFELY TO HER MOTHER
WHEN SHOTS RANG UP, HER PREGNANT
TEACHER SPRANG INTO ACTION.
>> SHE LOCKED THE DOOR.
AND PUT -- TAPED A PIECE OF
WHITE PAPER OVER THE DOOR.
THEN, SHE TOLD US TO GO IN THE
CORNER, THERE'S 19 PEOPLE IN OUR
CLASS AND SHE SAVED ALL OF US.
>> SHE SAVED ALL OF US, FROM
THAT LITTLE GIRL.
AMY ROBACH HERE WITH US TONIGHT.
>> WE LEARNED SOMETHING ELSE
ABOUT THAT PRINCIPAL.
>> SHE GOT ON THAT LOUD SPEAKER
EACH AND EVERY DAY, BE KIND TO
OTHERS THAT'S WHAT MATTERS MOST.
THOSE WORDS THAT SHE TRULY LIVED
BY BY ALL ACCOUNTS.
>> SHE LEFT SUCH GIFT FOR THIS
COMMUNITY.
GREAT REPORTING HERE FROM THE
BEGINNING.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK ON THE
BROADCAST HERE TONIGHT -- MUCH
MORE NEWS TO COVER, INCLUDING
THAT HEALTH SCARE FOR SECRETARY
OF STATE HILLARY CLINTON.
WE'RE BACK IN A MOMENT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
[ sniffs ] I TOOK DAYQUIL
BUT MY NOSE IS STILL RUNNY.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
DAYQUIL DOESN'T TREAT THAT.
REALLY?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus
FIGHTS YOUR WORST
COLD SYMPTOMS,
PLUS IT RELIEVES
YOUR RUNNY NOSE.
[ breathes deeply ]
AWESOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
YES, IT IS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
but with ADVAIR,
I'm breathing better.
So now I can be in
the scene.
ADVAIR is
clinically proven to help
significantly improve
lung function.
Unlike most COPD medications,
ADVAIR contains both an
anti-inflammatory
and a
long-acting bronchodilator
working together to help improve
your lung function all day.
ADVAIR won't
replace fast-acting inhalers
for sudden symptoms
and should not be used more
than twice a day.
People with
COPD taking ADVAIR
may have a higher chance
of pneumonia.
ADVAIR may increase your
risk of osteoporosis
and some eye problems.
Tell your doctor
if you have a heart condition
or high blood pressure before
taking ADVAIR.
If you're still
having difficulty breathing,
ask your doctor if including
ADVAIR could help
improve your lung function.
Get your
first full
prescription
free
and save
on refills
at
ADVAIRcopd.com.
THEN I READ AN ARTICLE
ABOUT A STUDY THAT LOOKED
AT THE LONG TERM HEALTH BENEFITS
OF TAKING MULTIVITAMINS.
THEY USED CENTRUM SILVER
FOR THE STUDY...
SO I GUESS MY WIFE WAS RIGHT.
[ Male Announcer ] CENTRUM.
ALWAYS YOUR MOST COMPLETE.
ANYONE HAVE OCCASIONAL
CONSTIPATION,
DIARRHEA, GAS, BLOATING?
YEAH.
ONE Phillips' Colon Health
PROBIOTIC CAP EACH DAY
HELPS DEFEND
AGAINST THESE DIGESTIVE ISSUES
WITH THREE STRAINS
OF GOOD BACTERIA.
APPROVED!
[ Female Announcer ]
LIVE THE REGULAR LIFE.
Phillips'.
>>> WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A MOMENT
NOW TO TAKE A TURN TO THE OTHER
NEWS MAKING HEADLINES TONIGHT.
IT INVOLVES A HEALTH SCARE FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON, A SCARE THAT LED TO A
FALL AND A CONCUSSION.
SO, WE WANT TO BRING IN ABC'S
DAVID KERLEY IN WASHINGTON,
FOLLOWING THIS,
HOW IS MRS. CLINTON TONIGHT?
>> WE KNOW THAT SHE CAME BACK
FROM HER LAST TRIP NINE DAYS AGO
WITH A STOMACH BUG, EARLIER IN
THE WEEK, SHE BECAME DEHYDRATED,
FAINTED, HAVE A CONCUSSION,
SHE DID NOT GO TO THE HOSPITAL.
DOCTORS ARE MONITORING HER.
THIS MEANS THAT SHE'LL NOT
TESTIFY THIS WEEK ABOUT THE
ATTACK ON THE MISSION IN
BENGHAZI AND THE KILLING OF OUR
AMBASSADOR THERE, THE REPUBLICAN
CHAIR OF THE HOUSE COMMITTEE NOT
HAPPY ABOUT THAT.
BUT ABC'S JAKE TAPPER HAS
LEARNED THAT JOHN KERRY WILL BE
TAPPED AS THE REPLACEMENT.
FOR HILLARY CLINTON.
SO, DAVID,
THERE'S A CHANCE SHE'LL NEVER
TESTIFY WHAT HAPPENED IN
BENGHAZI.
DAVID?
>> TWO DEVELOPMENTS TONIGHT,
HILLARY CLINTON RECOVERING FROM
A FALL AND A POSSIBLE SECRETARY
OF STATE KERRY IN OUR FUTURE.
DAVID KERLEY, THANK YOU TONIGHT.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK HERE ON
THE BROADCAST FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THE PROFOUND
QUESTION, HOW DOES THIS
COMMUNITY CELEBRATE CHRISTMAS?
LOOK, IF YOU HAVE COPD LIKE ME,
YOU KNOW IT CAN BE HARD TO
BREATHE, AND HOW THAT FEELS.
COPD INCLUDES CHRONIC
BRONCHITIS AND EMPHYSEMA.
SPIRIVA HELPS CONTROL
MY COPD SYMPTOMS
BY KEEPING MY AIRWAYS
OPEN FOR 24 HOURS.
PLUS, IT REDUCES COPD FLARE-UPS.
SPIRIVA IS THE ONLY ONCE-DAILY
INHALED COPD MAINTENANCE
TREATMENT THAT DOES BOTH.
SPIRIVA HANDIHALER TIOTROPIUM
BROMIDE INHALATION POWDER
DOES NOT REPLACE FAST-ACTING
INHALERS FOR SUDDEN SYMPTOMS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
KIDNEY PROBLEMS, GLAUCOMA,
TROUBLE URINATING, OR
AN ENLARGED PROSTATE.
THESE MAY WORSEN WITH SPIRIVA.
DISCUSS ALL MEDICINES
YOU TAKE, EVEN EYE DROPS.
STOP TAKING SPIRIVA AND SEEK
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
IF YOUR BREATHING
SUDDENLY WORSENS,
YOUR THROAT OR TONGUE
SWELLS, YOU GET HIVES,
VISION CHANGES OR EYE PAIN,
OR PROBLEMS PASSING URINE.
OTHER SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
DRY MOUTH AND CONSTIPATION.
NOTHING CAN REVERSE COPD.
SPIRIVA HELPS ME BREATHE BETTER.
(BLOWING SOUND)
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT SPIRIVA.
get Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
And the only one I use
to relieve my cold symptoms
without raising my blood
pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
>>> YOU'RE LOOKING TONIGHT AT AN
IMAGE THAT SUMS UP THE VOICE OF
AN ENTIRE COMMUNITY IN MOURNING.
BUT RESOLVING TO STAY STRONG,
SANDY HOOK TELLING THE WORLD
"OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN, OUR
SPIRITS ARE STRONG."
>>> AND FINALLY, YOU CAN SEE THE
IMAGE OF THE CHURCH BEHIND ME,
JUST ONE OF THE MANY CHURCHES IN
THIS COMMUNITY.
IT'S OPENED ITS DOOR, ALLOWING
PEOPLE TO COME IN,
THERE'S A NOT A SERVICE TAKING
PLACE, THEY SIMPLY SAID,
COME PRAY, COME ASK QUESTIONS,
ONE OF THE MAIN QUESTIONS
THEY'RE GRAPPLING WITH, AFTER A
TRAGEDY OF THIS SCOPE, OF THIS
NATURE, IS HOW DOES A COMMUNITY
THEN CELEBRATE CHRISTMAS?
AS YOU DRIVE THROUGH THIS
COMMUNITY, THEY'RE EVERYWHERE,
THE SIGNS, HUG A TEACHER, LOVE
WILL GET US THROUGH, THIS BENCH
FULL OF ROSES.
THE SMALL CHURCH ON MAIN STREET,
A LINE OF NEIGHBORS INSIDE THE
FRONT DOORS TALKING WITH THE
PASTOR.
BUT WHAT WE ALSO NOTICED TODAY
WERE THE MINIVANS, THE STATION
WAGONS, CARRYING HOME CHRISTMAS
TREES, FAMILIES DETERMINED TO
KEEP THIS TRAGEDY FROM STEALING
THE HOLIDAY, TOO.
MORE THAN 40 YEARS YOU HAVE BEEN
SELLING CHRISTMAS TREES HERE.
>> YES.
>> SHE SAID THAT THIS IS THE
TOUGHEST.
SHE GOT A CALL FROM THE FATHER
ON THE WAY TO TREE FARM TODAY.
>> BRING THE CHILD OUT.
I WANT TO PICK A TREE WITH HER.
IT WILL BE A BITTERSWEET
CHRISTMAS, I THINK, FOR MANY,
MANY PEOPLE.
>> AND FOR YOU, I CAN TELL.
INSIDE THE PHOTOS OF THE
FAMILIES WHO COME EVERY YEAR,
AROUND OUTSIDE, RIGHT THERE AT
HER FARM,
THE COUNSELOR THE FIRST
RESPONDER WE MET, THAT HELP THE
PARENTS AT THAT FIREHOUSE,
SHE'S TRYING TO KEEP HER
CHRISTMAS.
YOU GOT THE TREE ON THE TRUCK?
>> YES.
>> THERE THEY ARE.
>> OH, LOOK AT THIS GUY.
>> THE TREE ON THE ROOF.
THEIR FOUR DOGS INSIDE.
THEIR FAMILY DETERMINED TO KEEP
CHRISTMAS.
AND I GIVE GOT TO TELL YOU,
AFTER TALKING TO SO MANY
FAMILIES IN THIS TOWN,
THEY'RE DETERMINED TO MOVE
FORWARD AND MARK CHRISTMAS.
IT WILL BE DIFFICULT.
BUT THEY'RE NOT GOING TO LET
THIS GUNMAN STEAL THAT FROM THEM
>>> THAT'S THE BROADCAST.
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA" AND "THIS
WEEK" FIRST THING IN THE
MORNING.
GOOD NIGHT.
>> Ama: WE'RE LEARNING MORE
ABOUT THE SHOOTING THAT TOOK THE
LIVES OF 27 PEOPLE, AND NOW THE
FATHER OF THE SHOOTER SPEAKS
OUT.
>>> THE BAY AREA IN MOURNING
ALONG WITH THE NATION.
WE'RE LIVE AT ONE OF THE MANY
VIGILS TAKING PLACE TONIGHT.
>>> YOU'RE LOOKING AT LIVE
DOPPLER 7HD AS THE STORM MOVES
THROUGH.
IN THE FORECAST IS COMING UP.
ABC-7 NEWS AT 6:00 STARTS NOW.
>>> SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
>> Ama: A FATHER'S GRIEF AFTER
YESTERDAY'S TRAGEDY AS WE LEARN
THE NAMES OF THE CHILDREN AND
TEACHERS KILLED.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
YOUNG INNOCENT VICTIMS OF THE
MASSACRE IN CONNECTICUT.
THESE ARE JUST SOME OF THE EYE
COPPIC IMAGES FROM YESTERDAY'S
TRAGEDY, AND NOW WE'RE HEARING
ALL THE YOUNG CHILDREN KILLED
WERE ALL FIRST GRADERS, JUST
FIVE AND SIX YEARSEEST -- YEARS
OLD.
REPORTER: ANGUISHED RESIDENTS
STRUGGLED TO COPE WITH THE LOSS
OF SO MANY TO EVIL.
THE GOVERNOR PAID TRIBUTE TO THE
VICTIMS.
>> THOSE EDUCATORS AND THOSE
INNOCENT LITTLE BOYS AND GIRLS
WERE TAKEN FROM THEIR FAMILIES
FAR TOO SOON.
REPORTER: BUT IT SEEMS ALMOST
NOWHERE ARE EMOTIONS RUNNING
STRONGER THAN RIGHT HERE AS A
MAKESHIFT MEMORIAL THAT SPRUNG
UP JUST 500 YARDS FROM THE
SCHOOL.
PEOPLE ARE COMING HERE TO LIGHT
CANDLES AND TO REMEMBER.
REPORTER: ALL DAY LONG PEOPLE
CAME CARRYING FLOWERS AND
HONORING THE 20 CHILDREN AND SIX
ADULTS WHO DIED IN