"MOMMY, I'M OKAY, BUT ALL MY
FRIENDS ARE DEAD."
>> AND WE ARE NOW SEEING THE
FACES OF THE YOUNG VICTIMS AS
ONE FATHER STEPS FORWARD.
>> MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO GIVE
HER LOVE AND SUPPORT TO ALL
THOSE VICTIMS BECAUSE THAT'S THE
TYPE OF PERSON SHE IS.
>> Announcer: THIS IS A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA: TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL," LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>>> AND GOOD MORNING.
I'M DAN HARRIS REPORTING FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
BEHIND ME THE SANDY HOOK
VOLUNTEER FIRE DEPARTMENT WHERE
THEY TOOK THOSE CHILDREN RIGHT
AFTER THE MASSACRE FRIDAY
MORNING.
BIANNA GOLODRYGA IS BACK IN NEW
YORK CITY AT OUR ABC NEWS
HEADQUARTERS.
MUCH MORE COMING UP FROM HER.
WITH ME IS LARA SPENCER AND
AMY ROBACH.
>> IT IS HARD TO IMAGINE.
THERE IS EVEN MORE SADNESS AS WE
ARE STARTING TO SEE THE FACES.
WE KNEW THE NAMES LAST NIGHT,
BUT WE SEE THE FACES OF THOSE
YOUNG VICTIMS, STILL VERY YOUNG
VICTIMS.
IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE HOW QUICKLY
THEIR LIVES WERE TAKEN AWAY AND
HOW MUCH THEY STILL HAD TO LIVE.
>> WE ALSO WILL HEAR THE STORY
OF ONE OF THOSE LITTLE
SURVIVORS.
>> YEAH.
>> AND WE'RE GOING TO TALK ABOUT
RANDOM ACTS OF KINDNESS, HOW
THIS COMMUNITY AND STRANGERS
HAVE COME TOGETHER IN A WAY THAT
IS TRULY REMARKABLE IN AN
ATTEMPT TO BEGIN THE HEALING.
>> WE'LL HAVE INCREDIBLE
REPORTING COMING UP FROM BOTH OF
YOU.
WE'LL GET TO THAT IN JUST A
MINUTE.
>>> LET'S START WITH A LOOK AT
THE LATEST NEWS FROM NEWTOWN.
AS WE SAID, THE PRESIDENT WILL
BE VISITING LATER TODAY.
HE WILL BE ARRIVING HERE TO MEET
WITH THE VICTIMS AND ALSO THANK
THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
HE'LL BE SPEAKING AT AN
INTERFAITH VIGIL.
HERE IS A TELLING DETAIL.
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME IN FOUR
YEARS THAT THIS PRESIDENT HAS
PAID A VISIT AFTER A MASS
SHOOTING.
INCREDIBLE.
>>> ALSO THIS MORNING, POLICE
HAVE NOW RELEASED THE LIST OF
VICTIMS.
LOOK CLOSELY AT THE DATES OF
BIRTH, AND YOU WILL SEE THE
CHILDREN WERE ALL BORN BETWEEN
2005 AND 2006.
ONE OF THEM, A LITTLE GIRL BY
THE NAME OF JOSEPHINE GAY, JUST
HAD HER SEVENTH BIRTHDAY ON
TUESDAY.
>>> ONE OF OUR COLLEAGUES, QUITE
APTLY CALLED THIS MAYBE THE
SADDEST PIECE OF PAPER EVER
PRINTED.
THE FAMILIES ARE NOW RELEASING
PICTURES OF THE CHILDREN THEY
LOST.
AS A WRITER FOR THE ASSOCIATED
PRESS PUT IT, "THESE ARE VICTIMS
WHO STILL HAD THEIR BABY TEETH."
OVERNIGHT PETER LANZA, THE
FATHER OF ADAM LANZA, RELEASED
HIS FIRST PUBLIC STATEMENT
SAYING WE ARE IN A STATE OF
DISBELIEF AND TRYING TO FIND
WHATEVER ANSWERS WE CAN.
WE TOO ARE ASKING WHY."
SOURCES SAY NO NOTE OR MANIFESTO
FROM THE GUNMAN HAS BEEN FOUND
AT THIS POINT, AND THIS MORNING
AMERICANS OF ALL STRIPES ARE
HONORING THE VICTIMS.
TODAY, EVERY SINGLE NFL TEAM
WILL OBSERVE A MOMENT OF SILENCE
BEFORE THE GAMES.
THE GIANTS AND PATRIOTS WILL
PLAY WITH SPECIAL DECALS ON
THEIR HELMET.
AND LAST NIGHT ON AN EMOTIONAL
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE," THE
EMOTIONAL OPENING TO THE SHOW
WITH A CHILDREN'S CHOIR SINGING
"SILENT NIGHT."
ALSO THIS MORNING FOR THE FIRST
TIME WE'RE HEARING HOW ONE
LITTLE GIRL SURVIVED THE
MASSACRE, AND MY COLLEAGUE LARA
IS BACK WITH MORE ON THAT.
>> WE HAVE HEARD THE STORY OF
JUST ONE CLASS JUST DECIMATED.
THERE WAS ONE SMALL SURVIVOR,
AND LAST NIGHT I SPOKE TO THE
PERSON COUNSELING HER FAMILY.
THIS IS A STORY, A HARROWING
STORY OF HOW A 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL
LIVED BY PLAYING DEAD.
YOU HAVE ONE PARISHIONER WHO WAS
RIGHT THERE, A LITTLE GIRL, A
FIRST GRADER.
>> YEAH, SHE WAS THE FIRST
STUDENT WHO RAN OUT OF THE SANDY
HOOK SCHOOL, 6 1/2 YEARS OLD.
SHE RAN OUT OF THE SCHOOL
BUILDING COVERED IN BLOOD FROM
HEAD TO TOE, AND THE FIRST WORDS
SHE SAID TO HER MOM WHEN SHE GOT
OUTSIDE WAS, "MOMMY, I'M OKAY,
BUT ALL MY FRIENDS ARE DEAD."
SOMEHOW IN THAT MOMENT BY GOD'S
GRACE WAS ABLE TO ACT AS IF SHE
WAS ALREADY DECEASED.
>> WAS SHE THE ONLY CHILD IN
THAT CLASS THAT SURVIVED?
>> YEAH, OF THOSE WHO WERE LEFT
IN THE CLASSROOM OF FIRST
GRADERS, SHE WAS THE LONE
SURVIVOR.
>> WHAT DID SHE TELL HER MOM?
WHAT DID SHE SEE IN THERE?
>> WELL, SHE SAW SOMEONE WHO SHE
FELT WAS ANGRY AND SOMEBODY WHO
SHE FELT WAS VERY MAD.
>> HOW AT 6 1/2 YEARS OLD CAN
YOU BE THAT SMART, THAT BRAVE?
>> HMM, I THINK IT'S IMPOSSIBLE
OUTSIDE OF DIVINE INTERVENTION.
SHE HAS WISDOM BEYOND HER YEARS.
>> HOW ARE THE MOM AND DAD
DOING?
>> I THINK AS WELL AS YOU CAN
EXPECT THEM TO DO.
>> AND THEY MUST BE RELIEVED TO
HAVE THEIR CHILD BUT ON THE
OTHER HAND SO MANY FEELINGS.
>> YES, THE MOM TOLD ME -- AND I
FELT THIS WAS VERY INSIGHTFUL --
THAT SHE WAS SUFFERING FROM WHAT
CALLED SURVIVORS GUILT.
BECAUSE SO MANY OF THEIR FRIENDS
NO LONGER HAVE THEIR CHILDREN,
BUT SHE HAS HERS.
>> SHE SURVIVED BECAUSE SHE HAD
WISDOM BEYOND HER YEARS.
JUST AN INCREDIBLE STORY OF
SURVIVAL AND ALL BY A 6-YEAR-OLD
GIRL.
DAN?
>> AS YOU SAID AN INCREDIBLE
STORY AND HER FAMILY WITH
SURVIVOR'S GUILT, NO DOUBT
DEALING WITH THAT FOR AWHILE.
THANK YOU FOR THAT.
LARA, MUCH MORE FROM YOU LATER
IN THE BROADCAST.
>> SCHOOL IS GOING TO RESUME
HERE IN THIS SHATTERED TOWN ON
TUESDAY.
AND A FEW MOMENTS AGO I SPOKE
WITH BILL HART, A SPOKESPERSON
FOR THE NEWTOWN BOARD OF
EDUCATION.
THE PLAN IS TO RE-OPEN THE
SCHOOLS ON TUESDAY.
WHY IS IT SO IMPORTANT TO GET
THINGS MOVING AGAIN.
>> WELL, ALL THE MENTAL HEALTH
EXPERTS WE TALKED TO, AND THE
STATE HAS DONE A WONDERFUL JOB
OF BRINGING IN SOME HELP, TELL
US IT'S THE BEST THING TO DO TO
GET BACK TO NORMAL OPERATIONS AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
IT'S BEST FOR THE CHILDREN AND
FOR THE STAFF AND FOR THE
COMMUNITY.
>> WHAT DO YOU DO WITH THE
STUDENTS WHO ARE ENROLLED AT
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
>> WELL, THIS SCHOOL HERE, WE'RE
CLEARLY NOT GOING TO BE INTO
THIS BUILDING ANY TIME IN THE
FORESEEABLE FUTURE.
WE'RE VERY CLOSE TO A PLAN TO
MOVE THE COMMUNITY TO -- THE
SCHOOL COMMUNITY TO ANOTHER
LOCATION.
THOSE DETAILS WILL PROBABLY COME
OUT TODAY.
I'M NOT REALLY PREPARED TO
REALLY SAY BUT WE KNOW IT'LL
WORK.
>> I KNOW IT'S EARLY.
DO YOU THINK YOU CAN EVER
RE-OPEN THIS SCHOOL AND WHAT
WOULD YOU SAY TO PARENTS WHO SAY
I NEVER WANT TO SEND MY CHILD --
>> I WOULD PROBABLY FEEL VERY
MUCH THE SAME WAY.
I MEAN, MY THREE DAUGHTERS WENT
TO THIS SCHOOL, AND WE HAVE MANY
MEMORIES THERE.
I THINK TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO WITH THAT
IS A LONG PROCESS, AND, YOU
KNOW, WE'RE NOT ANYWHERE
PREPARED TO MAKE THOSE DECISIONS
NOW.
>> YOU TALKED ABOUT THE
IMPORTANCE OF RE-ESTABLISHING
ROUTINES, BUT IT'S GOING TO BE
HARD TO DO IN THIS ATMOSPHERE.
WHAT KIND OF SPECIAL ALLOWANCES
WILL YOU TAKE FOR THE STAFF AND
FOR THE STUDENTS WHO ARE REALLY
HURTING AS YOU TRY TO
REESTABLISH ROUTINES?
>> WELL, WE BROUGHT IN HEALTH
CARE PROFESSIONALS, MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS FROM ALL
OVER THE STATE AND HAVE SPECIAL
TRAINING FOR PEOPLE AND KNOW
SOME OF THE TEACHERS MIGHT NOT
BE PREPARED TO COME BACK AND
WE WILL BE PREPARED WITH
SUBSTITUTES AND WE'VE GOT
COUNSELING FOR ALL THE PEOPLE.
WE'RE PREPARED TO DO WHATEVER WE
HAVE TO DO TO HELP ALL OF OUR
COMMUNITY.
>> WE KEEP HEARING THESE STORIES
OF THE VALOR DISPLAYED BY THE
PRINCIPAL AT THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND ALSO SOME OF THE
TEACHERS.
WHAT ARE YOUR THOUGHTS ON THAT?
>> WELL, I THINK WE HAD --
THAT'S REALLY THE BIG STORY
HERE.
THERE'S SOME INCREDIBLE HEROES,
AND I THINK WHAT THEY DID MOVING
TO MOVE ALL THE OTHER CHILDREN
TO SAFE LOCATIONS AND GOING
THROUGH OUR LOCKDOWN PROCESS,
THAT SAVED COUNTLESS MORE LIVES.
THOSE TEACHERS, THE STAFF THAT
WERE THERE, THE FIRST RESPONDERS
WHO CAME IN, THEY'RE THE PEOPLE
WHO ARE THE REAL HEROES.
>> BILL HART, VERY DIFFICULT JOB
AND I WISH YOU THE BEST.
>> THANK YOU, DAN.
>> AS WE SAID HE HAS A VERY
DIFFICULT JOB.
ONCE AGAIN OUR THANKS TO BILL
HART.
LET'S GET IT BACK TO NEW YORK
NOW AND BIANNA.
>> SO HARD TO PROCESS THAT POINT
THAT YOU MADE, DAN.
THAT MOST OF THESE VICTIMS STILL
HAVE THEIR BABY TEETH.
SUCH A HEINOUS ACT AND SUCH
INNOCENCE LOST.
>>> WELL, WE ARE GETTING A MORE
COMPLETE PICTURE THIS MORNING OF
THE GUNMAN AS POLICE TRY TO
LEARN WHY 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA
WENT ON HIS BLOODY RAMPAGE.
ABC'S CHIEF INVESTIGATOR
CORRESPONDENT BRIAN ROSS IS
HERE.
AND YOU HEAR THE WEAPONS USED
WERE LIKELY LICENSED TO HIS
MOTHER WHO IS DESCRIBED AS A GUN
ENTHUSIAST.
>> THAT IS CORRECT, BIANNA.
AND AUTHORITIES SAY THEY ARE
MOVING QUICKLY WITH MORE
DEVELOPMENTS LIKELY TO COME
TODAY IN EFFORTS TO DETERMINE
THE HOW AND THE WHY OF THIS
STUNNING CRIME.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE ALREADY
FOUND IMPORTANT CLUES IN THE
LANZAS' FOUR-BEDROOM, $600,000
HOME WHERE THE KILLER'S MOTHER,
52-YEAR-OLD NANCY LANZA, WAS THE
FIRST VICTIM.
>> HOPEFULLY PAINTING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> Reporter: AUTHORITIES NOW SAY
NANCY LANZA OWNED THE SAME STYLE
OF GUNS THAT HER SON USED TO
KILL HER AND THE 26 VICTIMS AT
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAID MOST
WERE KILLED WITH MULTIPLE SHOTS
FROM THE HIGH-POWERED
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
>> THIS PROBABLY IS THE WORST I
HAVE SEEN.
>> Reporter: THE CONNECTION
BETWEEN ADAM LANZA AND THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL GOES BACK
TO THE TIME HE WENT TO SCHOOL
THERE, AND HIS MOTHER WORKED AS
A TEACHER'S AIDE.
ACCORDING TO ADAM'S AUNT MARSHA
LANZA --
>> I KNOW HE HAD ISSUES WITH
SCHOOL.
SHE EVENTUALLY WOUND UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT AND IN WHAT CAPACITY,
I'M NOT 100% CERTAIN IF IT WAS
BEHAVIOR.
IF IT WAS LEARNING DISABILITIES.
>> Reporter: AS A FULLER PICTURE
OF ADAM LANZA BEGAN TO EMERGE
INCLUDING HIS MEMBERSHIP IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL TECH CLUB, FORMER
CLASSMATES TELL ABC NEWS HE WAS
A SMART BUT SOCIALLY AWKWARD
STUDENT.
>> HE ALWAYS CARRIED A
BRIEFCASE.
AND THAT'S WHAT STICKS OUT MOST
IN MY MIND.
>> Reporter: ADAM'S PARENTS
PETER AND NANCY LANZA WENT
THROUGH AN UNCONTESTED DIVORCE
THREE YEARS AGO, AND ADAM'S AUNT
SAID THAT NANCY HAD PURCHASED SO
MANY WEAPONS BECAUSE SHE WAS
CONCERNED FOR HER SAFETY LIVING
ALONE.
>> I THINK THE REASON WHY NANCY
MAY HAVE HAD THEM FOR THE MANY
MORE OF US IN THIS COUNTRY,
SELF-DEFENSE AND NO OTHER
REASON.
>> Reporter: FRIENDS HAVE TOLD
US IS THAT NANCY LANZA HAPPY TO
TAKE HER SONS TO A NEARBY FIRING
RANGE BEFORE TARGET PRACTICE AND
WAS HAPPY TO DO THAT.
>> SHE COULD HAVE BEEN THERE
WHEN HE WAS LEARNING HOW TO
SHOOT THOSE GUNS.
IT LED TO HER DEATH AND THE
DEATH OF 26 OTHERS.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
DAN, I KNOW YOU HAVE MORE ON
THOSE 26 VICTIMS AS WELL NOW.
>> AS WE SAID WE NOW KNOW THEIR
NAMES.
THEY'RE SO YOUNG, ALL 6 AND 7
YEARS OLD, ALL IN THE FIRST
GRADE, ALL SHOT MORE THAN ONCE
BY A SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAYING
DEATH WAS MERCIFULLY SWIFT.
AND ADDED IT'S PROBABLY THE
WORST HE HAS EVER SEEN IN THREE
DECADES ON THE JOB.
AND AMY ROBACH IS HERE WITH MORE
ON THIS.
THIS IS REALLY THE HARDEST PART.
>> IT TRULY IS.
BECAUSE AS WE LEARN MORE ABOUT
THE VICTIMS, IT TRULY GETS
HARDER.
WE KNOW THE NAMES AND SEE THE
FACES OF THOSE SWEET LITTLE BOYS
AND GIRLS, THE TEACHERS WHO
LOVED THEM AND, OF COURSE, THE
PARENTS WHO SO DESPERATELY MISS
THEM.
12 LITTLE GIRLS AND 8 LITTLE
BOYS ALL ONLY IN FIRST GRADE AND
THE TEACHERS WHO TRIED TO SAVE
THEM.
ON SATURDAY PHOTOS AND DETAILS
OF LIVES CUT SHORT STARTED TO
EMERGE.
>> THE WORST THAT I KNOW OF ANY
OF MY COLLEAGUES HAVING SEEN.
>> NOAH POZNER HAD JUST TURNED
6.
HIS TWIN SISTER SURVIVED THE
SHOOTING BUT NOAH DID NOT.
7-YEAR-OLD GRACE McDONNELL,
FAMILY MEMBERS TELLING ABC NEWS
"OUR DAUGHTER GRACE WAS THE LOVE
AND LIGHT OF OUR FAMILY.
WORDS CANNOT ADEQUATELY EXPRESS
OUR SENSE OF LOSS."
ANA MARQUEZ-GREEN, THE DAUGHTER
OF A JAZZ MUSICIAN.
THEY'RE STRUGGLING TO WORK
THROUGH THIS NIGHTMARE.
CATHERINE HUBBARD'S FAMILY SAID
IN A STATEMENT SATURDAY, "WE ASK
THAT YOU CONTINUE TO PRAY FOR
US AND THE OTHER FAMILIES WHO
HAVE EXPERIENCED LOSS IN IN
TRAGEDY.
JESSE LEWIS WAS LOOKING FORWARD
TO MAKING GINGERBREAD HOUSES IN
SCHOOL THAT DAY.
HE WAS IN VICTORIA SOTO'S CLASS.
SHE, JUST 27 YEARS OLD.
HER FAMILY SAYS SHE WAS
SHIELDING SOME OF HER FIRST
GRADERS WHEN SHE DIED.
LAUREN RUSSEAU HAD JUST STARTED
AS A FULL-TIME TEACHER IN
SEPTEMBER.
SHE WAS HAVING THE BEST YEAR OF
HER LIFE, HER MOTHER SAID.
MARY SHERLACH, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, IN A STATEMENT
SATURDAY HER FAMILY SAID "MARY
FELT LIKE SHE WAS DOING GOD'S
WORK BY HELPING CHILDREN.
SHE HEADED TOWARDS THE SHOOTER
WHEN THE ASSAULT BEGAN."
JOINED BY THE SCHOOL'S BELOVED
PRINCIPAL.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, A MOTHER
HERSELF, IT IS NOW BELIEVED SHE
TURNED ON THE P.A.
SYSTEM WHEN THE SHOOTING STARTED
SO OTHERS COULD BE WARNED OF THE
DANGERS THAT HAD INVADED THEIR
SCHOOL.
IT IS SO DIFFICULT TO FIND THE
RIGHT WORDS AFTER SEEING HOW
MUCH THIS COMMUNITY HAS LOST,
BUT SOMEHOW, SOME WAY THE FATHER
OF LITTLE EMILIE PARKER FOUND
THOSE WORDS WHEN HE SPOKE TO
CAMERAS OUTSIDE OF A NEWTOWN
CHURCH.
>> AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES THAT SHE
WAS ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT
TIME HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING AS THOSE WERE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
THE STRENGTH THAT SHE GAVE US
AND THE EXAMPLE THAT SHE SHOWED
US WAS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON, AND
I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER DAD.
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO GET THROUGH
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
MY WIFE AND I DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW TO PROCESS ALL OF THIS AND
HOW TO GET OUR LIVES GOING.
I'M NOT MAD, BECAUSE I HAVE TO
MAKE SURE THAT I USE THIS EVENT
TO DO WHAT I CAN, TO DO WHATEVER
I CAN TO, ONE, MAKE SURE THAT MY
FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTERS ARE TAKEN CARE OF AND
THAT IF THERE'S ANYTHING THAT I
CAN DO TO HELP ANYBODY ANYWHERE,
I'D BE WILLING TO DO THAT.
>> WHAT AN INCREDIBLY STRONG AND
BRAVE AND COURAGEOUS MAN.
MY HAT IS CERTAINLY OFF TO HIM
AS A PARENT.
I DON'T THINK THAT I COULD DO
THAT.
>> AND COVERING THIS STORY AS A
PARENT, I KNOW YOU'VE GOT THREE
LITTLE GIRLS, EXTRAORDINARILY
DIFFICULT.
>> IT IS INCREDIBLY DIFFICULT.
SCHOOL IS CLOSED HERE IN NEWTOWN
TOMORROW, BUT EVERYONE AROUND
THE COUNTRY, EVERY PARENT OUT
THERE WHO IS GOING TO TAKE THEIR
CHILDREN TO SCHOOL TOMORROW,
IT'S GOING TO BE A FUNDAMENTALLY
DIFFERENT EXPERIENCE BECAUSE
THERE IS A FEAR FACTOR AND THE
SENSE THAT YOU DON'T KNOW.
THAT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ISN'T
SACRED ANYMORE.
IT'S NOT A SAFE PLACE ANYMORE
THAT WE ONCE THOUGHT IT WOULD BE
AND A LOT OF PARENTS WILL HUG
THEIR KIDS MORE TIGHTLY TOMORROW
AND TELL THEM THEY LOVE THEM
BEFORE THEY SEND THEM OFF.
>> INDEED, AND TAKING THINGS NOT
SO MUCH FOR GRANTED ANYMORE.
I KNOW LARA IN THE BROADCAST
YOU'RE GOING TO BE BACK ABOUT
HOW TO TALK TO CHILDREN ABOUT
THIS.
>> IT'S A BIG STRUGGLE.
>> AMY, EXCELLENT REPORTING.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> SUNDAY MORNING IS ALWAYS A
TIME FOR REFLECTION BUT EVEN
MORE SO ON THIS DAY AND IN THIS
PLACE.
ABC'S JUJU CHANG IS AT ONE OF
THE CHURCHES HERE IN NEWTOWN.
JUJU, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING, DAN.
YOU KNOW, CONGREGANTS ARE FILING
IN.
MASS IS ABOUT TO GET UNDER WAY
AND THE HOUSES OF WORSHIP
THROUGHOUT NEWTOWN AND, IN FACT,
THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY ARE
PROVIDING A SENSE OF COMMUNITY
THIS MORNING.
BUT ALSO A PLACE WHERE YOU CAN
ASK QUESTIONS TO WHICH THERE ARE
NO EASY ANSWERS LIKE HOW COULD A
GUNMAN WIPE OUT SUCH INNOCENCE?
HERE ON THE GROUNDS OF ST. ROSE
OF LIMA THERE ARE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS.
AND WHEN YOU WALK UP TO THEM,
YOU CAN SEE CANDLES AND FLOWERS
AND NOTES OF CONDOLENCES BUT
ALSO CHILDLIKE ITEMS, A SOCCER
BALL SIGNED BY THE NEWTOWN
SOCCER CLUB, LITTLE STUFFED
ANIMALS LIKE THE KIND A 6 OR
7-YEAR-OLD WOULD TAKE TO BED AND
A NOTE THAT SAID SIMPLY "SLEEP
IN HEAVENLY PEACE."
DAN?
>> AND THOSE CHILDLIKE ITEMS AS
YOU PUT IT, THEY ARE THE
TOUGHEST TO SEE.
JUJU, I KNOW SEVERAL FAMILIES
WHO BELONG TO THE CHURCH IN
FRONT OF WHICH YOU ARE STANDING
LOST CHILDREN.
HOW IS THE CHURCH DEALING WITH
THAT?
>> Reporter: DAN, IT IS SUCH A
POIGNANT THOUGHT.
MONSIGNOR ROBERT WEISS, AS YOU
KNOW, WHO IS THE PRIEST HERE WHO
HAD THE GUT-WRENCHING JOB OF
INFORMING FAMILIES THEY LOST
CHILDREN HAD SPENT LAST NIGHT
PLANNING FUNERALS FOR THOSE
EIGHT CHILDREN.
A CHURCH OFFICIAL TOLD ME THERE
ARE EIGHT CHILDREN, EIGHT
FAMILIES AND EIGHT FUNERALS THAT
ARE BEING PLANNED HERE IN THIS
CONGREGATION ALONE AT ST. ROSE
AND, YOU KNOW, THROUGHOUT THIS
TOWN, THE CHURCHES AND THE
HOUSES OF WORSHIP ARE NOT JUST
WRAPPING THEIR ARMS AROUND THE
FAMILIES THAT SUFFERED A DIRECT
LOSS BUT FOR THE ENTIRE
COMMUNITY WHICH SAYS THEY'LL
NEVER BE THE SAME.
AND ONE LAST DETAIL, DAN, THERE
ARE FOUR SERVICES PLANNED HERE
TODAY AND THERE ARE KLEENEX
BOXES ON EITHER SIDE OF EACH
AISLE OF THAT CHURCH.
>> EXTRAORDINARY.
WE ARE HEADING INTO THE WEEK
LEADING UP TO CHRISTMAS AND IN
THIS LITTLE TOWN, THEY'VE GOT
MORE THAN 20 FUNERALS TO PLAN
AND CARRY OUT, JUJU CHANG, THANK
YOU FOR YOUR REPORTING.
>>> A LOT OF OTHER NEWS ON THIS
SUNDAY MORNING.
FOR MORE ON THAT, LET'S GET BACK
TO NEW YORK AND BIANNA ONCE
AGAIN.
>> ALL RIGHT, DAN, WE'LL BE BACK
TO YOU IN NEWTOWN IN JUST A FEW
YOU MOMENTS BUT TO ANOTHER
DEVELOPING STORY, A HEALTH SCARE
FOR HILLARY CLINTON.
THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUFFERING
A CONCUSSION AFTER FAINTING FROM
DEHYDRATION.
ABC'S DAVID KERLEY HAS THE
LATEST FROM WASHINGTON AND,
DAVID, HOW SERIOUS IS HER
CONDITION?
>> Reporter: WELL, SHE IS
STAYING HOME FOR ABOUT A WEEK
NOW.
SECRETARY CLINTON'S HEALTH ISSUE
MEANS THAT SHE WILL NOT BE GOING
TO CAPITAL HILL TO TESTIFY ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI.
AND EVEN THOUGH SHE INJURED
HERSELF LAST WEEK, WE DIDN'T
LEARN ABOUT HER CONDITION UNTIL
HOURS AGO.
THIS MORNING HILLARY CLINTON IS
AT HOME RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION, AS WELL AS A STOMACH
VIRUS.
IN FACT, THE TWO ARE RELATED.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT SAYS THE
SECRETARY RETURNED FROM HER
LATEST TRIP WITH A STOMACH BUG.
THAT WAS NINE DAYS AGO BUT EARLY
LAST WEEK CLINTON BECAME
DEHYDRATED AND FAINTED AT HER
HOME.
SHE APPARENTLY HIT HER HEAD
BECAUSE OFFICIALS SAY SHE
SUFFERED A CONCUSSION.
IT'S THE SECOND TIME IN EIGHT
YEARS SHE HAS FAINTED BECAUSE OF
A STOMACH BUG, BUT SHE'S
GENERALLY HEALTHY AS SHE TOLD
BARBARA WALTERS RECENTLY WHO
ASKED ABOUT A POSSIBLE
PRESIDENTIAL RUN IN 2016.
>> IS YOUR AGE A CONCERN TO YOU?
>> IT REALLY ISN'T.
I AM THANKFULLY -- KNOCK ON WOOD
-- NOT ONLY HEALTHY BUT HAVE
INCREDIBLE STAMINA AND ENERGY.
>> Reporter: BUT STAYING HOME
THIS WEEK MEANS THE SECRETARY
WILL NOT TESTIFY ABOUT THE
TERRORIST ATTACK IN BENGHAZI,
LIBYA.
>> LOOK, I'VE SAID IT, AND I'LL
SAY IT ONE MORE TIME, NO ONE
WANTS TO FIND OUT WHAT HAPPENED
MORE THAN I DO.
>> Reporter: THE STATE
DEPARTMENT REPORTS ON WHAT LED
TO THE TERRORIST ATTACK.
THE DEATH OF AMBASSADOR CHRIS
STEVENS AND THREE OTHERS WILL
COME OUT IN THE NEXT COUPLE OF
DAYS.
CLINTON WAS SET TO TESTIFY
BEFORE BOTH HOUSES THURSDAY.
NOW SHE WILL STAY HOME AND TWO
DEPUTIES WILL FILL IN.
NOT GOOD ENOUGH SAYS THE
REPUBLICAN CHAIR OF THE HOUSE
COMMITTEE WHO DECLARED THE
QUESTION ABOUT BENGHAZI,
"REQUIRES A PUBLIC APPEARANCE BY
THE SECRETARY OF STATE HERSELF."
BUT THAT MAY NEVER HAPPEN.
ABC NEWS HAS LEARNED THAT THE
PRESIDENT WILL NOMINATE JOHN
KERRY AS SECRETARY OF STATE.
AS SOON AS HE IS CONFIRMED,
CLINTON WILL RETIRE, SO SHE MAY
NEVER TESTIFY ABOUT BENGHAZI,
AND, BIANNA, WE LEARNED THAT THE
PRESIDENT CALLED SECRETARY
CLINTON YESTERDAY TO MAKE SURE
SHE WAS DOING OKAY.
>> GLAD TO HEAR SHE IS DOING
BETTER.
ALL RIGHT.
DAVID, THANK YOU.
>>> NOW WITH A LOOK AT THE OTHER
STORIES MAKING HEADLINES HERE'S
RON CLAIBORNE.
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU, BIANNA,
GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
>>> WE BEGIN WITH ANOTHER
ERUPTION OF GUNFIRE, THIS TIME
IN A PARKING LOT IN A SHOPPING
MALL IN SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
THE SHOOTING WAS CAUGHT ON
SURVEILLANCE CAMERA.
POLICE IN NEWPORT BEACH,
CALIFORNIA, SAY THAT 42-YEAR-OLD
MARCOS GURROLA WAS ARRESTED
AFTER ALLEGEDLY FIRING ABOUT 50
SHOTS INTO THE AIR AND GROUND
OUTSIDE OF THAT MALL.
NO ONE INJURED, HOWEVER, BUT THE
MALL PACKED WITH HOLIDAY
SHOPPERS WENT INTO LOCKDOWN
UNTIL POLICE SECURED THE AREA.
>>> IN OKLAHOMA, A TEENAGER
UNDER AS REACCUSED OF A
FRIGHTENING PLOT TO SHOOT
STUDENTS AND BOMB HIS OWN HIGH
SCHOOL.
PROSECUTORS SAY THAT 18-YEAR-OLD
SAMMY CHAVEZ PLANNED TO TRAP
STUDENTS IN A LOCKED AUDITORIUM
AND START SHOOTING.
HE ALSO ALLEGEDLY WANTED TO
PLACE BOMBS AT THE DOORS FOR
WHEN POLICE ARRIVED.
STUDENTS REPORTED THE PLAN, THE
ALLEGED PLOT TO SCHOOL STAFF
MEMBERS AFTER CHAVEZ TRIED TO
RECRUIT THEM.
>>> AND A MAJOR CONCESSION BY
THE REPUBLICAN HOUSE LEADERS IN
THOSE FISCAL CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS.
ABC NEWS HAS LEARNED THAT HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER HAS
PROPOSED RAISING INCOME TAXES
FOR THE WEALTHIEST AMERICANS,
THOSE MAKING A MILLION DOLLARS A
YEAR OR MORE BUT ONLY IF THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION AGREED TO
MAJOR ENTITLEMENT CUTS.
THE WHITE HOUSE REJECTED
BOEHNER'S PROPOSAL OUT OF HAND.
>>> AND EGYPT'S MUSLIM
BROTHERHOOD IS DECLARING VICTORY
IN THE FIRST ROUND OF VOTING ON
A NEW CONSTITUTION IN THAT
COUNTRY.
THE REFERENDUM BY MOHAMMED MORSI
HAS POLARIZED EGYPT.
LEADING TO VIOLENT CLASHES
BETWEEN PRO AND ANTI-GOVERNMENT
GROUPS.
ANOTHER ROUND OF VOTING TAKES
PLACE THIS COMING WEEK.
>>> AND FORMER SOUTH AFRICAN
PRESIDENT NELSON MANDELA IS
RECOVERING THIS MORNING FROM
SURGERY TO HAVE GALLSTONES
REMOVED.
THE 94-YEAR-OLD WAS INITIALLY
HOSPITALIZED EIGHT DAYS AGO WITH
THE RECURRENCE OF A LUNG
INFECTION.
THIS IS THE SECOND TIME THAT
HE'S BEEN HOSPITALIZED THIS
YEAR.
BUT HANGING IN THERE.
>> AROUND THE WORLD WISHING HIM
THE BEST.
>> YEAH.
>> ALL RIGHT, RON, THANK YOU.
>>> TIME FOR WEATHER AND OVER TO
GINGER ZEE.
HEY, GINGER.
>> GOOD MORNING, BIANNA.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
IT WAS AN ICY, MESSY JUST
DISASTER IN PARTS OF MINNESOTA
YESTERDAY BECAUSE OF THIS LOW
PRESSURE SYSTEM.
FIRST CAME THE SNOW, THEN KIND
OF THIS WINTRY MIX AND YOU HAD A
LOT OF SLIDE-OFFS.
THAT SAME TYPE OF ENERGY IS NOW
MOVING TO THE NORTH AND EAST SO
PARTS OF NEW ENGLAND TONIGHT
THROUGH EARLY TOMORROW ARE IN
WINTER WEATHER ADVISORIES.
WINTER STORM WARNINGS EVEN.
SOUTH OF THE MID-ATLANTIC AND
NORTHEAST IT WILL STAY MOSTLY
RAIN BUT SOME HEAVY RAINS AT
TIMES.
JUST SOMETHING TO LOOK AHEAD TO.
ALSO SEVERE STORMS WITH THAT
MOISTURE PUMPING FROM THE GULF.
YOU COULD HAVE 70-MILE-PER-HOUR
GUSTS AND SMALL HAIL DOWN
THROUGH JACKSON, MISSISSIPPI,
EVEN TO HOUSTON TODAY SO THAT'S
SOMETHING TO TAKE NOTE OF.
AND THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST, THE
SOME BLIZZARD WARNINGS AND
WINTER STORM WARNINGS IN EFFECT
TOO.
THAT STARTS TONIGHT, UP TO
75-MILE-PER-HOUR GUSTS AND CAN
SEE HERE UP TO 1 OR 2 FEET OF
SNOW IN THE MOUNTAINS.
>> THAT IS A LOOK AT YOUR
NATION'S WEATHER.
WE'LL HEAD NOW BACK OUT TO DAN.
>> THANK YOU, GINGER.
>> COMING UP, MUCH MORE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
SOME PRACTICAL ADVICE TO
PARENTS.
HOW DO YOU TALK TO YOUR CHILDREN
ABOUT THIS.
>>> ALSO, WE'LL TAKE A LOOK AT
HOW THIS MASSACRE PUTS THE
CONTENTIOUS ISSUE OF GUN CONTROL
BACK IN THE NEWS.
THE CONTEND SHOES ISSUE OF
GUN CONTROL IS BACK IN THE NEWS.
F
OF GUN CONTROL IS BACK IN THE
NEWS.
STHE CONTEND SHOES ISSUE
OF GUN CONTROL IS BACK IN THE
NEWS.
THE CONTEND SHOES ISSUE
OF GUN CONTROL IS BACK IN THE
NEWS.
ITHE CONTEND SHOES
ISSUE OF GUN CONTROL IS BACK IN
THE NEWS.
STHE CONTEND SHOES
ISSUE OF GUN CONTROL IS BACK IN
THE NEWS.
GAM GAM "THE GAME."
"GOOD MORNING AMER GM.
>>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA ON
THIS SUNDAY MORNING, 48 HOURS
AFTER THE WORST SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN AMERICAN
HISTORY.
THIS MORNING AS THE FAMILIES OF
THE YOUNG VICTIMS RELEASE A
FLOOD OF BEAUTIFUL BUT WRENCHING
PHOTOGRAPHS, THESE QUESTION, HOW
DO YOU TALK TO YOUR CHILDREN
ABOUT THIS KIND OF DISASTER AND
WHAT, IF ANYTHING, CAN BE DONE
TO PREVENT THIS FROM HAPPENING
AGAIN?
GOOD MORNING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ONCE AGAIN I'M DAN
HARRIS, BIANNA GOLODRYGA IS IN
NEW YORK.
WE'LL GET BACK TO HER IN JUST A
MOMENT AND WE'LL BE TACKLING
BOTH OF THOSE QUESTIONS IN A
MOMENT BUT FIRST WE WANT TO
START WITH THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
TRAVELING HERE LATER TODAY TO
MEET WITH THE FAMILIES OF THOSE
WHO WERE LOST AND ALSO TO THANK
THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
HE WILL SPEAK AT AN INTERFAITH
VIGIL SCHEDULED FOR 7:00
EASTERN.
>>> WE NOW KNOW THE NAMES OF THE
DEAD AND WE KNOW THAT ALL OF THE
20 CHILDREN WERE IN THE FIRST
GRADE BORN IN 2005 OR 2006, THE
OLDEST VICTIM, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST BORN IN 1956.
THE MASSIVE SCOPE OF THE
SENSELESS SLAUGHTER, THE LATEST
IN A LONG STRING OF MASS
SHOOTINGS IN AMERICA HAS
RE-OPENED THE POLITICALLY
EXPLOSIVE SUBJECT OF GUN CONTROL
AND THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
ABC'S PIERRE THOMAS WHO IS OUR
SENIOR JUSTICE CORRESPONDENT HAS
BEEN LOOKING INTO IT.
GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING, DAN.
SO MANY DISTURBING QUESTIONS BUT
THIS TRAGIC EVENT HAS PUT A
SPOTLIGHT ON AMERICA'S THRIVING
GUN CULTURE.
THE STATISTICS ARE STAGGERING.
ON BLACK FRIDAY, U.S. SHOPPERS
WERE NOT JUST BUYING TOYS AND
ELECTRONICS BUT GUNS IN RECORD
NUMBERS.
ON THAT SINGLE DAY THE FBI DID
COMPUTERIZED BACKGROUND CHECKS
ON MORE THAN 154,000 PURCHASES
OF FIREARMS.
AND IN NOVEMBER ALONE, AMERICANS
TRIED TO BUY A WHOPPING 2
MILLION GUNS.
HERE ARE SOME FACTS THAT MIGHT
SURPRISE YOU.
THERE ARE MORE REGISTERED GUN
DEALERS IN STORES THAN MAJOR
SUPERMARKETS.
MORE GUN SELLERS THAN McDONALD'S
RESTAURANTS.
THE OVERWHELMING MAJORITY OF GUN
OWNERS ARE LAW-ABIDING CITIZENS
BUT AUTHORITIES TELL ABC NEWS
THE MILLIONS OF GUNS IN
CIRCULATION GUARANTEE THAT
DISTURBED PEOPLE WILL OFTEN BE
ABLE TO OBTAIN THEM EVEN IN
TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITIES LIKE
NEWTOWN.
WE SPOKE TO ATF'S ON-SCENE
COMMANDER TO NEWTOWN.
ROUGHLY HOW MANY GUN DEALERS ARE
IN THIS AREA?
>> THERE ARE ABOUT 400 GUN
DEALERS IN A FOUR-COUNTY AREA
JUST WITHIN TEN MILES OF THE
INCIDENT THERE ARE 36.
>> Reporter: IN THE CASE OF ADAM
LANZA, LAW ENFORCEMENT
SOURCE US TELL US THE TWO
HANDGUNS AND ASSAULT RIFLE USED
IN THE SHOOTING WERE BOUGHT
LEGALLY.
>> IN AMERICA UNLESS YOU HAVE A
FELONY CONVICTION OR YOU'RE
ADJUDICATED BY A COURT TO BE
MENTALLY INCOMPETENT, YOU HAVE
READY ACCESS TO FIREARMS.
>> Reporter: LANZA JOINS THE
RANKS OF MASS SHOOTERS JARED LEE
LOUGHNER, JAMES HOLMES AND THE
VIRGINIA TECH SHOOTER AND THIS
MORNING THE NATION IS LEFT WITH
A PERPLEXING QUESTION, HOW DO
YOU KEEP WEAPONS FROM MEN LIKE
THESE WHEN THERE ARE AN
ESTIMATED 200 MILLION PLUS GUNS
ALREADY IN CIRCULATION?
DAN, THERE ARE SIMPLY NO EASY
ANSWERS.
>> Reporter: NO, AND THIS IS AN
EXPLOSIVE ISSUE.
I KNOW YOU'LL BE TALKING ABOUT
IT LATER ON "THIS WEEK."
A SPECIAL EDITION OF "THIS WEEK"
FROM HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, GEORGE
STEPHANOPOULOS WILL TALK WITH
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT DAN
MALLOY AND OTHER ELECTED
OFFICIALS FROM THE STATE,
TACKLING QUESTIONS SUCH AS HOW
LEADERSHIP RESPONDS TO THE
TRAGEDY.
THAT IS THIS MORNING ON "THIS
WEEK WITH GEORGE
STEPHANOPOULOS."
LET'S GET BACK TO NEW YORK AND
RON WHO HAS A LOOK AT THE
MORNING'S TOP STORIES, ALSO
GINGER WITH THE WEATHER.
GINGER?
>> GOOD MORNING, ALONG WITH
SEVERE STORMS HERE'S WHAT WE'LL
LOOK FOR IN THE WAY OF DRENCHING
RAINS, SOME COMPUTER MODELS ARE
PUTTING OUT 1 TO EVEN 3 INCHES
OF RAIN FOR MISSISSIPPI AND BACK
THROUGH LOUISIANA AND EVENTUALLY
MAKE THEIR WAY THROUGH THE REST
OF THE SOUTHEAST.
I WANT TO LEAVE YOU WITH A LOOK
HERE ACROSS THE NATION,
REMEMBER, BLIZZARD WARNINGS,
WINTER STORM WARNINGS IN THE
PACIFIC NORTHWEST.
THAT STORM HITS TONIGHT THROUGH
TOMORROW.
SOME OF THE HIGHER ELEVATIONS
WILL BE TOUGH AND HAVE TO GET
CHAINS ON THE TIRES, CHICAGO, 48
AND RAIN THROUGHOUT THE
NORTHEAST DEVELOPS THIS
AFTERNOON THROUGH TONIGHT,
RAIN/SNOW MIX IN NEW ENGLAND.
UP TO 9 INCHES OF SNOW IN NEW
HAMPSHIRE.
THAT'S A LOOK AT THE BIG
PICTURE.
NOW A CHECK A
>> AND THAT IS A CHECK OF YOUR
NATION'S WEATHER.
WE HEAD NOW BACK OUT TO DAN.
>> AND THANK YOU, GINGER.
COMING UP ON "GMA," CHILDREN AND
TRAGEDY.
WHAT DO YOU TELL YOUR KIDS?
SOME EXPERT ADVICE AFTER THIS
QUICK BREAK.
EEEN YOU
NEED A QUICK HOLIDAY PRESENT,
GO TO WALGREENS.COM.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR PHOTO,
CREATE ANY NUMBER OF GIFTS
AND PICK THEM UP
THE SAME DAY.
RIGHT HERE.
AT THE CORNER
OF HAPPY AND HEALTHY.
Natural dog food is the smart
choice.
Let's look at the brand that
proves it.
Nutro Natural Choice Dog Food.
It has natural sunflower oil and
B Vitamins
that guarantee a visibly shiny
coat.
With natural ingredients,
guaranteed to promote healthy
digestion.
Make the Natural Choice today.
guaranteed to promote healthy
digestion.
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
>>> IT WAS PEACEFUL AND
EVERYTHING WAS FINE, EVERYTHING
WAS JUST NORMAL.
AS A REGULAR FRIDAY MORNING
WOULD BE TO EVERYONE AND THEN IT
ALL JUST CHANGED.
>> HEARD SCREAMING.
>> WE WERE LIKE ALL SCARED.
>> WE HEARD A LOUD BANG.
WE THOUGHT THAT SOMETHING FELL
THEN WE HEARD ANOTHER AND THEN
WE THOUGHT THAT THAT WAS A
GUNSHOT.
>> WE THOUGHT IT WAS A SAFETY
DRILL BUT THEN WE NOTICED IT WAS
REAL.
>> WE HID IN THE STORAGE ROOM
AND I ACTUALLY PRAYED TO GOD.
>> EVERYBODY WAS A LITTLE SCARED
CRYING AND I FELT ACTUALLY A
LITTLE SICK LIKE I WAS GOING TO
THROW UP.
>> IT FELT LIKE IT LASTED LIKE
AN HOUR BUT IT WAS REALLY LIKE
MAYBE 20 MINUTES.
>> WHEN I WENT TO THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT, WHEN I DIDN'T SEE
HIM, I WAS LIKE, OH, MY GOD,
WHAT HAPPENED TO MY BROTHER.
>> WHAT'S THE HARDEST PART?
>> THAT SOMEONE WOULD MURDER SO
MANY PEOPLE.
>> AND I FINALLY SAW ETHAN I WAS
VERY RELIEVED.
>> YOU SAID EARLIER YOU SAID YOU
THINK YOUR TEACHER SAVED YOUR
LIFE.
>> SHE SAVED ALL OF US.
THERE'S 19 PEOPLE IN OUR CLASS
AND SHE SAVED ALL OF US.
>> AND THE QUESTION FACING
PARENTS EVERYWHERE THIS MORNING
IS, OF COURSE, HOW DO I TALK TO
MY OWN CHILD ABOUT THESE
TERRIBLE EVENTS?
HOW CAN WE EXPLAIN THE
UNEXPLAINABLE?
THE UNEXPLAINABLE, DIFFICULT FOR
EVEN US TO COMPREHEND.
JOINING US IS JOURNALIST AND
AUTHOR WILLOW BAY WHO WROTE THE
BOOK ON THIS TOPIC "TALKING TO
YOUR KIDS IN TOUGH TIMES: HOW TO
ANSWER YOUR CHILD'S QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE WORLD WE LIVE IN."
SHE JOINS US FROM LOS ANGELES
AND WILLOW WAS A FORMER ANCHOR
HERE OF THIS PROGRAM.
WE WANT TO WELCOME YOU BACK TO
THE PROGRAM.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US.
>> NICE TO BE WITH YOU ON WHAT
IS REALLY A TRAGIC MORNING FOR
ALL OF US, FOR ALL PARENTS.
AND CHILDREN ALIKE.
>> WILLOW, I WANT TO START BY
ASKING YOU THE QUESTION THAT
WE'VE BEEN TALKING ABOUT THIS
MORNING, ALL THREE OF US BEING
PARENTS, HOW DO WE APPROACH THIS
TOPIC?
I KNOW MY KIDS WERE ASKING ABOUT
IT LAST NIGHT, WHERE I WOULD BE
THIS MORNING.
HOW DO YOU DO IT IN A WAY THAT'S
COMPASSIONATE AND GIVING THEM
THE INFORMATION THAT THEY NEED
BUT NOT TOO MUCH?
>> SO THE FIRST THING YOU WANT
TO DO IS ESTABLISH THAT THERE'S
NO QUESTION TOO SCARY FOR YOUR
CHILD TO TALK ABOUT, TO CREATE A
REALLY SAFE AND COMFORTABLE
PLACE FOR THEM TO COME AND TALK
TO YOU.
THE SECOND THING YOU WANT TO DO
IS SUPPRESS THE NORMAL PARENTAL
INSTINCT TO TELL THEM
EVERYTHING.
YOU WANT IT TO COME FROM YOU.
YOU WANT TO BE THE ONE TO TELL
THEM.
BUT THIS IS ONE OF THOSE
SITUATIONS WHERE WE NEED TO DO
WHAT WE DO AS JOURNALISTS AND
ASK OUR CHILDREN QUESTIONS SO WE
GET A BASELINE ON WHAT THEY'RE
UNDERSTANDING.
REMEMBER, THEY'RE PROCESSING
UNTHINKABLE INFORMATION AND
ADULT INFORMATION WITH THE MINDS
OF CHILDREN.
SO YOU WANT TO ASK THEM
QUESTIONS LIKE, WELL, WHAT DO
YOU THINK ABOUT THAT?
WHAT HAVE YOU HEARD ABOUT THAT?
ARE THE KIDS AT SCHOOL TALKING
ABOUT THAT?
JUST AS A WAY OF GETTING THE
CONVERSATION STARTED AND AS A
WAY OF GETTING MORE PRECISE
UNDERSTANDING OF WHAT EXACTLY
THEY KNOW AND THINK TO BE THE
TRUTH.
>> AND, WILLOW, ONE OF THE
QUESTIONS I RECEIVED FROM MY
10-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER, ONE OF THE
FIRST QUESTIONS OUT OF HER MOUTH
WAS WHY MOMMY.
WHY WOULD SOMEONE DO LIKE THIS
AND YOU KNOW WHAT, I DIDN'T HAVE
AN ANSWER FOR HER.
WHAT DO YOU TELL YOUR CHILDREN,
WILLOW, WHEN THEY ASK WHY?
>> BY THE WAY, MY 14-YEAR-OLD --
THAT WAS THE FIRST THING HE SAID
TO ME, HOW -- WHY WOULD SOMEBODY
DO THIS AND I THINK IN THAT
SITUATION IT'S FINE TO ANSWER
TRUTHFULLY, WHICH IS I DON'T
KNOW.
I THINK EVERYBODY IS ASKING THAT
QUESTION TODAY.
BUT THEN WITH A YOUNG CHILD
PARTICULARLY WITH A YOUNG CHILD
BECAUSE THE YOUNG CHILDREN THINK
VERY CONCRETELY.
THEY DON'T -- THEY HAVEN'T
MASTERED ABSTRACT THINKING.
ASK THEM, WELL, WHY DO YOU
THINK, WHY DO YOU THINK SOMEBODY
WOULD HAVE MADE A CHOICE LIKE
THAT AND IT'LL GET THEM
PROCESSING SOME OF THIS
INFORMATION IN THEIR OWN WAY.
AND THEN YOU CAN STEER THE
CONVERSATION TO WAYS PEOPLE
COULD MAKE BETTER CHOICES, FOR
EXAMPLE.
>> OKAY.
AND ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT
THINGS IS, OF COURSE, TO MAKE
THEM FEEL SAFE.
YOU HEARD A LITTLE GIRL I SPOKE
TO LAST NIGHT SAY SHE'S AFRAID
TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
CHILDREN EVERYWHERE WILL
EXPERIENCE SOME OF THESE
FEELINGS OF ANXIETY.
WHAT DO WE SAY TO THEM ABOUT
FEELING SAFE AND KNOWING THAT
THEY ARE SAFE?
>> WELL, AGAIN, CHILDREN, YOUNG
CHILDREN IN PARTICULAR THINK
VERY CONCRETELY SO IT'S VERY
HELPFUL TO REASSURE THEM IN VERY
CONCRETE AND SPECIFIC WAYS THAT
THEY WILL BE SAFE WHEN THEY GO
TO SCHOOL.
SO YOU REMIND THEM THAT THERE
ARE ADULTS OUT THERE WHOSE JOB
IT IS TO KEEP THEM SAFE, WHETHER
IT'S POLICEMEN.
THEIR SCHOOL PRINCIPAL.
THEIR TEACHERS.
AND WALK THEM THROUGH THE SAFETY
MEASURES IN THEIR SCHOOL.
THERE'S SOMEBODY STANDING AT THE
FRONT GATE.
THERE ARE DRILLS THAT WE DO,
PRACTICE YOUR DRILLS.
AGAIN, VERY CONCRETE AND
SPECIFIC THINGS THAT ARE GOING
ON IN THEIR SCHOOL TO KEEP THEM
SAFE.
ALSO, ASK THEM FOR THEIR OWN
IDEAS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK WE CAN DO TO
HELP KEEP YOU SAFER?
WHAT DO YOU THINK WOULD HELP YOU
FEEL SAFER?
OFTENTIMES ALLOWING THEM TO
PARTICIPATE WILL REALLY HELP
THEM FEEL BETTER, BUT THEN
ALWAYS COME BACK TO REMINDING
THEM THAT IT'S THE JOB OF ADULTS
AND THERE ARE A LOT OF US, HARD
AT WORK, TO KEEP THEM SAFE.
>> WILLOW BAY, FANTASTIC ADVICE
AND ADVICE THAT EACH AND EVERY
ONE OF US AS PARENTS AROUND THIS
ENTIRE COUNTRY CAN USE TODAY AS
OUR CHILDREN HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL
ON MONDAY.
WILLOW, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> GREAT TO HEAR FROM YOU,
WILLOW, AND MORE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHEN WE COME BACK.
TRY THIS.
IT'S OIKOS GREEK YOGURT.
IT'S CREAMY, NONFAT, AND IT
TURNS THE NEXT PERSON YOU SEE
INTO JOHN STAMOS
FOR FIVE SECONDS.
HONEY! I THINK
I'M GETTING BURNED! HEH!
EAT.
♪
TASTES PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
BEST YOGURT EVER.
YEAH!
[ men grunting ]
OPEN!
[ Male Announcer ]
DANNON OIKOS BERRY FLAVORS
BEAT CHOBANI 2 TO 1
IN A NATIONAL TASTE TEST.
OIKOS GREEK YOGURT.
POSSIBLY THE BEST YOGURT
IN THE WORLD.
OIKOS GREEK YOGURT.
Hey buddy, I bet Mom
would love this, huh?
Jack?
Jaaack?
Jaaack?!
Jack?!
Looks good
ladies!
Jack!
Come on,
stop the car.
JACK!
No, no, no, no, no!
The only thing more surprising
than finding the
perfect gifts..
Niice.
...is where you find them.
How did you know?
I had a little help.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
He is a good little monkey
and always very curious.
One day George got an important
letter...
He's built a rocket ship to
travel into space.
It's just the right size for a
clever monkey.
Do you want to go into space,
George?
You will have to be very brave.
Hi, Grandma!
Oh hi,. my little monkey!
Here.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Everyone got on and they were
off to the launching site.
Google, how far is Earth to the
Moon?
Moon is 238,900 miles...
The great moment had come...
...5...4...3...2...1
I'm mom at the playground
AND the dog park.
The kids get trail mix...
And YOU get a delicious Milo's
Kitchen Chicken Meatball.
They're 100% real...
I wish you liked MY
cooking that much.
The Best Treats Come
From The Kitchen.
Milo's Kitchen home-style
dog treats.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
>>> WELL, IT WILL BE A STRUGGLE
TO SAY THE LEAST TO MAKE SENSE
OF THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
ALREADY PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY ARE GOING THERE TO SHARE
IN THE GRIEF.
LET'S GO BACK TO LARA SPENCER IN
NEWTOWN.
SO ENCOURAGING TO SEE PEOPLE
FROM ACROSS THE COUNTRY WANTING
TO HELP.
>> BIANNA, IT HAS BEEN JUST AN
INCREDIBLY EMOTIONAL 24 HOURS
HERE AND I WILL TELL YOU THAT
WHAT STRUCK MOST OF US AS WE
WALKED AROUND TOWN LAST NIGHT
WAS THAT SENSE OF STRENGTH,
RESILIENCE, AND MOST OF ALL
KINDNESS.
ON A COLD, CRISP, NEW ENGLAND
NIGHT, RESIDENTS GATHERED IN
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS THROUGHOUT
TOWN TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF THE
IMPOSSIBLE.
>> I'M JUST WAITING TO WAKE UP
FROM THIS NIGHTMARE.
>> Reporter: THEN JOINED BY
HUNDREDS OF STRANGERS WHO
TRAVELED FAR AND WIDE TRYING TO
HELP.
WHY DID YOU NEED TO BE HERE?
>> I'M A MOTHER.
I'M A MOTHER.
>> Reporter: A MOTHER FROM NEW
YORK CITY, A CHAPLAIN FROM NORTH
CAROLINA.
HOW IMPORTANT IS IT TO GIVE BACK
TO THIS COMMUNITY?
>> I HAVE GRANDSONS EXACTLY THE
SAME AGE AS THE VICTIMS.
MY HEART WAS JUST -- I JUST WAS
MOVED.
>> Reporter: THIS FIREHOUSE IS
NOW THE SITE OF 26 CHRISTMAS
TREES, ONE FOR EACH LIFE TAKEN
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, EACH
DONATED BY A WOMAN FROM NORTH
CAROLINA AND NESTLED WITH TEDDY
BEARS.
HOW IS CHRISTMAS GOING TO BE?
>> NOT GOING TO FEEL LIKE
CHRISTMAS.
I THINK, YOU KNOW, IT'S
IMPORTANT TO KEEP THINGS AS
NORMAL AS POSSIBLE FOR EVERYONE.
IT'S ABOUT GIVING AND LOVING AND
KINDNESS.
>> Reporter: RANDOM ACTS OF
KINDNESS ABOUND.
TAKE MICHAEL CRAIGEN OFFERING UP
HIS BULLDOG FOR FREE HUGS AT A
LOCAL COFFEE SHOP.
AMANDA HARMON IS A GRIEF
COUNSELOR WHO LIVES AN HOUR AWAY
BUT DONATING HER TIME TO THOSE
HERE WHO NEED HER THE MOST.
>> OUT OF ALL THIS TRAGEDY MY
HEART HAS BEEN LIFTED FROM ALL
THE GOOD THAT'S COMING IN CROSS
COUNTRY AND AROUND THE WORLD.
INCREDIBLE EXPERIENCE.
>> AND THIS EVENING THE
PRESIDENT WILL BE HERE IN
NEWTOWN TO MEET WITH FAMILIES
WHO HAVE LOST AND ALSO TO SPEAK
AT AN INTERFAITH VIGIL.
BIANNA, BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> JUST WHEN YOU THINK YOU SEE
THE WORST PART OF SOCIETY, YOU
SEE THE KINDNESS, AS WELL AND I
THINK ALL OF US CAN SAY THIS
WEEKEND WE'RE ALL PART OF
NEWTOWN.
ALL RIGHT, LARA, THANK YOU, AND
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
ASK
I was living with
this all-over pain.
A deep, throbbing,
persistent ache.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can do more of
the things that I enjoy.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
GO TO WALGREENS.COM.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR PHOTO,
CREATE ANY NUMBER OF GIFTS
AND PICK THEM UP
THE SAME DAY.
RIGHT HERE.
AT THE CORNER
OF HAPPY AND HEALTHY.
>>> THAT'S GOING TO DO IT FOR
"GMA" ON THIS SUNDAY MORNING.
ON BEHALF OF BIANNA GOLODRYGA
WHO YOU SEE THERE IN NEW YORK
ALONGSIDE LARA SPENCER AND AMY
ROBACH HERE WITH ME IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, I WANT TO THANK YOU
FOR JOINING US.
AND REMIND YOU THERE'S MUCH MORE
COVERAGE COMING UP ON ABC NEWS
THROUGHOUT THE DAY, A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "THIS WEEK WITH
GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS" AND ABC'S
DAVID MUIR WILL HOST "WORLD
NEWS" FROM HERE LATER ON.
THANKS AGAIN FOR WATCHING.
TAKE CARE.
>>> THIS MORNING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, A SPECIAL EDITION
OF "THIS WEEK."
TRAGEDY AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> EVERYTHING WAS JUST NORMAL,
AND THEN IT ALL JUST CHANGED.
>> 27 KILLED, MOST IN THE FIRST
GRADE.
>> SHE IS A SPECIAL
TYPE OF PERSON,
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> EVIL MET BY BRAVERY.
>> I SAID THERE'S A BAD GUY OUT
THERE BUT MAKE WAY FOR THE GOOD
GUYS.