FORWARD.
GOOD MORNING.
LET'S LOOK AT WHAT IS GOING ON
AS FAR AS OUR TEMPERATURES.
IN THE 50s ONCE AGAINED TO
WITH -- AGAIN TODAY WITH
PARTLY CLOUDY CONDITIONS.
>>> PRETTY GOOD, LIGHT OUT
THERE, FIRST LOOK AT BAY
BRIDGE TOLL, ROADWORK
WESTBOUND FROM THE CANTILEVER
TO THE CENTER ANCHORAGE UNTIL
5:00 THIS MORNING.
NO METERING LIGHTS COMING OFF
THE WALDO ACROSS THE
GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE, NO FOG,
CLEAR AND VERY LIGHT TRAFFIC
DOWN TO TWO LANES THAT WILL
OPEN UP TO FOUR FOR YOUR
SOUTHBOUND COMMUTE.
ONE ACCIDENT PUSHED OFF THE
ROAD SOUTHBOUND 101 BEFORE
POPLAR IN SAN MATEO, SLOW AS
CREWS ARE ON THE SCENE.
>>> 30 WITHIN.
THE COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WILL BEGIN TO TRY
TO GET BACK TO NORMAL THIS
MORNING.
SCHOOLS WILL REOPEN AND MOST
STUDENTS WILL GO BACK TO
CLASS.
KATIE MARZULLO IS LIVE WITH
THAT.
>> Reporter: ALL SCHOOLS IN
NEWTOWN ARE OPENING FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING, EXCEPT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
STATE POLICE CEZANNE DID HOOK
WILL REMAIN A SECURE CRIME
SCENE, INDEFINITELY.
-- THERE WILL BE MORE CHILDREN
FUNERALS TODAY.
SEVERAL WAKES ARE SCHEDULED
FOR TODAY.
TWO 6-YEAR-OLD BOYS HAVE
ALREADY BEEN LAID TO REST JACK
PINTO AND NOAH POSNER.
WE ARE LEARNING JETBLUE JUMPED
TO HELP THE POSNER FAMILY WHEN
KNOW WITH WHAT'S PUT OUT A
CALL FOR HELP.
SHE WANTED TO BURY HANDWRITTEN
NOTES FROM FAMILY MEMBERS WITH
HER SON BUT HIS COUSIN LIVES
IN SALE.
WHEN OTHERS FAILED, JETBLUE
GOT THE LETTER ON A PLANE AND
DID IT MAKE IT THERE.
AS FOR THE INVESTIGATION
POLICE ARE TRYING TO GET
INFORMATION OUT OF A COMPUTER
FOUND AT THE HOME OF THE
SHOOTER ADAM LANZA AND HIS
MOTHER IT WAS BADLY DAMAGED
BUT THEY HOPE THEY CAN RECOVER
SOMETHING THAT WILL POINT TO A
MOTIVE.
AUTHORITIES HAVE TOLD ABC NEWS
THAT THE WEAPONS USED WERE
PURCHASED BY NANCY, BETWEEN
2010 AND 2012.
ACCORDING TO THE BUREAU OF
ALCOHOL, TOBACCO AND FIREARMS,
ADAM VISITED SHOOTING RANGES
SEVERAL TIMES IN RECENT YEARS,
AT LEAST ONE TIME WITH HIS
MOTHER.
KATIE MARZULLO, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> BAY AREA MAN IN CUSTODY
ACCUSED OF MAKING THREATS
ABOUT THE MASS SHOOTING
ONLINE.
FAIRFIELD POLICE ARRESTED HIM
AT HIS HOME.
POLICE SAY FRIDAY HE POSTED
COMMENTS THAT HE SUPPORTED THE
SHOOTER IN SANDY HOOK AND HAD
THOUGHTS ABOUT DOING SOMETHING
SIMILAR.
POLICE WILL PURSUE FELONY
CHARGES FOR MAKING CRIMINAL
THREATS.
HE HAS NOW APOLOGIZED ON HIS
FACEBOOK PAGE.
>>> CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY AND
GUN CONTROL DEBATE HAS THREAD
TO INCREASE IN GUN SALES
ACROSS THE COUNTRY AND HERE IN
THE BAY AREA.
CORNELL BERNARD HAS THAT
STORY.
>> Reporter: IT WAS A BUSY
WEEKEND IN NOVATO WHERE GUN
SALES HAVE INCREASED SINCE THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTING.
THE OWNER WON'T SAY HOW MANY
GUNS WERE SOLD OTHER DEALERS
REPORT RECORD SALES NATIONWIDE
HANDGUNS AND SHOTGUNS ARE
SELLING QUICKLY.
>> ONCE THE POWERS TO BE GET
ON TV AND START TALKING ABOUT
BANS AND TAKING THINGS AWAY,
IT IS A PUSH IN PEOPLE AND
INTEREST IN PURCHASING
FIREARMS THEY THINK MIGHT BE
TAKEN FROM THEM.
>> WAL-MART IS OUT OF
AMMUNITION.
>> Reporter: HE BUYING A GUN
BUT WORRIES IN NATIONAL
TRAGEDY COULD UNFAIRLY PUNISH
RESPONSIBLE, WOULD BEGUN
OWNERS.
>> THOSE GUNS NEVER SHOULD
HAVE BEEN IN THE HANDS OF THAT
YOUNG MAN.
YOU CAN'T STOP IT.
>> Reporter: SENATOR FEINSTEIN
IS PROMISING TO RE-INTRODUCE
AN ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN THAT
EXPIRED IN 2004 PROMPTED BY A
1993 MASS SHOOTING AT A
SAN FRANCISCO LAW FIRM.
CONGRESSWOMAN VOWS COMPANION
LEGISLATION IN THE HOUSE.
>> WE HAVE TO DO SOMETHING
ABOUT THE GUN VIOLENCE IN THIS
COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: SHE HELPED DRAFT
CALIFORNIA'S BAN AFTER SHE WAS
SHOT AND WOUNDED IN GUYANA,
ALONGSIDE CONGRESSMAN RYAN WHO
WAS KILL.
SHE SAYS THE FIGHT FOR GUN
CONTROL WASN'T EASY BACK THEN
AND WON'T BE TODAY.
>> I REMEMBER STANDING ON THE
ASSEMBLY FLOOR TAKING UP THE
MEASURE WHEN ONE OF MY
COLLEAGUES ASKED ME, HAVE YOU
EVER SHOT AN ASSAULT WEAPON?
I TURNED TO HIM AND SAID, HAVE
YOU EVER BEEN SHOT BY AN
ASSAULT WEAPON?
AND I HAVE.
CORNELL BERNARD, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
IS FELT JUST AS STRONGLY IN
THE BAY AREA BY FAMILIES WHO
DON'T KNOW THE VICTIMS.
LOCAL CLERGY ARE STEPPING UP
TO PROVIDE A PLACE WHERE
PEOPLE CAN GO TO BEGIN TO HEAL.
CONFUSED AND UPSET BY THE NEWS
MANY CAME TO BURLINGAME LAST
NIGHT.
FOR BETSY THERE'S A CLOSE
CONNECTION TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THAT'S WHERE SHE GREW UP AND
STILL HAS FRIENDS WHO WERE
FIRST RESPONDERS TO THE
SHOOTINGS.
SHE IS UPSET BUT PROUD THE WAY
THE TOWN HAS RESPONDED.
PASTOR ORGANIZED THE SERVICE
OF REMEMBRANCE, HEALING AND
HOPE TO GIVE PEOPLE A PLACE TO
SHARE TEARS.
HE SAYS THAT IS IMPORTANT TO
AVOID BECOMING CYNICAL ABOUT
THE TRAGEDY.
>>> POST OFFICE HAS ESTABLISH
ADD ADDRESS YOU CAN USE TO
EXPRESS CONDOLENCES TO THE
PEOPLE OF SANDY HOOK.
YOU CAN SEND LETTERS, CARE
PACKAGES, P.O. BOX 3700,
NEWTON, CONNECTICUT, 06470.
YOU WILL FIND THE ADDRESS ON
ABC7NEWS.COM.
YOU CAN SHOW SUPPORT TO THE
PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN BY POSTING
THIS BADGE TO YOUR FACEBOOK
WALL YOU CAN FIND THAT ON
FACEBOOK.COM/ABC7NEWS.
STAY WITH ABC7 NEWS FOR
CONTINUING COVERAGE OF THE
SCHOOL SHOOTING TRAGEDY.
THE ABC7 NEWS WEB TEAM IS
SENDING OUT UPDATES YOU CAN
SIGN UP FOR BREAKING NEWS
ALERTS AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
>>> THIS MORNING EIGHT PEOPLE
ARE RECOVERING AFTER BEING
EXPOSED TO TOXIC CHEMICALS,
INCLUDING MEMBERS OF A HAZ-MAT
CREW.
EIGHT PEOPLE WERE RUSHED TO
THE HOSPITAL AFTER BEING
EXPOSED TO CHEMICALS FROM A
HOUSEHOLD BUG BOMB AT A
TRAILER PARK NEAR REDWOOD
CITY.
TWO PEOPLE SET OFF THE DEVICE
INSIDE THE TRAILER BUT DIDN'T
LEAVE.
THE COUPLE WITH A NEIGHBOR
BECAME ILL.
WHEN RESPONDERS GOT THERE THEY
WENT IN WITHOUT REALIZING THE
AIR WAS TAX SICK.
ALL WERE TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL,
ALL -- WAS TOXIC.
ALL EXPECTED TO BE FINE.
>>> CANDLELIGHT VIGIL TONIGHT
FOR A 16-YEAR-OLD GIRL.
HER MOTHER IS UNDER ARREST.
HOMICIDE INVESTIGATORS SAY SHE
WAS FOUND UNCONSCIOUS ON A
SIDEWALK SUNDAY AVENUE IN THE
BAYVIEW DISTRICT.
POLICE SAY AUTHORITIES WHO
WENT TO THE GIRL'S HOME FIND
SIGNS OF ABUSE AND DETAINED
THE TEEN'S MOTHER.
>>> SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
ASKING FOR THE PUBLIC'S HELP
IN SOLVING THE MURDER OF
17-YEAR-OLD EAST BAY FOOTBALL
PLAYER.
BLAKELY PLAYED OFFENSE AND
DEFENSE FOR THE CONCORD HIGH
MINUTEMEN HE WAS SHOT AND
KILLED IN THE BAYVIEW DISTRICT
10:00 SATURDAY NIGHT.
AMY HOLLYFIELD IS IN CONCORD
THIS MORNING AND WILL HAVE THE
LATEST ON THE INVESTIGATION.
PLUS REACTION FROM STUDENTS
AND PARENTS, COMING UP.
>>> SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
SEARCHING FOR TWO MEN WHO SHOT
A CLERK WHILE HOLDING UP A
PHARMACY IN THE MISSION
DISTRICT AT AG PHARMACY LAST
NIGHT.
TWO MEN ENTERED PULLED OUT
WEAPONS AND TRIED TO HOLD-UP A
WORKER.
THE EMPLOYEE WAS SHOT IN THE
LEG, BUT SHOULD RECOVER.
POLICE ARE LOOKING FOR A THIRD
MAN THE GETAWAY DRIVER.
NO WORD ON WHAT THE ROBBERS
MADE OFF WITH, IF ANYTHING.
>>> CREWS ARE ON THE SCENE OF
A POTENTIAL SINKHOLE, MARSH
CREEK ROAD BETWEEN DEER VALLEY
PINE LANE AND CLAYTON IS
CLOSED.
CREWS SAY THE RAIN HAS
COMPROMISEED THE ROAD AND
SINKHOLE IS STARTING TO --
FORM THEY FEAR THE ROAD MAY
COLLAPSE.
THIS MORNING CREWS ARE
INSPECTING THE DAMAGE.
ANOTHER UPDATE AT 9:00 THIS
MORNING.
REMEMBER THE ONE IN LAFAYETTE
A COUPLE WEEKS AGO, WE HAVE
ANOTHER BIG STORM COMING.
>> YES, WE DO.
LET'S FIND OUT WHEN.
>>> I THINK THURSDAY, AGAIN
OVER THE WEEKEND WE ARE
WATCHING SOMETHING FOR THIS
MORNING, ESPECIALLY FOR
MARINERS AND FOLKS ALONG THE
COAST, OVER LAND, QUIET OVER
THE OCEAN WHERE THERE'S
GREATER INSTABILITY, SHOWERS.
WE TALKED ABOUT IN YESTERDAY
OUR NEXUS TELL WAS GOING TO
SLIDE DOWN THE -- OUR NEXT
SYSTEM WAS GOING TO SLIDE DOWN
THE COAST.
HEADING SOUTHEAST THEY ARE
GOING TO STAY OVER THE OCEAN
FOR THE MORNING COMMUTE.
OTHER BIG STORY, COOLER
CONDITIONS.
BACK IN THE 30s, FAIRFIELD,
NAPA, SANTA ROSA, MID TO UPPER
30s, REST OF US LOW TO MID 40s
MOUNTAIN VIEW AND SAN JOSE,
ANTIOCH 46, SAN FRANCISCO, 48
OAKLAND, FOR THE WARM SPOT
WITH HALF MOON BAY.
FIVE TO 20° COOLER THAN
QUESTIONED, HEAVY COAT THIS
MORNING.
MID TO UPPER 40s LUNCH TIME.
NEAR 50 4:00.
DROPPING BACK INTO THE LOW TO
MID 40s BY 7:00 WITH CLOUDS
DISSIPATING.
FROST ALMOST EVERYWHERE EXCEPT
COAST TOMORROW MORNING.
THEN YOU CAN SEE RAIN THURSDAY
AND WET AND WINDY CONDITIONS
FOR FRIDAY.
>>> OVERNIGHT ROADWORK
OTHERWISE THINGS ARE QUIET.
LIVE AT THE MacARTHUR MAZE 80
WESTBOUND FUNNELING IN, 580
FROM THE EAST AND 880 FROM THE
SOUTH, NO DELAYS AT THE BAY
BRIDGE ONCE YOU REACH THAT
DESTINATION TO THE TOLL, LIGHT.
>> SAN MATEO BRIDGE, A FEW
BRAKE LIGHTS ON THE FLAT
SECTION, SMOOTH SAILING UP AND
OVER TOWARDS FOSTER CITY,
FASHION ISLAND BOULEVARD AND
HAYWARD AREA LOOKING GOOD
EASTBOUND.
LITTLE SLOWING OUT OF ANTIOCH,
RIGHT NOW IT IS LOOKING GOOD
WITH SPEEDS AT THE LIMIT AS
YOU MAKE YOUR WAY TOWARDS
HIGHWAY 242 IN CONCORD AREA
WESTBOUND 4.
ROADWORK 880 BOTH DIRECTIONS
DOWN TO ONE LANE BETWEEN
FRUITVALE AND EMBARCADERO FOR
THE NEXT HALF HOUR OR SO.
WESTBOUND DUMBARTON BRIDGE,
ROADWORK FROM THE RADIO TOWERS
TO UNIVERSITY.
>>> 4:41.
>>> WASHINGTON MAY BE TAKING A
BIG STEP BACK FROM THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
THE OFFER FROM THE WHITE HOUSE
THAT REPUBLICANS WILL
CONSIDER.
>>> MYSTERY OF STOLEN
HOLLYWOOD FILM.
POLICE AND MOVIE STUDIO ARE
ÑUÑUñ
It's time
to change the way we clean.
It's time to free ourselves
from the smell
and harshness of bleach.
And free ourselves from worrying
about the ones we love.
New Lysol Power & Free has more
cleaning power than bleach.
How?
The secret
is the hydrogen peroxide
formula.
It attacks tough stains
and kills 99.9% of germs.
New Lysol Power & Free.
Powerful cleaning that's
family friendly.
Another step forward
in our Mission for Health.
>>> GOOD TUESDAY MORNING.
LIVE LOOK OUTSIDE FROM OUR
SUTRO CAMERA LOOKING DOWN AT
SAN FRANCISCO, ACROSS THE BAY
INTO THE EAST BAY.
IT IS DRY AND CLEAR.
ALBEIT COOL.
GRAB THE JACKET AND GET READY
FOR THE NEXT ROUND.
ANOTHER STORM.
>>> THIS MORNING HOUSE SPEAKER
BOEHNER WILL PRESENT THE
WHITE HOUSE'S LATEST FISCAL
CLIFF OFFER TO HOUSE
REPUBLICANS IT WOULD ELIMINATE
TAX CUT FOR AMERICANS OTHER
THANNING MORE THAN $400,000 A
YEAR, -- CUT 400 BILLION
DOLLARS FROM HEALTH CARE
PROGRAMS AND 200 BILLION
DOLLARS FROM OTHER PROGRAMS
OVER THE NEXT 10 YEARS.
THE OFFER WOULD NOT CHANGE THE
ELIGIBILITY AGE FOR MEDICARE,
THAT COULD BE A STICKING POINT
IN NEGOTIATIONS.
THE DEAL NEEDS TO BE IN PLACE
BY JANUARY 1st, OR SIZABLE TAX
INCREASES FOR MOST AMERICANS
WILL KICK IN.
>>> AUTHORITIES IN SANTA CRUZ
LOOKING FOR THE PERSON WHO
ABANDONED A DOG WEARING A SIGN
THAT SAYS "HOMELESS" FOUND
TIED TO A POLE INFECTED WOUND
VETS COULD NOT HEAL IT AND HAD
TO PUT HER DOWN.
THE SHELTER MANAGER SAYS NOT
PROVIDING VET CARE TO A
SUFFERING ANIMAL IS ILLEGAL.
>>> SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
WORKING FOR SECURE DAY AGENTS
FROM PARAMOUNT STUDIOS TO
RECOVER AN UNRELEASED FILM
STOLEN IN A CAR BURGLARY.
THE THEFT HAPPENED A MONTH AGO
AT A PIER 39 GARAGE.
A HARD DRIVE WAS AMONG
HUNDREDS OF ITEMS STOLEN.
SECURITY CAMERAS LED TO THE
ARREST OF SUSPECTS.
WHILE A TROUGH OF STOLEN ITEMS
WERE RECOVERED THE HARD DRIVE
WITH THE FILM IS STILL
MISSING.
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS CAN
ONLY SPECULATE WHAT HAPPENED.
>> THAT'S COMMON NOW PEOPLE GO
ON CREATE A CD OR DVD I SHOULD
SAY AND SELL IT ON THE STREET.
>> ONE LAW ENFORCEMENT SOURCE
SPECULATED THE HARD DRIVE
COULD HAVE BEEN SOLD AT A
STREET VALUE OF $30 TO $40.
>>> TAHOE GETTING READY FOR
WHITE CHRISTMAS.
NATURAL BASE BETTER THAN IT
HAS BEEN IN YEARS.
OPERATIONS ARE ABLE TO OPEN
MORE RUNS AND EXPECT MORE SNOW
TO MAKE ONE OF THE BEST
SEASONS IN A DECADE.
TWO MORE STORMS ON THE WAY
WILL DUMP MORE SNOW ON TAHOE
BEFORE THE HOLIDAY WEEK.
>> THE TRICK MIGHT BE GETTING
UP THERE.
>> YEAH, BECAUSE IT IS HITTING
THURSDAY AND FRIDAY, PEOPLE
ARE TRYING TO HEAD UP EITHER
OF THOSE DAYS THEY WILL RUN
INTO CHALLENGES AND IT IS
SNOWING THERE TODAY, ALSO SNOW
SHOWERS IN THE FORECAST FOR
TAHOE DOWN TOWARDS YOSEMITE
AND MOM MOUTH.
GOOD MORNING, IF YOU ARE --
AND MA'AM PHOUD.
GOOD MORNING.
4:47, CLEAR OUTSIDE, LET'S
LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD, THE
RADAR RETURNS AND THE CLOUDS
BOTH SUPERIMPOSED, MOST CLOUDS
OVER THE OCEAN WHERE MOST OF
OUR RADAR RETURNS HAVE BEEN,
THAT'S WHERE I THINK THEY ARE
GOING TO STAY, ONE OR TWO MAY
STRAY TOWARDS THE COAST KEEP
AN EYE TO YOUR WEST FOR THE
BETTER PART OF TODAY IN CASE
ONE COMES YOUR WAY.
IN THE 30s AND 40s, DRESS FOR
COLDER TEMPERATURES IN MORNING,
39 IN WATSONVILLE, LOW TO MID
40s SANTA CRUZ, GILROY SALINAS,
50 MONTEREY.
GOING TO BE PARTLY CLOUDY
TODAY, SHOWERS OVER THE OCEAN.
FREEZING COLD JUST ABOUT
EVERYWHERE TONIGHT, PETS,
PLANTS AND PIPES, JUST ABOUT
EVERYWHERE WE HAVE A FREEZE
WARNING FOR THE NORTH BAY
VALLEYS, FROST ADVISORY EAST
BAY VALLEYS, BAY SHORE AND
ALSO THE SANTA CLARA VALLEY
COAST ONLY AREA NOT UNDER THAT
ADVISORY.
STORMY PATTERN STARTS THURSDAY
THROUGH THE WEEKEND.
COLD FRONT FROM YESTERDAY
PUSHING THROUGH.
NEXT SYSTEM REINFORCING COLD
AIR STAYING OFFSHORE THAT IS
WHAT IS GOING TO INTRODUCE US
TO THE FREEZING TEMPERATURES
TONIGHT.
THURSDAY'S STORM AND ON THE
LEFT THAT'S OUR WEEKEND STORM,
COMING IN A LITTLE FURTHER TO
THE SOUTH, A LITTLE FARTHER
SOUTH, MAY HAVE MORE MOISTURE
WITH IT COME THE WEEKEND.
TOMORROW YOU CAN SEE DRY,
OVERNIGHT HOURS THURSDAY
MORNING AT 6:00, LIGHT RAIN
NORTH BAY, THROUGH THE DAY IT
SLOWLY SINKS SOUTH, BECAUSE OF
THAT WE ARE GOING TO HAVE
HEALTHY AMOUNTS OF RAIN LAY
LONG THE COASTYbR AND NORTH BAY
-- THURSDAY AND THURSDAY NIGHT
INTO FRIDAY ANOTHER DOSE OF
ENERGY THAT WILL MAKE IT WET
AND WINDY FRIDAY ALSO AND
QUICKLY ON ITS HEELS, NEXT
STORM SATURDAY AND INTO
SUNDAY.
FINALLY, JUST IN TIME FOR
MONDAY AND TUESDAY, IT IS OUT
OF HERE.
BUMPY RIDE THURSDAY THROUGH
SUNDAY.
>>> SAN JOSE QUIET NORTHBOUND
87 PAST THE JULIAN EXIT A FEW
HEADLIGHTS PASSING THROUGH
NORTHBOUND NO DELAYS AT THIS
HOUR THROUGH SAN RAFAEL LUCAS
VALLEY ROAD FREITAS PARKWAY
PASSING MARIN YMCA TRAFFIC
LIGHT LEAVING NOVATO HEADED
FOR CENTRAL SAN RAFAEL OR
SOUTHERN MARIN NO DELAYS WALDO
TO THE GOLDEN GATE EITHER.
OUT OF THE CENTRAL VALLEY GOOD
FROM 205 TRACY UP AND OVER THE
ALTAMONT NO DELAYS TOWARDS
LIVERMORE AND PLEASANTON AREA.
ROADWORK FOR A FEW MORE
MINUTES UNTIL 5:00, 880 BOTH
DIRECTS ONE LANE BETWEEN
FRUITVALE AND EMBARCADERO.
>>> INDEPENDENT INVESTIGATION
INTO THE DEADLY ATTACK ON U.S.
CONSULATE IN LIBYA WILL BE
SENT TO CONGRESS TODAY.
THE ATTACK IN BENGHAZI KILLED
THE AMBASSADOR STEVENS AND
THREE OTHER AMERICANS.
THE REVIEW BORE HAS BEEN
LOOKING INTO WHETHER ENOUGH --
GIVEN TO POTENTIAL THREATS AND
HOW WASHINGTON RESPONDED.
HOUSE AND SENATE COMMITTEES
WILL HOLD HEARINGS TOMORROW
AND THURSDAY.
SECRETARY OF STATE CLINTON HAD
BEEN EXPECTED TO TESTIFY, BUT
SHE IS RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION.
>>> CON RECOLLECTION --
CONGRESS IS DEBATING HOW MUCH
RELIEF MONEY TO SPEND FOR
SUPERSTORM SANDY.
THE PACKAGE INVOLVES MORE THAN
60 BILLION DOLLARS IN
EMERGENCY SPENDING.
DEMOCRATS WANT IT OUT BY
CHRISTMAS, IT HAS BEEN SEVEN
WEEKS SINCE STORM RAVAGED THE
NORTHEAST KILLING MORE THAN
120 IN NEW YORK, NEW JERSEY
AND CONNECTICUT.
REPUBLICANS ARE SAYING NOT SO
FAST.
THEY SAY THERE'S TOO MUCH WORK
IN THE -- PORK IN THE PACKAGE
INCLUDING MONEY FOR SALMON
FISHERIES IN ALASKA, NEW CARS
FOR THE GOVERNMENT AND
EXPANSION PROJECT FOR AMTRAK.
>>> SOUTHWEST AIRLINES HAS A
NEW FEE.
NEXT, WHY YOU WANT TO GET TO
THE AIRPORT ON TIME.
>>> WHY A P
Every time someone chooses
Finish over Cascade,
it sparks a movement.
Because people can't
keep it to themselves.
Look !
No ugly spots !
Awesome!
Incredible shine.
I'm switching for good.
Love, love, love Finish!
Over a million people
have switched to Finish.
Visit us on Facebook.
.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
TUESDAY MORNING, CHILLY OUT
THERE, AS YOU LOOK AT THE
EMBARCADERO, DRY.
ONLY GOING TO BE THAT WAY A
COUPLE MORE DAYS.
MIKE WILL TELL YOU MORE,
COMING UP.
>>> WESTFIELD SHOPPING CENTER
WILL BE OPEN AFTER A SMALL
SCARE LAST NIGHT.
A FIRE BROKE OUT AT A
RESTAURANT ON THE 4th FLOOR.
THE RESTAURANT INSIDE THE MALL
ON MARKET STREET WAS EVACUATED
WHILE CREWS PUT OUT THE FIRE.
INVESTIGATORS ARE TRYING TO
DETERMINE THE CAUSE.
>>> PROPONENTS OF NEW WOMEN'S
JAIL IN SANTA CLARA COUNTY
HAVE MORE SUPPORT.
RISING WATER LEVELS FROM LAST
WEEK'S KING TIDES DISRUPTED
OPERATIONS OVER THE WEEKEND.
HIGH WATER LEVEL MADE ROADS
IMPASSABLE INTO AND OUT OF THE
SEA LEVEL FACILITY.
FOOD SERVICE AND VISITOR
PRIVILEGES WERE DISRUPTED.
SAN MATEO OFFICIALS ARGUE THE
FACILITY IS UNSAFE FOR STAFF
AND PRISONER.
THE SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT IS
LOBBYING DEPARTMENT OF
CORRECTIONS FOR A NEW FACILITY
AT A DIFFERENT LOCATION.
>>> YOU SAID THE WORD STORMS
NOT THAT I'M COUNTING, I WANT
TO KNOW FROM MIKE HOW MANY
COMING OUR WAY
>> I KNOW THERE'S MORE THAN
ONE.
>>> THERE'S A COUPLE COMING
OUR WAY AT LEAST TWO, ONE
COMING TODAY YOU CAN SAY THREE
IT IS GOING TO STAY OVER THE
OCEAN LIVE DOPPLER SHOWING A
FEW RADAR RETURNS.
IT IS QUIET RIGHT NOW.
AROUND THE REST OF THE STATE
SHOWERS AROUND BAKERSFIELD,
RAIN IN THE GRAPEVINE, GOOD
NEWS, SNOW IN THE SIERRA EVEN
SNOW NORTH CHECK OUT THE
THUNDERSTORM OVER THE OCEAN
NOW TO THE WEST OF CRESCENT
CITY THAT'S HOW MUCH
INSTABILITY IS OUT THERE MOST
SHOWERS WILL STAY OUT OVER THE
OCEAN IF YOU ARE HEADING NORTH
WATCH OUT FOR THE SNOW RAIN
AROUND PALM SPRINGS.
>>> ROADWORK ON THE BAY BRIDGE
UNTIL 5:00 WESTBOUND TWO LANES
BETWEEN CANTILEVER AND CENTER
AGE COREAGE BEHIND THE TOLL
TRAFFIC LIGHT COMING INTO
SAN FRANCISCO NO DELAYS NO
DELAYS SOUTHBOUND 101 THROUGH
SAN RAFAEL, WESTBOUND
DUMBARTON ROADWORK FOR THE
NEXT FEW MINUTES EASTBOUND
UNTIL 6:00 THIS MORNING
WESTBOUND PICKED UP AT 5.
DRIVE TIMES HEADING OUT NOW,
FROM THE CENTRAL VALLEY UP AND
OVER THE ALTAMONT NOT BAD OUT
OF ANTIOCH AND HIGHWAY 80 INTO
THE MAZE.
>>> THIS IS FOR PARENTS.
RECALL FOR A POPULAR GROUP OF
TOYS.
THE TOYS EXPAND WHEN PLACED IN
WATER.
THEY ARE SOLD UNDER THE NAME
WATER BALLS, AND FABULOUS
FLOWERS THEY ARE THE SIZE OF
MARBLE BUT CAN EXPAND TO 400
TIMES ORANGE SIZE UNDER WATER.
BIG TROUBLE IF A KID SWALLOWS
ONE, LIQUIDES IN THE BODY CAN
CAUSE THEM TO EXPAND.
A -- BABY NEEDED SURGERY AFTER
INGESTING ONE.
>>> SOUTHWEST AIRLINES NO
LONGER GOING TO ALLOW
PASSENGERS WHO MISS FLIGHTS
REBOOK FOR FREE.
THE AIRLINE PLANS TO START
CHARGING A NO-SHOW FEE FOR
PASSENGERS WHO DON'T CANCEL
BEFORE MISSING THE FLIGHT.
ALSO WILL RAISE FEES TO CHECK
A NERD BAG FROM $25 TO $75 --
AND RAISE PRICE OF EARLY
CHECK-IN TO $12.50.
>>> CHRISTMAS TOUR OF THE
WHITE HOUSE ENDED WITH A
MARRIAGE PROPOSAL.
U.S. MARINE CORPS CAPTAIN
MATTHEW PHELPS PROPOSED TO HIS
PARTNER IN WHAT IS BELIEVED TO
BE THE FIRST SAME-SEX
ENGAGEMENT CALL THE ON CAMERA
WHITE HOUSE.
IT SHOWS HIM ON BENDED KNEE
ASKING HIS BOYFRIEND TO MARRY
HIM.
INSTANT INTERNET SENSATIONS
THOUSANDS OF LIKES ON
FACEBOOK.
>> Reporter: IT WILL BE A
SMALL MOVE TOWARD NORMALCY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT THIS
MORNING WITH CHILDREN GOING
BACK-TO-SCHOOL.
THE COMMUNITY IS LONG FROM
RECOVERED, AS MORE YOUNG
CHILDREN WILL BE LAID TO REST
TODAY.
>>> MICHAEL FINNEY HELPS PLANT
A DREAM.
EAST BAY ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
THAT HOPES TO BECOME THE
LITTLE SCHOOL THAT COULD.
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>>> GOOD MORNING.
THANKS FOR JOINING US I'M
KRISTEN SZE.
>>> I'M ERIC THOMAS.
IT IS DRY OUT THERE, BUT STILL
COLD.
>> IS IT FROSTYáeú?
>>> GETTING CLOSE, ESPECIALLY
AROUND NAPA WHERE 36 NOW.
BETTER CHANCE OF JUST ABOUT
ALL OF US SEEING FROST
TOMORROW MORNING.
TOMORROW MORNING WILL BE THE
COLDEST MORNING WE'VE HAD SO
FAR THIS SEASON.
DOPPLER QUIET, A