WINDSHIELD.
>> YOU MAY HAVE TO SING, BABY
IT'S COMBED OUT THERE.
>> LET MIKE SING IT.
>> I WOULD LOVE TO HEAR A DUET
BETWEEN YOU TWO.
DEAN MARTIN AND WHOEVER SINGS
THE DUET OR KECHB ANY ROGERS.
>> YES, THERE ARE ALL SORTS --
LET'S MOVE ON.
LIVE DOPPLER, YOU CAN SEE IT IS
SHOWING SOME RETURNS BUT BLUE
AND WITH THIS DRY AIR OUT
UNDERNEATH THE RADAR RETURN,
NONE OF IT IS MAKING TO THE
GROUND.
SO LET'S TALK ABOUT WHAT IS
GOING ON.
WE HAVE A CHANCE FOR THIS
INITIAL PUSH AND ANOTHER CHANCE
THAT IS GOING TO MOVE THROUGH
THE MORNING HOURS.
JUST BECAUSE IT'S NOT RAINING
RIGHT NOW, THERE IS STILL A
POSSIBILITY.
BIG STORY, FROSTY CONDITIONS
INLAND AND LOOK AT REDWOOD CITY,
36 THIS MORNING AND SAN JOSE,
ABOUT 39.
TEMPERATURES WILL BE STUCK IN
THE 40s FOR MOST OF US TODAY.
WE MAY GET INTO THE LOW 50s
AROUND THE BAY.
>>> DRY ROADS AND LIGHT TRAFFIC,
THAT IS HOW WE LIKE FRIDAY
MORNING.
COMING UP WITH A SHOT OF 80 TO
BERKELEY AND MacARTHUR MAZE.
A LITTLE BIT OF BUNCHING WHERE
THEY MERGE BY GOLDEN GATE FIELDS
BUT LOOKING PRETTY GOOD.
GREENVILLE, ROAD WORK, WESTBOUND
IS LOOKING PRETTY GOOD THIS
MORNING.
EASTBOUND DUMBARTON ROAD WORK
UNTIL 6:00.
NORTH 101 ON THE OTHER SIDE OF
THE BAY, TO 6:00 BETWEEN 92 AND
THIRD AVENUE.
>> Eric: IN THE NEWS, NEW THIS
MORNING, TWO BIG QUAKES RATTLED
THE SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA COAST
OVERNIGHT.
BOTH STRUCK AT 2:36 THIS
MORNING.
THEY WERE SECONDS APART.
6 PONTD 4 AND 6.1 BUT THEY HAVE
DOWNGRADED THEM TO 6.3 AND 4.7.
THEY WERE CENTERED AT LEAST 88
MILES SOUTHWEST OF CATALINA
ISLAND.
THERE IS WAS NO TSUNAMI WARNING
ISSUED AND PEOPLE WERE SHAKEN
OUT OF BED BUT SO FAR NO REPORTS
OF DAMAGE OR INJURY.
>> STUDENTS RETURNING TO TWO
CUPERTINO SCHOOLS AFTER A BOMB
SCARE SKAIR WILL NOTICE EXTRA
SECURITY.
TERRY?
>> ADDITIONAL SHERIFF'S DEPUTIES
WILL BE HERE AT MONTEVISTA AS
WELL AS LINCOLN ELEMENTARY.
TWO SCHOOLS SHUT DOWN ALL DAY
YESTERDAY AS A RESULT OF A BOMB
SCARE THAT CAME FROM FOUR AND A
HALF MILES AWAY ALL THE WAY OVER
IN SAN JOSE.
TAKE A LOOK AT THE GRAFFITI.
THIS IS FROM LINBROOK HIGH
SCHOOL.
IT TALKED ABOUT A BOMB AND
SPECIFIC TEACHER AT MONTEVISTA.
THAT THREAT LED SHERIFF'S
DEPUTIES TO SHUT DOWN MONTEVISTA
AND LINCOLN ELEMENTARY.
THERE WAS ROOM BY ROOM SEARCH
AND THEY ALL TURNED UP NOTHING,
JUST A HOAX BUT NO ONE WAS
LAUGHING.
>> WHEN THEY GO OVER THE EDGE,
COLUMBINE -- WE'VE HAD SEVERAL,
IT'S NOT A PRANK.
THAT IS VERY SERIOUS MATTER WHEN
YOU TALK ABOUT BLOWING UP
PEOPLE.
>> SHERIFF'S OFFICE TAKING IT
VERY SERIOUSLY.
IT HAS ASSIGNED DEPUTIES TO THE
HOME OF THE THREATENED TEACHER.
THE PERSON RESPONSIBLE MAY BE
FACING A FELONY.
SCHOOL IS IN SESSION TODAY.
ADDITIONAL SHERIFF'S DEPUTIES
WILL BE OUT ONLY AT MONTEVISTA
AND LINCOLN ELEMENTARY AS WELL.
>> Eric: FIRE INVESTIGATORS HOPE
TO GET THEIR FIRST LOOK MY A
GUTTED MACHINE SHOP IN FREMONT
LATER TODAY.
A FAST-MOVING FIRE ENGULFED THE
PLANT YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
NOBODY WAS HURT BUT IT WIPED OUT
NEARLY EVERYTHING INSIDE.
THEY MAKE COMPONENTS IN THE
HIGH-TECH INDUSTRY.
ABOUT 60 PEOPLE WORK THERE.
THEY WILL LEARN LATER ABOUT THE
COMPANY'S PLANS TO REOPEN
ANOTHER ANOTHER LOCATION.
AMY HOLLYFIELD WILL HAVE MORE ON
THE FIRE IN A LIVE REPORT AT
5:30.
>> SAN JOSE POLICE HAVE REVEALED
THE IDENTITY OF A YOUNG MAN WHO
WAS SHOT TO DEATH EARLIER THIS
WEEK.
18-YEAR-OLD JOHN CODY SONNEBERG
DIED ON TUESDAY AFTER BEING SHOT
INSIDE A PICKUP.
AT FIRST IT APPEARED THAT HE HAD
BEEN HURT IN ACCIDENT BUT
PARAMEDICS DISCOVERED HE HAD
BEEN SHOT WHEN THEY TRIED TO
HELP HIM.
>>> THIS MORNING, OAKLAND POLICE
ARE INVESTIGATING THAT CITY'S
LATEST HOMICIDE.
POLICE FOUND A MAN SHOT IN THE
MIDDLE OF A RESIDENTIAL STREET
IN EAST OAKLAND YET.
THIS WAS THE SCENE FROM SKY7HD.
IT HAPPENED AT 83rd AVENUE AND
"E" STREET EAST OF THE COLISEUM.
THEY CLOSED OFF THE BLOCK FOR
SEVERAL HOURS.
NO WORD ON MOTIVE OR POSSIBLE
SUSPECTS.
>> CABINET WEEK IS STAKES NOW
THAT SUSAN RICE IS OUT OF THE
RUNNING AS SECRETARY OF STATE.
NEW NAMES ARE GAINING MOMENTUM.
KATIE MARZULLO IS LIVE IN THE
NEWSROOM TO BREAK IT DOWN FOR
US.
>> AS THE HIGH STAKES GAME OF
MUSICAL CHAIRS WHO WILL MAKE UP
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S NATIONAL
SECURITY TEAM.
WE KNOW NOT AMBASSADOR SUSAN
RICE, ALL SIGNS POINT TO JOHN
KERRY.
HE HAS NO COMMENT ON THAT.
MANY REPUBLICANS SAY HE WILL
BREEZE THROUGH THE NOMINATION
PROCESS BUT IT IS LIKELY HE WILL
FACE TOUGH QUESTIONS ABOUT HIS
PAST SUPPORT FOR SYRIAN
PRESIDENT.
IF KERRY GETS THE JOB, HIS
SENATE SEAT BECOMES AVAILABLE.
SCOTT BROWN MAY RUN IN THE
SPECIAL ELECTION.
AMBASSADOR RICE HAS BEEN EMBROID
L BRIOMD IN CONTROVERSY OVER THE
TERRORIST ATTACKS IN BENGHAZI.
SHE TOLD NBC THAT IS WHY SHE IS
STEPPING ASIDE.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY POLITICIZED
AND VERY DISTRACTING.
>> OTHER OPENINGS, SECRETARY OF
DEFENSE.
KERRY'S NAME WAS FLOATED FOR THE
JOB BUT CHUCK HAGEL WHO BECAME
THE CRITIC OF THE IRAQ WAR HAS
THE EDGE.
JOHN BRENNAN AND MIKE MORALE ARE
CONSIDERED THE TOP CONTENDERS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA HAS ACCEPTED HER
DECISION AND MEETING WITH HER IN
PRIVATE.
>> Eric: NEW THIS MORNING, A
FEDERAL COURT WILL HEAR BARRY
BONDS WILL HEAR HIS OBSTRUCTION
OF JUSTICE CONVICTION.
THEY HAVE SET ORAL ARGUMENTS FOR
FEBRUARY 13th.
LAST YEAR A JURY CONVICTED BONDS
OF ONE FELONY OBSTRUCTION COUNT
FOR GIVING AN EVASIVE ANSWER
WHEN HE WAS ASKED WHETHER HE
RECEIVED DRUGS THAT REQUIRED A
SYRINGE.
BONDS LAWYERS ARGUE THE ANSWER
WAS ACCURATE AND WAS NOT MEANT
TO OBSTRUCT JUSTICE.
>> THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO IS
ASKING TO DISMISS A LAWSUIT
CHALLENGING THE NUDITY BAN.
FOUR PEOPLE CHALLENGED THE LAW
LAST MONTH.
THEY HAVE FILED A MOTION TO GET
THE SUIT THROWN OUT.
HE SAYS THE SUIT IS WITHOUT
MERIT.
THE PUBLIC NUDITY BAN WILL TAKE
PLACE FEBRUARY 1st AND ALLOW IT
IN EVENTS LIKE BAY TO BREAKERS
AND FOLSOM STREET FAIR.
>> DEFINITELY NOT THAT SORT OF
WEATHER.
>> YOU HAVE ON TO BUNDLE UP.
>> MIKE HAS THE FORECAST.
>> IT IS KIND OF COLD IS
MOTIVATING, YOU WANT TO DRESS
FOR THE COLD, DRESS IN LAYERS
THIS MORNING AND WATCH OUT FOR
THE POSSIBILITY OF LIGHT RAIN.
IT'S A POSSIBILITY UP IN THE
NORTH BAY.
WE'VE GOT BLUES, USUALLY JUST
DRIZZLE AND LIGHT GREENS,
POSSIBLY LIGHT RAIN BUT RIGHT
NOW BEING UNDERCUT BY THE LAYER
OF DRY AIR.
I HAVE SEEN ANY TRUTH THIS IS
REACHING THE GROUND.
YOU TWEET ME AT MIKE NICCO AND
LET ME KNOW IF YOU SEEN ANY IN
YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD OR GO TO
FACEBOOK.
RIGHT NOW, THE RADAR IS PICKING
IT UP BUT IT'S STAYING IN THE
CLOUDS WHICH IS GOOD NEWS.
NOW, WHEN WE DON'T HAVE THE
CLOUDS AND HAVEN'T HAD THEM FOR
THE BETTER PART OF THE MORNING,
EAST BAY, HOLLISTER, NORTHERN
SALINAS, THAT IS WHERE WE HAVE
THE FROST ADVISORY FROM 2:00 TO
8:00.
CLOUDS OR THE WAY AND
TEMPERATURES ARE STARTING TO
HOLD STEADY.
32 AT LIVERMORE.
OUTLYING AREAS, DEFINITELY
SEEING FROST.
36 IN REDWOOD CITY.
WE HAVE A CHANCE OF RAIN
TOMORROW.
BETTER CHANCE THAN TODAY.
A STRAY SHOWER POSSIBLE ON
SUNDAY AND ANOTHER CHANCE ON
MONDAY BUT TEMPERATURES WILL BE
OUT OF THE 40s FOR THE HIGHS AND
BACK IN THE 50s.
>>> LIVE LOOK AT THE SAN MATEO
BRIDGE, HAYWARD SIDE OVER TO SAN
MATEO.
YOU CAN SEE THE TAILLIGHTS
HEADED WESTBOUND.
LIGHT TRAFFIC, BRAKE LIGHTS
BEFORE THE HIGH-RISE BUT
EVERYTHING IS MOVING WELL.
NO ISSUES THERE.
LIGHT TRAFFIC SOUTH 101 RIGHT
PAST FREITAS AND EVERYBODY IS
OUT OF THE LIMIT SOUTHBOUND OUT
OF NOVATO.
FOUR LANES SOUTHBOUND OUT OF
WALDO AND LOOKING PRETTY GOOD
HERE.
NO FOG AND VERY FEW CARS HEADED
INTO SAN FRANCISCO.
CHECK IN BART, CALTRAIN, ALL
MASS TRANSIT IS RUNNING ON
SCHEDULE.
GREAT WAY TO GO THIS FRIDAY
MORNING.
ROAD WORK, REVERSE COMMUTE
BETWEEN MILL VALLEY AND LARKSPUR
PAVING PROJECT IS UNDER WAY
UNTIL 6:00 THIS MORNING.
NORTHBOUND 880 AT WASHINGTON
BOTH DIRECTIONS ROAD PAINTING
UNTIL 6:00 THIS MORNING.
>>> QUEEN ELIZABETH TAKES A
FIELD TRIP TO SEE HOW MONEY IS
MADE.
THE SHINY BARS THAT GOT HER
SPECIAL ATTENTION.
>> HOLIDAY SHOPPING HELP FROM "7
ON YOUR SIDE," MICHAEL FINNEY
WITH 25 WEBSITE THAT HAS OFFER
COOL GIFTS.
>> SPEAKING OF MONEY, THIS
MORNING'S MONEY REPORT.
>> PEOPLE ARE OPENING UP THEIR
WALLETS ON STORES AND ONLINE.
RETAIL SALES WROTE .3%.
THEY WERE ACTUALLY UP A SOLID
.8%.
PEOPLE ARE DOING A GOOD JOCK OF
PAYING THEIR CREDIT CARD BILLS.
THE RATE OF BORROWERS SHOULD
STAY LOW NEXT YEAR.
TECH COMPANIES PAY WILL AND
FACEBOOK PAYS INTERNS MORE THAN
$5,600 A MONTH, ABOUT $67,000 A
YEAR.
THAT IS $25,000 MORE THAN THE
AVERAGE WORKER TAKES HOME.
>>> GOOD FRIDAY MORNING, HERE IS
A LIVE LOOK AT DOWNTOWN SAN
FRANCISCO.
WHAT YOU CAN'T SEE IS HOW COLD
IT IS OUT THERE.
DOWNRIGHT FROSTY.
COLDEST TEMPERATURE MIKE HAS IS
34 DEGREES.
WHERE IS IT?
THINK ABOUT THAT.
HE WILL TELL US IN A MOMENT.
TELL US ABOUT THE LIGHT RAIN
THAT MAY START HITTING US SOON
AND SERIES OF STORMS COMING OUR
WAY.
>> Eric: 5:14.
>> WALGREEN'S WILL PAY A HUGE
FINE TO SETTLE A ENVIRONMENTAL
LAWSUIT.
THEY WILL PAY $16.5 MILLION
AFTER PROSECUTORS SAID THEY
ILLEGALLY DUMPED BIOHAZARD US ON
WASTE INTO REGULAR TRASH BINS.
THEY ALSO DUMPED PATIENTS'
RECORDS.
ALL 34 STORES WERE FOUND TO BE
IN VIOLATION.
SETTLEMENT COVERS MORE THAN HALF
IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA.
>> IN VALLEJO THEY EXPECT TO SEE
MORE OFFICERS OUT THIS WEEKEND.
THEY WILL BE CONDUCTING SPECIAL
HOLIDAY PATROLS IN THE SHOPPING
CENTERS AND DOWNTOWN AREA AND
OFFICERS WILL PATROL ON FOOT AND
ON BIKE.
THEIR GOAL TO MAKE THEMSELVES
MORE VISIBLE.
>>> IF YOU ARE LIKE A LOT OF
PEOPLE YOU ARE LOOKING FOR
UNIQUE GIFT IDEAS.
MICHAEL FINNEY SHOWS US WHERE TO
FIND SOME AT AN AFFORDABLE
PRICE.
FOLKS AT SHOP SMART COMPILED 25
WEBSITES WHERE YOU CAN FIND COOL
GIFTS FOR UNDER $25.
>> LINDSAY IS FILLING A LOT OF
ORDERS TO MEET THE HOLIDAY RUSH.
SHE OPERATES SET BY TOKE.
SHE SELLS ONE OF A KIND ITEMS
LIKE THIS TABLET COVER.
>> THESE ARE UNDER $20, REALLY
INTERESTING THEY ARE MADE OUT OF
MITSUBISHI CAR SEATS.
>> IT WAS MADE WITH COMPETENCE
MATERIAL.
EVERYBODY EVERYTHING SHE SELLS
LIKE $20 RECYCLED GLASS
NECKLACES OR $24 EARRINGS COME
FROM MANUFACTURE THERE'S ARE
FAIR TRIED CERTIFIED.
IT'S ONE OF 25 RETAIL WEBSITES
FEATURED THIS N SHOP SMART
MAGAZINE.
>> IF YOU SPEND $20 THEY WILL
DONATE FIVE DOLLARS TO THE
CHARITY OF YOUR CHOICE.
>> EACH ONE FEATURED WERE
PRE-SCREENED FOR THEIR GOOD
CUSTOMER SERVICE AND PRIVACY
POLICIES.
THAT INCLUDES ALL TIME KENNEDY
CANDY.
-- THAT INCLUDES ALL TIME
YOU WILL FIND NOVELTY ITEMS,
LIKE HAND CRANKED MARCH MELLOW
OR HOTDOG ROASTER.
FINALLY IF YOU WOULD RATHER SHOP
SOMEWHERE WITH MORE NAME
RECOGNITION, THEY LIKE PIER
1.COM.
WE FOUND ENDEDIAN GRAFTED
CANDLES FOR $8.
>> THEY HAVE UNIQUE THINGS AT
VERY LOW PRICE POINTS.
>> DON'T FORGET ABOUT ALL YOUR
MOM AND POP SHOPS.
IT'S NICE TO SHOPPING AND BUNDLE
UP.
IT'S SO COLD.
>> MAKE YOU SHOP FASTER.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
DEFINITELY COLD OUT THERE.
BIG STORY SO FAR.
GOOD MORNING.
WE'LL TAKE A LOOK OUTSIDE FROM
SUTRO TOWER.
VISIBILITY PRETTY MUCH UNLIMITED
RIGHT NOW AS WE LOOK OFF TOWARDS
THE EAST OF THE JUST RECEIVED A
TWEET FROM JOHN FROM SANTA ROSA.
YOU SAY NO RAIN REACHING THE
GROUND HERE BUT IT IS DEFINITELY
COLD.
JUST TO LET YOU HOW COLD IT WAS
UP THERE.
THAT IS THE POWER OF TWITTER AND
FACEBOOK AND ALL THE SOCIAL
MEDIA.
WE SURE APPRECIATE THAT.
LIVE DOPPLER SHOWING SOME OF IT
FALLING BUT EVAPORATING BEFORE
IT REACHES THE GROUND.
EVEN IN SAN FRANCISCO SHOWING
RADAR RETURNS BUT AIR IS TOO
DRY.
WE HAVE A LOT OF VERGA OUT THERE
AND BECAUSE OF THE CLOUDS ARE
TAKING OVER, WE HAVE STOPPED THE
COOLING.
WE'RE AT THE FROSTY TEMPERATURES
RIGHT NOW.
EAST BAY VALLEYS AND COULD BE
THERE UNTIL 8:00.
THAT IS WHEN THEY WILL LET THE
FROST ADVISORY GO.
LIVERMORE 32, NOW IT'S 34 THAT
IS THE POWER OF THE CLOUD COVER.
IT STOPS THE COOLING.
REDWOOD CITY, 36, NOW 38.
HASN'T MADE IT TO THE SOUTH BAY
BUT JUST ABOUT THERE.
OAKLAND IS 43.
SAN FRANCISCO UP FROM 43.
AROUND THE MONTEREY BAY, NO
CLOUDS HERE YET.
GILROY, FROSTY AND WATSON
VPVILLE, 46.
HERE IS WHAT WILL HAPPEN.
BEST CHANCE OF RAIN IS CLOSER TO
THE OCEAN.
MORE CHANCES NEXT WEEK.
HERE IS WHAT IS HAPPENING.
FIRST SYSTEM COMING ON DOWN.
YOU CAN SEE THE CLOUD COVER WITH
IT.
IT'S A VERY THIN BUT IT'S NOT
GOING LAST VERY LONG.
THERE IS TONIGHT'S WEATHER AND
TOMORROW'S WEATHER AS YOU GO OFF
TO THE WEST, LEFT SIDE OF THE
SCREEN THERE IS ANOTHER SYSTEM
THAT WILL COME IN FOR NEXT WEEK.
5:00 IN THE MORNING, MOST OF THE
RADAR RETURNS, THIS SIDE OF
SCREEN.
MOST OF THE RADAR RETURNS ARE
STAYING OUT OVER THE OCEAN.
THAT IS WHERE OUR BEGS CHANCES,
AS WE HEAD TOWARDS NOON, FAST
MOVING SYSTEM.
SCATTERED SHOWER POSSIBLE DURING
THE AFTERNOON HOURS, BY THE
EVENING HOURS, NEED THE HEAVY
COAT AS TEMPERATURES WILL BE
DROPPING BACK INTO THE 30s AND
40s.
CLOUD COVER COMING IN FOR
TOMORROW MORNING, BETTER CHANCE
OF RAIN BY 11:00.
THEN SCATTERED LIGHT RAIN DURING
THE EVENING HOURS AND SCATTERED
LIGHT RAIN FOR SUNDAY.
KEEP THE WET WEATHER GEAR HANDY.
TEMPERATURES WILL WARM UP MID TO
UPPER 50s BY SUNDAY WITH ANOTHER
CHANCE OF RAIN.
>> NICE DRIVE IF YOU ARE
TRAVELING NORTHBOUND 280 OUT OF
SAN JOSE PAST HIGHWAY 17.
JUNCTION HERE AND ON INTO
CUPERTINO, SERVICING AT THE
LIMIT.
JUST A FEW HEADLIGHTS MAKING IT
NORTHBOUND.
FEW MORE CARS COMING THROUGH AND
NO PROBLEMS THE INCLINE.
CAN'T LEER SECTION THROUGH THE
TUNNEL AND WESTERN SPAN ALL
LOOKING GOOD.
DUMBARTON, ROAD WORK UNTIL 6:00.
YOU CAN SEE A LITTLE BIT OF SLOW
TRAFFIC ON THE NEWARK SIDE OF
THINGS.
ELSEWHERE, ROAD WORK ON THE
PENINSULA THAT IS GOING TO WRAP
UP AT 6:00.
NORTHBOUND 101 BETWEEN 92 AND
THIRD.
>> 5:21.
HOW ONE OF THE MOST FAMOUS
PIANOS COULD BE YOURS.
>> AND SURPRISING ENCOUNTER, THE
KAYAKERS WHO GOT
>>> 12-YEAR-OLD GIRL IS BEING
HAILED AS A HERO FOR SAVING HER
BEST FRIEND'S MOM DURING A
DOMESTIC VIOLENCE FIGHT.
>> MY FRIEND'S MOM IS TEASING
HER.
>> THAT WAS SKAY LAR WITH A
EMERGENCY DISPATCHER IN CONCORD.
SHE RECEIVED A LOCAL 911 HERO
AWARD.
AFTER HER FRIEND WAS KNOCKED TO
THE GROUND.
SHE RAN TO A NEARBY HOUSE TO
CALL POLICE.
THE PERSONAL TRAGEDY MADE HER
ACT DESPITE HER FEAR.
>> THE MOM, I'M NOT GOING TO
WATCH MY FRIEND'S MOM DIE.
>> SHE GAVE A GREAT JOB GIVING
ME ALL THE INFORMATION.
SHE DID A REALLY GOOD JOB.
>> THE DISPATCHER WHO ANSWERED
THE CALL WAS ALSO HONORED.
>>> THAT IS GREAT.
TIME FOR A LOOK AT THE FORECAST.
YEAH, YOU MIGHT ENCOUNTERED
FROST AS YOU HEAD IT ON THE
DOOR.
>> YOU NEED TO BE ASHAMED OF
YOURSELF NOT TO BE ABLE TO FIND
YOUR SCRAPER.
>> ONE THING I SHOULD BE ASHAMED
ABOUT.
IT WOULD TAKE A WHOLE SHOW.
>> WE'LL CHARGE YOU MORE THAN A
NICKEL FOR YOUR THERAPY.
LET'S MOVE ON.
GOOD MORNING EVERYBODY.
THEY ARE GOING TO BE 40s WHERE
IT WILL BE COOLEST THIS MORNING.
RECORD COLD-HIGH TEMPERATURES
FOR THIS TIME OF THE YEAR.
MOST OF THEM COME FROM 1972 AND
LOW 40s.
SYSTEM COMING DOWN THE COAST.
THERE WILL BE SCATTERED SNOW
SHOWERS IN THE SIERRA TODAY AND
MOST OF RAIN STAYS OFF THE COAST
UNTIL IT GETS DOWN TO SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA WHERE WE GET A FEW
SHOWERS.
LAKE TAHOE FORECAST, LOOK AT THE
LOWS IN SINGLE DIGITS THE NECK
COUPLE OF NIGHTS.
SNOW WILL START SATURDAY NIGHT
AND SEE A FEW INCHES OF POWDER
TO SKI ON.
>> NO CHAIN REQUIREMENTS FOR 50
AND 80.
THAT IS GOOD NEWS.
BAY BRIDGE, TRAVEL IS LIGHT AT
5:25 IN THE MORNING, NO METERING
LIGHTS SO FAR.
SAME WITH GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE
COMING SOUTHBOUND, FOUR LANES
FOR YOUR COMMUTE.
CLEAR SAILING OFF THE WALDO
GRADE AND THROUGH THE WALDO
TUNNEL.
ROAD WORK EASTBOUND 4 CLOSED AT
LEVY RIDGE.
WESTBOUND IS STAG TO SLOW OUT OF
ANTIOCH AND WE HAVE A PROBLEM
FOR SAN FRANCISCO VAN NESS AT
FELL.
POLICE ARE WORKING AND THE
INTERSECTION IS BLOCKED OFF.
>>> IF YOU ARE A FAN OF
CASABLANCA, CHANCE TO PLAY IT
AGAIN.
ONE OF TWO PIANOGS WILL BE
AUCTIONED OFF TODAY IN NEW YORK.
IT IS EXPECTED TO SELL FOR MORE
THAN JUST A SONG.
YOU RUSS REMEMBER THIS.
THEY HOPE TO FETCH $1.2 MILLION.
>> YOU'LL REMEMBER THIS ONE.
A GROUP OF KAYAKERS GOT AN
UNEXPECTED ENCOUNTER WITH
DANGEROUS CREATURES.
CHECK IT OUT.
IT SHOWS THE KAYAKERS GETTING
VERY CLOSE LOOK AT A POT OF
MIGRATING ORCAS.
>> OH, MY GOD!
>> THEY SOUNDED EXCITED.
THE WHALES SAM RIGHT AROUND
KAYAK AND UNDER THE KAYAKS, I
DON'T HAVE TO IMAGINE THAT.
>> IT HAPPENED TO YOU.
WHAT WAS IT LIKE.
>> THEY WERE COMING AT ME AND
THEY DISAPPEARED RIGHT IN FRONT
OF ME.
IT MAKES YOU A LITTLE NERVOUS.
A FEW SECONDS THEY EMERGED WAY
BEHIND ME.
I WAS JUST HOLDING ON FOR DEAR
LIFE.
NO VIDEO.
>> FLAMES RECIPIENT THROUGH A
BUSINESS IN THE EAST BAY.
WHAT INVESTIGATORS ARE SAYING
ABOUT THE POSSIBLE CAUSE AND THE
CLUES THEY WILL BE LOOKING FOR
THIS MORNING.
>> NEW THIS MORNING, SURPRISING
ADMISSION FROM PG&E ABOUT AN
♪Me and you -
a little rendezvous.♪
♪That special something that
will carry you through...♪
♪that little reward for
all the things you do.♪
Luscious, creamy filling -
combined with our slow
melting chocolate -
>> Kristen: THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR WAKING UP AND JOINING US.
I'M KRISTEN SZE.
>> Eric: HOUR ADVICE IS TO
BUNDLE UP.
>> Kristen: PULL THE COMFORTER
OVER YOU.
IT IS COLD OUT THERE.
>> IT DEFINITELY IS BECAUSE THE
COLD AIR AND VERY QUIET.
WE HAVEN'T HAD ANY REPORTS OF
MAKING IT DOWN TO THE GROUND.
THIS IS BLUES AND GREENS AND
DRIZZLE TO LIGHT RAIN.
THAT IS EVAPORATING BEFORE IT
REACHES THE GROUND.
IT IS THE CLOUD COVER AND
STARTING TO BRING TEMPERATURES
UP JUST A LITTLE BIT.
YOU CAN HAVE A SPRINKLE FROM THE
BAY BRIDGE ALL THE WAY 101 TO
HEALDSBURG THIS MORNING.
TEMPERATURES MID M I HAD TO
UPPER 30s INLAND AND WE'RE NOT
GOING VERY FAR TODAY.
ONLY TO NEAR 50 AT THE COAST
WHERE WE HAVE THE BEST CHANCE OF
RAIN, 53 AROUND THE BAY WITH
LIMITED RAIN AND MAINLY CHILLY
INLAND 49 DEGREES.
>> LIGHT TRAFFIC ON THE EAST
SHORE FREEWAY AS YOU MAKE YOUR
WAY RICHMOND AND TO O THROUGH
BERKELEY.
A LITTLE BIT OF SLOWING AS YOU
PASS THE 580 MERGE.
EASTBOUND 580 AT GREENVILLE,
ROAD WORK, THREE LANES BLOCKED
THERE.
WESTBOUND IS LOOKING PRETTY GOOD
AS YOU MAKE YOUR WAY TOWARDS THE
DUBLIN INTERCHANGE ON 580 WEST.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT ABC WAZE
APP, VAN NESS AT FELL.
SLOW TRAFFIC ON FELL STREET.
YOU MIGHT WANT TO NAVIGATE
AROUND THAT.
WASEAPP IS FREE AND IT WILL HELP
YOU NAVIGATE YOUR COMMUTE.
>>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
NEW THIS MORNING, TWO
EARTHQUAKES OR POSSIBLY ONE,
THERE IS SOME CONFUSION ABOUT
THIS NOW.
HIT OFF THE COAST OF SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA, THEY STRUCK AT 2:36
THIS MORNING.
ORIGINALLY REPORTED AT 6.4 AND
6.1.
IF THERE ARE TWO EARTHQUAKES
THEY HAVE BEEN DOWNGRADED TO 6.3
AND 4.7 WHICH THEY CONSIDER
LIGHT.
IT WAS CENTERED 88 MILES
SOUTHWEST OF CATALINA ISLAND.
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA SAYS THEY
WERE SHAKEN OUT OF BED BUT NO
REPORTS OF DAMAGE OR INJURIES.
>> FIRE INVESTIGATORS HOPE TO
GET THEIR FIRST LOOK INSIDE A
FREMONT MACHINE SHOP GUTTED BY A
MASSIVE FIRE.
AMY HOLLYFIELD IS LIVE AT THE
PLANT.
EMPLOYEES NEED TO KNOW WHEN THEY
WILL BE GOING BACK TO WORK
AGAIN?
>> THEY WILL NOT BE GOING INSIDE
THIS BUILDING ANYTIME SOON.
LOOK AT THE DAMAGE BEHIND ME.
THERE WILL BE A MEETING TODAY
WHERE EMPLOYEES WILL GET MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT WHETHER THEY
WILL BE ABLE TO START DOING
BUSINESS SOMEWHERE ELSE AND WHEN
THAT WILL START.
TAKE A LOOK AT HUGE FIRE THAT
STARTED BEFORE 2:00 YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON.
THIS WAS BOGGS AVENUE IN
FREMONT.
60 PEOPLE WERE INSIDE BUT ALL
MADE IT OUT OKAY.
FIREFIGHTERS FOUGHT THE FIRE
FROM THE OUTSIDE.
IT WAS JUST TOO DANGEROUS TO GO
IN.
>> EARLY IN THE FIRE, IT'S
UNSAFE TO GO IN UNTIL WE HAVE
DAYLIGHT AND BUILDING
CONSTRUCTION ENGINEERS AND KIND
OF STABILIZE FOR IT.
>> WE HAVE A GOOD INSURANCE
POLICY ON THE COMPANY.
THE BUSINESS WE DO FOR THE SEMI
CONDUCTOR INDUSTRY.
THE EMPLOYEES WILL BE COVERED AS
FAR AS THE LOSS SALARY AND WAGES
>> THEY MAKE COMPONENTS THAT IS
USED IN THE SEMI CONDUCTOR
INDUSTRY.
FIREFIGHTERS WERE CONCERNED
ABOUT THE HAZARDOUS MATERIALS
THAT COULD BE BURNING IN THIS
FIRE.
THEY ASKED EVERYONE IN THE AREA
TO PUT A SHELTER IN PLACE BUT IT
TURNED OUT IT WAS FINE BECAUSE
CHEMICALS HERE AND NO ONE WAS
HURT IN THIS FIRE.
TODAY, FIREFIGHTERS WILL TRY TO
FIGURE OUT WHAT STARTED THIS
WHILE THE COMPANY TRIES TO
FIGURE OUT WHERE THEY ARE GOING
TO GO FROM HERE.
>> Eric: THERE WILL BE EXTRA
SECURITY AT TWO SOUTH BAY
SCHOOLS WHEN THEY REOPEN THIS
MORNING.
SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT DECHGS WILL
BE ON HAND AT THE TWO SCHOOLS
AFTER A BOMB THREAT FORCE FORCED
CLOSURE YESTERDAY.
GRAFFITI SCRAWLED ON A WALL AT A
SCHOOL IN SAN JOSE CLAIMED THERE
WAS BOMB AT MONTEVISTA BUT THERE
WAS NO DEVICE FOUND.
THEY ARE MAKING SURE THE TEACHER
NAMED IN THE THREAT REMAINS
UNDER PROTECTION.
IN THE NEXT HALF-HOUR WE'LL GO
LIVE TO THE SCHOOL.
>> THAT YOU THIS MORNING, PG&E
IS RUSHING TO INSPECT MORE THAN
1500 PIECES OF UNDER GROUND
ELECTRICAL EQUIPMENT IN THE BAY
AREA FOR POSSIBLE SAFETY
HAZARDS.
THEY REPORT THIS COMES AFTER
REQUIRED INSPECTIONS TO HEAD OFF
DISASTROUS ACCIDENTS MAY NOT
HAVE BEEN PERFORMED.
PG&E HAS EXPERIENCED EXPLOSIONS
AND FIRES IN UNDER GROUND VAULTS
IN SAN FRANCISCO INCLUDING ONE
IN UNION SQUARE IN 2005 THAT
SENT A MANHOLE COVER INTO THE
AIR AND SERIOUSLY INJURING A
PASSERBY.
THEY SAY THEY HAVE FIRED THE
WORKERS WHO HAVE CLAIMED TO
INSPECTED EQUIPMENT WHEN THEY
ACTUALLY HAD NOT.
>> THE WOMAN ACCUSED OF
ABANDONING HER NEWBORN BABY IS
EXPECTED TO BE ARRAIGNED TODAY
ON CHARGES OF CHILD CRUELTY.
THEY FOUND THE BABY BOY LYING ON
A STREET.
THE MOM WAS NEARBY COVERED IN
BLOOD.
OFFICERS PERFORMED CPR ON THE
BABY WHILE RUSHING HIM TO SAN
FRANCISCO GENERAL HOSPITAL.
DOCTORS SAY THEY FOUND TRACES OF
COCAINE IN THE NEWBORN'S SYSTEM.
>> A SIXTH SUSPECT ACCUSED OF
SHOOTING THE VICTIMS.
STEVEN READ DIED AT HOSPITAL
HOURS AFTER HE AND HIS
GIRLFRIEND WERE FOUND TIED UP IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE STREET.
THEY BELIEVE THEY THE WERE
BRUTAL HOME INVASION SCAM.
19-YEAR-OLD TYLER MILLER IS
SCHEDULED TO BE ARRAIGNED AT
ONE-THIRD.
THE OTHER SUSPECTS ARE EXPECTED
IN COURT FOR THAT HEARING.
>> POLICE IN THE EAST BAY ARE
SEARCHING FOR SUSPECTS IN A 36
HOUR CRIME SIMPLY THAT TARGETED
PHARMACIES.
THEY HIT PHARMACIES IN DUBLIN
AND PLEASANTON.
IN EACH CASE, THE ROBBER HANDED
OVER A SIMILAR NOTE DEMANDING
PRESCRIPTION DRUGS AND CLAIMING
TO BE ARMED.
INVESTIGATORS SAY TWO OR MORE
PEOPLE WERE WORKING AS A TEAM.
>> WOMAN IS RECOVERING THIS
MORNING AFTER FALLING INTO THE
BAY AT EMBARCADERO IN SAN
FRANCISCO.
IT HAPPENED LAST NIGHT BETWEEN
THE WATERFRONT AND FERRY
BUILDING.
SHE WAS RESCUED QUICKLY BY FIRE
CREWS.
SHE APPEARED INTOXICATED.
SHE WAS TAKEN TO THE HOSPITAL AS
A PRECAUTION.
>> Eric: GOOD THING SHE WAS
RESCUED QUICKLY BECAUSE THE
WATER COULDN'T HAVE BEEN VERY
WARM OUT THERE.
>> Kristen: MIKE NICCO WILL LET
US KNOW WHO HAS THE COLDEST
TEMPERATURE.
>> IT BOB LIVERMORE AT 34 BUT
THERE ARE OTHER PEOPLE IN THAT
THEIR NEIGHBORS WHERE IT IS
COOLER.
29 AT ONE POINT ON MY DRIVE IN
ACCORDING TO THE THERMOMETER ON
MY CAR.
LIVE LOOK AT 7 HD, ANYBODY OUT
THERE ON TWITTER, LET ME KNOW
WHAT IS GOING ON IN YOUR
NEIGHBORHOOD AT FACEBOOK.
I WANTED TO THANK, JOHN DYSON HE
DID SEND IN A TWEET FROM SANTA
ROSA AND SAID IT IS COLD HERE.
NO RAIN FALLING YET.
A LOT IS STILL EVAPORATING.
BECAUSE OF THE LATE ARRIVAL OF
THE CLOUDS AND FROST, WE'LL HAVE
FROST POSSIBLE IN THE EAST BAY
AND VALLEYS, HOLLISTER AND ALSO
IN SALINAS.
CLOUDS ARE STARTING TO COME INTO
ALL OF OUR NEIGHBORHOODS AROUND
THE BAY.
THAT IS GOING TO LOCK OUR
TEMPERATURES IN.
LIVERMORE IS ONE OF THOSE, 32
AND 34 NOW.
WE'RE IN THE 30s TO MID 40s
THROUGH 7:00 WITH RAIN POSSIBLE.
TAPER AT NOON, AN ISOLATED
SHOWER WITH LOW 50s AT 4:00 AND
THEN CLEAR AND CHILLY 4 N THE
40s.
BETTER CHANCE OF RAIN FOR
TOMORROW AND THESE TEMPERATURES
WILL BE NEAR 60 BY MONDAY.
>> TAKE A LOOK AT SAN MATEO
BRIDGE, NO PROBLEMS UP TOWARDS
THE HIGH-RISE, OVER TOWARDS
FOSTER CITY, NO REPORTS OF
PROBLEMS THIS MORNING ON THE SAN
MATEO BRIDGE.
AT BAY BRIDGE, NO PROBLEMS BUT A
FEW CARS THERE BACKING UP
HEADING INTO SAN FRANCISCO.
EASTBOUND DUMBARTON BRIDGE,
ABOUT 20 MORE MINUTES WITH ONE
LANE GETTING BY.
NO PROBLEM WESTBOUND.
A LOOK AT SOME OF THE BUSIER
COMMUTES, COMING OFF ALTAMONT
PASS COMING OVER INTO DUBLIN AN
PLEASANTON.
EAST SHORE FREEWAY 20 MINUTES
INTO THE CARQUINEZ BRIDGE.
>> NEXT, THE CYBER CROOKS
PREPARING TO FUNNEL MONEY OUT OF
YOUR BANK ACCOUNT.
>> AND A NEW TWIST IN ALAMEDA'S
SUPERVISOR NADIA LOCK YEAR SEX
AND DRUG SCANDAL.
>>> ONE OF BAY AREA'S BIGGEST
POLITICAL SCANDALS OF 2012 HAS
TAKEN A MAJOR TURN.
WE HAVE LEARNED THAT FORMER
SUPERVISOR NADIA LOCK YEAR HAS
ALLOWED A RESTRAINING ORDER
AGAINST HER BOYFRIEND EXPIRE.
LOCK YEAR RESIGNED FROM THE
BOARD AFTER HE TALKED ABOUT THE
DRUG USE AND SEX TAPE.
SHE REMAINED IN DRUG REHAB SO AN
ATTORNEY APPEARED IN COURT
YESTERDAY.
>> THIS MAY BE A GOOD CHANCE
THIS MAY DIE HERE.
SHE WILL RECONSIDER HER OPTIONS
AND ONE OF THEM IS CONTINUE TO
PURSUE THIS OR LET MATTERS LIE
THE WAY THEY ARE AND MOVE ON
WITH THEIR LIFE.
>> THE I-TEAM ALSO LEARNED THE
PENDING DIVORCE BETWEEN HER AND
HER HUSBAND APPEARS TO BE ON
HOLD.
HE IS FOOTING THE BILL FOR HER
REHAB.
>> WELLS FARGO, CITIBANK, OR
CHASE, MAJOR BANKS ARE PLANNING
FOR A POSSIBLE CYBER ATTACK AND
IT COULD AFFECT YOUR ACCOUNTS.
SANTA CLARA BASED McAFEE IS
INVESTIGATING THE ATTACK.
THE PLAN IS FUNNELING MONEY OUT
OF BANK ACCOUNTS.
THEY HAVE DETECTED HUNDREDS OF
COMPUTERS WITH SOPHISTICATED
MALWARE MANUFACTURED IN RUSSIA.
>> IT WILL ACTIVATED AND WHAT IT
DOES IT REPLICATES OR CLONES
YOUR PC ON SERVE THEY ARE
RUSSIA.
ONCE THEY CLONE YOUR PC THEY TRY
TO LOG INTO THE BANK USING THOSE
CREDENTIALS.
>> THEY SAY THE PLAN LIKELY
INVOLVES TARGET PEOPLE OF HIGH
NET WORTH BUT ALL CUSTOMERS ARE
ADVISED TO MAKE SURE THEIR
ANTI-VIRUS SOFTWARE IS WORKING.
>> HERE IS JANE KING WITH THIS
MORNING'S BUSINESS REPORT.
>> A SOURCE SAYS BLOOMBERG TWO
DOZEN COMPANIES ARE BIDDING FOR
ALL OF ABRUPT HOSTESS BRAND.
IT MAY BAD NEWS FOR JEALOUS
SPOUSES, JUDICIARY COMMITTEE
THAT WOULD MAKE IT A CRIME FOR
COMPANIES TO MAKE STALKING APPS
BY LOCATIONS OF CELLPHONE.
IF YOU ARE LOOKING FOR A JOBS,
ONLINE ADS RECRUITERS RELY ON
SOCIAL WEBSITES TO FIND BETTER
OFFERS.
>> ARE YOU FEELING GENEROUS THIS
HOLIDAY SEASON?
ANSWER IS MORE LIKELY TO BE YES
IF YOU ARE GUY.
A NEW SURVEY 31% OF WOMEN PLAN
TO SPEND LESS ON HOLIDAY GIFTS.
ONLY 19% OF MEN FELT THAT WAY.
I'M JANE KING WITH THE BLOOMBERG
BUSINESS REPORT.
>>> AND ROYAL NEWS, THE QUEEN
AND DUKE WERE GIVEN A SPECIAL
TOUR OF THE BANK OF ENGLAND.
THE ROYAL COUPLE TOWARD VAULTS
PILED HIGH WITH GOLD BULLION
WORTH BILLIONS OF DOLLARS.
THEY INSPECTED SOME OF THE
SLABS.
THEY ALSO SIGNED A MILLION
DOLLAR.
IT WAS THEIR EIGHTH VISIT TO THE
BASK OF ENGLAND.
>> THOSE BRICKS ARE PRETTY
HEAVY.
I HEAR.
I WOULDN'T KNOW MYSELF.
>> IT'S COLD LOOK FOR THE
MORNING HOURS.
IT IS IMPROVING WITH THE CLOUD
COVER OUT THERE.
WE'LL SHOW YOU FROM VOLLMER PEAK
HOW CLEAR IT IS UNDER THE CLOUD
DECK.
WE'RE LOOKING AT LIVE DOPPLER
7-HD AND PICKING UP RADAR
RETURNS.
WE GET THE LIGHTED BLUES AND
SPRINKLES AND EVEN GREENS AND
POSSIBLY LIGHT RAIN.
SO FAR, NOT HITTING ANY OF THE
REPORTING STATIONS.
THE BEST I COULD SAY, MAYBE
SPRINKLES THIS MORNING FOR YOUR
COMMUTE.
THE CLOUDS ARE STARTING TO KEEP
THE TEMPERATURES UP WHICH IS
GOOD.
WE HAVE THIS CHANCE AND SEE THE
SPINNING MASS THAT IS ACTUALLY
DISSIPATING AS IT HEADS DOWN
FROM CRESCENT CITY TOWARDS US.
THAT IS ANOTHER PUSH THAT WILL
BRING US A CHANCE OF STRAY
SHOWER AS WE HEADED INTO THE
AFTERNOON HOURS.
LET'S TAKE ABOUT TEMPERATURES
THEN.
34 IN LIVERMORE.
35 IN NAPA AND SANTA ROSA, 36 IN
FAIRFIELD.
38 IN REDWOOD CITY.
36 IN LOS GATOS.
MOST OF THE TEMPERATURES ARE UP
FROM WHERE THEY WERE BECAUSE OF
THE CLOUD COVER.
DEFINITELY GOT THICK FROST
AROUND GILROY AND FROST THIS
MORNING WAS THICKER THAN IT WAS
YESTERDAY MORNING.
MADE MID THAT UPPER 30s IN
SALINAS AND 41 IN MONTEREY.
LET'S TALK ABOUT TODAY.
TODAY'S RAIN IS BEST OVER THE
OCEAN SO THE CLOSER YOU ARE TO
THE BEACHES MORE LIKELY WILL YOU
YOU'LL GET SOME OF THE RAIN.
BETTER CHANCE TOMORROW.
COUPLE MORE CHANCES STILL
LOOKING UNSETTLED FOR NEXT WEEK.
HERE IS A LOOK AT THE COLD FRONT
HOW QUICKLY IT IS MOVING DOWN
TOWARDS US, IT MOVES OUT THERE.
>> IS A SMALL WINDOW THIS
MORNING.
WE HAVE A COUPLE OF STORM
SYSTEMS RIDING THE JETSTREAM ON
THE WAY TOWARDS US.
NEXT SYSTEMS, COMING A LITTLE
MORE FROM THE WEST THAN THEY ARE
FROM THE NORTHWEST.
IT MEANS WE'LL START TO MODIFY
THE AIR MASS.
IT WON'T BE SO COLD THE NEXT
COUPLE OF DAYS.
5:00 IN THE MORNING, WE HAVE A
LOT OF CLOUD COVER OUT HERE.
AS WE HEAD TOWARDS THE LATTER
PARTS OF MORNING INTO THE
AFTERNOON HOURS, YOU CAN SEE THE
STEADY RAIN GONE, JUST A FEW
SHOWERS.
WE'LL SEE SUNSHINE DURING THE
AFTERNOON HOURS.
BECAUSE OF THE CLEAR SKY TONIGHT
ANOTHER CHILLY NIGHT BEFORE THE
CLOUDS COME IN AROUND 8:00 THIS
MORNING.
YOU CAN SEE THE RAIN STARTING TO
ROLL IN AROUND 11:00 AND JUST
SCATTERED LIGHT RAIN THROUGH THE
AFTERNOON AND INTO THE EVENING
HOURS.
IT WILL TAPER OVER NIGHT THROUGH
SUNDAY MORNING AND AS WE HEAD
INTO SUNDAY AFTERNOON, ANOTHER
CHANCE OF SCATTERED, LIGHT RAIN.
BY THEN TEMPERATURES WILL BE
JUMP IN THE 40s TO 50s AND MID
TO UPPER 50s AND 60 BY SUNDAY
MONDAY WITH ANOTHER CHANCE OF
RAIN.
>> SAN JOSE RIGHT NOW, DRIVE
TAKES YOU NORTHBOUND 280, PAST
HIGHWAY 17.
17 COMING OUT OF SANTA CRUZ
MOUNTAINS, NO PROBLEMS ON 17.
NO PROBLEMS ON 280 JUST A FEW
HEADLIGHTS GOING TOWARDS THE
CUPERTINO DIRECTION.
FROM NOVATO OUT OF SAN RAFAEL,
LUCAS VALLEY ROAD, AND MARIN
YMCA AND PAST THE CIVIC CENTER,
FOG FREE THIS MORNING.
NO DELAYS TO THE GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE.
580, WE HAVE THREE LANES BLOCKED
UNTIL 9:00 WITH CONSTRUCTION.
WESTBOUND DIRECTION STARTING TO
SLOW.
THAT IS NORMAL COMPUTE CAN YOU
TELL XHOOTD 20 MINUTES FROM THE
ALTAMONT.
TAKING A LOOK AT WAZE APP,
SHOWING SAN FRANCISCO CITY
STREETS, VAN NESS AT FELL WHERE
THEY ARE REPORTING AN ACCIDENT.
>> TWO POLICE OFFICERS IN MEXICO
HAVE BEEN ARRESTED FOR STEALING
EVIDENCE FROM THE SITE WHERE
SINGER JENNI RIVERA'S PLANE
CRASHED IN MEXICO.
THE ITEMS WERE FOUND AT THE
OFFICER'S HOMES.
LAST NIGHT A CAR CARRIED KAERG
HER REMAINS WERE GIVEN A POLICE
ESCORTED IN THE TOWN OF LONG
BEACH.
DRUG ENFORCEMENT IS
INVESTIGATING THE COMPANY THAT
OWNS THE LUXURY JET THAT CRASHED
AND KILLED THE POP SUPERSTAR.
STARWOOD MANAGEMENT HAD TWO
PLANES SEIZED THIS YEAR.
>> A JUDGE HAS RECEIVED A PUBLIC
ADMONISHMENT STEMMING FROM
COMMENTS HE MADE THIS FROM THE
BENCH ABOUT A RAPE VICTIM.
ORANGE COUNTY SUPERIOR JUDGE GOT
HIMSELF A HOT WATER, I'M NOT A
GYNECOLOGIST, IF SOMEONE DOESN'T
WANT TO HAVE SEXUAL INTERCOURSE
THE BODY SHUTS DOWN.
HE SAID THAT WHETHER HE
SENTENCED THE VICTIM'S EX-BIOV
BACK IN 2008.
PROSECUTORS WANTED A 15 YEAR
SENTENCE.
>> COMING UP, BART HAS YOUR
BACK.
MEET THE PEOPLE WHO WILL BE
KEEPING YOU SAFER DURING THE
HOLIDAYS.
>> THINKING ABOUT GOING OUT FOR
AN EARLY MORNING JOB?
WHY YOU MIGHT WANT
>>> SOME BART RIDERS TOOK
ADVANTAGE OF THE EFFORT TO KEEP
FOLKS SAFE.
THEY PROVIDED FREE ES COURT'S
FOR PEOPLE WALKING TO THEIR
CARS.
THE ESCORTS GAVE THEM AN EXTRA
SENSE OF SECURITY ESPECIALLY
SINCE IT GETS DARKER THIS TIME
OF YEAR.
>> PEOPLE FOR THE HOLIDAYS, IT'S
BETTER TO BE SAFE THAN SORRY.
>> YOU ARE ON YOUR CELLPHONE AND
NOT PAYING ATTENTION, YOU COULD
BECOME A VICTIM OF A CRIME OF
OPPORTUNITY.
>>> BART POLICE POINT OUT THEY
ALSO WALK ESCORTS YEAR ROUND AT
ALL STATION.
ALL YOU HAVE TO DO IS ALASKA
BART STATION FOR HELP OR.
>> WE HAVE BEEN TALKING ABOUT
POTENTIAL FROST ON THE WIND
WINDSHIELD.
>> THEY HAVE TO BE GETTING COLD.
>> HOPEFULLY YOU BROUGHT THE
PLANTS IN AND BROUGHT PETS BRING
IN FRESH WATER IN CASE IT
FREEZES.
JUST GOT A NOTE FROM CHRISTINE
SMITH IN LAKE PORTED, A TWEET
FROM HER, IT'S CLOUDY BUT NO
RAIN.
TEMPERATURES IN THE 40s IN
INLAND VALLEYS.
LOW 50s AND HOW RAIN IS GOING IN
TWO SPURTS AND CHAPS OF
SPRINKLES THIS MORNING.
CHANCE OF A SCATTERED SHOWER AND
BETTER CHANCE ON SUNDAY.
>> A LITTLE BUSIER AT BAY BRIDGE
TOLL PLAZA.
NO METERING LIGHTS.
YOU CAN SEE THE FASTRAK ARE A
WHIZZING ON BY.
FIRST REPORTS OF A STALL 680 AT
SOUTH MYZ BLOCKING THE OFF-RAMP
IN THE OAKLAND AREA.
A LOOK AT YOUR DRIVE OUT OF
ANTIOCH IS SLOWING AS YOU MAKE
YOUR WAY TOWARDS HILLCREST.
JUST ABOUT 20 MINUTE DRIVE.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, THE SENATE
IS TURNING ITS ATTENTION TO A
$60 BILLION DISASTER AID PACKAGE
FOR SUPER STORM SANDY VICTIMS.
THEY WILL DEBATE THE BILL ON
MONDAY BUT REPUBLICANS ARE
LOOKING AT A SMALLER PACKAGE TO
COVER IMMEDIATE NEEDS.
THEY ARE WAITING FOR MORE
DETAILED EVIDENCE FOR DAMAGE ON
ADDITIONAL SPENDING.
NEW YORK CITY TEACHERS' UNION
ARE PLEDGING A BILLION DOLLARS
TO HELP REPAIR ROADS AND BRIDGES
AND OTHER DAMAGED
INFRASTRUCTURE.
>> IF YOU ARE AN EARLY RISER TO
GET THE WORK OUT, IT MAY BE BEST
IN THE AFTERNOON.
THEY THOUGHT THEY WOULD SEE THE
BEST RESULTS FROM MORNING
EXERCISE, INSTEAD THEY FOUND
MICE THAT RAN LATER PRODUCED
MORE PROTEINS.
PREVIOUS STUDIES HAVE LINKED
DISRUPTIONS IN OUR BODY CLOCKS
TO INCREASED RISK OF OBESITY,
DEPRESSION, MEMORY LOSS,
DIABETES AND EVEN CERTAIN TYPES
OF CANCER.
>> A NEW STUDY SHOWS THE
FEELINGS YOU HAVE WHEN QUITTING
JUNK FOOD IS SIMILAR TO BRAG
DRUG HABIT.
RESEARCHERS SAY A HIGH FAT DIET
CAUSES CHEMICAL CHANGES IN YOUR
BRAIN AND THEY COULD LEAD TO
STRESS AND WITHDRAWAL SYMPTOMS.
THE CHEMICALS ARE SIMILAR TO
THOSE IN HUMAN BRAINS.
THE STUDY IS IN THE
INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF
OBESITY.
IT MIGHT BE HARD TO BREAK AT
FIRST BUT ONCE YOU DO IT THE
HORRIBLE FEELINGS WILL PASS,
RIGHT.
>> THAT IS WHAT I HEAR.
NEW LAWS AROUND THE CORNER FOR
CAB HOW THEY WILL PROTECT
PASSENGERS.
>> AND HOW STAKES GAME OF
MUSICAL CHAIRS.
WHO IS LINING UP FOR SECRETARY
OF STATE AFTER A MAJOR CANDIDATE
DROPS OUT.
>> AND HOW A COMMON HOUSEHOLD
APPLIANCE IS CLAIMING THE LIVES
OF CHILDREN ON AN AVERAGE ONCE
EVERY THREE WEEKS.
>>> THIS MORNING, FREMONT FIRE
INVESTIGATORS WILL TRY TO FIND
OUT WHY A COMPANY WENT UP IN
FLAMES.
>> STUDENTS HEAD BACK TO CLASS
WITH EXTRA SECURITY IN CUPERTINO
FOLLOWING A BOMB THREAT
YESTERDAY.
>> U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE IS
SCHEDULED TO MEET WITH PRESIDENT
OBAMA TODAY.
SHE SURPRISED WASHINGTON
YESTERDAY WHEN SHE TOOK HERSELF
OUT OF THE RUNNING FOR SECRETARY
OF STATE AND NOW NEW NAMES ARE
EMERGING.
>> GOOD MORNING.
I'M KRISTEN SZE.
IT'S 6:00.
>> Eric: I'M ERIC THOMAS.
IS IT COLD OUT THERE.
YOU THOUGHT IT WAS COLD
YESTERDAY.
MIKE CHECK OUT THIS.
>> FOG IS THICKER BUT CLOUDS ARE
STARTING TO SPREAD ACROSS OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS AND HOLDING OUR
TEMPERATURES IF NOT LETTING THEM
RISE A LITTLE BIT.
HERE IS THE REASON WHY WE HAVE
THE CLOUD COVER.
GOT MOISTURE IN THE AIR.
I HAVEN'T HEARD A SINGLE REPORT