FRIENDS ARE DEAD.
>> AND WE ARE NOW SEEING THE
FACES OF THE YOUNG VICTIMS AS
ONE FATHER STEPS FORWARD.
>> MY DAUGHTER EMILIE WOULD BE
ONE OF THE FIRST ONES TO GIVE
HER LOVE AND SUPPORT TO ALL
THOSE VICTIMS.
BECAUSE THAT'S THE TYPE OF
PERSON SHE IS.
>> Announcer: THIS IS A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA," "TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL," LIVE FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
CONNECTICUT.
>> AND GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
I'M HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, CONNECTICUT, BEHIND
ME THE SANDY HOOK FIRE
DEPARTMENT, BIANNA GOLODRYGA IS
BACK IN NEW YORK.
SHE WILL JOIN US SHORTLY.
WITH ME HERE THIS MORNING MY
WEEKDAY COLLEAGUE LARA SPENCER
AND AMY ROBACH.
>> DAN, EVEN MORE SADNESS AS THE
DEAD ARE IDENTIFIED WE'RE SEEING
THE FACES OF THOSE SO VERY YOUNG
VICTIMS.
I'M GOING TO HAVE THAT STORY.
IT'S A REALLY TOUGH ONE BUT IT'S
AN IMPORTANT ONE SO WE CAN
REMEMBER THOSE WHO SPENT SO MUCH
TIME IN THAT SCHOOL AND WERE
LOVED BY SO MANY.
>> LARA, YOU HAVE A STORY COMING
UP.
>> AS THE HEALING HAS BEGUN, THE
FOLKS ARE PULLING TOGETHER
TRYING TO OVERCOME THIS
UNIMAGINABLE TRAGEDY AND I'LL
HAVE THAT REPORT.
>> WELL, THOSE STORIES COMING UP
BUT TO THE LATEST NEWS.
AS WE SAID PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL
ARRIVE IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
TONIGHT, HE'LL BE MEETING WITH
THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS
THANKING FIRST RESPONDERS AND
SPEAKING AT AN INTERSTATE VIGIL.
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME IN FOUR
YEARS THIS PRESIDENT HAS PAID A
VISIT AFTER A MASS SHOOTING.
ALSO THIS MORNING POLICE HAVE
NOW RELEASED THIS LIST OF THE
VICTIMS.
LOOK CLOSELY AT THE AGES.
2004, 2006.
JOSEPHINE GAY JUST HAD HER
SEVENTH BIRTHDAY LAST TUESDAY.
ONE CALLED IT THE SADDEST PIECE
OF PAPER EVER PRINTED.
THE FAMILIES ARE RELEASING
PICTURES OF THE CHILDREN THEY
LOST.
AS THE WRITER OF THE ASSOCIATE
PRESS PUT IT, THEY STILL HAD
THEIR BABY DOOET.
>> ADAM LANZA'S FATHER SAYS "WE
ARE STILL IN DISBELIEF.
WE TOO ARE ASKING WHY."
SOURCES SAY NO NOTE OR MANIFESTO
HAS BEEN FOUND.
ALSO HIS MOTHER HAD NO
CONNECTION TO THE SCHOOL.
AND THIS MORNING AMERICANS ARE
HONORING THE VICTIMS.
EVERY NFL TEAM WILL OBSERVE A
MOMENT OF SILENCE.
THE GIANTS AND PATRIOTS WILL
PLAY WITH SPECIAL DECALS ON
THEIR HELMETS.
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE," THE
CHILDREN'S CHOIR SINGING "SILENT
NIGHT."
ALSO THIS MORNING FOR THE FIRST
TIME WE'RE HEARING HOW ONE
LITTLE GIRL SURVIVED THE
MASSACRE AND MY COLLEAGUE LARA
IS BACK NOW WITH THAT STORY.
INCREDIBLE STORY.
>> UNBELIEVABLE STORY.
16 KIDS IN THIS CLASSROOM.
ONE SURVIVED.
I SPOKE LAST NIGHT WITH THE
PASTOR WHO HAS BEEN COUNSELING
THIS LITTLE GIRL'S MOTHER.
A HARROWING STORY OF HOW A FIRST
GRADER LIVED BY PLAYING DEAD.
>> YOU HAVE ONE PARISHIONER WHO
WAS RIGHT THERE, A LITTLE GIRL,
A FIRST GRADER.
>> SHE WAS THE FIRST STUDENT WHO
RAN OUT OF THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL, 6 1/2 YEARS OLD.
SHE RAN OUT OF THE SCHOOL
BUILDING COVERED IN BLOOD FROM
HEAD TO TOE AND THE FIRST WORDS
SHE SAID TO HER MOM WHEN SHE GOT
OUTSIDE WAS, MOMMY, I'M OKAY,
BUT ALL MY FRIENDS ARE DEAD.
SOMEHOW IN THAT MOMENT GOD'S
GRACE WAS ABLE TO ACT AS IF SHE
WAS ALREADY --
>> WAS SHE THE ONLY ONE IN THAT
CLASS THAT SURVIVED.
>> YI, OF THOSE WHO WERE LEFT IN
THE CLASSROOM OF FIRST GRADERS
SHE WAS THE LONE SURVIVOR.
>> WHAT HAS SHE TOLD HER MOM?
WHAT DID SHE SEE IN THERE.
>> WELL, SHE SAW SOMEONE WHO SHE
FELT WAS ANGRY AND SOMEBODY WHO
SHE FELT WAS VERY MAD.
>> HOW AT 6 1/2 YEARS OLD CAN
YOU BE THAT SMART, THAT BRAVE?
>> I THINK IT'S IMPOSSIBLE
OUTSIDE OF DIVINE INTERVENTION.
SHE HAS WISDOM BEYOND HER YEARS.
>> HOW ARE THE MOM AND DAD
DOING?
>> I THINK AS WELL AS YOU CAN
EXPECT THEM TO DO.
>> THEY MUST BE RELIEVED TO HAVE
THEIR CHILD BUT --
>> THE MOM TOLD ME THAT SHE WAS
SUFFERING FROM WHAT SHE CALLED
SURVIVOR'S GUILT BECAUSE SO MANY
OF THEIR FRIENDS NO LONGER HAVE
THEIR CHILDREN BUT SHE HAS HERS.
>> A LONG ROAD AHEAD.
AN INCREDIBLE STORY OF SURVIVAL
AND ALL BY A 6-YEAR-OLD GIRL.
DAN?
>> AND HER FAMILY WITH
SURVIVOR'S GUILT, NO DOUBT
DEALING WITH THAT FOR AWHILE.
THANK YOU FOR THAT.
>>> A FEW MOMENTS AGO I SPOKE
WITH BILL HART, A SPOKESPERSON
FOR THE NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
BOARD OF EDUCATION.
HERE'S WHAT HE HAD TO SAY.
>> THE PLAN IS TO RE-OPEN THE
SCHOOLS ON TUESDAY.
WHY IS IT SO IMPORTANT TO GET
THINGS MOVING AGAIN.
>> WELL, ALL THE MENTAL HEALTH
EXPERTS WE TALKED TO AND THE
STATE HAS DONE A WONDERFUL JOB
OF BRINGING IN SOME HELP TELL US
IT'S THE BEST THING TO DO TO GET
BACK TO NORMAL OPERATIONS AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
BEST FOR THE CHILDREN AND FOR
THE STAFF AND FOR THE COMPLUPTS.
>> WHAT DO YOU DO WITH THE
STUDENTS WHO ARE ENROLLED AT
THIS ELEMENTARY SCHOOL?
>> WELL, THIS SCHOOL HERE, WE'RE
CLEARLY NOT GOING TO BE IN THIS
BUILDING ANY TIME IN THE
FORESEEABLE FUTURE BUT CLOSE TO
A PLAN TO MOVE THE COMMUNITY
TO -- THE SCHOOL COMMUNITY TO
ANOTHER LOCATION.
THOSE DETAILS WILL PROBABLY COME
OUT TODAY.
I'M NOT REALLY PREPARED TO
REALLY SAY BUT WE KNOW IT'LL
WORK.
>> DO YOU THINK YOU CAN EVER
RE-OPEN THIS SCHOOL AND WHAT
WOULD YOU SAY TO PARENTS WHO SAY
I NEVER WANT TO SEND MY CHILD --
>> I WOULD PROBABLY FEEL VERY
MUCH THE SAME WAY.
MY THREE DAUGHTERS WENT TO THIS
SCHOOL AND WE HAVE MANY MEMORIES
THERE.
I THINK TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO WITH THAT
IS A LONG PROCESS AND, YOU KNOW,
WE'RE NOT ANYWHERE PREPARED TO
MAKE THOSE DECISIONS NOW.
>> YOU TALKED ABOUT THE
IMPORTANCE OF RE-ESTABLISHING
ROUTINE BUT IT'S GOING TO BE
HARD TO DO IN THIS ATMOSPHERE.
WHAT KIND OF SPECIAL ALLOWANCES
WILL YOU TAKE FOR THE STAFF AND
STUDENTS WHO ARE REALLY HURTING
AS YOU TRY TO REESTABLISH --
>> WE BROUGHT IN MENTAL HEALTH
PROFESSIONALS FROM ALL OVER THE
STATE AND HAVE SPECIAL TRAINING
FOR PEOPLE AND KNOW SOME OF THE
TEACHERS MIGHT NOT BE PREPARED
TO COME BACK AND BE PREPARED
WITH SUBSTITUTES AND COUNSELING
FOR ALL THE PEOPLE.
WE'VE PREPARED TO DO WHATEVER WE
HAVE TO DO TO HELP ALL OF OUR
COMMUNITY.
>> WE KEEP HEARING THESE STORIES
OF THE VALOR DISPLAYED BY THE
PRINCIPAL AT THIS ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND ALSO SOME OF THE
TEACHERS.
WHAT ARE YOUR THOUGHTS ON THAT.
>> WELL, I THINK WE HAD --
THAT'S REALLY THE BIG STORY
HERE.
THERE'S SOME INCREDIBLE HEROES
AND I THINK WHAT THEY DID MOVING
TO MOVE ALL THE CHILDREN TO SAFE
LOCATIONS AND GOING THROUGH OUR
LOCKDOWN LOCATION SAVED
COUNTLESS MORE LIVES.
THOSE TEACHERS, THE TAFF THAT
WERE THERE, THE FIRST RESPONDERS
WHO CAME IN, THEY'RE THE PEOPLE
WHO ARE THE REAL HEROES.
>> BILL HART, YOU SO A DIFFICULT
JOB AND I WISH YOU THE BEST.
>> THANK YOU, DAN.
>>> ONCE AGAIN OUR THANKS TO
BILL HART.
LET'S GET IT BACK TO NEW YORK
NOW AND BIANNA.
BIANNA, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> DAN, I'M STILL DEALING WITH
THAT SENTENCE YOU SAID, SO MANY
OF THESE VICTIMS STILL HAVE
THEIR BABY TEETH.
SO HARD HITTING.
AND WE ARE GETTING A MORE
COMPLETE PICTURE OF THE GUNMAN
AS POLICE TRY TO LEARN MORE
ABOUT WHY 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA
WENT ON HIS BLOODY RAMPAGE.
ABC'S CHIEF INVESTIGATIVE
CORRESPONDENT BRIAN ROSS IS HERE
WITH THE LATEST.
BRIAN, YOU'RE HAPPENING THE
WEAPONS HE USED WERE LIKELY
LICENSED TO HIS MOTHER WHO IS
DESCRIBED AS A GUN ENTHUSIAST.
>> CORRECT ACCORDING TO PEOPLE
ON THE SCENE.
AUTHORITIES ARE MOVING WITH MORE
DEVELOPMENTS LIKELY TO COME
TODAY IN THEIR EFFORTS TO
DETERMINE THE HOW AND THE WHY OF
THIS STUNNING CRIME.
POLICE SAY THEY HAVE ALREADY
FOUND IMPORTANT CLUES IN THEIR
HOME WHERE THE KILLER'S MOTHER,
52-YEAR-OLD NANCY LANZA WAS THE
FIRST VICTIM.
>> HOPEFULLY PAINTING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE AS TO HOW AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> Reporter: AUTHORITIES NOW SAY
NANCY LANZA OWNED THE SAME STYLE
OF GUNS THAT HER SON USED TO
KILL HER AND THE 26 VICTIMS AT
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER SAID MOST
WERE KILLED WITH MULTIPLE SHOTS
FROM THE HIGH-POURERED
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
>> THIS IS PROBABLY THE WORST I
HAVE SEEN.
>> THE CONNECTION BETWEEN ADAM
LANZA AND THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL GOES BACK TO
THE TIME HE WENT TO SCHOOL THERE
AND HIS MOTHER WORKED AS A
TEACHER'S AIDE.
ACCORDING TO ADD GAM'S AUNT.
>> I KNOW SHE HAD ISSUES WITH
SCHOOL.
SHE EVENTUALLY WOUND UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT AND WHAT TOOK PLACE I'M
NOT 100% CERTAIN IF IT WAS
BEHAVIOR.
>> Reporter: AS A FULLER PICTURE
OF ADAM LANZA BEGAN TO EMERGE
INCLUDING HIS MEMBERSHIP IN THE
TECH CLUB, HE WAS A SMART BUT
SOCIALLY AWKWARD STUDENT.
>> HE ALWAYS CARRIED A
BRIEFCASE.
>> Reporter: ADAM'S PARENTS
PETER AND NANCY LANZA WENT
THROUGH AN UNCONTESTED DIVORCE
AND ADAM'S AUNT SAID THAT NANCY
HAD PURCHASED SO MANY WEAPONS
BECAUSE SHE WAS CONCERNED FOR
HER SAFETY LIVING ALONE.
>> I THINK NO REASON WHY NANCY
MAY HAVE HAD THEM FOR
SELF-DEFENSE AND NO OTHER
REASON.
>> Reporter: FRIENDS HAVE TOLD
US THAT NANCY LANZA ENJOYED
TAKING HER SONS TO THE FIRING
RANGE FOR PRACTICE.
>> SHE COULD HAVE BEEN THERE
WHEN HE WAS LEARNING HOW TO
SHOOT THOSE GUNS.
>>> SO MANY VICTIMS TO TALK
ABOUT.
26 INNOCENT LIVES LOST AND, DAN,
I KNOW YOU HAVE MORE ON THAT.
>> YES, WE NOW KNOW THEIR NAMES.
THEY ARE SO YOUNG, ALL IN THE
FIRST GRADE, AUGUST OF THEM SHOT
MORE THAN ONCE BY A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
THEY'RE SAYING DEFENDANT WAS
SWIFT AND SAID THIS IS THE WORST
CASE HE EVER SEEN AND HOME
ROBACH IS MORE ON THIS.
THIS IS THE HARDEST PART.
>> DAN, IT'S SO TRUE.
EVERY DAY WE LEARN MORE ABOUT
THE VICTIMS AND THIS STORY JUST
GETS HARDER AND HARDER.
THIS MORNING WE KNOW THE NAMES.
WE SEE THE LITTLE FACES OF THOSE
SWEET LITTLE BOYS AND GIRLS AND
THE TEACHERS WHO LOVED THEM AND
THE PARENTS WHO SO SES
SEPARATELY MISS THEM.
12 LITTLE GIRLS AND 8 LITTLE
BOYS ALL ONLY IN FIRST GRADE AND
THE TEACHERS WHO TRIED TO SAVE
THEM.
ON SATURDAY, PHOTOS AND DETAILS
OF LIVES CUT SHORT STARTED TO
EMERGE.
>> THE WORST THAT I KNOW OF ANY
OF MY COLLEAGUES HAVING SEEN --
>> NOAH POZNER HAD JUST TURNED
6.
7-YEAR-OLD GRACE McDONNELL,
FAMILY MEMBERING TELLS ABC NEWS
"OUR DAUGHTER WAS THE LOVE AND
LIGHT OF OUR FAMILY.
WORDS CANNOT ADEQUATELY EXPRESS
OUR SENSE OF LOSS.
ANA MARK QUESTION GREEN, THEY'RE
STRUGGLING TO WORK THROUGH THIS
NIGHTMARE.
HUBBARD HUBBARD SA-- CATHERINE
FAMILY SAID "WE ASK THAT YOU
CONTINUE TO PRAY FOR US.
JESSE LEWIS WAS LOOKING FORWARD
TO MAKING GINGERBRED HOUSES.
HE WAS IN VICTORIA SOTO'S CLASS.
SHE WAS SHIELDING SOME OF HER
FIRST GRADERS WHEN SHE DIED.
LAUREN RUSSEAU HAD JUST STARTED
AS A FULL-TIME TEACHER IN
SEPTEMBER HAVING THE BEST YEAR
OF HER LIFE, HER MOTHER SAID.
MARY SHERLACH, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, HER FAMILY SAID
"MARY FELT LIKE SHE WAS DOING
GOD'S WORK BY HELPING CHILDREN.
S
SHE."
SHE HEADED TOWARDS THE SHOOTER
WHEN IT BEGAN.
JOINED BY THE PRINCIPAL DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, A MOTHER HERSELF, IT
IS NOW BELIEVED SHE TURNED ON
THE P.A. SYSTEM WHEN THE
SHOOTING STARTED SO OTHERS COULD
BE WARNED OF THE DANGERS THAT
HAD INVADED THEIR SCHOOL.
IT IS SO DIFFICULT TO FIND THE
RIGHT WORDS AFTER SEEING HOW
MUCH THIS COMMUNITY HAS LOST,
BUT SOMEHOW, SOME WAY THE FATHER
OF LITTLE EMILIE PARKER FOUND
THOSE WORDS WHEN HE SPOKE TO
CAMERAS OUTSIDE OF A NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT CHURCH.
>> AS THE DEEP PAIN BEGINS TO
SETTLE INTO OUR HEARTS, WE FIND
COMFORT REFLECTING ON THE
INCREDIBLE PERSON THAT EMILIE
WAS AND HOW MANY LIVES THAT SHE
WAS ABLE TO TOUCH IN HER SHORT
TIME HERE ON EARTH.
EMILIE WAS BRIGHT, CREATIVE AND
VERY LOVING AS THOSE WERE THE
GIFTS THAT WERE GIVEN TO HER BY
HER HEAVENLY FATHER.
THE STRENGTH AND EXAMPLE SHE
SHOWED US WAS REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON.
AND I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER
DAD.
I DON'T KNOW HOW TO GET THROUGH
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
MY WIFE AND I DON'T UNDERSTAND
HOW TO PROCESS ALL OF THIS AND
HOW TO GET OUR LIVES GOING.
I'M NOT MAD BECAUSE I HAVE TO
MAKE SURE THAT I USE THIS EVENT
TO DO WHAT I CAN TO DO WHATEVER
I CAN TO, ONE, MAKE SURE THAT MY
FAMILY AND MY WIFE AND MY
DAUGHTERS ARE TAKE KANE CARE OF
AND IF THERE'S ANYTHING I CAN DO
TO HELP ANYBODY ANYWHERE, I'D BE
WILLING TO DO THAT.
>> WHAT AN INCREDIBLY STRONG AND
BRAVE AND COURAGEOUS MAN.
MY HAT IS CERTAINLY OFF TO HIM
AS A PARENT.
I DON'T THINK THAT I COULD DO
THAT.
>> AND COVERING THIS STORY AS A
PARENT, I KNOW YOU'VE GOT THREE
LITTLE GIRLS, EXTRAORDINARILY
DIFFICULT.
>> IT IS INCREDIBLY DIFFICULT.
SCHOOL IS CLOSED HERE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT TOMORROW,
BUT EVERYONE AROUND THE COUNTRY,
EVERY WHO IS GOING TO TAKE THEIR
SCHOOL TOMORROW, IT IS GOING TO
BE A FUNDAMENTALLY DIFFERENT
EXPERIENCE.
THERE IS A FEAR FACTOR AND THE
SENSE THAT YOU DON'T KNOW, THAT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL ISN'T SACRED
ANYMORE.
IT'S NOT A SAFE PLACE ANYMORE
THAT WE ONCE THOUGHT IT WOULD BE
AND A LOT OF PARENTS WILL HUG
THEIR PARENTS MORE TIGHTER
BEFORE THEY SEND THEM OFF.
>> TAKING THINGS NOT SO MUCH FOR
GRANTED ANYMORE.
I KNOW LARA IN THE BROADCAST AND
YOU WILL BE BACK ABOUT HOW TO
TALK TO CHILDREN ABOUT THIS.
AMY, EXCELLENT REPORTING.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
>> SUNDAY MORNING IS ALWAYS A
TIME FOR REFLECTION BUT EVEN
MORE SO ON THIS DAY AND IN THIS
PLACE.
ABC'S JUJU CHANG IS AT ONE OF
THE CHURCHES.
JUJU, GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING, DAN.
CONGREGANTS ARE FILING IN.
MASS IS ABOUT TO GET UNDER WAY
AND THE HOUSES OF WORSHIP
THROUGHOUT NEWTOWN ARE PROVIDING
A SENSE OF COMMUNITY BUT ALSO A
PLACE WHERE YOU CAN ASK
QUESTIONS TO WHICH THERE ARE NO
EASY ANSWERS LIKE HOW COULD A
GUNMAN WIPE OUT SUCH INNOCENCE?
HERE ON THE GROUND OF ST. ROSE
OF LIMA THERE ARE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIALS.
YOU CAN SEE CANDLES AND FLOWERS
BUT ALSO CHILDLIKE ITEMS, A
SOCCER BALL SIGNED BY THE
NEWTOWN SOCCER CLUB AN A NOTE
THAT SAID SIMPLY "SLEEP IN
HEAVENLY PEACE."
DAN?
>> AND THOSE CHILDLIKE ITEMS AS
YOU PUT IT, THEY ARE THE
TOUGHEST TO SEE.
JUJU, I KNOW SEVERAL FAMILIES
WHO BELONG TO THE CHURCH IN
FRONT OF WHICH YOU ARE STANDING
LOST CHILDREN.
HOW IS THE CHURCH DEALING WITH
THAT?
>> Reporter: DAN, IT IS SUCH A
POIGNANT THOUGHT.
MONSIGNOR ROBERT RICE WHO HAD
THE JOB OF INFORMING FAMILIES
THEY HAD LOST THEIR CHILDREN HAD
SENT LAST NIGHT PLANNING
FUNERALS FOR THOSE CHILDREN.
A CHURCH OFFICIAL TOLD ME THERE
ARE EIGHT CHILDREN, EIGHT
FAMILIES AND EIGHT FUNERALS THAT
ARE BEING PLANNED HERE IN THIS
CONGREGATION ALONE AT ST. ROSE
AND, YOU KNOW, THROUGHOUT THIS
TOWN, THE CHURCHES AND THE
HOUSES OF WORSHIP ARE NOT JUST
WRAPPING THEIR ARMS AROUND THE
FAMILIES THAT SUFFERED A DIRECT
LOSS BUT TO THE ENTIRE COMMUNITY
THAT SAYS THEY'LL NEVER BE THE
SAME.
ONE LAST DETAIL, THERE ARE FOUR
SERVICES PLANNED HERE TODAY AND
THERE ARE KLEENEX BOXES ON
EITHER SIDE OF EACH AISLE OF
THAT CHURCH.
>> EXTRAORDINARY, WE ARE HEADING
INTO THE WEEK LEADING UP TO
CHRISTMAS AND IN THIS LITTLE
TOWN, THEY'VE GOT MORE THAN
FUNERALS TO PLAN AND CARRY OUT,
JUJU CHANG, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
REPORTING.
>>> A LOT OF OTHER NEWS ON THIS
SUNDAY MORNING.
FOR MORE LET'S GET BACK TO NEW
YORK AND BIANNA ONCE AGAIN.
>> ALL RIGHT, DAN, WE'LL BE BACK
TO YOU IN NEWTOWN IN A FEW
MOMENTS BUT TO ANOTHER
DEVELOPING STORY, A HEALTH SCARE
FOR HILLARY CLINTON.
THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUFFERING
A CONCUSSION AFTER FAINTING FROM
DEHYDRATION.
ABC'S DAVID KERLEY HAS THE
LATEST FROM WASHINGTON AND,
DAVID, HOW SERIOUS IS HER
CONDITION?
>> WELL, SHE IS STAYING HOME FOR
ABOUT A WEEK NOW.
SECRETARY CLINTON'S HEALTH ISSUE
MEANS SHE WILL NOT BE GOING TO
CAPITAL HILL TO TESTIFY ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED IN BENGHAZI.
EVEN THOUGH SHE INJURED HERSELF
LAST WEEK WE DIDN'T LEARN ABOUT
HER CONDITION UNTIL HOURS AGO.
THIS MORNING HILLARY CLINTON IS
AT HOME RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION AS WELL AS A STOMACH
VIRUS, IN FACT, THE TWO ARE
RELATED.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT SAYS THE
SECRETARY RETURNED FROM HER
LATEST TRIP WITH A STOMACH BUG.
THAT WAS NINE DAYS AGO BUT EARLY
LAST WEEK CLINTON BECAME
DEHYDRATED AND FAINTED AT HER
HOME, SHE APPARENTLY HIT HER
HEAD BECAUSE SHE SUFFERED A
CONCUSSION.
IT'S THE SECOND TIME IN EIGHT
YEARS SHE HAS FAINTED BECAUSE OF
A STOMACH BUG BUT SHE'S
GENERALLY HEALTHY AS SHE TOLD
BARBARA WALTERS WHO ASKED ABOUT
A POSSIBLE PRESIDENTIAL RUN IN
2016.
>> IS YOUR I'M A CONCERN TO YOU.
>> IT REALLY ISN'T.
I AM THANKFULLY KNOCK ON WOOD
NOT ONLY HEALTHY BUT HAVE
INCREDIBLE STAMINA AND ENERGY.
>> BUT STAYING HOME THIS WEEK
MEANS THE SECRETARY WILL NOT
TESTIFY ABOUT THE TERRORIST
ATTACK IN BENGHAZI, LIBYA.
>> LOOK, I'VE SAID IT AND I'LL
SAY IT ONE MORE TIME, NO ONE
WANTS TO FIND OUT WHAT HAPPENED
MORE THAN I DO.
>> Reporter: THE STATE
DEPARTMENT REPORTS ON WHAT LED
TO IT.
THE DEATH OF AMBASSADOR CHRIS
STEVENS AND THREE OTHERS WILL
COME OUT IN THE NEXT COUPLE OF
DAYS.
SHE WAS SET TO TESTIFY BEFORE
BOTH HOUSES THURSDAY.
NOW SHE WILL STAY HOME AND TWO
DEPUTIES WILL FILL IN.
NOT GOOD ENOUGH SAYS THE
REPUBLICAN CHAIR OF THE HOUSE
COMMITTEE WHO DECLARED THE
QUESTION ABOUT BENGHAZI,
"REQUIRES A PUBLIC APPEARANCE BY
THE SECRETARY OF STATE HERSELF."
BUT THAT MAY NEVER HAPPEN.
ABC NEWS HAS LEARNED THAT THE
PRESIDENT WILL NOMINATE JOHN
KERRY AS SECRETARY OF STATE.
AS SOON AS HE IS CONFIRMED
CLINTON WILL RETIRE SO MAY NEVER
TESTIFY ABOUT BENGHAZI AND WE
LEARNED THAT THE PRESIDENT
CALLED SECRETARY CLINTON
YESTERDAY TO MAKE SURE SHE WAS
DOING OKAY.
>> GLAD TO HEAR SHE IS DOING
BETTER.
DAVID, THANK YOU.
>>> NOW WITH A LOOK AT THE OTHER
STORIES MAKING HEADLINES HERE'S
RON CLAIBORNE.
>> GOOD MORNING TO YOU, BIANNA,
WE BEGIN WITH ANOTHER ERUPTION
OF GUNFIRE.
THIS TIME IN A PARKING LOT IN A
SHOPPING MALL IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
IT WAS CAUGHT ON SURVEILLANCE
CAMERA.
POLICE IN NEWPORT BEACH,
CALIFORNIA, SAY THAT 42-YEAR-OLD
MARK COST GOROLO WAS ARRESTED
AFTER FIRING 50 SHOTS INTO THE
AIR AND GROUND OUTSIDE OF THAT
MALL.
NO ONE INJURED BUT THE MALL
PACKED WITH HOLIDAY SHOPPERS
WENT INTO LOCKDOWN UNTIL POLICE
SECURED 9 AREA.
>>> A TEENAGER UNDER ARREST FOR
A PLOT TO SHOOT STUDENTS AND
BOMB HIS HIGH SCHOOL.
SAMMY CHAVEZ PLANNED TO TRAP
STUDENTS IN A LOCKED AUDITORIUM
AND ALLEGEDLY WANTED TO PLACE
BOMBS AT THE DOORS FOR WHEN
POLICE ARRIVED.
STUDENTS REPORTED THE PLAN, THE
ALLEGED PLOT TO SCHOOL STAFF
MEMBERS AFTER CHAVEZ TRIED TO
RECRUIT THEM.
>>> AND A MAJOR CONCESSION BY
THE REPUBLICAN HOUSE LEADERS IN
THOSE FISCAL CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS.
ABC NEWS LEARNED THAT HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER HAS
PROPOSED RAISING INCOME TAXES
FOR THE HEALTHIEST AMERICANS,
THOSE MAKING A MILLION DOLLARS A
YEAR OR MORE.
BUT ONLY IF THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION AGREED TO MAJOR
ENTITLEMENT CUTS.
THE WHITE HOUSE REJECTED
BOEHNER'S PROPOSAL OUT OF HAND.
>>> EGYPT'S MUSLIM BROTHERHOOD
IS CLAIRING VICTORY IN THE FIRST
ROUND OF VOTING IN THAT COUNTRY.
THE REFERENDUM BY MOHAMMED MORSI
HAS POLARIZED EGYPT.
ANOTHER ROUND OF VOTING TAKES
PLACE THIS COMING WEEK.
>>> AND FORMER SOUTH AFRICAN
PRESIDENT NELSON MANDELA IS
RECOVERING FROM SURGERY TO HAVE
GALLSTONES REMOVED.
HE WAS INITIALLY HOSPITALIZED
EIGHT DAYS AGO WITH THE
RECURRENCE OF A LUNG INFECTION,
THE SECOND TIME HE'S BEEN
HOSPITALIZED THIS YEAR.
BUT HANGING IN THERE.
>> AROUND THE WORLD WISHING HIM
THE BEST.
>> YEAH.
>> ALL RIGHT, RON, THANK YOU.
>>> TIME FOR WEATHER AND OVER TO
GINGER ZEE.
HEY, GINGER.
>> GOOD MORNING, BIANNA.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE.
IT WAS AN ICY, MESSY, JUST
DISASTER IN PARTS OF MINNESOTA
YESTERDAY BECAUSE OF THIS LOW
PRESSURE SYSTEM.
FIRST CAME THE SNOW, THEN THIS
WINTRY MIX AND HAD A LOT OF
SLIDE OFF.
THAT SAME TYPE OF ENERGY IS NOW
MOVING TO THE NORTH AND EAST SO
PARTS OF NEW ENGLAND TONIGHT
THROUGH EARLY TOMORROW ARE IN
WINTER WEATHER ADVISORIES.
IN THE MID-ATLANTIC AND
NORTHEAST IT WILL STAY MOSTLY
RAIN BUT SOME HEAVY RAINS AT
TIMES.
ALSO SEVERE STORMS WITH THAT
MOISTURE PUMPING FROM THE GULF.
YOU COULD HAVE 70-MILE-PER-HOUR
GUSTS AND SMALL HAIL DOWN
THROUGH JACKSON, MISSISSIPPI,
EVEN TO HOUSTON TODAY SO
SOMETHING TO TAKE NOTE OF.
THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST, THE SOME
BLIZZARD WARNINGS AND WINTER
STORM WARNINGS IN EFFECT TOO
THAT STARTS TONIGHT, UP TO
75-MILE-PER-HOUR GUSTS AND CAN
SEE HERE UP TO ONE OR TWO FEET
OF SNOW IN THE MOUNTAINS.
THAT'S A BIG PICTURE.
>> THAT IS A LOOK AT YOUR
NATION'S WEATHER.
NOW BACK OUT TO DAN.
>> COMING UP MUCH MORE OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
HOW DO YOU TALK TO YOUR CHILDREN
ABOUT SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
WE HAVE EXPERT ADVICE.
>>> A LOOK AT HOW THE PASS KERR
PUTS THE CONTENTIOUS ISSUE OF
GUN CONTROL BACK IN THE NEWS.
AS WE SAID MUCH MORE FROM
NEWTOWN ON "GMA" AFTER THIS
QUICK BREAK.
♪
I MUST HAVE
THE WRONG HOUSE.
SISTER?
WE MISSED YOU.
THEY WAITED UP ALL NIGHT
FOR YOU, YOU KNOW.
IT'S A LONG WAY
FROM WEST AFRICA.
AHH...COFFEE.
[ inhales deeply ]
HE'S HERE.
I BROUGHT YOU SOMETHING.
[ chuckles ]
REALLY?
♪
[ chuckles ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU'RE MY PRESENT
THIS YEAR.
♪ THE BEST PART OF WAKIN' UP
♪ IS FOLGERS IN YOUR CUP
ATTENTION...
HE WENT TO JARED.
[ Female Announcer ]
JARED THE GALLERIA OF JEWELRY
HAS THOUSANDS OF LOOSE DIAMONDS
AND HUNDREDS OF SETTINGS
TO CREATE YOUR
OWN, ONE-OF-A-KIND RING.
OH.
PLEASE RETURN YOUR Fiancée TO
HER ORIGINAL UPRIGHT POSITION.
[ Female Announcer ]
THAT'S WHY HE WENT TO JARED.
A DELICIOUS NEW WAY TO GET
ESSENTIAL VITAMINS YOU NEED.
JUST BITE
INTO THE TASTY SHELL...
TO A CHEWY VITAMIN CORE
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
NEW CENTRUM FLAVOR BURST.
BECAUSE FOUR OUT OF FIVE DOGS
OVER THE AGE OF THREE
DEVELOP GUM DISEASE,
AND TARTAR BUILDUP
IS A CONTRIBUTING FACTOR.
[ Dog ] OR NEW DENTASTIX FRESH.
CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO FIGHT TARTAR
AND NOW WITH ADDED INGREDIENTS
TO FIGHT DOG BREATH, TOO.
>>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA ON
THIS SUNDAY MORNING, 48 HOURS
AFTER THE WORST SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN AMERICAN
HISTORY.
THIS MORNING AS THE FAMILIES OF
THE YOUNG VICTIMS RELEASE A
FLOOD OF BEAUTIFUL BUT WRENCHING
PHOTOGRAPHS, THESE QUESTION, HOW
DO YOU TALK TO YOUR CHILDREN
ABOUT THIS KIND OF DISASTER AND
WHAT, IF ANYTHING, CAN BE DONE
TO PREVENT THIS FROM HAPPENING
AGAIN?
GOOD MORNING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, ONCE AGAIN I'M DAN
HARRIS, BIANNA GOLODRYGA IS IN
NEW YORK.
WE'LL GET BACK TO HER IN JUST A
MOMENT AND WE'LL TACKLE BOTH OF
THOSE QUESTIONS IN A MOMENT BUT
FIRST WE WANT TO START WITH THE
LATEST DEVELOPMENTS.
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
TRAVELING HERE LATER TODAY TO
MEET WITH THE FAMILIES OF THOSE
WHO WERE LOST AND ALSO TO THANK
THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
HE WILL SPEAK AT AN INTERFAITH
VIGIL SCHEDULED FOR 7:00 IRON.
>>> WE NOW KNOW THE NAMES OF THE
DEAD AND WE KNOW THAT ALL OF THE
20 CHILDREN WERE IN THE FIRST
GRADE BORN IN 2005 OR 2006, THE
OLDEST VICTIM, THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST BORN IN 1956.
THE MASSIVE SCOPE OF THE
SENSELESS SLAUGHTER, THE LATEST
IN A LONG STRING OF MASS
SHOOTINGS IN AMERICA HAS
RE-OPENED THE POLITICALLY
EXPLOSIVE SUBJECT OF GUN CONTROL
AND THE SECOND AMENDMENT.
ABC'S PIERRE THOMAS WHO IS OUR
SENIOR JUSTICE CORRESPONDENT HAS
BEEN LOOKING INTO IT.
>> GOOD MORNING, DAN.
SO MANY DISTURBING QUESTIONS BUT
THIS EVENT HAS PUT A SPOTLIGHT
ON AMERICA'S THRIVING GUN
CULTURE.
THE STATISTICS ARE STAGGERING.
ON BLACK FRIDAY, U.S. SHOPPERS
WERE NOT JUST BUYING TOYS AND
ELECTRONICS BUT GUNS IN RECORD
NUMBERS.
ON THAT SINGLE DAY THE FBI DID
COMPUTERIZED BACKGROUND CHECKS
ON MORE THAN 154,000 PURCHASES
OF FIREARMS.
AND IN NOVEMBER ALONE, AMERICANS
TRIED TO BUY A WHOPPING 2
MILLION GUNS.
HERE'S SOME FACT THAT IS MIGHT
SURPRISE YOU.
THERE ARE MORE REGISTERED GUN
DEALERS IN STORES THAN MAJOR
SUPERMARKETS.
>>> MORE GUN SELLERS THAN
McDONALD'S RESTAURANTS.
THE OVERWHELMING MAJORITY OF GUN
OWNERS ARE LAW-ABIDING CITIZENS
BUT AUTHORITIES TELL ABC NEWS
THE MILLIONS OF GUNS IN
CIRCULATION GUARANTEE THAT
DISTURBED PEOPLE WILL OFTEN BE
ABLE TO OBTAIN THEM EVEN IN
TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITIES LIKE
NEWTOWN.
WE SPOKE TO ATF'S ON-SCENE
COMMANDER TO NEWTOWN.
IN ROUGHLY HOW MANY GUN DEALERS
ARE IN THIS AREA.
>> THERE ARE ABOUT 400 GUN
DEALERS IN A FOUR-COUNTER AREA
JUST WITHIN TEN MILES OF THE
INCIDENT THERE ARE 36.
>> Reporter: IN THE CASE OF ADAM
LANZA LAW ENFORCEMENT
AUTHORITIES TELL US THE TWO
HANDGUNS AND ASSAULT RIFLE USED
IN THE 14509ING WERE BOUGHT
LEGALLY.
>> IN AMERICA UNLESS YOU HAVE A
FELONY CONVICTION OR YOU'RE
ADJUDICATED BY A COURT TO BE
MENTALLY INCOMPETENT, YOU HAVE
READY ACCESS TO FIREARMS.
>> Reporter: LANZA JOINS THE
RANKS JARED LEE LOUGHNER, JAMES
HOLMES AND THE VIRGINIA TECH
SHOOTER AND THIS MORNING THE
NATION IS LEFT WITH A PERPLEXING
QUESTION HOW DO YOU KEEP WEAPONS
FROM MEN LIKE THESE WHEN THERE
ARE ESTIMATED 200 MILLION PLUS
GUNS ALREADY IN CIRCULATION?
DAN, THERE'S SIMPLY NO EASY
ANSWERS.
>> Reporter: NO, AND THIS IS AN
EXPLOSIVE ISSUE.
I KNOW YOU'LL BE TALKING ABOUT
IT LATER ON "THIS WEEK."
A SPECIAL EDITION OF "THIS WEEK"
FROM HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, GEORGE
STEPHANOPOULOS WILL TALK WITH
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT DAN
MALLOY TACKLING QUESTIONS SUCH
AS HOW LEADERSHIP RESPONDS TO
THIS TRAGEDY, THAT IS THIS
MORNING ON "THIS WEEK WITH
GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS."
LET'S GET BACK TO NEW YORK AND
RON WHO HAS A LOOK AT THE
MORNING'S TOP STORIES, ALSO
GINGER WITH THE WEATHER.
GOOD MORNING.
>> GOOD MORNING, ALONG WITH
SEVERE STORMS HERE'S WHAT WE'LL
LOOK FOR IN THE WAY OF DRENCHING
RAINS, SOME COMPUTER MODELS ARE
PUTTING OUT 1 TO EVEN 3 INCHES
FOR PARTS OF MISSISSIPPI BACK
THROUGH LOUISIANA AND EVENTUALLY
MAKE THEIR WAY THROUGH THE REST
OF THE SOUTHEAST.
A LOOK HERE ACROSS THE NATION,
REMEMBER, BLIZZARD WARNINGS,
WINTER STORM WARNINGS IN THE
PACIFIC NORTHWEST.
THAT STORM HITS TONIGHT THROUGH
TOMORROW.
SOME OF THE HIGHER ELEVATIONS
WILL BE TOUGH AND HAVE TO GET
CHAINS ON THE TIRES, CHICAGO, 48
AND RAIN THROUGHOUT THE
NORTHEAST DEVELOPS THIS MORNING
THROUGH TONIGHT, RAIN/SNOW MIX
IN NEW ENGLAND, UP TO 9 INCHES
OF SNOW IN NEW HAMPSHIRE.
THAT'S A LOOK AT THE BIG
PICTURE.
NOW A CHECK A LITTLE CLOSER TO
HOME.
AND THAT IS A CHECK OF YOUR
NATION'S WEATHER.
WE HEAD NOW BACK OUT TO DAN.
>> AND THANK YOU, GINGER.
COMING UP ON "GMA," CHILDREN AND
TRAGEDY.
WHAT DO YOU TELL YOUR KIDS?
SOME EXTRA ADVICE AFTER THIS
QUICK BREAK.
EEEN YOU
NEED A QUICK HOLIDAY PRESENT,
GO TO WALGREENS.COM.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR PHOTO,
CREATE ANY NUMBER OF GIFTS
AND PICK THEM UP
THE SAME DAY.
RIGHT HERE.
AT THE CORNER
OF HAPPY AND HEALTHY.
Natural dog food is the smart
choice.
Let's look at the brand that
proves it.
Nutro Natural Choice Dog Food.
It has natural sunflower oil and
B Vitamins
that guarantee a visibly shiny
coat.
With natural ingredients,
guaranteed to promote healthy
digestion.
Make the Natural Choice today.
guaranteed to promote healthy
digestion.
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
>>> IT WAS PEACEFUL AND
EVERYTHING WAS FINE, EVERYTHING
WAS JUST NORMAL.
AS A REGULAR FRIDAY MORNING
WOULD BE TO EVERYONE AND THEN IT
ALL JUST CHANGED.
>> HEARD SCREAMING.
>> WE WERE LIKE ALL SCARED.
>> WE HEARD A LOUD BANG.
WE THOUGHT THAT SOMETHING FELL
THEN WE HEARD ANOTHER AND THEN
WE SAW A GUN SHOT.
>> WE THOUGHT IT WAS A SAFETY
DRILL BUT THEN WE NOTICED IT WAS
REAL.
>> WE HID IN THE STORAGE ROOM
AND I ACTUALLY PRAYED TO GOD.
>> EVERYBODY WAS A LITTLE SCARED
CRYING AND I FELT ACTUALLY A
LITTLE SICK LIKE I WAS GOING TO
THROW UP.
>> IT FELT LIKE IT LASTED LIKE
AN HOUR BUT IT WAS REALLY LIKE
MAYBE 20 MINUTES.
>> WHEN I WENT TO THE FIRE
DEPARTMENT, WHEN I DIDN'T SEE
HIM, I WAS LIKE OH MY GOD WHAT
HAPPENED TO MY BROTHER.
>> WHAT'S THE HARDEST PART?
>> THAT SOMEONE WOULD MURDER SO
MANY PEOPLE.
>> AND I FINALLY SAW ETHAN I WAS
VERY RELIEVED.
>> YOU SAID EARLIER YOU SAID YOU
THINK YOUR TEACHER SAVED YOUR
LIFE.
>> SHE SAVED ALL OF US.
THERE'S 19 PEOPLE IN OUR CLASS
AND SHE SAVED ALL OF US.
>> AND THE QUESTION FACING
PARENTS EVERYWHERE THIS MORNING
IS, OF COURSE, HOW DO I TALK TO
MY OWN CHILD ABOUT THESE
TERRIBLE EVENTS?
HOW CAN WE EXPLAIN THE
UNEXPLAINABLE?
THE INEXPLAINABLE, DIFFICULT FOR
EVEN US TO COMPREHEND.
JOINING US IS JOURNALIST AND
AUTHOR WILLOW BAY WHO WROTE THE
BOOK ON THIS TOPIC "TALKING TO
YOUR KIDS IN TOUGH TIMES" HOW TO
ANSWER YOUR CHILD'S QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE WORLD WE LIVE IN.
SHE JOINS US FROM LOS ANGELES
AND WILLOW WAS A FORMER ANCHOR
HERE OF THIS PROGRAM.
WE WANT TO WELCOME YOU BACK TO
THE PROGRAM.
THANKS FOR BEING WITH US.
>> NICE TO BE HERE WITH YOU ON
WHAT IS REALLY A TRAGIC MORNING
FOR ALL OF US, FOR ALL PARENTS.
>> WILLOW, I WANT TO START BY --
WELL, I WANT TO START BY ASKING
YOU THE QUESTION THAT WE'VE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT THIS MORNING, ALL
THREE OF US BEING PARENTS, HOW
DO WE APPROACH THIS TOPIC?
I KNOW MY KIDS WERE ASKING ABOUT
IT LAST NIGHT, WHERE I WOULD BE
THIS MORNING.
HOW DO YOU DO IT IN A WAY THAT'S
COMPASSIONATE AND GIVING THEM
THE INFORMATION THAT THEY NEED
BUT NOT TOO MUCH?
>> SO THE FIRST THING YOU WANT
TO DO IS ESTABLISH THAT THERE'S
NO QUESTION TOO SCARY FOR YOUR
CHILD TO TALK ABOUT, TO CREATE A
REALLY SAFE AND COMFORTABLE
PLACE FOR THEM TO COME AND TALK
TO YOU.
THE SECOND THING YOU WANT TO DO
IS SUPPRESS THE NORMAL PARENTAL
INSTINCT TO TELL THEM
EVERYTHING.
YOU WANT IT TO COME FROM YOU.
WAUGH WANT TO BE THE ONE TO TELL
THEM BUT THIS IS ONE OF THOSE
SITUATIONS WHAT THEE NEED TO DO
AS WE DO AS JOURNALISTS AND ASK
OUR CHILDREN QUESTION SO WE GET
A BASELINE ON WHAT THEY'RE
UNDERSTANDING.
REMEMBER THEY'RE PROCESSING
UNTHINKABLE INFORMATION AND
ADULT INFORMATION WITH THE MINDS
OF CHILDREN.
SO YOU WANT TO ASK THEM
QUESTIONS LIKE, WELL, WHAT DO
YOU THINK ABOUT THAT?
WHAT HAVE YOU HEARD ABOUT THAT?
ARE THE KIDS AT SCHOOL TALKING
ABOUT THAT JUST AS A WAY OF
GETTING THE CONVERSATION STARTED
AND I'M GETTING A MORE PRECISE
UNDERSTANDING OF WHAT EXACTLY
THEY KNOW AND THEY THINK TO BE
THE TRUTH.
>> AND, WILLOW, ONE OF THE
QUESTIONS I RECEIVED FROM MY
10-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER, ONE OF THE
FIRST QUESTIONS OUT OF HER MOUTH
WAS WHY MOMMY.
WHY WOULD SOMEONE DO LIKE THIS
AND YOU KNOW WHAT, I DIDN'T HAVE
AN ANSWER FOR HER.
WHAT DO YOU TELL YOUR CHILDREN,
WILLOW, WHEN THEY ASK WHY?
>> BY THE WAY, MY 14-YEAR-OLD --
THAT WAS THE FIRST THING HE SAID
TO ME, HOW -- WHY WOULD SOMEBODY
DO THIS AND I THINK IN THAT
SITUATION IT'S FINE TO ANSWER
TRUTHFULLY, WHICH IS I DON'T
KNOW.
I THINK EVERYBODY IS ASKING THAT
QUESTION TODAY.
BUT THEN WITH A YOUNG CHILD
PARTICULARLY WITH A YOUNG CHILD
BECAUSE THE YOUNG CHILDREN THINK
VERY CONCRETELY.
THEY DON'T -- THEY HAVEN'T
MASTERED ABSTRACT THINKING.
ASK THEM, WELL, WHY DO YOU
THINK, WHY DO YOU THINK SOMEBODY
WOULD HAVE MADE A CHOICE LIKE
THAT AND IT'LL GET THEM
PROCESSING SOME OF THIS
INFORMATION IN THEIR OWN WAY.
AND THEN YOU CAN STEER THE
CONVERSATION TO WAYS PEOPLE
COULD MAKE BETTER CHOICES, FOR
EXAMPLE.
>> OKAY.
AND ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT
THINGS IS, OF COURSE, TO MAKE
THEM FEEL SAFE.
YOU HEARD A LITTLE GIRL I SPOKE
TO LAST NATE SAID SHE'S AFRAID
TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
CHILDREN EVERYWHERE WILL
EXPERIENCE SOME OF THESE
FEELINGS OF ANXIETY.
WHAT DO WE SAY TO THEM ABOUT
FEELING SAFE AND KNOWING THAT
THEY ARE SAFE?
>> WELL, AGAIN, CHILDREN, YOUNG
CHILDREN IN PARTICULAR THINK
VERY CONCRETELY SO IT'S VERY
HELPFUL TO REASSURE THEM IN VERY
CONCRETE AND SPECIFIC WAYS THAT
THEY WILL BE SAFE WHEN THEY GO
TO SCHOOL.
SO YOU REMIND THEM THAT THERE
ARE ADULTS OUT THERE WHOSE JOB
IT IS TO KEEP THEM SAFE, WHETHER
IT'S POLICEMEN.
THEIR SCHOOL PRINCIPAL.
THEIR TEACHERS.
AND WALK THEM THROUGH THE SAFETY
MEASURES IN THEIR SCHOOL.
THERE'S SOMEBODY STANDING AT THE
FRONT GATE.
THERE ARE DRILLS THAT WE DO,
PRACTICE YOUR DRILLS.
AGAIN, VERY CONCRETE AND
SPECIFIC THINGS THAT ARE GOING
ON IN THEIR SCHOOL TO KEEP THEM
SAFE.
ALSO, ASK THEM FOR THEIR OWN
IDEAS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK WE CAN DO TO
HELP KEEP YOU SAFER?
WHAT DO YOU THINK WOULD HELP YOU
FEEL SAFER?
OFTENTIMES ALLOWING THEM TO
PARTICIPATE WILL REALLY HELP
THEM FEEL BETTER, BUT THEN
ALWAYS COME BACK TO REMINDING
THEM THAT IT'S THE JOB OF ADULTS
AND THERE ARE A LOT OF US, HARD
AT WORK, TO KEEP THEM SAFE.
>> WILLOW BAY, FANTASTIC ADVICE
AND ADVICE THAT EACH AND EVERY
ONE OF US AS PARENTS AROUND THIS
ENTIRE COUNT CAN USE AS OUR
CHILDREN HEAD BACK TO SCHOOL ON
MONDAY.
WILLOW, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> GREAT TO HEAR FROM YOU WILLOW
AND MORE FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, WHEN WE COME BACK.
TRY THIS.
IT'S OIKOS GREEK YOGURT.
IT'S CREAMY, NONFAT, AND IT
TURNS THE NEXT PERSON YOU SEE
INTO JOHN STAMOS
FOR FIVE SECONDS.
HONEY! I THINK
I'M GETTING BURNED! HEH!
EAT.
♪
TASTES PRETTY GOOD, HUH?
BEST YOGURT EVER.
YEAH!
[ men grunting ]
OPEN!
[ Male Announcer ]
DANNON OIKOS BERRY FLAVORS
BEAT CHOBANI 2 TO 1
IN A NATIONAL TASTE TEST.
OIKOS GREEK YOGURT.
POSSIBLY THE BEST YOGURT
IN THE WORLD.
OIKOS GREEK YOGURT.
Hey buddy, I bet Mom
would love this, huh?
Jack?
Jaaack?
Jaaack?!
Jack?!
Looks good
ladies!
Jack!
Come on,
stop the car.
JACK!
No, no, no, no, no!
The only thing more surprising
than finding the
perfect gifts..
Niice.
...is where you find them.
How did you know?
I had a little help.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
He is a good little monkey
and always very curious.
One day George got an important
letter...
He's built a rocket ship to
travel into space.
It's just the right size for a
clever monkey.
Do you want to go into space,
George?
You will have to be very brave.
Hi, Grandma!
Oh hi,. my little monkey!
Here.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Everyone got on and they were
off to the launching site.
Google, how far is Earth to the
Moon?
Moon is 238,900 miles...
The great moment had come...
...5...4...3...2...1
I'm mom at the playground
AND the dog park.
The kids get trail mix...
And YOU get a delicious Milo's
Kitchen Chicken Meatball.
They're 100% real...
I wish you liked MY
cooking that much.
The Best Treats Come
From The Kitchen.
Milo's Kitchen home-style
dog treats.
[ coughs ]
[ baby crying ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
ROBITUSSIN® LIQUID FORMULA
SOOTHES YOUR THROAT ON CONTACT
AND THE ACTIVE INGREDIENT
RELIEVES YOUR COUGH.
ROBITUSSIN®. DON'T SUFFER
THE COUGHEQUENCES™.
>>> WELL, IT WILL BE A STRUGGLE
TO SAY THE LEAST TO MAKE SENSE
OF THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
ALREADY PEOPLE FROM ALL OVER THE
COUNTRY ARE GOING THERE TO SHARE
IN THE GRIEF.
LET'S GO BACK TO LARA SPENCER IN
NEWTOWN.
SO ENCOURAGING TO SEE PEOPLE
FROM ACROSS THE COUNTRY WANTING
TO HELP.
>> BIANNA, IT HAS BEEN JUST AN
INCREDIBLY EMOTIONAL 24 HOURS
HERE AND I WILL TELL YOU THAT
WHAT STRUCK MOST OF US AS WE
WALKED AROUND TOWN LAST NIGHT
WAS THAT SENSE OF STRENGTH,
RESILIENCE, AND MOST OF ALL
KINDNESS.
ON A COLD, CRISP, NEW ENGLAND
NIGHT, RESIDENTS GATHERED IN
MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS THROUGHOUT
TOWN TRYING TO MAKE SENSE OF THE
IMPOSSIBLE.
>> I'M JUST WAITING TO WAKE UP
FROM THIS NIGHTMARE.
>> Reporter: THEN JOINED BY
HUNDREDS OF STRANGERS WHO
TRAVELED FAR AND WIDE TRYING TO
HELP.
WHY DID YOU NEED TO BE HERE?
>> I'M A MOTHER.
I'M A MOTHER.
>> Reporter: A MOTHER FROM NEW
YORK CITY, A CHAPLAIN FROM NORTH
CAROLINA.
HOW IMPORTANT IS IT TO GIVE BACK
TO THIS COMMUNITY?
>> I HAVE GRANDSONS EXACTLY THE
SAME AGE AS THE VICTIMS.
MY HEART WAS JUST -- I JUST WAS
MOVED.
>> Reporter: THIS FIREHOUSE IS
NOW THE SITE OF 26 CHRISTMAS
TREES, ONE FOR EACH LIFE TAKEN
AT SANDY HOOK SCHOOL EACH
DONATED FROM A WOMAN FROM NORTH
CAROLINA AND NESTLED WITH TEDDY
BEARS.
HOW IS CHRISTMAS GOING TO BE?
>> NOT GOING TO FEEL LIKE
CHRISTMAS.
I THINK, YOU KNOW, IT'S
IMPORTANT TO KEEP THINGS AS
NORMAL AS POSSIBLE FOR EVERYONE.
IT'S ABOUT GIVING AND LOVING AND
KINDNESS.
>> Reporter: RANDOM ACTS OF
KINDNESS ABOUND.
TAKE MICHAEL CRAIGEN OFFERING UP
HIS BULLDOG FOR FREE HUGS AT A
LOCAL COFFEE SHOP.
AMANDA HARMAN LIVES IN AN HOUR
AWAY BUT DONATING HER TIME HERE
TO THOSE WHO NEED HER MOST.
>> OUT OF ALL THIS TRAGEDY MY
HEART HAS BEEN LIFTED FROM ALL
THE GOOD THAT'S COMING IN CROSS
COUNTRY AND AROUND THE WORLD.
INCREDIBLE EXPERIENCE.
>> AND THIS EVENING THE
PRESIDENT WILL BE HERE IN
NEWTOWN TO MEET WITH FAMILIES
WHO HAVE LOST AND ALSO TO SPEAK
AT AN INTERSTATE VIGIL.
BIANNA, BACK TO YOU IN NEW YORK.
>> JUST WHEN YOU THINK YOU SEE
THE WORST PART OF SOCIETY, YOU
SEE THE KINDNESS, AS WELL AND I
THINK ALL OF US CAN SAY THIS
WEEKEND WE'RE ALL PART OF
NEWTOWN.
ALL RIGHT, LARA, THANK YOU, AND
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
I was living with
this all-over pain.
A deep, throbbing,
persistent ache.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can do more of
the things that I enjoy.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
GO TO WALGREENS.COM.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR PHOTO,
CREATE ANY NUMBER OF GIFTS
AND PICK THEM UP
THE SAME DAY.
RIGHT HERE.
AT THE CORNER
OF HAPPY AND HEALTHY.
>>> THAT'S GOING TO DO IT FOR
"GMA" ON THIS SUNDAY MORNING.
ON BEHALF OF BIANNA GOLODRYGA
WHO YOU SEE THERE IN NEW YORK
ALONGSIDE LARA SPENCER AND AMY
ROBACH HERE WITH ME IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, I WANT TO THANK YOU
AND REMIND YOU THERE'S MUCH MORE
COVERAGE COMING UP ON ABC NEWS
THROUGHOUT THE DAY, A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "THIS WEEK WITH
GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS" AND ABC'S
DAVID MUIR WILL HOST "WORLD
NEWS" FROM HERE LATER ON.
THANKS AGAIN FOR WATCHING.
TAKE CARE.
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOU CAN COUNT ON.
INTRODUCING AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
WITH MORE SPEED OPTIONS,
RELIABILITY
AND Wi-Fi HOT SPOTS THAN EVER.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW TO GET
U-verse HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
IT'S ALL THE SPEED YOU NEED
ALL AT A GREAT PRICE.
OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network
GIVES YOU MORE
OF WHAT YOU ENJOY ONLINE.
AND WITH AT&T,
OUR WIRELESS GATEWAY
TURNS YOUR HOME
INTO A PRIVATE Wi-Fi HOT SPOT
THAT CONNECTS
YOUR Wi-Fi DEVICES
AND CAN EVEN SAVE ON YOUR
SMART PHONE DATA USAGE AT HOME.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW
TO GET AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT INCLUDES ACCESS ON-THE-GO
TO OUR ENTIRE NATIONAL
Wi-Fi HOT SPOT NETWORK,
WITH OVER 30,000 HOT SPOTS.
AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET.
NOW ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOUR WHOLE HOUSE
CAN COUNT ON.
♪
>> DEVELOPING NEWS FEDERAL
AGENTS TURN THEIR FOCUS TO THE
GUN STORES IN THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
STORIES OF HEALING AND HEROISM
OUT OF CONNECTICUT.
THE WOMEN CREDITED WITH SAVING
COUNTLESS LIVES.
POLICE SHUT DOWN A SAN FRANCISCO
NEIGHBORHOOD AS THEY SEARCH FOR
A SUSPECTED GUNMAN.
>> GOOD MORNING EVERYONE.
THANKS FOR