AND VACUUM COMPONENTS.
>> VIEWERS SENT IMAGES OF THE
FIRE.
AMY SENT THIS PICTURE, SHOWING
HUGE PLUMES OF SMOKE, COMING
FROM THE FIRE.
THIS VIEWER TWEETED THE PICTURES
FROM THE SMOKE FROM THE FIRE, AS
HE WAS DRIVING NEARBY AND
ANOTHER VIEWER SHOWS CREWS
FIGHTING THE FLAMES.
FIREFIGHTERS ARE TRYING TO KNOCK
THE FLAMES DOWN, POURING WATER
ON ALL SIDES.
>> A MAJOR INVESTIGATION INTO A
DISTURBING THREAT IN A SOUTH BAY
HIGH SCHOOL.
LYNBROOK HIGH SCHOOL IN SAN JOSE
HAD A GRAFFITI MESSAGE,
THREATENING THE LIFE OF A
TEACHENER MONTE VISTA HIGH.
MONTE VISTA WAS SHUT DOWN AND SO
WAS NEARBY LINCOLN ELEMENTARY.
THIS THREAT IS BEING TAKEN VERY
SERIOUSLY.
>> Reporter: IT CERTAINLY IS.
THERE IS REALLY NO EXPLANATION
AS TO WHY THE GRAFFITI FOUND IN
SAN JOSE MENTIONED A BOMB HERE.
THERE IS SOME RIVALRIES BETWEEN
THE SCHOOLS, BUT THEY ARE IN THE
SAME SCHOOL DISTRICT.
WE ARE HERE AT MONTE VISTA,
WHICH WAS CLOSED ALONG WITH
LINCOLN ELEMENTARY, RIGHT DUN
THE BLOCK.
BOTH WERE CLOSED BECAUSE OF THIS
GRAFFITI FOUND FOUR AND-A-HALF
MILES AWAY.
POLICE AND STUDENTS SAY THE
GRAFFITI FOUND AT LYNBROOK HIGH
SCHOOL AT 6:40 THIS MORNING,
CROSSED A FRIGHTENING LINE.
>> IT'S A PRETTY BIG DEAL, EVEN
AS I PRANK.
FIRST OF ALL, THIS WAS A NAME, A
TEACHER'S NAME.
>> Reporter: THIS IS THE
PICTURE OF THE SPRAY-PAINTED
MESSAGE.
WE HAVE BLURRED OUT THE NAME OF
THE TEACHENER CUPERTINO TO
PROTECT THE TEACHER'S IDENTITY.
IT SAID A BOMBING WAS PLANTED AT
MONTE VISTA TO KILL HIM.
>> THAT'S THE SHOCKING PART.
HE'S ONE OF THE MOST POPULAR
TEACHERS AT THE SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: IN CUB CUPERTINO,
THE SANTA CLARA SHERIFFS DEPUTY
SHUT DOWN MONTE VISTA AND
LINCOLN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
NO EXPLOSIVE DEVICE WAS FOUND,
BUT BOTH SCHOOLS WERE CLOSED THE
ENTIRE DAY.
NEIGHBORS SAY THEY SUPPORT THE
RESPONSE BY LAW ENFORCEMENT.
>> WHEN THEY GO OVER THE EDGE,
LIKE COLUMBINE -- WE HAVE HAD
SEVERAL -- YEAH, THAT'S NOT A
PRANK.
THAT'S A VERY SERIOUS MATTER
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT BLOWING UP
PEOPLE.
>> Reporter: INVESTIGATORS
WITH THE SHERIFFS OFFICE ARE NOT
TAKING ANY CHANCE WHEN IS IT
COMES TO THE TEACHER'S SAFETY.
>> WE HAVE A COUPLE OF DEPUTIES
STAYS WITH THE TEACHER AND HIS
FAMILY AT THIS POINT, TOO
TOPROVIDE THAT PROTECTION.
>> Reporter: STUDENTS SAY THEY
WOULDN'T BE SURPRISED IF THE
TEACHER IS NOT IN CLASS
TOMORROW.
>> HE ALWAYS HAD A PICTURE OF
HIS KIDS AND THEY WERE SO CUTE.
HE WAS JUST LIKE -- HE WAS SUCH
A FAMILY MAN, YOU KNOW?
HE WAS REALLY FAMILY ORIENTED.
>> REPORTER: WHETHER THE PERSON
RESPONSIBLE EVER INTENDED TO ACT
ON THE THREAT, THE DAMAGE HAS
BEEN DONE.
>> IT'S LIKE YELLING FIRE IN A
CROWDED THEATER, MASS
DISRUPTION.
>> Reporter: BOTH SCHOOLS HERE
IN CUPERTINO WILL REOPEN
TOMORROW WITH EXTRA DEPUTIES
PATROLLING AND SHERIFF
INVESTIGATORS SAY THEY ARE
FOLLOWING UP LEADS TO IDENTIFY A
SUSPECT.
AND THE PERSON RESPONSIBLE FOR
THAT BOMB SCARE COULD FACE
FELONY CHANGES.
IN CUPERTINO, ABC7.
>> THANK YOU.
POLICE ARE LOOKING FOR A MAN WHO
DISRUPTED SERVICES IN A FREMONT
MOSQUE.
WITNESSES SAY HE BARGED INTO THE
ISLAMIC CENTER DURING PRAYER
SERVICES YESTERDAY AFTERNOON AND
SHOUTED THAT HE HAD A GUN AND
WANTED TO USE IT TO KILL THE
WORSHIPPERS.
MEMBERS OF THE CONGREGATION
CONFRONTED HIM AND KICKED HIM
OUT BEFORE POLICE ARRIVED.
HE WAS SEEN DRIVING AWAY IN WHAT
LOOKED LIKE AN OLD GRAY CAMRY.
>> A SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
OFFICER WHO POSTED A
CONTROVERSIAL VIDEO, SAYING HE
TOOK A HIGH-SPEED DRUNKEN RIDE
IS BEING INVESTIGATED.
THE POLICE CHIEF DID NOT LIKE
WHAT HE SAW IN THE VIDEO.
CAROLYN TYLER IS LIVE AT THE
HALL OF JUSTICE.
HARSH WORDS FROM THE OFFICER.
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT.
THE POLICE CHIEF KNOWS THE
OFFICER IN QUESTION VERY WELL.
ME AND SERGEANT CARL "T"
ATTENDED THE ACADEMY TOGETHER.
THEY HAVE SERVED ON THE FORCE
FOR MORE THAN 30 YEARS AM BUT
NOW, SERGEANT "T" HAS BEEN TAKEN
OFF THE STREETS BECAUSE OF WHAT
THE CHIEF CALLS POOR JUDGMENT.
>> OBVIOUSLY, IT'S JUST BEYOND
IRRESPONSIBLE AND DUMB.
>> Reporter: THE SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE CHIEF IS WANT MINCING
WORDS ABOUT THE OFFICER WHOSE
ONLINE VIDEO HAS CREATED THE
LATEST SCANDAL FOR THE
DEPARTMENT.
THE VIDEO WAS FOUND ON HIS
FACEBOOK PAGE.
SERGEANT "T," BRAGGING ABOUT A
HIGH-SPEED DRUNKEN JOYRIDE WITH
FRIENDS IN A LAMBORGHINI IN THE
TUNNEL.
100 MILES PER HOUR IN THE LAMBO,
ROOMIER THAN YOU WOULD THINK AND
PLUS, WE WERE ALL DRUNK.
SERGEANT TNCHS IS NO LONGER ON
DUTIY AND WAS TRANSFERRED TO A
DESK JOB AT HEADQUARTERS, WHILE
AN INTERNAL AFFAIRS
INVESTIGATION IS UNDERWAY.
>> IF IT PLAYS OUT THE WAY IT
CERTAINLY LOOKS IT'S GOING TO,
THE DISCIPLINE WILL BE SWIFT AND
SEVERE.
>> Reporter: WHAT MIGHT THAT
BE.
>> IT WILL BE A VERY STIFF
SUSPENSION, TO BE SURE.
DID.
>> Reporter: BUT SERGEANT "T"
APPEARS TO BE BACKING AWAY FROM
HIS FACEBOOK POST, SELL TELLING
SF WEEKLY, QUOTE, THERE WAS NO
DRUNKENNESS, NO, NO, GOD NO.
THAT WAS DONE TONGUE IN CHEEK.
AND THE OFFICER SAID, HE WAS A
PASSENGER, NOT THE DRIVER.
THE MAYOR BELIEVES WHATEVER WAS
GOING ON WAS IRRESPONSIBLE.
>> TO THE EXTENT THAT THE VIDEO
HAS ANYBODY -- WHETHER IT'S AN
OFFICER OR SOMEBODY PROMOTING OR
BEING PROUD OF GOING 100 MILES
PER HOUR IN THE BROADWAY TUNNEL
IS ABSOLUTELY DANGEROUS.
AND PEOPLE SHOULD BE HELD
ACCOUNTABLE.
>> Reporter: THAT TUNNEL,
WHICH RUNS FROM LARKIN STREET IN
RUSSIAN HILL TO POWELL IN BUSY
CHINATOWN HAS A POSTED SPEED
LIMIT OF 35 MILES PER HOUR.
IT TOOK OUR NEWS CREW 40 SECONDS
TO GET THROUGH.
WE TIMED SERGEANT "T"'S VIDEO
AND IT APPEARS TO TAKE HIS CAR,
16 SECONDS.
>> IT IS MY DISTRICT.
AND THAT ACTIVITY IS INCREDIBLY
DANGEROUS, COMPLETELY
UNACCEPTABLE.
>> Reporter: WE STILL HAVE
BEEN UNABLE TO TALK TO SERGEANT
CARL TNCHTS, BUT THE POLICE
CHIEF SAYS HE HAS AND HE HAS
TOLD HIM HE IS EMBARRASSED AND
CONTRITE.
CARL "T" WILL HAVE A CHANCE TO
TELL HIS SIDE OF THE STORY,
DURING THE POLICE INVESTIGATION.
LIVE OUTSIDE THE HAUL -- HALL OF
JUSTICE, CAROLIB TYLER.
>> A COMMUNITY-BASED EFFORT TO
REDUCE GUN VIOLENCE, THE OAKLAND
AND SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
DEPARTMENTS WILL BUY WEAPONS FOR
CASH ON SATURDAY LIKE THEY DID
AT THIS EVENT LAST JUNE.
RESIDENTS WILL GET $200 PER GUN
OR RIFLE.
IN OAKLAND, THE PROGRAM WILL BE
HELD AT SAINT BENEDICT'S CHURCH
IN SABFRAN AT THE OMEGA BOYS
CLUB.
IN BOTH, IT IS FROM 10:00 A.M.
TO THREE 3:00 P.M. ON SATURDAY.
TO FIND THE ADDRESSES, GO TO OUR
WEB SITE AND CLICK ON SEE IT ON
TV.
>> WE HAVE LEARNED THE NAME OF
THE WOMAN WHO ABANDONED HER
NEW-BORN BABY IN SAN FRANCISCO
BECAUSE SHE IS CHARGED WITH A
CRIME.
POLICE TELL US, 39-YEAR-OLD
NANECKA NASH WILL BE APORING IN
COURT TOMORROW ON ONE FELONY
COUNT OF WILLFUL CRUELTY AND ONE
MISDEMEANOR COUNT OF FAIL TOWER
CARE FOR A CHARGE.
NASH IS FROM THE BAYVIEW
DISTRICT.
SHE GAVE BIRTH TO THE CHILD ON
THE STREET AND HANDED THAT BABY
BOY OVER TO A MAN.
THE BABY IS RECOVERING IN SAN
FRANCISCO GENERAL HOSPITAL.
>> LTHE BAY AREA HOUSING MARKET
IS HEADED TOWARD NORMALCY,
THAT'S ACCORDING TO INDUSTRY
ANALYST DATA QUICK.
7200 NEW AND EXISTING HOMES WERE
SOLD LAST MONTH, DOWN FROM
OCTOBER, BUT UP 15 1/2 PERCENT
FROM A YEAR AGO.
THE MEDIAN PRICE WAS $438,000,
UP 20% FROM NOVEMBER 2011.
THE NUMBER OF BAY AREA HOMES
SOLD LAST MONTH FOR OVER A HALF
MILLION DOLLARS WAS UP 36%,
WHILE THE NUMBERS BELOW HALF A
MILLION WAS DOWN ALMOST 13%.
>> THE ALINEMENT OF THE SUN,
EARTH AND MOON, CREATING VERY
HIGH TIDES TO THE CALIFORNIA
COAST, CALLED KING TIDES.
IN SAN FRANCISCO, IT SWALLOWED
UP STEPS AT THE YACHT CLUB T.
SURGED MORE THAN 9 FEET IN SOME
AREAS INFORM SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA, THE COMMUNITY OF
SEAL BEACH EXPERIENCED FLOOD
FROM THIS TIDES.
THE WATER CAME UP TO THE STEPS
OF THE HOTEL.
THE BEST WAY TO MOVE AROUND --
CHECK IT OUT -- SURF BOARDS.
MORE KING TIDES ARE EXPECTED
TOMORROW.
>> WHAT A PICTURE.
>> U.N. AMBASSADOR -- TO THE
U.S., SUSAN RICE WILL NOT BE THE
NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
SHE WERE YOU FROM CONSIDERATION,
SAYING THE CONFIRMATION WOULD BE
LENGTHY, DISRUPTIVE AND COSTLY.
SHE WAS CONSIDERED THE
FRONTRUNNER TO REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON, WHO IS EXPECTED TO STEP
DOWN.
BUT SHE FACED CRITICISM FROM
SENATE REPUBLICANS OVER HER
INITIAL STATEMENTS ABOUT THE
U.S. CONSULATE ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI, LIBBIA.
THE PRESIDENT ACCEPTED THE
WITHDRAWAL, BUT NOTED THE UNFAIR
AND MISLEADING ATTACKS LEVELED
AGAINST HER.
STILL NO DEAL ON THE FISCAL
CLIFF, FOLLOWING AN UNSCHEDULE
THE MEETING AT THE WHITE HOUSE
THIS AFTERNOON, BETWEEN
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER.
THEY MET FOR AN HOUR, WITH BOTH
SIDES SAYING ONLY THAT THE TWO
HAD A FRANK DISCUSSION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND BOEHNER HAVE
STRUGGLED TO BREAK THEIR IMPASSE
OVER TAXES.
THE PRESIDENT WANTS A RATE HIKE
ON THE TOP 2% OF THE INCOME
EARNERS.
BOEHNER OPPOSES THAT FIERCELY.
A DEAL MUST BE REACH BIDE
DECEMBER 31 TO AVOID THE
SO-CALLED FISCAL CLIFF.
THE COMBINATION OF TAX INCREASES
AND SPENDING CUTS.
>> A SAN RAPHAEL MOTHER HAS
RETURNED FROM THE MIDDLE-EAST
WITH WHAT SOME MAY CALL A
HOLIDAY MIRACLE.
SHE NEGOTIATED AN AGREEMENT
BETWEEN ISRAEL AND THE
PALESTINIAN AUTHORITY TO BEGIN
REMOVING BAND MINES FROM BETH
LEHE. THEY ARE WORKING TO REMOVE
THE DEVASTATION OF LAND MINES.
THEY TOOK A CHECK OF $141,000 TO
PAY FOR THE LAND MINE REMOVAL.
A FAMILY VISITED ABC7 LAST YEAR.
>> IT'S BEEN A TERRIBLE
EXPERIENCE.
AND IT'S A NEED FOR OTHER
CHILDREN.
>> THE ROOTS OF PEACE LAND MINE
REMOVAL EFFORT IS DUE TO START
IN BETHLEHEM NEXT MONTH.
>> GET READY FOR ANOTHER CHANGE
IN THE WEATHER, JUST IN TIME FOR
THE WEEKEND.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE HAVE A WET SEVEN-DAY
FORECAST.
AND I MEAN UNSETTLED.
IL SHOW YOU HOW MANY DAYS OF
RAIN IS COMING AND GET READY FOR
ANOTHER NIGHT OF FREEZING COLD
CONDITIONS IN PARTS OF THE BAY
AREA.
DETAILS ARE COMING UP.
>> I HAVE A DIFFERENT TYPE OF
SHOWERS FALLING FROM THE SKY AND
THE PEAK VIEWING TIME TO CATCH
THE METEOR SHOWERS.
>> THE BAY AREA STARTUP WHERE
GIRLS CAN MAKE THEIR OWN DREAM
DOLL HOUSE AND LEARN THE
BUILDING BLOCKS FOR A CAREER AT
THE SAME TIME.
STAY WITH US.
THE NEWS CONTINUES HERE IN JUST
>> GOOD NEWS AND BAD NEWS ABOUT
CALIFORNIA STUDENTS.
CIGARETTES SMOKING HAS DECLINED.
BUT THE USE OF SMOKELESS TOBACCO
HAS JUMPED SIGNIFICANTLY.
WE HAVE MORE ON THE NEW REPORT
FROM CALIFORNIA'S DEPARTMENT OF
PUBLIC HEALTH.
>> Reporter: TOBACCO USE
TRENDS IN CALIFORNIA AMONG THE
YOUNG ARE RAISING RED FLAGS AT
THE STATE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC
HEALTH.
NEARLY 9% STORES ILLEGALLY SOLD
TO MINORS LAST YEAR, UP 5%.
18 TO 24-YEAR-OLDS ARE MOKING
MORE THAN ANY OTHER AGE GROUP IN
CALIFORNIA.
>> YOUTH AND YOUNG ADULTS GET
ADDICTED TO TOBACCO AND END UP
SMOKING THEIR ENTIRE LIVES AND
THEN THEY AND THEIR FAMILIES
SUFFER THE HEALTH CONSEQUENCES.
>> Reporter: THE STATE
PROJECTS TELL SPEND $6.5 BILLION
TO DEAL WITH ADULT HEALTH CARE,
RELATED TO SMOKING.
THAT'S $400 PER TAXPAYER.
IT IS UNCLEAR WHY YOUNGER PEOPLE
ARE PICKING UP THE HABIT.
BUT THE PREV VANS -- PREV LANCE
WAS HIGHER WITH NEIGHBORHOODS
WITH FIVE OR MORE STORES SELLING
TOBACCO.
SMOKELESS PRODUCTS ARE MORE AND
MORE POPULAR.
>> THE SMOKELESS TOBACCO
PRODUCTS ARE NOT SAFER.
THE TRENDS ARE VERY CONCERNING.
>> Reporter: WE FOUND THAT ON
THIS COLLEGE CAMPUS, STUDENTS
SAY THEY SMOKE BECAUSE THEY'RE
STRESSED, READING TUITION COSTS
AND JUGGLING CLASSES AND JOBS
ARE JUST TOO MUCH.
THE YOUNG SMOKERS WE SPOKE WITH
STARTED IN HIGH SCHOOL.
>> SCHOOL TREND, TO COLLEGE AND
WORRIES ABOUT MONEY AND THEN
JOBS.
I HAVE THREE JOBS RIGHT NOW.
SO ALL OF THAT WAS KIND OF A LOT
OF PRESSURE ON ME.
>> Reporter: THE CAMPAIGN FOR
TOBACCO-FREE KIDS HAS BEEN
CRITICAL OF STATES LIKE
CALIFORNIA FOR NOT SPENDING
ENOUGH OF THE 1998 MULTI-BILLION
DOLLAR SETTLEMENT FROM TOBACCO
COMPANIES ON PREVENTION.
THIS LIFE-LONG SMOKER ALSO
AGREES.
>> I DON'T THINK THEY ARE USING
THE FUNDS EFFECTIVELY.
>> Reporter: FOR EVERY DOLLAR
IT SPENDS ON ANTI-SMOKING
CAMPAIGN, THE TOBACCO INDUSTRY
SPENDS $8 TO ATTRACT MORE
SMOKERS.
IN SACRAMENTO, ABC7.
>> ALL RIGHT.
AMERICAN AIRLINES HAS A TWIST TO
THE EXTRA FEES THAT THE AIRLINE
TRAVELERS ARE PAYING.
>> OH, BOY.
WE ARE BREAKING IT DOWN.
>> PLEASE!
>> KIND OF GOOD NEWS.
KIND OF.
THE NEW FARE STRUCTURE ALLOWS TO
YOU BUNDLE THE SERVICES YOU WANT
TO PAY FOR OR NOT AT ALL.
IF YOU WANT THE CHOICE FARE, YOU
CAN CONTINUE TO PAY FOR CHECKED
BAGS, PREFERRED SEATING AND THE
MEALS THE WAY YOU DO, A LA
CARTE.
BUT FOR $68 EXTRA, YOU GET ONE
CHECKED BAG, NO CHANGE FEES AND
PRIORITY BOARDING.
NO CHANGE FEINGS IS THE BIG
THING.
$88 WILL GET YOU THREE ITEMS, A
PREMIUM BEVERAGE, A MILE-CREDIT
AND A SAME-DAY CHANGE.
THE NEW FARES COULD HELP
PASSENGERS AVOID THE COSTLY
CHANGE FEES ON NON-REFUNDABLE
FARES.
THAT'S A VERY GOOD DEAL.
BLUE SHIELD IS PROPOSING RAISING
THE HEALTH INSURANCE RATES AS
MUCH AS 20% ON INDIVIDUAL POLICY
HOLDERS.
>> SHAME ON YOU!
>> Reporter: PAST RATE HIKES
HAVE ATTRACTED PROTESTERS
OUTSIDE THE WHETHER BLUE SHIELD
CORPORATE OFFICES.
UNDER THE PLAN, THE RATE HIKE
WOULD BE 12%.
BUT SOME COULD SEE RATE
INCREASES AS HIGH AS 20%.
CONSUMER GROUPS ARE CRYING FOUL.
THEY POINT TO BLUE SHIELD'S HUGE
CASH RESERVE OF NEARLY $4
BILLION AND SOME SAY, SOME OF
THE MONEY SHOULD BE USED TO
OFF-SET THE RATE INCREASE.
BLUE SHIELD SAYS THE MONEY IS
NEEDED TO ENSURE IT CAN ALWAYS
PAY ALL CLAIMS.
>> TOUGH.
>> WHILE SANTA STUFFS HIS SLEIGH
FULL OF TIES FOR GIRLS AND BOYS,
A COUPLE OF RECENT STANFORD
GRADS ARE STUFFING BOXES WITH A
NEW TOY, JUST FOR GIRLS.
BUT AS JONATHAN BLOOM EXPLAINS,
RUMINATE IS DIFFERENT FROM ANY
DOLL HOUSE YOU HAVE EVER SEEN.
WATCH.
>> Reporter: IN CASE YOU ARE
WORNING, THIS IS A SPINNING
ELECTRIC FIREPLACE IN AN
IMAGINARY SKI CABIN.
>> A BOBSLED APPEARS AND YOU CAN
MAKE STAIRS FOR THE LOFT.
>> Reporter: IT WAS BUILT WITH
RUMINATE, A BUILDING TOY SET FOR
GIRLS, AGES 6 TO 10.
>> TODAY, THERE ARE NOT VERY
MANY BUILDING TOYS FOR GIRLS.
IT'S ALL DOLLS AND PRINCESSES.
SO WE WANTED TO DO SOMETHING.
>> Reporter: THEY STARTED THE
TOY COMPANY AT STANFORD START
"X" BUSINESS ACCELERATOR, AFTER
GRADUATING WITH MOSTLY MALE
ENGINEERS.
>> SOMETHING NEEDS TO BE DONE AT
AN EARLIER STAGE TO GET GIRLS TO
UNDERSTAND THAT SCIENCE AND
ENGINEERING ARE FUN AND THEY ARE
AN OPTION FOR THEM.
>> Reporter: WHILE MOST DOLL
HOUSES TEACH INTERIOR DESIGN,
THEY TEACH STRUCTURAL
ENGINEERING.
>> THESE ARE THE BUILDING PIECES
FOR THE FURNITURE.
AND INCLUDED IN THAT IS A MINI
CATALOG OF IDEAS THAT YOU CAN
MAKE WITH THAT.
>> Reporter: THERE IS AN
ELECTRIC MOTOR FOR FANS, AND
WASHING MACHINES.
>> A LITTLE ONE HERE.
>> Reporter: AND NOW...
THE ORDERS ARE POURING IN.
>> IT'S JUST BEEN BEYOND
ANYTHING THAT WE EXPECTED.
>> Reporter: THEY HAVE ALREADY
SOLD 2,000 TOYS THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON.
AND THE LATEST BATCH IS WELL ON
THE WAY TO SELLING OUT.
THAT MEANS BETWEEN NOW AND
CHRISTMAS, THEY WILL BE WORKING
SOME VERY LONG HOURS.
WORKING TOGETHER, THEY CAN
LABEL, BOX AND SHIP ONE ORDER A
MINUTE.
>> IT IS NOT GLAMOROUS.
THAT'S WHAT I HAVE LEARNED ABOUT
ENTREPRENEURSHIP IN THE LAST
YEAR.
IT IS ABOUT DOING EVERYTHING
THAT HAS TO HAPPEN.
>> Reporter: BUT SEEING KIDS
CAPTIVATED MAKES IT ALL WORTH
IT.
>> THE PARENTS ARE LIKE, WE HAVE
TO GO -- I AM NOT DONE.
>> Reporter: JONATHAN BLOOM.
ABC7 NEWS.
>> THAT'S SO COOL.
TONIGHT, IT'S THE PERFECT NIGHT
TO KEEP YOUR EYES ON THE SKIES.
IT IS TIME FOR THE ANNUAL METEOR
SHOWER TONIGHT AND TOMORROW T.
HAPPENS ABOUT THIS TIME EVERY
YEAR, AS THE EARTH PASSES
THROUGH THE DEBRIS TRAIL OF AN
ASTEROID.
YOU CAN SEE IT TONIGHT, STARTING
AT 11:00, THE BEST TIME IS 2:00
TO 3:00 IN THE MORNING.
>> I ALWAYS GET A BAD HAIR DAY.
>> METEOR SHOWERS TO MANE
RAINSHOWERS.
>> WE DO.
BUT IF YOU ARE WORKING, ARE YOU
GOING TO BE ABLE TO SEE IT?
YES!
BUT YOU MAY FREEZE YOUR YOU KNOW
WHAT OFF.
SO BUNDLE UP.
THIS IS A LIVE VIEW EYE AM NOT
ANSWERING THAT.
FROM THE HIGH-DEFINITION SOUTH
CAMERA, LOOKING AT THE FUTURE
TOWER, WE ARE HEADED INTO A
FREEZING COLD NIGHT FOR SOME
PARTS OF THE BAY AREA.
MAKE SURE, IF YOU GO AND CHECK
IT OUT, YOU LOOK TO THE
SOUTHWEST AND BUNDLE UP IN A
DARK LOCATION.
THEY DO PEAK AT 2:00 A.M. IN THE
MORNING.
ON THE LIVE DOPPLER, WATCHING
THE WEATHER DEVELOPMENTS.
WE HAVE SEEN AN ISOLATED SHOWER
THIS AFTERNOON.
IT IS STILL THERE AS WE LOOK
DOWN TOWARD THE SOUTH BAY,
AROUND GILROY.
HIGHWAY 101, HEADING OUT TO THE
PASS, WE HAVE BEEN SEEING THE
RAIN THERE.
AN ISOLATED SHOWER.
REHEATED MOISTURE FROM
YESTERDAY'S TORM STORM.
YOU GET THE DAYTIME HEAT FROM
THIS SUN AND THAT CREATED THAT.
TEMPERATURES ARE FALLING.
46 DEGREES IN FAIRFIELD.
50 IN HALF BOONE MOON BAY.
49 IN FREMONT.
WE ARE HEADED TO A COLD NIGHT.
THE HIGHS WERE ON THE CHILLY
SIDE.
BELOW NORMAL, ANOTHER FROSTY
NIGHT INLAND.
LIGHT RAIN ARRIVES TOMORROW.
AND BIGGER STORMS NEXT WEEK.
HERE'S A LOOK AT THE FROST
ADVISORY FROM WOO'CLOCK TO 8:00
A.M. FRIDAY T. COVERS THE
INTERIOR VALLEYS.
TEMPERATURES LOW TO MID 30s.
WATCH OUT FOR PATCHY FROST.
SLIPPERY SIDEWALKS.
THE ONLY REASON WHY THE NORTH
BAY VALLEY'S NOT INCLUDED, WE DO
HAVE HIGHER CLOUDS MOVING IN TO
THE NORTH BAY FIRST AS THE NEXT
STORM APPROACHES.
YOU MAY GET SHELTERED FROM
REALLY DROPPING TOO MUCH.
SO WE ARE GOING TO GO WITH THE
COLDEST READINGS, DOWN TO 32 IN
MORGAN HILL, 33 IN LIVERMORE,
VALLEJO 35.
NAPA, SANTA ROSA, LOW TO
MID 30s.
WE ARE GOING TOW SEE QUITE A --
GOING TO SEE QUITE A BIT OF
CLOUD COVER.
38 IN SAN JOSE AND SANTA CRUZ.
BUNDLE UP IN THE MORNING.
MAKE SURE YOU HAVE YOUR UMBRELLA
WITH YOU.
HERE'S THE STORM THAT IS GOING
TO BRING RAIN ON FRIDAY.
IT WILL BE COLD.
WE WILL SEE VERY LIGHT RAINFALL
AMOUNTS.
A COUPLE MORE SYSTEMS LINED UP.
WE WILL GO WITH A SERIES OF
STORMS.
BUT THE STORMS, THE FIRST COUPLE
OF THEM, HEADING INTO WEEKEND,
REALLY LIGHT RAINFALL TOTALS.
5:00 A.M., TOMORROW MORNING,
JUST SOME CLOUD COVER, AS YOU
LOOK AT THE COMPUTER ANIMATION,
LIGHT RAIN BY 8:00 A.M.,
POSSIBLE.
MAINLY ALONG THE COAST AND WE
MAY SEE THE RAIN DEVELOPING
ACROSS OTHER PARTS OF THE BAY
AREA BY THE AFTERNOON.
A 10th INCH OR LESS AND THEN
YOU WILL NOTICE THAT IT TAPERS
OFF FRIDAY EVENING.
BUT OWNING ONLY FOR MORE SHOWERS
TO RETURN.
CHILLY IN THE AFTERNOON.
YOU WILL NEED TO DRESS IN
LAYERS.
THESE ARE HIGHS, NOT LOWs.
MID 40S TO THE LOW 50s.
MONTEREY BAY, UPPER 40s TO LOW
50s.
A RAW DAY.
ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST, LIGHT
RAIN ON SATURDAY, TAPERS ON
SUNDAY, WET AND BREEZY FOR
MONDAY.
COLD SHOWERS ON TUESDAY, MORE
RAIN ON WEDNESDAY AND THURSDAY.
THE FORECAST LOOKS WORSE THAN IT
IS.
THE SHOWERS BETWEEN TOMORROW AND
SUNDAY, ONE/10 TO 1/3 INCH, SO
NOT A LOT OF RAIN.
>> STILL TO COME, A BRAVE AREA
GIRL IS LEARNED.
>> TO STOP A DOMESTIC SPAT IN
>> HD LIVE OVER THE SCENE OF A
HOMICIDE IN OAKLAND.
POLICE HAVE CLOSED OFF 83rd
AVENUE AND "E" STRAIGHT WHILE
THEY INVESTIGATE A SHOOTING.
ONE PERSON IS DEAD ON THE
STREET.
HOPE TO HAVE MORE FOR YOU ON
ABC7 NEWS AT 6:00.
>> A 12-YEAR-OLD GIRL WAS
HONORED FOR QUICK ACTION DURING
A DOMESTIC VIOLENCE INCIDENT IN
A FRIEND'S HOUSE IN SAN BRUNO.
SHE RAN TO A NEIGHBOR'S HOUSE TO
CALL 911.
>> WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
>> I AM AT MY FRIEND AND MY --
MY FRIEND'S MOM IS --
[INAUDIBLE].
>> THAT WAS SKYLER POMEROY.
SHE RECEIVED A LOCAL 911 HERO
AWARD T. HELPED TO KEEP A TENSE
SITUATION FROM GETTING WORSE.
>> MY FRIEND HAD GOTTEN THROWN
TO THE GROUND AND SHE BROKE HER
ANKLE.
I SAW HER MOM GETTING CHOKED
OUT.
SO I RAN DOWN THE TEARS AND TO
THE NEIGHBOR'S AND THEY -- THEY
SAID I COULD USE THEIR PHONE.
>> THE 911ACH DISPATCHER FROM BO
WHO ANSWERED THE CALL WAS ALSO
HONORED AT THE CEREMONY.
WHAT A BRAVE YOUNG GIRL.
>> IN THE ABC7 NEWSROOM, COMING
UP NEW AT 6:00, A NEW CHAPTER IN
THE SEX AND DRUG SCANDAL.
THE ITEAM ON HER EFFORT TO GET
CLEAN AND HER TROUBLED LOVER'S
TEXT.
AND HOLIDAY SHOPPING HELP.
A LIST OF 25 WEB SITES WITH COOL
GIFTS UNDER $25.
THE HOBIT IS HERE, BUT FIND OUT
WHY ABC7'S DAWN SANCHEZ WAS NOT
HAPPY ABOUT WHEN HE SAW IN THE
HIGHLY ANTICIPATED FILM.
THAT'S COMING UP AT 6:00.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WE WANT TO THANK THOSE OF YOU
FOR MAKING ABC7'S SHARE YOUR
HOLIDAY FOOD DRIVE SUCH A GREAT
SUCCESS.
>> YOU DONATED MORE THAN
$22,000, FOR FOOD FOR THOUSANDS
OF PEOPLE.
>> THE DRIVE CONTINUES.
DONATE BY CALLING...
>> OR GIVE $10, EASY, TEXT FEED
TO 800-77.
>> IT WAS A GREAT DAY YESTERDAY.
WE WILL CONTINUE WITH WORLD NEWS
COMING UP NEXT.
>> FOR ALL OF US HERE, THANK YOU
FOR WATCHING.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR TIME.
SEE YOU AT 6:00.
>>> THIS IS "WORLD NEWS."
TONIGHT, OUT OF THE FIGHT.
THE PRESIDENT'S TOP CHOICE FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE PULLS OUT.
SUSAN RICE SAYS THE BRUISING
ATTACKS WOULD DISTRACT THE
NATION AS THE PRESIDENT DEFENDS
HER AGAIN.
>>> END GAME?
EVEN THE FRIENDS OF THE SYRIAN
DICTATOR, TONIGHT, ARE SAYING
HIS DAYS ARE NUMBERED.
WILL AMERICA BE SAFER OR IN
GREATER DANGER IF HE FALLS?
>> WHAT IS THIS?
>>> ARE THEY RIGGED?
SOME OF AMERICA'S FAVORITE
REALITY SHOWS UNDER FIRE
TONIGHT.
>>> AND, MOVES LIKE JAGGER.