>> IT IS 2:00 IN NEWTOWN RIGHT
NOW.
FIRST TWO FUNERALS BEGIN AT
1:00.
THE COMMUNITY WILL SPEND THE
NEXT SEVERAL DAYS CARRYING OUT
THE GRIM TASK TIME AND AGAIN.
PARENTS BEARING THEIR BABIES
DOING WHAT NO PARENT SHOULD HAVE
TO DO.
>> RESIDENTS ARE GALVANIZED IN
THEIR GRIEF AND BEGINNING THEIR
GOODBYES TO THE INNOCENT
VICTIMS.
NOAH IS BEING BURIED.
HE CELEBRATED HIS SIXTH BIRTHDAY
WITH TWIN SISTER LAST MONTH.
SHE SURVIVED THE SHOOTING
RAMPAGE.
SCHOOL CLASSMATE JACK PINTO IS
BEING LAID TO REST.
HE LOVED THE NEW YORK GIANTS AND
BIG FAN OF VICTOR CRUZ.
PARENTS TOLD HIM THEY WILL BURY
JACK IN HIS FAVORITE JERSEY.
>> I'M GOING TO STAY STRONG AND
DO WHATEVER I CAN DO TO HONOR
THEM.
>> THEY ARE STILL GOING TO
INTERVIEW MANY CHILDREN WHO
SURVIVED THE BLOOD BATH.
>> ANY INTERVIEWS WILL BE DONE
WITH PROFESSIONALS.
>> WE KNOW THE SHOOTER FORCED
HIS WAY INTO THE SCHOOL AND
CARRIED AN ARSENAL OF WEAPONS
INCLUDING A BUSHMASTER ASSAULT
RIFLE AND HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS OF
HIGH POWERED AMMUNITION.
>> EVERY SINGLE FACET OF THE
WEAPONS WILL BE ANALYZED.
EVERY SINGLE ROUND OF AMMUNITION
WILL BE LOOKED AT.
>> A PAINSTAKING INVESTIGATION
BEGINS.
LAST NIGHT, PRESIDENT OBAMA
SPOKE TO THE COMMUNITY IN PAIN
VOWING TO TAKE ACTION USING THE
POWER OF HIS OFFICE TO MAKE SURE
THAT ANOTHER MASSACRE LIKE THIS
HAPPENS AGAIN.
>> WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS
ANYMORE.
>> AFTER THEY ARE LAID ARREST
RES TODAY THE REST OF THE
CHILDREN WILL BE BURIED LATER
THIS WEEK.
>>> THIS MORNING, WE'RE HEARING
A NEW STORY OF SURVIVAL.
SANDY HOOK SCHOOL NURSE IS
TALKING FOR THE FIRST TIME ABOUT
THE MOMENT WHEN SHE SAID SHE
KNEW SOMETHING TERRIBLE WAS
HAPPENING.
IN AN EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW SHE
SAID SHE HEARD LOUD UPCOMING
NOISES AND HID UNDER HER COMPUTE
DESK.
>> I COULD SEE HIM FROM THE
KNEES DOWN.
>> RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU?
>> 20 FEET AWAY, HIS BOOTS WERE
FACING MY DESK AND THEN HE
TURNED AROUND WALKED OUT.
I HEARD THE DOOR CLOSE.
>> SHE AND THE SCHOOL SECRETARY
CALLED 911 AND STAY LID EN FOR
ALMOST FOUR HOURS.
THEY WERE PETRIFIED AND DIDN'T
KNOW HOW MANY SHOOTERS THERE
WERE.
>> THERE IS ARE IN DETAILS ABOUT
THE GUNMAN.
A SPOKESMAN SAYS LANZA TOOK
CLASSES THERE WHEN SHE WAS JUST
16 EVEN EARNING SOME A'S BUT
EVENTUALLY DROPPING OUT.
FACULTY MEMBER HE SUFFERED A
CONDITION WHERE HE PHYSICALLY
FELT NO PAIN.
>> IF HE CUT HIMSELF OR HURT
HIMSELF HE WOULD NOT KNOW IT OR
FEEL IT.
>> HE WOULD HAVE PERIODS OF
TIMES WHEN HE WOULD WITHDRAW
ENTIRELY ONTO HIMSELF.
>> RICHARD SAYS LANZA HAD
SEVERAL DISORDERS AND WAS SEEING
THE SCHOOL PSYCHOLOGIST.
THE BUT WERE WORRIED THAT HE
COULD BE BULLIED OR HARM
HIMSELF.
>> THEY SAY IT DEMANDS IMMEDIATE
NATIONAL ACTION.
ANNOUNCEMENT COMES AS NEW POLL
SHOWS THAT 54% OF THOSE SURVEYED
WANT STRICTER GUN LAWS, 59%
SUPPORT A BAN ON HIGH CAPACITY
CLIPS AND 52% WANT A BAN ON
SEMI-AUTOMATIC HANDGUNS.
>> I THINK IT SHOULD BE ILLEGAL
TO HAVE A WEAPON WHOSE ONLY
PURPOSE IS TO KILL LARGE NUMBERS
OF PEOPLE.
I THINK IT SHOULD BE ILLEGAL TO
SELL BULLETS WHOSE ONLY PURPOSE
IS TO PIERCE ARMORED VESTS.
LAST TIME I SAW A DEER WEARING
AN ARMORED VEST WAS LONG TIME
AGO.
>> DIANNE FEINSTEIN SAYS SHE
PLANS TO CALL FOR A VOTE ON AN
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN.
>> BAY AREA PARENTS ARE ALSO
REACT GO TO THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT INCLUDING ONE SOUTH
BAY SCHOOL THAT HAS HAD TWO
SCARES IN ONE WEEK.
WE'LL HAVE CONTINUING COVERAGE
ON A CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TRAGEDY
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
LAURA ANTHONY IS IN CONNECTICUT
AND WE'LL HAVE LIVE REPORTS AT
5:00, 6:00 AND 11:00 AND ABC
NEWS WILL HAVE SPECIAL EDITIONS
OF WORLD NEWS AT 5:30 AND
"NIGHTLINE" AT 11:35.
>> RIGHT NOW, WIDELY SCATTERED
SHOWERS BUT NOT LIKE THE STEADY
RAIN WE SAW THIS MORNING THAT
CAUSED ACCIDENTS AND EVEN A
COUPLE OF RAINBOWS.
TERRY McSWEENEY IS LIVE IN SAN
JOSE TO TELL US MORE.
>> SOME PEOPLE LOOK AT THIS
STUFF AND THEY SAY IT'S NOTHING
BUT NUISANCE RAIN AND CAUSES CAR
CRASHES AND DOESN'T PRODUCE
ENOUGH RUNOFF TO HELP THE LOW
RESERVOIRS IN THE SANTA CLARA
VALLEY BUT SOME PEOPLE SAY, IT'S
A BEAUTIFUL DAY.
>> THIS IS VIDEO OF I-280 IN
BURLINGAME.
A PICTURE SIMILAR TO THE VIEW
FROM THE FRONT SEAT OF CARS
THROUGHOUT THE BAY AREA THIS
MORNING.
WITH THE RAIN, COME SPINOUTS
NEAR THE 380 INTERCHANGE.
MANNY MAYBE MORE DRIVERS SHOULD
FOLLOW HER ADVICE.
>> SLOW DOWN.
PEOPLE DON'T KNOW HOW TO
SLOWDOWN IN CALIFORNIA WHEN IT
STARTS TO RAIN.
>> THE RAIN BRINGS BEAUTY LIKE
THE RAINBOW IN THE SOUTH BAY.
JEWEL CAN TELL YOU ABOUT
RAINBOWS.
>> THEY ARE PRETTY AND THEY ARE
COLORFUL WITH RED AND BLUE AND
THEY EVEN HAVE BROWN AND BLACK.
IF THERE ARE NO COLORS IT'S JUST
A BLACK RAINBOW IT WOULDN'T BE
LIKE THAT.
>> AND IN THE SANITY CRUZ
MOUNTAINS, THE HEAVY MIST CAME
DOWN FOR HOURS AND HOURS.
THEY WERE THINKING ABOUT WHAT
RAIN DOES FOR HER SCHEDULE AT
SCHOOL.
>> WE WATCH A MOVE.
>> WHAT IS THE MOVE TODAY?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
>> WHAT DO YOU WANT IT TO BE?
>> AND SOME PEOPLE WEREN'T
THINKING MUCH ABOUT THE RAIN AT
YOU WILL ALL?
>> NO.
>> DOESN'T MAKE YOU LATE FOR
WORK?
>> NO, I LIVE CLOSE BY.
WEATHER IS KIND OF NOTHING TO
YOU?
>> IT DOESN'T MATTER.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> I'M GOING TO STAY DOWN HERE
IN THE SANTA CLARA VALLEY AND
LOOK FOR SOME OF THOSE WHITE AND
BLACK RAINBOWS THAT SHE WAS
TALKING ABOUT.
>> IF YOU FIND THEM BE SURE TO
LET US KNOW.
>> YOU SAW THE VIDEO AROUND
BURLINGAME.
WE GOT AN ALERT, SOUTHBOUND 280
AT HILLCREST AVENUE THAT IS
MILLBRAE, ALL THE LANES ARE
CLOSED RIGHT NOW EXCEPT FOR ONE.
ONE LANE GETTING THROUGH BECAUSE
OF A MAJOR INJURY ACCIDENT.
SAN MATEO COUNTY OFFICIALS SAY
THEY WILL BE ON THE SCENE FOR
SOME TIME THERE.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
GOOD MORNING EVERYBODY.
YOU CAN SEE THE BEST RADAR
RETURNS NORTH AND ALSO SOUTH.
LET'S START OVER IN THE EAST BAY
WE HAVE A FEW AREAS OF RAIN,
COMING OUT OF LIVERMORE SOUTH OF
PLEASANTON AND SEE OVER TOWARDS
FREMONT, SUNOL GRADE, MOST OF
THE RAIN IS FARTHER SOUTH IN
SOUTH SAN JOSE.
MANY OF THE STATES, CAMDEN
AVENUE AND SANTA TERESA
BOULEVARD, THAT WHOLE AREA IS
WHERE WE GET BETTER RADAR
RETURNS.
THE RADAR IS NOT AS IMPRESSIVE
AS THE RAINFALL THAT HAVE BEEN
COMING DOWN.
BODEGA AVENUE, OVER TOWARDS
MARIN COUNTY AND PETALUMA ROAD
THAT IS WHERE WE'RE SEEING
BETTER RADAR RETURNS RIGHT NOW.
WE HAVE RAIN UP IN THE NORTH AND
SCATTERED SHOWERS IN THE
AFTERNOON.
STEADY RAIN AND WAIT UNTIL YOU
SEE THURSDAY THIS WEEKEND, BIG
STORM ON ITS WAY.
>> STILL AHEAD, PARENTS ARE
GRAPPLING WITH THE THREAT AT A
SOUTH BAY SCHOOL.
HOW THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT IS IMPACTING.
>> SECURITY MEASURES THAT BAY
AREA SCHOOLS ARE FOCUSING ON IN
THE WAKE OF LAST WEEK'S
SHOOTING.
>>> STUDENTS ARE BACK IN CLASS
AT TWO SOUTH BAY SCHOOLS THAT
WERE SHUT DOWN BECAUSE OF
THREATS TO TEACHERS.
NEWS REPORTER KARINA RUSK IS
LIVE IN COUPE WITH THIS STORY.
>> Reporter: WE DON'T KNOW
SPECIFICALLY IF THE TEACHER WHO
WAS NAMED IN THAT GRAFFITI
THREAT HAS RETURNED TO CLASS.
WE DO KNOW BECAUSE AN ARREST HAS
BEEN MADE THE TEACHER AND HIS
FAMILY ARE NO LONGER RECEIVING
PERSONAL PROTECTION FROM THE
SANTA CLARA COUNTY SHERIFF'S
OFFICE.
THE BOMB THREAT ON THURSDAY HAS
LEFT LASTING REPERCUSSIONS
ESPECIALLY IN LIGHT OF NEWTOWN
ON FRIDAY.
INVESTIGATORS WERE VERY AWARE OF
THOSE HORRIFIC SHOOTINGS AS THEY
WORK AROUND THE CLOCK TO FIGURE
OUT WHO WAS RESPONSIBLE AND
ARRESTED A 16-YEAR-OLD STUDENT
THAT CONFESSED THAT SAID THAT
BOMB WAS PLANTED TO KILL A SPECK
TEACHER.
NOT ONLY WITH MONTEVISTA CAMPUS
CLOSED AND LINCOLN ELEMENTARY
WAS SHUT DOWN WHERE PARENTS SAY
THE TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT MADE
IT MORE DIFFICULT TO HAVE A
CONVERSATION WITH THEIR CHILDREN
ABOUT THE SITUATION.
>> IT'S VERY DELICATE WAY YOU
HAVE TO EXPLAIN IT TO THE KIDS.
THEY CAN'T REALLY UNDERSTAND THE
DETAILS IN THEIR MINDS IN A WAY
THAT SAFETY IS NECESSARY
>> Reporter: COUNSELORS ARE
BEING MADE AVAILABLE FOR
STUDENTS IS STOONDZ THAT NEED TO
TALK OR PARENTS THAT NEED TO
TALK TO THEIR CHILDREN.
AS FOR THE 16-YEAR-OLD ARRESTED
FOR THE THREATS HERE IN
CUPERTINO.
HE DOES FACE FELONY CHARGES BUT
BECAUSE OF HIS AGE, THIS CASE IS
BEING HANDLED BY THE JUVENILE
PROBATION DEPARTMENT.
KARINA RUSK, "ABC 7 NEWS."
>>> WITH HEIGHTENED CONCERN OVER
KIDS' SAFETY MANY SCHOOL
DISTRICTS ARE EMPHASIZING
SECURITY PROCEDURES.
AMY HOLLYFIELD IS LIVE AT SAN
FRANCISCO SCHOOL DISTRICT
HEADQUARTERS TO CONTINUE OUR
COVERAGE.
>> I JUST SPOKE WITH THE
SUPERINTENDENT.
HE TELLS ME THAT HE HAS ASKED
ALL HIS PRINCIPALS TO TAKE
ANOTHER LOOK AT EMERGENCY
RESPONSE PLAN AND SEE IF THEY
HAVE QUESTIONS OR IF THEY NEED
ANY CHANGES.
PARENTS ALREADY SAW A CHANGE
FIRST THING THIS MORNING.
>> AND SHERMAN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IN SAN FRANCISCO PARENTS WATCHED
WITH SURPRISE BUT UNDERSTANDING
AS ADMINISTRATORS TIGHTENED
SECURITY THIS MORNING.
>> THEY LOCKED THE DOORS.
THAT IS THE REALITY.
UNFORTUNATELY THAT IS THE WORLD
WE'RE LIVING IN.
WE HAVE TO LOCK DOWN THE DOORS.
>> IT'S THE FIRST DAY BACK AND
PARENTS SAY THE TRAGEDY WAS
DEFINITELY ON THEIR MINDS AS
THEY DROPPED OFF THEIR KIDS.
>> ANYBODY THAT IS BRINGING KIDS
TO SCHOOL, THEY ARE WELL AWARE
OF ALL THE THOUGHTS THAT ARE
GOING ON WITH THE FAMILIES AND
KIDS, OF COURSE, AND THE
TEACHERS.
>> THE PRINCIPAL AT SHERMAN TOLD
US IT IS AN EXTREMELY DIFFICULT
DAY FOR SCHOOLS.
SHE DIDN'T WANT TO TALK TO
CAMERA BECAUSE SHE WANTED TO BE
WITH HER STUDENTS.
PARENTS HEARD FROM HER AND THEY
APPRECIATED THAT.
>> SO IT'S AN EFFORT TO WORK
WITH FIRST RESPONDERS SO THEY
ARE VERY PRO-ACTIVE ABOUT THAT.
>> AND SHE SAID THE SHOOTINGS
MADE HER REALIZE SHE WANTED TO
KNOW MORE ABOUT HER SCHOOL
EMERGENCY PLAN.
>> BECAUSE WE'RE TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT, WE NEED TO HAVE MORE
MEETINGS AND FIGURE OUT WHAT IS
GOING ON.
>> HE SAYS HE REALIZES THIS WILL
NOT BE AN ORDINARY DAY AND
EXPERTS WILL BE WATCHING THE
KIDS.
>> WE HAVE NUMBER OF INDIVIDUALS
THAT HAVE BEEN TRAINED ON GOING
THROUGH TRAUMATIC INCIDENTS AND
DEBRIEFING THAT AND GRIEVANCE
PROCESS.
SO WE HAVE TRAINED INDIVIDUALS
AND WE'LL BE THERE THE REST OF
THIS WEEK.
>> Reporter: THE TEAMS OF
COUNSELORS OUT ON THE CAMPUSES,
THEY ALSO HAVE SAN FRANCISCO AND
CAMPUS OFFICERS LOOKING FOR ANY
PROBLEMS OR CONCERNS.
>> MEMORIALS TO REMEMBER THE
VICTIMS OF THE TRAGEDY CONTINUE
TONIGHT IN THE BAY AREA.
ON THE PENINSULA A SERVICE OF
REMEMBRANCE GETS UNDERWAY AT
7:00 AT THE FIRST PRESBYTERIAN
CHURCH IN BURLINGAME.
IT WILL TAKE PLACE ON THE CHURCH
A EL CAMINO REAL.
>> STILL LOOKING AT DELAYS AT
SFO ABOUT 45 MINUTES BUT YOU ARE
STARTING TO SEE BREAKS IN THOSE.
THAT IS GOING TO MEAN SOME
FROSTY NIGHTS BEFORE WE LOWER
THE HAMMER ON THURSDAY AND
SATURDAY.
BIG STORMS COMING OUR WAY.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT THEY MEAN.
>> AND TIGHT SQUEEZE, A MAN
SPENT HIS NIGHT STUCK IN
>>> IN SAN FRANCISCO,
FIREFIGHTERS RESCUED A MAN THAT
WAS STUCK THAT CHIMNEY
OVERNIGHT.
IT HAPPENED AROUND MIDNIGHT ON
CLAY STREET IN THE LAUREL
HEIGHTS NEIGHBORHOOD.
IT CAUSED QUITE A COMMOTION FOR
PEOPLE THAT LIVE THERE.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHY HE WAS IN
CHIMNEY.
FIRE CREWS HAD TO GET HIM OUT.
>> WE DON'T THINK HE WAS
DELIVERING PRESENTS EITHER.
>> WE HAVE A PRESENT, IF YOU
WOULD LIKE RAINY WEATHER BUT IT
WILL DRY OUT PRETTY SOON.
>> WE HAVE A COUPLE DAYS,
TOMORROW AND WEDNESDAY TO GET
READY FOR THE NEXT ROUND OF
STORMS WHICH WILL BE INTENSE.
ONE THURSDAY WILL SET THE STAGE
FOR SATURDAY AND FLOODING AND
POSSIBLE OF POWER OUTAGES.
I KNOW IT'S MONDAY BUT WE NEED
TO KEEP OUR EYE ON TO GET OUT OF
WORK AND SHOPPING.
HERE IS A LOOK AT SAN JOSE.
YOU SEE IT'S GRAY AND ONE OF THE
BEST AREAS SO STEADIER RAIN AS
COLD FRONT SLOWLY MOVING THROUGH
THE BAY AREA.
TRAINING ECHOES AND ALAN
E-MAILED ME, INCH AND A HALF
LAST EVENING.
HERE IS A LOOK AS WE LOOK AT
VOLLMER PEAK, EAST BAY, SOME OF
THE WET WEATHER, IN FACT YOU CAN
SEE IT ON LIVE DOPPLER, SUNOL
GRADE COMING OUT OF LIVERMORE,
HEADING DOWN 680 AND ALSO 880
HEADING OUT OF FREMONT.
IT'S DOWN IN THE SOUTHERN
SECTIONS OF SANTA CLARA VALLEY,
WE'RE PICKING UP THE GREENS,
HEADING TOWARDS MORGAN HILL AND
LOS GATOS, 17, AND 35 GETTING
MORE RAIN.
SCATTERED SHOWERS, A LITTLE BIT
OF SUNSHINE, A LITTLE BIT OF
COLD AIR.
YOU HAVE A SHOWER OR TWO BUT
STEADY RAIN IS GOING TO BE OVER
SHORTLY.
RAINFALL AMOUNTS, ABOUT HALF AN
INCH IN SANTA ROSA.
QUARTER OF AN INCH IN NAPA AND
OAKLAND, LOOK AT REDWOOD CITY,
THIRD OF AN INCH, ABOUT .04.
52 IN FREMONT TO ABOUT 58 IN
NAPA.
THAT IS ABOUT AS WARM AS IT IS
GOING TO GET.
UNTIL THEN, MID-50s TO ABOUT 61
AROUND MONTEREY BAY AND INLAND.
STEADY RAIN FOR THE NEXT HOUR OR
TWO AND THEN SHOWERS THIS
AFTERNOON.
IT'S GOING TO BE FLOSS AT THIS
NOT ONLY TONIGHT BUT WEDNESDAY
MORNING COULD BE THE COLDEST
MORNING ALL WEEK.
COLD FRONT IS MOVING MORE TO THE
EAST AND THEN IT IS TO THE SOUTH
AND THAT IS THE LOW IS MOVING
AWAY FROM US.
THIS IS THE COLDER AIR AND IT'S
COMING STRAIGHT DOWN FROM ALASKA
AND INTO OUR NEIGHBORHOODS.
COLD FRONT MOVING SOUTHWARD.
YOU CAN SEE THE STEADY RAIN AND
HARDLY ANY SHOWERS BY 5:00.
WE'LL KEEP A STRAY ONE IN HERE.
NEXT ONE IS GOING TO STAY OVER
THE OCEAN AND SHOWERS OVER THE
OCEAN.
THAT WILL CONTINUE UNTIL ABOUT
NOON.
5:00 THE CLEARING AND COLDEST OF
THE AIR COMES IN.
THAT IS WHEN WE HAVE THE
WIDESPREAD FOG.
MOST OF DAY WE'LL SEE INCREASING
CLOUDS AND LIGHT SHOWERS
WEDNESDAY IN THE NORTH BAY BUT
LOOK AT THIS.
YELLOW AND ORANGE IS COMING DOWN
FOR THURSDAY.
THAT IS BIGGER STORM ON THE WAY
WITH THE GUSTY WINDS AND HEAVIER
RAIN.
THAT IS THURSDAY.
ANY, PERIODS OF RAIN.
SATURDAY ANOTHER SYSTEM COMES ON
THE HEELS OF THAT AND AFTER
THURSDAY, THE ONE ON SATURDAY
WITH THE POWER OUTAGES AND
FLOODING.
LOOKS LIKE MORE SHOWERS ON
SUNDAY THIS WEEKEND.
COULD BE A WASHOUT.
HOPEFULLY THAT WILL CHANGE BY
THE TIME WE GET THERE
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
>>> COMING UP AT 3:00 ON KATIE,
COPING WITH THE EMOTIONAL
IMPACT.
ARE WE READY FOR SERIOUS
SOLUTIONS FOR GUN VIOLENCE?
CREDIT CARD COMPANIES GIVING YOU
MONEY BACK, WHY YOU MAY SEE A
CREDIT ON UP COMING BILL AND
TAKING GUESSWORK OUT OF THE FLU
SHOTS.
NEW VACCINE MAY TARGET THE
STRAIN IN ANY GIVEN YEAR.
THOSE STORIES AT 4:00 AND 5:00.
>> FOR ALL OF US, THANK YOU FOR
JOINING US.
>> "WHO WANTS TO BE A
MILLIONAIRE" IS COMING UP NEXT.
>> AND THERE IS HOSTED OF FREE
APPS, DOWNLOAD ONE FOR YOUR
[dramatic music]
♪
>> HELLO, AND WELCOME TO
MILLIONAIRE.
KICKING THINGS OFF TODAY IS
MILLIONAIRE'S SELF-PROCLAIMED
BIGGEST FAN.
FROM MOULTRIE, GEORGIA, PLEASE
WELCOME SHAWN SUTHERLAND.
HEY, SHAWN.
OKAY, WHAT MAKES YOU OUR BIGGEST
FAN?
GIVE ME PROOF.
>> OH, IN AUGUST, 1999, I FELL
IN LOVE WITH THIS SHOW
THE FIRST WEEK IT WAS ON WITH
REGIS PHILBIN.
I SAW A LADY GOING FOR $16,000
ON A TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD
QUESTION.
SAW IT WAS MULTIPLE CHOICE,
IT WAS REAL QUESTIONS FOR REAL
MONEY.
I FELL IN LOVE IMMEDIATELY.
I STARTED KEEPING TRACK OF EVERY
CONTESTANT THAT WAS ON.
I SAW EVERY EPISODE.
IF I WAS GONNA BE OUT OF TOWN,
I RECORDED 'EM.
I GOT ALL OF THEM.
>> YOU NEED HELP.
YOU NEED HELP.
>> I NEED A LOT OF HELP.
I NEED A MILLION DOLLARS.
>> NO, WHEN I TOOK OVER.
I MISSED THE BEST PART.