OF THE BUILDING.
AND BY THE TIME OUR FOLKS GOT
HERE, IT WAS WELL INVOLVED.
>> YOU HAVE DONE A GOOD JOB.
RIGHT NOW, THEY ARE GOING
INSIDE, MAKING SURE, LOOKING AT
THE DAMAGE, CHECKING FOR HOT
SPOTS.
WE APPRECIATE ALL THE WORK THAT
YOU HAVE DONE TODAY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
NO INJURIES THAT WE KNOW OF, AT
THIS POINT.
THE FIRE IS BASICALLY OUT.
THEY ARE JUST CHECKING FOR HOT
SPOTS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
CERTAINLY, WE SAW JUST THAT
THICK, BLACK SMOKE IN THE AIR,
EARLIER TODAY.
>> RIGHT.
LET'S CHECK IN WITH OUR
METEOROLOGIST TO LOOK AT THE
WIND CONDITIONS, SPECIFICALLY IN
THE FREMONT AREA.
>> Reporter: CURRENTLY, AS WE
LOOK IN THE VICINITY OF THE
FIRE, WE DO HAVE VERY LIGHT
WINDS BEING REPORTED.
FREMONT NOW, OUT OF THE
NORTH-NORTHWEST, 3 MILES PER
HOUR.
RELATIVE HUMIDITY, 62%.
TEMPERATURE IS 53 DEGREES.
WITH THE WIND FROM THE NORTH
HISTORY NORTHWEST AT 3.
IT WAS NORTH-NORTH EASTERLY
EARLIER, BUT IT HAS BEEN LIGHT.
ONCE AGAIN, THE WIND LIGHT IN
THE VICINITY OF THAT FIRE.
I WILL BE BACK WITH A LOOK AT
THE FORECAST, WHICH INCLUDES THE
POSSIBILITY OF FROST.
I WILL SHOW YOU THE FROST
ADVISORY, HOW COLD TONIGHT AND
UNSETTLED WEATHER IN THE
ACCU-WEATHER SEVEN-DAY FORECAST.
HOW MANY DAYS OF RAIN, COMING
UP.
>> THANKS.
SEE YOU SHORTLY.
DEBBIE TWEETED PHOTOINGS TO US.
WE SPOKE TO DEBBIE.
SHE WORKS ACROSS THE STREET FROM
THE FIRE.
SHE TOLD US SHE HEARD THE ROOF
COLLAPSE AND THEN SAW THE DEBRIS
FALLING.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS VIDEO.
THIS WAS SENT TO YOU REPORT IT.
THAT'S THE THICK, BLACK SMOKE WE
HAVE BEEN TALKING ABOUT.
BUT IT'S AN IMPORTANT COMPLEX IN
THE FOREGROUND.
AND THE SMOKE POURING FROM THE
BUILDING, BEHIND T. NO INJURIES
AREN'TED AT THE SCENE --
REPORTED AT THE SCENE.
NO ONE'S GONE TO THE HOSPITAL
WITH RESPIRATORY PROBLEMS.
WE HAVE POSTED VIDEOS AND PHOTOS
ON OUR WEB SITE.
>> OMINOUS LOOKING AT THE SKY.
NOW AT 4:00, A SURPRISE IN
WASHINGTON.
U.N. AMBATIONZ DORSUSAN RICE HAS
TAKEN HERSELF OUT OF THE RUNNING
FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE.
>> SHE HAD BEEN THE FRONTRUNNER
THE FEDERAL POST.
SHE FACED CRITICISM FROM SENATE
REPUBLICANS WHO HAVE TAKEN ISSUE
WITH HER INITIAL STATEMENTS
ABOUT THE U.S. CONSULATE ATTACK
IN BENGHAZI, LIBYA.
RICE SUBMITTED A LETTER TO
PRESIDENT OBAM APREDICTING THE
CONFIRMATION PROCESS WOULD BE
LENGTHY, TIME CONSUMING AND
COSTLY.
NOTING THE UNFAIRNESS OF THE
ATTACKS, MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR,
JOHN KERRY IS NOW THE PROJECTED
FRONTRUNNER FOR THAT POST.
>> THE UNSCHEDULED FISCAL CLIFF
MEETING AT THE WHITE HOUSE
BETWEEN PRESIDENT OBAMA AND BABE
BANE IS OVER.
NO WORD OF PROGRESS.
THE TWO MET FOR ABOUT AN HOUR
THIS AFTERNOON.
THIS WAS THEIR FIRST
FACE-TO-FACE TALK SINCE SUNDAY.
MR. OBAMA AND BOEHNER HAVE
STRUGGLED TO MAKE THE IMPASSE
OVER TAXES.
THE PRESIDENT WANTS TAX RATES TO
RISE FOR THE TOP 2% OF INCOME
EARNERS, WHICH BOEHNER IS
OPPOSED TO.
THE DEAL MUST BE REACHED BY
DECEMBER 31 TO AVOID THE FISCAL
CLIFF, WHICH WOULD TRIGGER A
SERIES OF TAX INCREASES AND
SPENDING CUTS.
>> A CONTROVERSIAL FACEBOOK
POSTING, BY SERGEANT CARL TNCHTS
OF HIMSELF, RIDING THROUGH THE
BROADWAY TUNNEL AND CLAIMED HE
WAS WITH OTHERS IN A
LAMBORGHINI, GOING 100 MILES PER
HOUR AND SAID THEY WERE ALL
DRUNK.
TODAY THE CHIEF SAYS HE IS
OUTRAGED.
>> OBVIOUSLY, IT IS BEYOND
IRRESPONSIBLE AND DUMB.
I WAS OUT OF TOWN YESTERDAY, SO
MY FIRST ACT TO GET BACK WAS TO
REASSIGN THE SERGEANT OUT OF
PATROL.
NOBODY WITH SUCH POOR JUDGMENT
SHOULD BE AROUND THE YOUNGER
OFFICERS.
>> SERGEANT CARL TNCHTS, WHO
LEGALLY CHANGED HIS NAME IS ON
DESK DUTY, PENDING AN
INVESTIGATION INTO THIS
INCIDENT.
>> THERE IS DISBELIEF AND
ANGUISH OVER THE STATE'S THREAT
TO SHUT DOWN AN INSTITUTION FOR
HUNDREDS OF PATIENTS WITH SEVERE
DISABILITIES IN SONOMA.
>> THE STATE MOVED TO YANK THE
LICENSE OF THE FACILITY
YESTERDAY.
WE HAVE THE LATEST ON THE FOR
ONLY ON ABC7 NEWS.
>> Reporter: FAMILIES ARE
DEVASTATED BY THE DECISION OF
STATE REGULATORS TO DE-CERTIFY
SONOMA DEVELOPMENTAL CENTERS
BOARDING CARE FACILITIES FOR
SOME 300 RESIDENTS WITH
INTELLECTUAL DISABILITIES.
THE STATE PUBLIC HEALTH
DEPARTMENT, WHICH MONITORS
HEALTH AND SAFETY AT THE FIVE
DEVELOPMENTAL CENTERS CONCLUDED
THAT PATIENTS HAVE BEEN
REPEATEDLY PUT AT RISK OF
INJURY, SEXUAL ABUSE AND EVEN
DEATH AT THE FACILITY.
THE HEALTH DEPARTMENT'S DECISION
WOULD MEAN SHUTTING DOWN A MAJOR
PORTION OF THE INSTITUTION.
THE PROGRAM THAT CARES FOR
SEVERELY DISABLED PATIENT WHO IS
ARE NOT BEDRIDDEN, BUT LIVE ON
THE PREMISE.
THE ACTION COMES AFTER A SERIES
OF REPORTS ABOUT ABUSES AND LAX
INVESTIGATIONS AT THE FACILITY,
WHICH ABC7 NEWS AND ITS MEDIA
PARTNER, CALIFORNIA WATCH,
EXPOSED
EXPOSED THIS PAST YEAR.
THEY INCLUDE AN INCIDENT IN THE
FALL OF LAST YEAR, WHERE A DOZEN
PATIENTS AT THE CENTER HAD BEEN
TASERED.
THE OFFICE OF PROTECTIVE
SERVICES, THE FACILITY'S
INTERNAL POLICE FORCE,
DISCOVERED A TASER GUN IN THE
CAR OF A STAFF MEMBER.
HE WAS LATER FIRED.
BUT NO CRIMINAL CHARGES WERE
FILED AGAINST HIM OR ANYBODY
ELSE.
DECERTIFICATION WOULD MEAN THE
LOSS OF TENS OF MILLIONS OF
DOLLARS IN MEDICAID FUNDING FOR
THE PROGRAM.
THE DEPARTMENT OF DEVELOPMENTAL
SERVICES SAYS IT WILL APPEAL THE
DECISION, AS IT STRIVES TO MAKE
CHANGES IN THE PROGRAM.
DURING THE APPEALS PROCESS, THE
SONOMA CENTER CAN REMAIN OPEN,
AS IT CONTINUES TO RECEIVE
FEDERAL FUNDING.
>> AN ALL CLEAR WAS GIVEN AFTER
TWO CUPERTINO SCHOOLS WERE
CLOSED DUE TO A BOMB THREAT.
THIS MORNING, GRAFFITI WAS
DISCOVERED AT LYNBROOK HIGH
SCHOOL.
>> THAT REFERENCED A BOMB SQUARE
IN CUPERTINO.
BECAUSE OF ITS CLOSE PROXIMITY
TO THE HIGH SCHOOL, LINCOLN
ELEMENTARY WAS ALSO SHUT DOWN.
POLICE MADE SURE THE TEACHER
NAMED IN THE GRAFFITI IS
PROTECTED.
>> THERE IS A DEPUTY OR TWO,
STAYING WITH THE TEACHER AND HIS
FAMILY AT THIS POINT.
TO ENSURE HIS SAFETY AND THE
SAFETY OF HIS FAMILY MEMBERS.
HE IS HOLDING UP QUITE WELL.
>> NO DEVICE WAS FOUND AT THE
SCHOOL.
POLICE ARE INVESTIGATING TO
DETERMINE WHO MADE THAT THREAT.
CLASSES AT BOTH SCHOOLS WILL
RESUME TOMORROW.
>> THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO HAS
ASKED A JUDGE TO DISMISS A
CONSTITUTIONAL CHALLENGE THAT
THE CITY'S PUBLIC NUDITY BAN.
CITY ATTORNEY FILED THE MOTION
AND DROPPED THE SUIT IN U.S.
DISTRICT COURT.
THE ORDINANCE PASSED EARLIER
THIS MONTH AND BANS NUDITY ON
PUBLIC STREET, SIDEWALKS AND
PUBLIC TRANSIT AND GOES INTO
EFFECT FEBRUARY 1.
>> JOSEPH CRIENZ HAS BEEN NAMED
THE CHIEF OF POLICE.
HE HAS BEEN SERVING AS INTERIM
CHIEF SINCE JULY.
HE HAS 32 YEARS OF EXPERIENCE.
HIS APPOINTMENT IS EFFECTIVE ON
SATURDAY.
>> GOT A COUPLE OF SPORTS
ARTICLES.
THE GIANTS ARE BRINGING BACK A
FAMILIAR FACE.
>> THEY SIGNED AN DESCRES
TORRESTO A DEAL WORTH $2
BHILLION.
HE WAS IN THE 2010 CHAMPIONSHIP
RUN AND WAS TRADED TO THE METS.
TORRES IS EXPECTED TO BE IN A
DEAL.
>> THE TALK OF THE NBA, IN THE
VICTORY OVER THE NBA CHAMPIONS
IN MIAMI HAS GOTTEN EVERYBODY'S
ATTENTION.
DAVID LEE'S PLAYING GREAT.
22 POINTS, THE WARRIORS SHOWING
TOUGHNESS.
LEE, HAMMERING LEBRON JAMES.
THEY CALLED IT A FLAFRANT FOUL.
BUT HE STAYED IN THE GAME.
THAT'S THE GAME-WINNING PLAY.
97-95 AND WITH LESS THAN A
SECOND LEFT, LEBRON JAMES TRIED
TO GO FOR THE TIE -- NO GOOD.
AND THE WARRIORS PULL OFF A
STUNNING VICTORY IN MIAMI.
THEY ARE ON A ROAD TRIP.
NEXT STOP TOMORROW IN ORLANDO.
>> THEIR SUCCESS ON THE ROAD
REALLY PHENOMENAL.
>> REMARKABLE FOR A TEAM THAT
HASN'T HAD THIS KIND OF A ROLL
FOR QUITE A WHILE.
IT'S FUN TO WATCH.
>> STILL AHEAD, ANOTHER
LEADERSHIP SHAKE-UP AT YAHOO.
WE ARE INVESTIGATING THE PLOT TO
KILL A SUPER STAR, JUSTIN
BIEBER.
>> CONSUMER COMPLAINTS AND A
WARNING FROM POLICE.
>> OUR FIRST CHECK OF TRAFFIC.
LOOKING AT THE SKYWAY IN DUN
TOWN SAN FRANCISCO, IT IS BUMPER
TO BUMPER IN BOTH DIRECTIONSES
ON THE BAY BRIDGE, HEADING TO
THE EAST BAY.
THE OTHER SIDE, TRYING TO GET TO
THE PENINSULA AND 101 SOUTH.
IT IS SLOW IN BOTH DIRECTIONS.
STAY WITH US.
MORE TO COME ON ABC7 AT 4:00. AK
IN VERY OLD HABITS
OF USING TOOTHPASTE
TO CLEAN THEIR DENTURE.
BUT DENTURES ARE VERY DIFFERENT
TO REAL TEETH.
THEY'RE ABOUT 10 TIMES SOFTER
AND MAY HAVE SURFACE PORES WHERE
BACTERIA CAN GROW AND MULTIPLY.
POLIDENT
IS SPECIFICALLY DESIGNED
TO CLEAN DENTURES DAILY.
ITS UNIQUE MICRO-CLEAN FORMULA
KILLS 99.9%
OF ODOR CAUSING BACTERIA
AND HELPS DISSOLVE STAINS,
CLEANING IN A BETTER WAY
THAN BRUSHING WITH TOOTHPASTE.
THAT'S WHY DENTISTS
RECOMMEND POLIDENT.
[ Male Announcer ] POLIDENT.
CLEANER, FRESHER,
BRIGHTER EVERY DAY.
>> PROMISING NEWS FOR THE
HOUSING MARKET.
INDUSTRY ANALYSTS SAYS IT'S
RETURNING TO NORMAL.
>> 7300 NEW AND EXISTING HOMES
WERE SOLD LAST MONTH.
THAT'S DOWN A LITTLE FROM
OCTOBER, BUT UP 15 1/2 PERCENT
FROM A YEAR AGO.
THE MEDIAN PRICE FOR A HOM LAST
MONTH WAS $438,000, UP 20% FROM
NOVEMBER OF 2011.
THE NUMBER OF HOMES SOLD IN THE
BAY AREA FOR HALF A MILLION
DOLLARS WAS UP 36%.
>> GOOGLE MAPS AND APPLE DWISES
ARE BACK TOGETHER.
THE APP RETURN TO THE ITUNES
STORE, ALLOWING iPad AND
iPHONE USERS TO USE THE
MAPPING PROGRAM, NEARLY THREE
MONTHS AFTER APPLE REPLACED IT
WITH ITS OWN MAPPING APP,
PLAGUED WITH WRONG AND MISSING
INFORMATION.
ON MONDAY, AUSTRALIAN POLICE
WARNED USERS NOT TO USE APPLE
MAPS AFTER RESCUING PEOPLE
STRAND IN THE WILDERNESS BECAUSE
THEY FOLLOWED THE APPLE MAP
DIRECTIONS.
>> WE WANT TO THANK ALL OF YOU
FOR MAKING THE SHARE YOUR
HOLIDAY FOOD DRIVE A GREAT
SUCCESS.
>> YOU DONATED MORE THAN $22,000
TO BAY AREA FOOD BANKS
YESTERDAY, TRANSLATING TO FOOD
FOR 70,000 PEOPLE.
>> OUR SHARE YOUR HOLIDAY FOOD
DRIVE CONTINUES THROUGH DECEMBER
31.
YOU CAN DONATE.
1-877-37 MR.
THE NEED IS AS GREAT AS IT HAS
EVER BEEN.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
WE SAW MAJOR CHANGES.
SANDY WARNED US IT WOULD BE
COLD.
>> WE ARE SHIVERING!
>> I KNOW.
YOU WILL BE SHIVERING AGAIN
TOMORROW MORNING.
WE ARE LOOKING AT FROST
ADVISORIES OVERNIGHT TONIGHT.
LET ME SHOW YOU A LIVE PICTURE.
THE TEMPERATURES DROPPED DOWN
BELOW FREEZING IN SOME OF OUR
INLAND VALLEYS.
AND WEARE HEADING OUT IN TOWARDS
ANOTHER NIGHT OF CHILL.
A LIVE PICTURE FROM EMERYVILLE.
YOU CAN SEE A FEW CLOUD THERE
IS.
MOISTURE FROM YESTERDAY'S
SYSTEM, HEATED BY THE SUN.
AND THE RESULT HAS BEEN -- CHECK
OUT THE LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD, A FEW
SHOWERS HAVE DEVELOPED BETWEEN
GILROY AND HOLISTER.
WE HAVE MOISTURE ON MT.
ST. HELENA.
YOU CAN SEE FROM GILROY TOWARDS
HOLISTER, WE HAVE ISOLATED
SHOWER, BRIEF DOWNPOURS AND
SMALL HAIL NOT OUT OF THE
QUESTION.
THIS WILL BE OUT OF HERE BY THE
TIME THE SUN GOES DOWN.
THE TEMPERATURES LOOK LIKE THIS,
IN THE 50s AND ON THE COOL
SIDE.
50 DEGREES IN FREMONT.
ONLY 52 IN SAN FRANCISCO.
AND SAN JOSE.
FAIRFIELD, 52 DEGREES.
HERE ARE THE HIGHLIGHTS.
ANOTHER FROSTY NIGHT, INLAND.
LIGHT RAIN TOMORROW.
WE ARE LOOKING AT BIGGER STORMS.
IT IS REALLY GOING TO BE AN
UNSETTLED PATTERN.
AS YOU LOOK AT THE FROST
ADVISORY.
IT GOES UP FOR THE ACE BAY
INTERIOR VALLEYS, 2:00 A.M.
UNTIL 8:00 A.M., THE
TEMPERATURES ARE EXPECTED TO
DROP DOWN, THROW MID 30s.
WATCH OUT FOR FROSTY WINDSHIELDS
AND SLIPPERY SIDEWALKS AS PATCHY
FROST IS EXPECTED TO FORM
HEADING INTO THE NUMBER.
BY MORNING, DOWN TO 33 IN
LIVERMORE, 34 IN FAIRFIELD.
34 IN SANTA ROSA.
NAP, 33 DEGREES.
THE ONLY THING THAT WILL SAVE
YOU FROM DROPPING TOO LOY IN THE
NORTH BAY IS THE CLOUD COVER IN
ADVANCE OF THE RAIN.
LET'S CHECK OUT THE STORM
SYSTEM.
THIS IS THE ONE PRODUCING RAIN
FOR US FOR YOUR FRIDAY.
COLD WITH LIGHT RAIN ON FRIDAY.
IN THE MORNING, IT'S A CHANCE.
AND THEN REALLY DEVELOPS BY THE
AFTERNOON.
SERIES OF STORMS LINED UP IN THE
PACIFIC THE NEXT 7 DAYS.
WE WILL BE SEEING THAT WET
WEATHER.
AHEAD, TONIGHT, 7:00 P.M., WE
ARE LOOKING AT CLEAR SKIES.
AS WE HEAD INTO TOMORROW, LIGHT
RAIN EXPECTED FOR YOUR FRIDAY.
AS WE HEAD INTO SATURDAY AND
SUNDAY, IN MORE LIGHT RAIN
COMING IN.
SIERRA WILL SEE SNOW AS WE SEE
THE COLDER STORMS.
MONDAY'S GOING TO BE WET AND
WINDY WITH ANOTHER STORM MOVING
IN.
REALLY, SHOWERS CONTINUE WITH
ANOTHER STORM, THE STRONGEST OF
THE SERIES, COMING IN ON
WEDNESDAY NIGHT, GOING INTO
THURSDAY.
SO THIS IS GOING TO BE
UNSETTLED.
HIGHS FOR TOMORROW, CHILLY.
UPPER 40s TO LOW 50s IN MOST
AREAS.
AS WE CHECK OUT THE FORECAST, IT
IS UNSETTLED.
LIGHT RAIN FOR THE WEEKEND.
WE WILL SEE MILDER WEATHER IN
THE MORNINGS.
COLD SHOWERS ON TUESDAY AND RAIN
IS LIKELY WEDNESDAY NIGHT INTO
THURSDAY, AS I MENTIONED.
STAYING ON THE COOL SIDE,
TEMPERATURES MAINLY IN THE
50s.
>> UNSETTLED IS CODE WORD FOR
WEAK?
>> WE ARE NOT OFFENDING ANYONE
WHO ENJOYS THE RAIN.
>> THAT'S A LITTLE BETTER.
WE ARE GOING TO BLOOMBERG, NOW,
RIGHT?
BIG CHANGES TO THE YAHOO BOARD.
APPLE LOSES ON ONE LEGAL FRONT,
REACHING A SETTLEMENT ON OTHER
ANOTHER.
>> LIVE FROM BLOOMBERG WEST.
>> Reporter: YEAH, GUYS.
MARISSA MEYER REMAKING THE YAHOO
BOARD.
IN THE STATEMENT, MEYER PRAISED
THE STRONG PRODUCT AND TECH
EXPERTISE AND TWO OTHER
EXECUTIVES ARE LEAVING, THE
INTUIT CEO AND THE WEATHER
CHANNEL CEO ARE GONE, EFFECTIVE
IMMEDIATELY.
YAHOO'S 11 BOARD MEMBER, ODD
NUMBERS ARE GOOD ON EYE BOARD.
AND THEY HAVE REVAMPED THEIR
EMAIL AND THE FLICKER
PHOTO-SHARING SERVICE THIS WEEK.
APPLE IS ON THE END OF A LOSING
END OF A PATENTS LAWSUIT.
FINING THAT THE APPLE iPHONE
INFRINGED ON THREE PATENTS HELD
BY MOBILE MEDIA IDEAS, A PATENT
HOLDING COMPANY HELD BY SONY AND
NOKIA, RELATED TO THE iPHONE
CAMERA AND THE WAY IT ACCEPTS
AND REJECTS CALLS.
A SEPARATE TRIAL WILL DETERMINE
DAMAGES.
APPLE DID NOT COMMENT.
IN OTHER NEWS -- MORE LEGAL NEWS
FOR APPLE, FOUR PUBLISHERS HAVE
SETTLED ANTI-TRUST
INVESTIGATIONS IN EUROPE AND THE
EUROPEAN UNION OVER eBOOK
PRICE FIXING.
APLE  AND THE PUBLISHERS WILL
DROP THE PRICING AGREEMENTS,
AIMED TO UNDERCUT AMAZON, TO
RESTORE NORMAL, COMPETITIVE
CONDITIONS TO THE eBOOK
MARKET.
APPLE AND McMILLAN AND PENGUIN
ARE FACING A SIMILAR PROBE IN
THE U.S.
TESTING THE NEW BLACKBERRY 10
PHONES.
U.S. IMMIGRATIONS AND CUSTOMS
WILL START TO TEST THE DEVICES
NEXT YEAR.
IT'S INTERESTING BECAUSE THEY
SAID THEY WOULD BUY iPHONES
EARLIER.
NOW THEY SAY THEY WILL USE BOTH
DEVICES.
TURNING TO TRADING, STOCKS
LOWERS WITH THE FISCAL CLIFF
IMPASSE OVERSHADOWING RETAIL
AGAINS IN SALES.
APPLE AND ORACLE LEADING THE
DECLINE.
TODAY, SAN FRANCISCO START UP
UBER SEEMS TO BE A THREAT TO NEW
YORK CITY CAB DRIVERS, APPROVING
A ONE-YEAR PILOT PROGRAM TO
ALLOW PEOPLE TO HAIL CABS WITH
THEIR MOBILE PHONES, WHICH IS
EXACTLY WHAT UBER DOES FOR CAR
SERVICES.
THE PROGRAM WILL START IN EARLY
FEBRUARY.
IN SAN FRANCISCO, I'M COREY
JOHNSON WITH BLOOMBERG WEST.
BACK TO YOU.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
UP NEXT, IT IS A LOVE MOTEL FOR
YOUR PET.
UNIQUE THINGS FOR ANIMAL LOVERS
AND THEIR FURRY FRIENDS.
>> THAT'S FRIGHTENING.
>> WE'LL TELL YOU WHO GOT THE
BIG NOD IN THE GOLDEN GLOBE
NOMINATIONS, JUST AHEAD.
>> LET'S CHECK THE TRAFFIC AT
THE GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE.
IF YOU ARE COMING INTO THE CITY,
A LITTLE HEAVIER NORTHBOUND INTO
MARIN.
MORE TO COME ON ABC7 NEWS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THIS IS A REALLY STRANGE ONE.
POLICE IN THREE STATES ARE
SORTING THROUGH A PLOT TO KILL
JUSTIN BIEBER.
AUTHORITIES IN NEW MEXICO SAY
CONVICTED KILLER DANA MARTIN
ORCHESTRATED THIS PLOT FROM HIS
PRISON CELL.
HE THEN ENLISTED A FORMER PRISON
BUD SCBE HIS NEPHEW TO STRANGLE
TWO ACQUAINTANCES OF MARTIN'S
AND THEN HEAD TO NEW YORK TO
KILL BIEBER.
MARTIN WAS ANGRY AT BIEBER
BECAUSE HE HAD WRITTEN THE
SINGER SEVERAL TIMES WITHOUT A
RESPONSE.
MARTIN WAS INFATUATED WITH THE
POP STAR, TATTOO TOOING AN IMAGE
OF BEEB OR HIS LEG.
>> COMPLETLY BIZARRE.
MANY OF YOUR FAVORITE STARS WOKE
UP TO A GOLDEN PHONE CALL.
>> THAT'S THE KIND YOU DON'T
MIND.
ONE SINGER MAKES HIS PERMANENT
MARK IN HOLLYWOOD.
>> Reporter: THE HOLLYWOOD
AWARDS RACES IS ON.
THE GOLDEN GLOBE NOMINATIONS
WERE ANNOUNCED THIS MORNING.
THERE IS FIERCE COMPETITION.
>> BEST MOTION PICTURE DRAMA...
ARGO, JANGO UNCHAINED, LIFE OF
PI, LINCOLN, ZERO DARK 30Y.
>> JESSICA ALBA, MEGAN FOX AND
ED HELMS MADE THE ANNOUNCEMENT.
CHECK OUT THE FULL LIST OF
NOMINEES.
IT'S A GREAT DAY TO BE HUGH
JACKSON.
HE OWNER EARNED A GOLDEN GLOBE
NOD AND EARNED A STAR ON THE
WALK OF FAME.
CATCH LE MIS, OUT CHRISTMAS DAY.
THE PREMIERE OF THE NEW COMEDY,
THIS IS 40.
IT IS PACKED UP WITH
OVER-THE-HILL HILARITY, WHICH
THE STARS CAN RELATE TO.
>> I DON'T THINK 40 IS SO
DIFFERENT FROM 39 OR ANYTHING,
BUT IT DOES FORM ON THE LIPS
DIFFERENTLY.
>> SOME DAYS, I AM NOT FEELING
AS GOOD ABOUT IT, WHEN I SEE THE
GRAY HAIRS HERE AND THERE.
>> THIS IS 40 OPENS DECEMBER 21.
KEEP UP WITH YOUR FAVORITE STARS
ANY TIME.
I'M ON THE RED CARPET IN LOS
ANGELES.
>> ALL RIGHT.
PEOPLE LOVE THEIR DOGS AND A FEW
ARE ORBSESSED WITH POOCHES, NO
MORE THAN BRAZILIANS.
>> A PET COMPLEX NOW FEATURES A
LOVE MOTEL FOR DOGS, FEATURING
ROOMS WITH MIRRORS ON THE
CEILINGS, AS WELL AS OTHER
DOGGIE AMENITIES FOR $50.
>> THERE YOU CAN SEE IT, THE
JAPANESE SOAKING TUB FOR THE
POOCHES.
>> THEY ARE PAMPERED.
THEY ARE THE LATEST STATUS SIM
BELLE BOL IN BRAZIL.
IT ALSO FEATURES SPAS, ANIMAL
DAY CARE AND RESTAURANTS WITH
DOGGIE MENUS.
>> I'M, I'M FIDO.
BIZARRE.
>> NORTH KOREAN LEADER HAS BEEN
VOTED PERSON OF THE YEAR IN TIME
MAGAZINE'S READERS POLL.
>> THIS IS A DRAWING OF KIM KIM
JONG UN WITH THE TITLE LITTLE
KIM, RECEIVING 5 1/2 MILLION
VOTE, IN A COMPLETELY
UNSCIENTIFIC POLL.
>> THE MAGAZINE ADMITS THEY WERE
INFLATED BY ONLINE CAMPAIGNS.
IT COMES A DAY AFTER NORTH KOREA
DEFIED U.N. SANCTIONS AND
LAUNCHED A ROCKET INTO ORBIT.
THIS DOES NOT MEAN IT IS TIMES
PERSON OF THE YEAR.
THAT IS MADE BY THE EDITORS OF
TIME AND WILL BE ANNOUNCED NEXT
WEEK.
>> A WARNING FOR ANYBODY WITH A
BANK ACCOUNT.
PLUS --
>> SAN FRANCISCO LAUNCHES A NEW
DOMESTIC VIOLENCE CAMPAIGN, AT A
TIME WHEN TENSIONS CAN RUN HIGH
IN HOMES.
>> WAS IT ALL A PUBLICITY STUNT?
CLAIMS FROM SOFTWARE PIONEER
JOHN MacAFEE ABOUT HIS RUN
FROM AUTHORITIES IN CENTRAL
AMERICA.
>> MICHAEL FINNEY.
TYPING ON A TOUCH SCREEN CAN BE
FRUSTRATING.
NOW A TABLET COMPUTER ACCESSORY
COULD END THAT.
I WILL TELL YOU WHETHER IT'S
>> ABC7 NEWS WITH LIVE, BREAKING
NEWS.
>> AN UPDATE ON THE BREAKING
NEWS WE TOLD YOU ABOUT AT THE
BEGINNING OF THE NEWSCAST IN THE
EAST BAY.
A LARGE FIRE IN A FREMONT
MACHINE SHOP IS IN THE MOP-UP
PHASE.
WE WERE OVER THE SCENE, SHORTLY
AFTER FLAMES BURST OUT OF A
METAL AND FABRICATING COMPANY.
LOCATED NEAR THE MISSION
BOULEVARD EXIT OFF INTERSTATE
680.
HEAVY OILS CONTRIBUTED TO HEAVY,
THICK, SOOTY SMOKE.
THE 60 PEOPLE INSIDE THE SHOP,
GOT OUT SAFELY.
THE CAUSE OF THE FIRE IS UNDER
INVESTIGATIONS.
>> THEY GOT OUT BEFORE THE ROOF
COLLAPSED OF JUST A MESS.
>> THE MAYOR WANTS THE CITY TO
BE PARTICULARLY AWARE OF
DOMESTIC VIOLENCE DURING THIS
HOLIDAY SEASON.
>> HE LAUNCHED A NEW PUBLIC
AWARENESS CAMPAIGN AT THE END OF
THE YEAR IN WHICH DOMESTIC
VIOLENCE HAS RECEIVED
UNPRECEDENTED ATTENTION IN THE
CITY.
MARK?
>> Reporter: EVER SINCE THE
SHERIFF GRABBED HIS WIFE'S ARM
ON NEW YEAR'S EVE, THERE HAS
BEEN A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF
ATTENTION TOPAID TO WHETHER OR
NOT HE SHOULD KEEP HIS JOB AND
TO DOMESTIC VIOLENCE ISSUES IN
GENERAL.
SOME OF THE SHERIFF'S MOST
POLITICALLY EMPOWERED OPPONENTS
CAME DIGNITARY TO LAUNCH THIS
NEW DOMESTIC AWARENESS CAMPAIGN.
>> DOMESTIC VIOLENCE GOES UP
DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
THERE IS A LOT OF DEPRESSION
THAT GOES ALONG WITH HOLIDAYS
AND WE UNDERSTAND THAT.
PEACE AT HOME IS THERE TO
ADDRESS THAT, RIGHT AWAY.
>> THE MAYOR OF JOINED BY THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS, AND THE
DISTRICT ATTORNEY, ALL THREE ARE
ON THE RECORD SAYING THAT ROSS
MERCURINI SHOULD NOT BE SHERIFF
BECAUSE OF HIS CONVICTION
STEMMING FROM THE ARGUMENT WITH
HIS WIFE.
BUT THE SHERIFF SAYS HE SUPPORTS
THE MAYOR'S PEACE AT HOME
CAMPAIGN.
>> WE ARE MOVE TOGETHER AND
MOVING FORWARD.
GOOD WORK IS GETTING DONE.
THE LIGHT SIDE AND THE POSITIVE
SIDE, WHICH YOU ARE CATCHING ON
CAMERA IS OUR TOY DRIVE AT
WOMAN'S RESOURCE CENTER,
AFFILIATED WITH THE SHERIFFS
DEPARTMENT.
>> THAT'S WHERE WE CAUGHT UP
WITH HIM HE FEEL SAYS HE WILL
NOT RESIGN, EVEN THOUGH THERE IS
AN EFFORT TO RECALL HIM.
HE SAYS HE IS NOT FOCUSES ON THE
RECALL.
COMING UP AT 6:00, WE WILL HEAR
FROM THE DIRECTOR OF THE
DOMESTIC VIOLENCE CONSORTIUM
ABOUT WHY THIS CAMPAIGN IS
NEEDED AND WHY IT HAS NOTHING TO
DO WITH THE SHERIFF.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
THERE IS STILL NO WORD ON A
MOTIVE FOR THE SHOOTING SPREE
THAT KILLED TWO SHOPPERS TUESDAY
AT A SUBURBAN PORTLAND, OREGON,
MALL.
BUT FRIENDS OFIA COB ROBERTS
INSIST HE WAS THE LEAST LIKELY
PERSON TO GO ON A SPREE.
HIS EX-GIRLFRIEND SAID HE HAD
QUIT HIS JOB, SOLD HIS STUFF AND
HAD A PLANE TICKET TO HAWAII,
BUT GOT DRUNK AND MISSED HIS
FLIGHT.
SHE SAYS HE IS SOFT SPOKEN AND
CANNOT IMAGINE WHAT MADE HIM
SNAP.
>> HE IS JUST TOO SWEET.
HE WAS NEVER MEAN TO ANYBODY --
EVER.
EVERYBODY LOVED HIM.
>> USING A STOLEN SEMI-AUTOMATIC
RIFLE AND WEARING A PROTECTIVE
VEST AND HOCKEY MASK, HE OPENED
FIRE, RANDOMLY IN A CLACKAMAS
MALL BEFORE KILLING HIMSELF.
A WOUNDED TEENAGED GIRL IS IN
THE HOSPITAL IN SERIOUS
CONDITION.
>> MILLION AIRSOFTWARE MOGUL
JOHN MacAFEE IS BACK IN THE
U.S.
HE SAID HE WAS ONLY PRETENDING
TO BE UNSTABLE BECAUSE THAT WAS
HIS ONLY WAY OUT OF BELIZE,
WHERE HE IS WANTED FOR
QUESTIONING IN A MURDER.
WE HAVE THE LATEST ON A TRULY
BIZARRE STORY.
>> Reporter: JOHN MacAFEE
SAYS HE'S BROKE, BUT NOT SHORT
ON CASH, THANKS TO THE KINDNESS
OF STRANGERS.
HE SAT DOWN FOR AN INTERVIEW
WITH ABC'S MATT GUTMAN.
SOMEONE DROPPED THESE BILLS OFF
AT THE HOTEL FOR HIM.
HE IS STAYING AT THE BEACON, IN
MIAMI, ARRIVING AT IN THE U.S.
FROM GUATAMALA LAST NIGHT.
>> THEY CALLED HIS NAME AND
SAID, JOHN MacAFEE MAY YOU
PLEASE COME TO THE FRONT.
HE WALKED TO THE FRONT.
>> Reporter: HE HAS BEEN ON
THE MOVE AND IN THE HEADLINES
FOR WEEKS.
HE SNUCK OUT OF BELIZE, WHERE
AUTHORITIES WANT TO QUESTION HIM
IN THE MURDER OF HIS NEIGHBOR,
AN AMERICAN CITIZEN.
HE SLIPPED ILLEGALLY INTO
GUATAMALA, ONLY TO BE DEPORTED
TO THE U.S.
HIGH TELLS ABC, IT WAS PART OF
HIS MASTER PLAN, THAT HE FAKED
HEART PROBLEMS TO MAKE IT
HAPPEN.
WHAT ABOUT YOUR ILLNESS?
>> WHAT ABOUT MY ILLNESS.
>> WAS THAT PART OF THE
DECEPTION?
>> OF COURSE.
IT KEPT ME FROM GOING BACK TO
BELIZE.
>> Reporter: HE FAKED MORE
THAN THAT.
>> WHAT IS THE BETTER STORY --
MILLIONAIRE MAD MAN ON THE RUN?
YOU SAVED MY [BLEEP]
WHY?
BECAUSE YOU PAID ATTENTION TO
THE STORY.
>> BECAUSE YOU ACTED LIKE A MAD
MAN?
>> I DID.
AND IT WORKED.
>> Reporter: THIS IS A WIN FOR
MacAFEE, HE IS NOT WANTED IN
THE U.S. AND FOR THAT MATTER, HE
IS NOT OFFICIALLY WANTED IN
BELIZE.
>> NOT ONLY HAS HE NOT BEEN
CHARGED.
HE HAS NOT BEEN NAMED A SUSPECT.
SO AT THIS POINT, THERE IS A GUY
IN THE U.S. WHO BELIZE WOULD
LIKE TO TALK TO.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S NOT AN ENORMOUS LEGAL
HURDLE.
>> Reporter: MacAFEE SAYS
HIS LEGAL WOES ARE NOT HIS FIRST
PRIORITY.
HE IS FOCUSING ON GETTING HIS
GIRLFRIENDS TO THE U.S -- BOTH
OF THEM -- AGES 20 AND 17.
>> HE SAYS HE DID NOT KILL HAS
NEIGHBOR.
ON HIS BLOG, HE IS OFFERING A
$25,000 REWARD TO HELP FIND THE
REAL KILLER.
>> TWO STATE POLICE OFFICERS ARE
IN CUSTODY IN MEXICO, ACCUSED OF
STEALING ITEMS FROM THE WRECKAGE
OF THE PLANE CRASH THAT KILLED
JENNY RIVERA. AUTHORITIES FOUND
CRASH SCENE IMAGE OSES THE SMART
PHONE OF ONE OF THE OFFICERS,
TRYING TO DETERMINE HOW THE
REPORTERS GOT PHOTOGRAPHS OF THE
SECURED SITE.
THE ITEMS WERE FOUND IN A SEARCH
OF THE OFFICERS' HOMES.
THEY ARE NOT SURE WHAT THEY
WERE.
AUTHORITIES TURNED OVER RIVERA'S
BODY TO HER FAMILY TODAY.
THE INVESTIGATORS ARE TRYING TO
DETERMINE THE CAUSE OF SUNDAY'S
CRASH.
>> BRITISH AUTHORITIES SAY THE
NURSE WHO DIED AFTER A HOAX CALL
TO THE HOSPITAL, TREATING THE
DUTCHESS OF CAMBRIDGE, HANGED
HERSELF.
OFFICIALS TODAY CONFIRMED THAT
THE NURSE WAS FOUND HANGING FROM
A SCARF AT LONDON'S KING EDWAR
VII HOSPITAL ON FRIDAY.
THREE NOTES WERE FOUND IN THE
ROOM.
THERE WERE NO SUSPICIOUS
CIRCUMSTANCES.
MEANTIME, THE TWO AUSTRALIAN
D.J.s WHO MADE THE CALL FOR A
PROTECTED SAFE HOUSES.
>> U.S. BANKS AND BROKERAGE
FIRMS ARE PREPARING FOR A
THREATENED CYBER-ATTACK, CALLED
BLITZKRIEG.
THERE IS EVIDENCE THAT A
WELL-PLANNED ATTACK BY EASTERN
EUROPEAN HACKERS COULD OCCUR IN
THE SPRING OR SOONER.
THEY BEGAN PLANTING MALICIOUS
SOFTWARE IN APRIL.
$5 MILLION HAS BEEN STOLEN AND
WHAT AMOUNTED TO A TEST RUN BY
THE HACKERS.
THE BANK OF AMERICA RISK
MANAGEMENT DEPARTMENT SAYS IT'S
OPERATING UNDER THE ASSUMPTION
THAT AN ATTACK WILL TAKE PLACE
AND IS DEFENDING ITSELF
ACCORDINGLY.
>> IF YOU THINK OUR CONGRESS
DOESN'T GET ALONG, TAKE A LOOK
AT WHAT IT IS LIKE IN UKRAINE.
THE ISSUES THAT HAVE THE
LAWMAKERS PACKING REAL PUNCHES.
>> LOOK OUTSIDE, THESE TWO TEENS
DO AN ACOUSTIC VERSION OF
GANGHAM STYLE.
>> MOSTLY SUNNING SKIES FROM THE
EAST BAY HILLS.
GET READY FOR ANOTHER COLD
NIGHT.
WE HAVE FROST ADVISORIES IN THE
EAST BAY AND PATCHY FROST LIKELY
FOR THE MORNING.
CHILLY, WET WEATHER COMING.
DETAILS ARE COMING UP.
>> LATER, A BAY AREA FAMILY'S
SUCCESSFUL EFFORT TO GET THE
FIREPLACE INDUSTRY TO MAKE
CHANGES AFTER THEIR YOUNG
DAUGHTER WAS SERIOUSLY BURNED.
>> TAKE A LOOK AT THE TRAFFIC.
WE ARE LOOKING AT A HIGH 80 FROM
BERKELEY, PERCHED ATOP
EMERYVILLE.
SLOW GOING IN BOTH DIRECTIONS.
RIGHT SIDE AND UP TOWARDS
BERKELEY, EAST BOUND AND SLOW
TOWARD THE CITY AS WELL.
STAY WITH U
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>> YOU THINK FISCAL CLIFF TALKS
ARE TOUGH IN WASHINGTON, CHECK
OUT THE MELEE IN A PARLIAMENTARY
DEBATE IN UKRAINE.
LAWMAKERS COULD NOT AGREE TO
DISAGREE ABOUT WHO SHOULD BE
PRIME MINISTER SO THEY WENT AT
EACH OTHER.
WHEN THE DUST SETTLED, THE
OPPOSITION PARTY LOST.
>> OH, BOY.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S GET ANOTHER CHECK ON THE
FORECAST RIGHT NOW.
>> YES.
>> YEAH, AS WE LOOK AT THE LIVE
DOPPLER 7 HD, THERE IS NOTHING
HAPPENING HERE IN THE BAY AREA.
BUT WE DO HAVE A FEW SHOWERS TO
THE SOUTH.
DOWN BETWEEN GILROY AND
HOLISTER, OVER THE HIGHER
TERRAIN.
LIGHT SHOWERS RIGHT NOW.
WATCH OUT.
COULD BE SMALL HAIL.
AS WE LOOK AT THE NATIONAL
FORECAST, RAIN IN DALLAS, 60
DEGREES, 46 IN DENVER.
CHILLY, 42 IN SALT LAKE CITY,
LOOKING AT SNOW.
IF YOU HAVE TRAVEL PLANS, COULD
BE ON THE DICEY SIDE FOR YOUR
FRIDAY.
AS YOU LOOK AT THE STATEWIDE
CONDITIONS, RAIN IS MOVING IN
TOWARDS BIG SUR, 53 DEGREES.
SNOW UP TO THE NORTH AND THE
NORTHERN CALIFORNIA MOUNTAINS.
33 DEGREES IN TAHOE, SNOW BY
TOMORROW NIGHT AND PALM SPRINGS
COULD BE LOOKING AT RAIN, 64
DEGREES.
HERE IN THE BAY AREA, IT IS
GOING TO BE A RAW DAY, AS YOU
WILL NOTICE HERE, YOU WILL NEED
THE RAINGEAR AND A COAT OR A
JACKET.
TEMPERATURES ONLY IN THE
MID 40s TO THE LOW 50s AT
BEST.
51 IN SAN FRANCISCO.
52 IN SAN JOSE.
BUT LOOK AT THE NORTH.
NORTH BAY, NAP A47 DEGREES.
49 IN CONCORD.
LIVERMORE, WE DO HAVE A FROST
ADVISORY ON FRIDAY FOR THE
INLAND EAST BAY VALLEYS.
KEEP THAT IN MIND.
WATCH OUT FOR ICY SIDEWALKS AND,
OF COURSE, FROST ON THE
WINDSHIELD.
YOU WILL NEED TO BUNDLE UP AND
MAKE SURE HAVE YOU YOUR
RAINGEAR.
>> THANK YOU.
COOL WEATHER MEANS IT FEELS LIKE
THE HOLIDAY SEASON, FINALLY.
THAT SPIRIT IS GOING VIRAL.
HERE'S THE UTALK SHOW, WHAT IS
TRENDING WITH THE TOP VIDEOS.
>> THANK YOU.
ANOTHER LOOK AT THE HOTTEST
VIDEOS, BLOWING UP ON youtube.
FIRST UP, JIMMY KIMMEL ASKS KIDS
ON THE STREETS OF HOLLYWOOD TO
RELEASE THE STORY OF CHRISTMAS.
>> SHOOTING STAR IN THE SKY AND
IT WAS REALLY BEAUTIFUL.
>> HE WAS BORN IN A MANSION.
>> REMEMBER, YOU CAN CATCH MORE
HILARITY EVERY WEEK NIGHT AT
MIDNIGHT.
RIGHT HERE ON, ABC7.
UP NEXT, ACAPPELLA CENTER STARS
ARE -- SUPER STARS ARE BACK WITH
LEGENDARY BOY BAND, NSYNC.
SEE MORE TONIGHT ON OUR BIG
HOLIDAY SPECTACULAR AT 6:00 P.M.
PACIFIC TIME.
WE ARE PRESENTING THIS AMAZING
BENEFIT FOR COVENANT HOUSE,
ALONG WITH VIRGIN MOBILE, WITH
YOUR FAVORITE youtube STARS.
AND THAT WILL DO IT FOR THE
BIGGEST VIDEOS ONLINE.
SEE YOU NEXT TIME, BAY AREA.
>> ALL RIGHT, THANKS.
>> UP NEXT, A NEW ERA IN
TELEVISION WATCHING TAKES EFFECT
TODAY.
>> I'M MICHAEL FINNEY, TYPING ON
A VIRTUAL KEYBOARD DRIVES SOME
PEOPLE CRAZY.
UP NEXT, ANOTHER OPTION.
THE LOOK AT
[SINGING].
>> THIS IS ANOTHER VIDEO GAINING
A LOT OF TRACTION TODAY ONLINE.
TEENAGED GIRL, HOPE AND MAGGIE
ARE BECOMING WEB CELEBS WITH
THEIR UKULELE GUITAR COVER OF
GANGHAM STYLE.
THEY ADMIT THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT
THE WORDS MEAN.
BUT THEY GOT THE TUNE DOWN.
>> GOOD JOB.
ONE OF THE GREATEST IRRITANTS OF
WATCHING TELEVISION HAS COME TO
AN END -- ARE THEY TAKING ME
OFF?
NO!
NOT YET.
STARTING TODAY, IT'S ILLEGAL FOR
BROADCASTERS AND PAID TV
PROVIDERS TO AIR EXPRESSIVELY
LOUD COMMERCIALS.
>> THE SFCC SAYS ALL ADS MUST
HAVE THE SAME VOLUME AS THE
PROGRAMS THEY ACCOMPANY.
>> WE ALL KNOW WHAT THIS IS.
WE HAVE ALL ENDURED IT.
WE HAVE ALL HEARD THE ADS.
TODAY IS THE BEGINNING OF A NEW
ERA OF QUIETER TV.
>> I AM GOING TO STOP SHOUTING,
ALSO.
THE LEGISLATION CALLED THE
COMMERCIAL ADVERTISEMENT
LOUDNESS MITIGATION OR CALM, FOR
SHORT, MANDATED THE CHANGE, BACK
IN 2010.
>> BUT NOW, IT'S OFFICIAL.
>> YES.
>> CONSUMER RESPECTS HAS A
REPORT ON THE TABLET KEYBOARDS.
>> Reporter: TABLETS ARE EASY
TO TAKE WITH YOU EVERYWHERE.
>> YEAH.
>> Reporter: THUS YOUR PROOF.
BUT TYPING ON A TOUCH SCREEN,
ESPECIALLY FOR LONG PERIODS OF
TIME, CAN BE FRUSTRATING.
SO IF YOU HAVE A TABLET LOVER,
OR IF YOU ARE LOOKING TO MAKE
YOUR OWN LIFE EASIER, A KEYBOARD
MAY BE THE PERFECT HOLIDAY GIFT.
>> TYPING ON A VIRTUAL KEYBOARD
CAN DRIVE SOME PEOPLE VIRTUALLY
CRAZY.
>> I WANT TO BANG MY HEAD
AGAINST THE WALL.
IT'S CRAZY.
>> Reporter: IT'S A COMMON
COMPLAINT.
WHEN MICROSOFT UNVEILED THE NEW
SURFACE TABLET TOFFERRED TWO
KEYBOARDS FOR SALE, RIGHT FROM
THE GET-GO.
CONSUMER REPORTS SAYS BOTH HAVE
FULL-SIZED KEYS, ARE THIN AND
LIGHT AND DOUBLE AS A COVER.
IF YOU ALREADY HAVE A TABLET AND
WANT A SEPARATE KEYBOARD, THERE
ARE OPTION THERE IS.
CHARLIE DAVIDMAN, AN ELECTRONICS
EXPERT AT CONSUMER RESPECTS,
LOOKED AT FOUR MORE KEYBOARDS
FROM TARGEUS, LOGITECH.
>> THEY OFFER A PHYSICAL
KEYBOARD AND KEYS YOU DON'T
OFTEN FIND ON A TABLET.
>> Reporter: LIKE A TAB KEY
AND DEDICATED NUMBER AND SYMBOL
FUNCTIONS.
THE $65 TARGEUS KEYBOARD WORKS
WITH iPad OR ANDROID.
IT'S MAUL AND LIGHT WITH
VIRTUALLY THE SAME SIZE KEYS AS
A TYPICAL LAPTOP.
IT RUNS ON TRIPLE-A BATTERIES.
>> THE DOWN SIDE IS THAT IT
DOESN'T ACT AS A CASE OR A
STAMP.
SO YOU ARE LUGGING AROUND AN
EXTRA ACCESSORY.
>> Reporter: FOR A BIT MORE,
CONSIDER A $100 MARIEL
ZAGUNISFOLIO CASE, ONE FOR
LATER iPadS OR ANDROID.
IT HAS LARGE KEYS AND DOUBLES AS
A STAND.
PLUS IT LATCHES SECURELY.
THE CARBON FIBER CASE...
FEELS VERY PROTECTIVE.
>> NOW WHEN YOU GO TO BUY A
KEYBOARD, CHECK ITS
COMPATIBILITY WITH THE TABLET
THAT YOU PLAN TO PAIR IT WITH,
PARTICULARLY IF YOU HAVE AN
EARLIER MODEL.
ALL THE KEYBOARDS CONSUMER
REPORTS TESTED ARE BLUETOOTH
COMPATIBLE AND CAN BE USED
WIRELESSLY.
YOU LIKE THE LOOKS OF THOSE.
>> THE LAST ONE LOOKS GREAT WITH
THE PROTECTIVE CASE AND THE
KEYBOARD.
>> THEY MAKE A BIG DIFFERENCE.
>> A NEW STUDY SHOWS THAT MORE
PEDESTRIANS ARE TALKING OR
TEXTING WHILE CROSSING BUSY
STREETS.
26% OUT OF MORE THAN 1,000
WALKERS USED DEVICES, GOING
THROUGH INTERSECTIONS.
THEIR STUDY SHOWS THAT
DISTRACTED WALKERS FAILED TO
OBSERVE SAFETY RULES.
SIMPLE ONES LIKE LOOKING FOR
CARS.
THIS WEEK, THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT REPORTED THAT THE
DEATHS ARE INCREASING AND THE
STUDY IS IN THE JOURNAL INJURY
PREVENTION.
>> YOU SEE THE PEOPLE WALKING
AROUND.
>> STILL AHEAD, BAY AREA
FAMILY'S EFFORT TO WARN OTHERS
ABOUT THE DANGERS OF GAS
FIREPLACES AFTER THEIR YOUNG
DAUGHTER WAS SEVERELY BURNED.
>> AN EARLY HOLIDAY GIFT FOR SAN
FRANCISCO STUDENTS.
TEACHERS HAVE A LEARNING TOOL TO
USE.
>> DAN ASHLEY IN THE NEWSROOM,
NEW AT 5:00, THE ONE TYPE OF
TOBACCO USE ON THE READS FOR
CALIFORNIA TEENAGERS AND THE
BIGGEST REASON WHY.
>> AND THE BAY AREA STARTUP,
DELIVERING A BUILD-IT-YOURSELF
DOLL HOUSE AND TEACHING THE
BUILDING BLOCKS OF AN
ENGINEERING CAREER.
STAY WITH US.
THE NEWS AT 4:00 CONTINUES IN
JUST A MOM
>> A BIG CHANGE IS COMING TO
GLASS-FRONTED GASES FIREPLACES,
NEW GUIDELINES WILL BE PUBLISHED
IN THE N-FEW WEEKS.
>> THE HOPE IS THAT WILL STOP
THE THENS OF BURN INJURIES
CAUSED BY THESE FIREPLACES EVERY
YEAR.
>> Reporter: LARRY, A
FIREPLACE INDUSTRY GROUP
ESTIMATES THERE ARE 11 MILLION
GAS-FRONTED GAS FIREPLACES IN
THE U.S. AND MORE THAN HALF OF
THE OWNERS DON'T REALIZE
TOUCHING THAT GLASS COULD CAUSE
SEVERE BURNS.
THE INDUSTRY HAS RESPONDED TO
MOUNTING PRESSURE AND LAWSUITS
TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT THAT BY
LAUNCHING A CONSUMER EDUCATION
CAMPAIGN.
THAT STARTED LAST MONTH.
AND IT'S ADOPTING NEW VOLUNTARY
STANDARDS OF PERMANENTLY
ATTACHED SCREENS OR BARRIERS
BEGINNING 2015.
ONE OF THE LAWSUITS THAT HAS LED
TO THE CHANGE WAS BROUGHT BY THE
WHELANFAMILY IN SAN FRANCISCO.
IN 2010, THEIR 21-MONTH-OLD
DAUGHTER GOT THIRD DEGREE BURNS
ON THEIR HANDS.
THE FIREPLACE WAS ACCIDENTALLY
TURNED ON WHEN THE OLDER BROTHER
ACCIDENTALLY PUT THE FIREPLACE
ON WITH THE REMOTE.
THE WHELANS WISHED THE
MANUFACTURER HAD DONE MORE TO
WARN AND PROTECT THEM.
>> I THINK THE INDUSTRY WILL
TAKE IT ON.
I MEAN, THERE HAS BEEN -- AT
LEAST ONE CLASS-ACTION LAWSUIT
THATY WOO KNOW OF.
I THINK THAT THEY WILL CHANGE,
AND THEY WILL EDUCATE THE PUBLIC
>> WE TALKED TO THE FATHER
TODAY.
WE WILL HAVE MORE AT 6:00 WITH
HIS REACTION TO THE INDUSTRY'S
SAFETY CAMPAIGN AND PLANS TO ADD
PERMANENT SCREENS.
IN THE NEWSROOM, ABC7 NEWS.
>> THANKS.
STUDENTS AND TEACHERS AT JAMES
LAKE MIDDLE SCHOOL IN SAN
FRANCISCO, EAGERLY OPENED STACKS
OF AMAZON KINDLS, THANKS TO THE
GENEROSITY OF A BANK, ALLOWING
THE STUDENTS TO CHECK THEM OUT
TO READ BOOKS THEY DON'T HAVE IN
PRINT.
>> THEY DO GOOD THINGS.
FOR ENGLISH LEARNERS, THEY WILL
SPEAK THE WORDS AFTER THEY ARE
READ.
>> THE BANK IS DONATING 65
KINDLES AND THEY GAVE THE SCHOOL
A 700 GIFT CARD, SO THE TEACHERS
CAN BUY MORE ELECTRONIC BOOKS,
SET UP BY THE SAN FRANCISCO
EDUCATION FUND, WHICH RECRUITS
BUSINESSES TO DONATE NEEDED
ITEMS TO SCHOOLS.
>> CHECK OUT THE SCENE OF
ST. MARY'S MEDICAL SCHOOL.
VOLUNTEERS WERE THERE TO HELP
FIREFIGHTERS PACK UP HUNDREDS OF
TOYS, DONATED TO PATIENTS AND
STAFF.
SO MUCH TO CHOOSE FROM HERE.
MORE THAN 700 FROM BARBIES TO
GIANT STUFFED ANIMALS.
AT LEAST WEEK'S GIVEAWAY, THE
FIREFIGHTERS TOY PROGRAM RAN OUT
OF GIFTS, SO THE NEED IS GREAT.
THEY ARE STILL COLLECTING TOYS.
THE FIREFIGHTERS TOY PROGRAM
EXPECTS TO HELP MORE THAN 50,000
FAMILIES THIS YEAR.
NOW, TO FIND A TOY DRIVE NEAR
YOU, VISIT OUR WEB SITE.
AND CLICK UNDER SEE IT ON TV.
>> YESTERDAY, WE WERE OUT AT THE
HOLIDAY FOOD DRIVE AND YOU KNOW,
YOU DON'T THINK ABOUT IT, SOME
OF THESE ARE JUST LIKE SILENT
CRISIS, BUT FOOD AND TOYS FOR
KIDS, SO IMPORTANT THIS TIME OF
YEAR.
>> AND HELP JOIN THE EFFORT.
>> THANKS FOR JOINING US FOR
ABC7 NEWS AT 4:00.
>> ABC7 GIFT TO YOU THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON IS A HOST OF FREE APPs
FOR SMART PHONES AND TABLETS
THAT HOPEFULLY, ONE OF YOUR
LOVED ONES WILL BE GETTING FUR.
CAROLYN?
>> I WILL GET YOU A FREE APP.
YOU CAN DOWNLOAD OUR HIT ALARM
CLOCK APP FOR YOUR iPHONE OR
ANDROID OR THE TABLET.
AND THAT'S AVAILABLE FOR ALL OF
THOSE DEVICESES AS WELL AS THE
iPad.
>> I WAS HOPING FOR THE
IPad.
>> I KNEW IT.
>> YOU CAN DOWNLOAD OUR APPs
FOR FREE.
THE NEWS AT 5:00 STARTS RIGHT
NOW WITH DAN AND SHERYL.
>> THANK YOU.
AN EAST BAY BUSINESS GOES UP IN
SMOKE IN A FIRE THAT COULD BE
SEEN FOR MILES.
WE WILL HAVE LIVE COVERAGE ON
THE HEALTH SCARE IT CAUSED.
>> FROSTY COLD TONIGHT AND
CHILLY RAIN TOMORROW.
I WILL HAVE A LOOK AT THE
WEEKEND FORECAST, COMING UP.
>> SAN FRANCISCO'S POLICE CHIEF
TELLS ABC7 NEWS THE FIRST TING
TING -- THING HE DID AFTER ONE
OF HIS OFFICERS MAY HAVE GONE ON
IA 100-MILE-PER-HOUR JOYRIDE.
>> A FREMONT BUSINESS IS
EVACUATED AS THICK, BLACK SMOKE
AND FEROCIOUS FLAMES RACED OUT
OF THE COMPLEX.
THIS IS HOW THE MAJOR FIRE
LOOKED AT ITS PEAK THIS
AFTERNOON.
GOOD EVENING.
>> THE FREMONT MACHINE SHOP IS
JUST GUTTED TODAY.
WE GO LIVE ON THE SCENE WITH
MORE ON THE STORY.
>> WELL, WHEN FIREFIGHTERS GOT
HERE, THEY WERE, OF COURSE, VERY
CONCERNED ABOUT THAT ROOF.
THE BUILDING HERE WAS COMPLETELY
ENGHUFLED WITH FLAMES AND, OF
COURSE, THEY WERE RIGHT, THE
ROOF DID EVENTUALLY COLLAPSE.
WHEN THE FIRE BEGAN, THERE WERE
ABOUT 60 EMPLOYEES INSIDE THAT
BUILDING, ALL OF THEM WERE
SUCCESSFULLY EVACUATED.
NO ONE WAS INJURED.
NOW, CNH ENTERPRISES, A MACHINE
SHOP WHICH PRODUCES COMPONENT,
MAINLY ALUMINUM, USED IN THE
SEMICONDUCTOR INDUSTRY.
TOXIC FUMES WERE RELEASED INTO
THE AIR.
>> I THINK THE REASON WE WERE
SEEING THAT HEAVY, BLACK SMOKE
WAS ALL THE COMBUSTIBLE OIL,
FLAMMABLE LIQUID AND GASES.
>> Reporter: NOW, THESE ARE
THE FIRST PICTURES WE HAVE OF
THE SIDE OF THE BUILDING.
COMPLETELY OPEN BECAUSE, OF
COURSE, THE ROOF COLLAPSED.
THOSE ARE STORAGE RACKS.
NOW, THE COMPANY SAYS TELL TRY
TO RESUME OPERATIONS, AS SOON AS
POSSIBLE.
>> WE HAVE TO GET SOME TEMPORARY
EQUIPMENT IN THERE AND GET THE
PEOPLE WORKING AGAIN.
BUT, YEAH.
IT'S DEVASTATING.
YOU KNOW, YOU LOOK AT THIS AND
THIS IS AMAZING HOW FAST IT ALL
WENT UP.
>> I'M REALLY DEVASTATED.
YOU KNOW.
IT'S JUST MY JOB -- I DON'T
KNOW, I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO SAY
OR WHAT TO DO RIGHT NOW.
>> IT'S DEVASTATING.
>>
>> Reporter: THE COMPANY TOLD
ME IT HAS GOOD INSURANCE.
EMPLOYEREES WILL BE COVERED.
THEY WILL CONTINUE TO BE PAID
AND THE COMPANY TOLD ME, THEY
WILL MEET TOMORROW MORNING WITH
EMPLOYEES TO TRY TO FIGURE OUT A
PLAN ON HOW TO RESUME AGAIN,
OPERATIONS, AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
SO FAR, THE CAUSE, UNKNOWN.
I'M LIVE IN FREMONT.
>> THANKS VERY MUCH.
HERE ARE THE PICTURES FROM CNH
ENTERPRISES WEB SITE, SHOWING
WHAT THE MACHINE SHOP LOOKED
LIKE BEFORE THE FIRE.
A NICE FACILITY.
THE COMPANY SAYS IT SPECIALIZES
IN FABRICATING PARTS AND HAS AN
ON-SITE WELD