OUR WINTER WIPEOUT ZONE.
THE EPIC COMPETITION
BEGINS NOW.
ONE WILL BECOME A CHAMPION,
BUT ALL WILL...
WIPEOUT.
(woman) THIS TOTALLY LOOKS
DIFFERENT THAN THE VIDEO GAME!
HELLO, AMERICA, AND WELCOME
TO WINTER "WIPEOUT."
I'M JOHN ANDERSON,
HERE AS ALWAYS WITH JOHN HENSON.
AND, UH... IS YOUR CHILD
SUPPOSED TO BE HERE?
NOT UNLESS HE LEARNED
HOW TO DRIVE.
I WAS REFERRING TO
THE BABY BACKPACK.
(scoffs) OKAY, FIRST OF ALL,
IT'S A BABY FRONTPACK.
SECOND OF ALL,
IT'S AWESOME.
AND THIRD OF ALL, IT'S SUPPOSED
TO BE HOLDING SMALLSY.
THIS IS DAY TWO OF OUR
BIG BROTHERS AND SMALL BALLSYs
WEEK OF FUN.
MM-HMM.
BUT WHEN I WOKE UP
THIS MORNING,
THERE WAS NOTHING IN HERE
BUT A BUNCH OF CANDY WRAPPERS
AND AN EMPTY BOTTLE
OF COOKING SHERRY.
THAT IS UNFORTUNATE.
I HOPE YOU LOCATE HIM SOON.
UH, RIGHT NOW, HOWEVER,
WE HAVE 24 PEOPLE OF LEGAL AGE
READY TO TAKE ON
OUR SNOW-COVERED COURSE
FOR THEIR CHANCE AT $50,000.
FIRST UP, THE CHALLENGE OF
OUR WONDERFUL WINTERY QUALIFIER,
AND IT STARTS TODAY
WITH THE SKI LAUNCH.
CAREFUL.
YOU MIGHT LOSE YOUR LAUNCH.
THEN BURIED UNDER THE SNOW
IS A SKI BOOT.
LIKE ALL SKI BOOTS,
IT'LL MAKE YOU WALK FUNNY.
FROM THERE,
IT'S UP TO THE BIG BALLS.
CAPTURE THE PENGUIN
OFF THE FOURTH BALL--
THAT'S A $500 BONUS.
(chirps)
NEXT, CONTESTANTS CONFRONT
A GENTLE SNOWFALL.
IT'S NO SNOW ANGEL.
AND FINALLY, IT'S A FREEZING
TRIPCTIC CIRCLE,
WITH AN AUTHENTIC
ESKIMO VILLAGE.
(snoring softly)
HEY, THAT'S NO ESKIMO!
THAT'S SMALLSY!
OH, DON'T WAKE HIM, JOHN.
HE'LL JUST START CHEWING
ON MY SHOES AGAIN.
I WILL DO MY BEST.
CAN'T MAKE ANY PROMISES
FOR THE 24 MEN AND WOMEN
WHO ARE ABOUT TO TAKE A SHOT
AT OUR COURSE.
ALL RIGHT,
LET'S GO TO VANESSA LACHEY
AND SEE WHO'S FIRST.
RIGHT NOW ON DECK,
WE HAVE KATIE HELMUTH.
KATIE GAGA IS GONNA SHOW
THOSE RED BALLS HER POKER FACE!
KATIE GAGA NOT AFRAID,
JOHN.
I HOPE. (chuckles)
SHE WAS BORN THAT WAY.
(air horn blows)
AH, IT'S PERFECT. KATIE HELMUTH
IS A LADY GAGA IMPERSONATOR.
OH, WELL,
CAN SHE DO LINDSEY VONN?
AAH!
AH!
(laughs) NO! GOODNESS, NO.
OH, HO HO!
AAH!
OHH!
POKER FACE IS ALL-IN.
AAH!
I THINK I SPOTTED HER TELL.
AAH! OH!
KATIE GAGA NOW ON TO
THE SKI BOOT,
WHERE HER 15-INCH PLATFORMS
ARE NO MATCH
FOR OUR 8-FOOT PLATFORM...
AND THE SKI BOOT.
AAH! AAH! NO!
HA HA HA!
OHH, HO HO!
JOHN, I THINK THAT WRINKLED
HER OUTFIT MADE OF CHIPPED HAM
AND LIVE BEES.
(buzzing)
AAH!
NO!
KATIE GAGA GETTING AN EYEFUL
OF OUR MONSTER BALLS,
WHERE SHE CAN PUT HER MEAT SUIT
UP AGAINST A PENGUIN SUIT
FOR A CHANCE TO WIN
500 BUCKS.
(chirps)
BIG BALLS!
IS HER POKER FACE HIDING
FOUR OF A KIND?
AAH!
(squawks)
AW, YEAH!
OH, HO HO!
YEAH!
HEY, 500 BUCKS
FOR KATIE GAGA.
I HAVEN'T SEEN
A PENGUIN MASSACRE THAT BAD
SINCE DANNY DeVITO
IN "BATMAN."
AAH!
(squawks)
WOW. I THOUGHT SHE WAS SUPPOSED
TO LIKE ANIMALS.
OH, MAN!
KATIE GAGA SITTING ATOP
THE SNOWFALL,
READY TO RECORD
ANOTHER SMASH HIT.
AAH!
RAH, RAH, ROMA--OW!
MM!
WOW! THAT'LL LEAVE
A COMPACT DISC.
AAH!
IT'S CERTAINLY
AN ORIGINAL MOVE.
YOU'RE RIGHT. SHE DIDN'T
STEAL THAT FROM MADONNA.
(crunch)
(slo-mo voice) AAH!
THAT ONE HURT!
WELL, KATIE GAGA CAN
PUT A LITTLE ICE ON IT
HERE AT THE ARCTIC CIRCLE,
HOME OF THE ESKIMO VILLAGE.
(groans)
AND GARY.
HELLO!
HE'S YOUR NUMBER ONE FAN.
THIS IS SO EXCITING!
(chuckles nervously)
OH, BOY. OH. HEH.
OH, UH, THAT FEELS FUNNY.
UH-OH. (chuckling nervously)
COME ON, CALM DOWN. WOW. HE DOES
NOT GET OUT OF THE IGLOO MUCH.
OH, BOY.
OOH, BOY!
OOH, HO HO!
CHILI!
YEAH, KATIE GAGA, GARY'S KNOWN
FOR HIS ESKIMO CHILI...
(chuckles)
MADE WITH REAL ESKIMO.
KATIE GAGA INCHING TOWARDS
THE HOWIE MANDEL OF POLAR BEARS.
THAT POLAR BEAR
WAS ON "ST. ELSEWHERE"?
(grumbles)
NO. SEE, HE'S A GERMOPHOBE.
HEY, POLAR BEAR.
SHE'LL BE FINE AS LONG
AS SHE DOESN'T TOUCH IT.
OH, NOT--NOT GOOD.
UH-OH.
(polar bear growling,
Smallsy snoring)
OH, HO!
OHH!
AH, THAT LITTLE SCAMP
CAN SLEEP THROUGH ANYHOW.
AAH! AAH!
KATIE GAGA SLIDES OVER,
BUT I WOULD ADVISE AVOIDING
THE BEAR'S FOOD SUPPLIES.
UHH! AH!
OHH!
AH! GO FISH.
(growls) HEY.
KATIE GAGA--SHE'S THE REAL DEAL,
HOWEVER,
SETTING A GREAT OPENING TIME--
3 MINUTES AND 10 SECONDS.
I'M GONNA DIE. OHH!
HEADED UP TO THE SKI LAUNCH NOW
IS CHRIS WHITHORN.
WHOO!
MAYBE HE'LL HAVE
BETTER LUCK--
YOU KNOW,
SINCE YOU HOT WAXED THE SKIS.
I DIDN'T WAX THEM, JOHN.
THEY WERE ALREADY HAIRLESS.
YEAH, NOT WHAT I MEANT.
AAH!
OH, BOY.
OHH, HO! WOW.
MM!
I REALLY THOUGHT HE HAD IT
WHEN HE FLAPPED HIS ARMS, JOHN.
WORKS SO WELL IN CARTOONS.
YEAH,
THAT WENT DOWNHILL FAST.
VANESSA, WHAT'S THIS GUY'S
SKILL SET?
ANYTHING FUNKY?
LIKE, ARE YOU DOUBLE-JOINTED?
CAN YOU SING? CAN YOU DANCE?
DO YOU HAVE CRAZY VOICES?
UM, I DO HAVE CRAZY VOICES.
I HAVE A PERSON LIVING
IN MY HEAD NAMED LEONARD.
(cuckoo clock chimes)
ALL RIGHT.
SO... WHAT DOES LEONARD THINK
ABOUT THE SHOW?
(goofy voice)
LEONARD LOVES THIS SHOW.
UM, HE THINKS IT'S GONNA BE
A FUN TIME TODAY.
WHAT KIND OF SKILLS
DO YOU HAVE?
(normal voice)
SKILLS IN WHAT WAY?
LEONARD, NOT CHRIS.
(goofy voice) I'M THE BRAINS
OF THIS SITUATION.
I MEAN, SO...
OF COURSE.
(John H.) ALL RIGHT, LEONARD,
BACK IN THE HEAD.
(John A.) WOW, 2-FOR-1!
I LOVE IT.
A COUPLED ENTRY
HEADED TO THE BIG BALLS.
I WONDER WHO WE'RE GONNA SEE.
(normal voice) WHOO!
THAT PENGUIN'S GOING DOWN!
PHEW! IT'S CHRIS.
(goofy voice)
THAT PENGUIN'S GOING DOWN!
OH, NO. IT'S LEONARD.
AAH!
OHH!
OHH, HO!
OH, YOU'D THINK
ONE OF HIS VOICES
WOULD TELL HIM
TO KEEP HIS LEGS CLOSED.
OH, MY GOD!
UP AHEAD,
EXPLORING THE ARCTIC CIRCLE
IS ALISHA KHATWANI.
AAH!
OH, HO!
AH! GARY JUST TOSSED HER
INTO THE CHILI.
I HATE CHILI, AND I'M INDIAN.
OH. (laughs)
I CAN'T TAKE SPICES.
OOH! WELL,
THAT OUGHTA COOL YOU OFF.
WOW, THESE ESKIMOS ARE DEADLY
WITH A SNOWBALL.
HEY, WAIT, THAT'S VANESSA.
NO!
PRETTY GOOD HOSE
ON THAT GAL.
YEAH, TOO BAD
FOR THE CONTESTANTS,
BUT GREAT FOR
THE COMPANY SOFTBALL TEAM.
EAT IT,
LADIES OF "THE VIEW"!
YA!
OH, HO!
(laughs)
THAT CHILI'S NASTY.
HEY, YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO DOUBLE-DIPPED.
YO, BRO.
THINK ABOUT HOW THAT
GERMOPHOBIC POLAR BEAR FEELS.
(growling)
AAH! AAH!
ALISHA FLIPS OVER.
OW!
OH, HO!
VANESSA WITH ANOTHER STRIKE.
AAH!
D'OH!
AND GOOSED BY THE FISH!
GOOSE. FISH. I GET IT.
(laughs)
WHOO-HOO! PARTY TIME, BABY!
WHOO!
WHY AM I PARTYING, JOHN?
WHAT'S UP, BABY?
BECAUSE THIS IS WEDDING SINGER
RICKY LaCORTE.
HEY, I LOVE WEDDING SINGERS!
THE COVER SONGS,
THE SKINNY TIES...
EVERYBODY, MAKE SOME NOISE!
THE WAY THEY GET YOU SO EXCITED
THAT YOU DON'T EVEN CARE
THAT THE BRIDE WAS
YOUR GIRLFRIEND FOR FIVE YEARS
BEFORE SHE STARTED CHEATING
ON YOU WITH THE GROOM.
(John A.) TOO PERSONAL?
YOU OKAY?
BETTER THAN THIS GUY.
OH, HO!
AH!
HE THREW HIS LEGS IN THE AIR
LIKE HE JUST DIDN'T CARE, JOHN.
(stretch, smack)
OOH!
NOW HE'LL BE ABLE TO SING
ALL THE LADY PARTS.
OH! NOW GETTING A PAT
ON THE BACK AT THE SKI BOOT
IS 27 YEAR OLD ERIN BENNETT.
AAH!
OHH!
OHH! AND ANOTHER SHOT
TO THE BACK.
SHE'S GONNA HAVE
SOME SERIOUS SWELLING.
(stretch)
AAH! UGH!
AAH! HOLY COW!
GET HER AN ICE PACK, STAT!
OOH!
ACTUALLY,
SHE MEANT TO DO THAT.
SHE LIKES TO POP OUT
HER SHOULDER BLADES,
MAKE HERSELF LOOK LIKE
A PTERODACTYL.
(Vanessa) CAN YOU MAKE
THE PTERODACTYL SOUNDS?
(screeches)
(laughs)
(John H.) YEAH, I KINDA WISH
I COULD UNSEE THAT.
BUT THOSE PTERODACTYL WINGS
COULD HELP HER ON THE BIG BALLS.
I'M NOT SURE
THIS IS ENTIRELY FAIR, JOHN,
BUT SHE'S GOT A GIFT.
OH! (screeches)
(clank)
OHH!
OH, HO!
OH, LIKE ICARUS, SHE DARED SAIL
TOO HIGH, JOHN...
OH! (screeches)
AND TRIPPED ON HER
TINY LITTLE PTERODACTYL FEET.
(groaning)
IS SHE MAKING
PTERODACTYL SNOW ANGELS NOW?
NO, JOHN,
THE ICE IS MELTING.
(screeches)
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS?
SPRING?
YOU WISH!
IT'S MAN VERSUS ANIMAL.
GLOBAL WARMING UPSETS
THE DELICATE BALANCE OF NATURE.
OHH!
OH, HO!
WELL, HE DOES SEEM HOSTILE.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS
JUST FROM BEING TOUCHED.
AH!
OH, HO HO!
OOH!
OHH!
CLEARLY HE'S NERVOUS.
YOU MELT THE POLAR ICE CAPS,
AND YOU RELEASE
PREHISTORIC BEASTS.
(roars)
AAH!
YABBA DABBA...
D'OH!
SERIOUSLY?
THAWED-OUT DINOSAURS?
OH, HO HO!
AH!
IT'S SCIENCE, JOHN.
THEY CAN'T PUT IT ON
THE INTERNET IF IT ISN'T TRUE.
HOW ELSE DO YOU EXPLAIN
MOTIVATOR-SAURUS REX?
(metallic chomping)
BET SHE'LL RECYCLE NOW.
(roars)
AAH!
UH-OH, SHE'S EXTINCT.
MM, HMM HMM HMM!
OH, HO HO HO! MAN!
AND WHAT ABOUT
E
FROZEN IN
THE ALASKAN SEWER SYSTEM?
(screeches)
OH, MY GOD.
AAH! OH, THAT'S SCARY!
(snarls)
JOHN, WHERE DID YOU STUDY
SCIENCE?
AAH!
ED'S BAIT AND TACKLE
AND COMMUNITY COLLEGE. WHY?
SEE YOU LATER, ALLIGATOR!
AAH!
(crunch)
THERE'S BRANDI BERG.
WATCH OUT!
OH, WHAT THE HECK IS THAT?
AAH!
OH, HO! WOW!
BIGGEST PARMESAN GRATER EVER!
(groaning)
ARE YOU DONE NOW, JOHN?
JUST A SEC.
AAH! UHH!
YEP, THAT'LL DO IT.
(burps)
NOW COMING UP TO THE SKI BOOT
IS AIMEE REILLY.
WHOO! I'M CRAZY!
WELL,
MOST OF OUR CONTESTANTS ARE.
AH!
OHH!
MM!
OHH, HO!
WELL, JOHN, AIMEE SAID SHE'S
KNOWN FOR BEING WILD AND CRAZY,
AND VANESSA TOOK A TRIP WITH HER
TO HER CRAZYTOWN.
(train whistle blows)
WHAT'S, LIKE, THE CRAZIEST THING
THAT YOU'VE DONE?
OH. UH, I HAVE A...
GOOD ONE.
(John H.) GO ON.
HAVE YOU EVER TRIED
EATING A PEANUT BUTTER SANDWICH
WITH NO MILK?
HAVE YOU EVER DONE THAT?
I DON'T--I'M CONFUSED. ARE THERE
LIVE ROACHES ON THE SANDWICH?
YOU REALLY NEED THE MILK
TO WASH IT DOWN.
OR THE JELLY.
THAT, TOO.
(John H.) WHAT ARE THE CHANCES
THIS STORY ENDS
IN A FISTFIGHT WITH TWO NUNS,
A HIGH-SPEED CHASE,
AND A FELONY ARREST?
(John A.) I DON'T KNOW. 2%?
BUT COMING ON "WIPEOUT" IS
ACTUALLY PRETTY WILD AND CRAZY.
WELL, THAT WILD AND CRAZY GAL
IS NOW ON A 40-FEET SLIDE
WITH A PEANUT BUTTER
SANDWICH...
AAH!
AND NO MILK!
AY!
OH, HO HO HO!
OHH! SORRY, AIMEE.
OH, THE CRAZY'S GETTING
PRETTY THICK OUT HERE.
I THINK NOW'S A GOOD TIME
FOR A BREAK.
THAT KINDA HURT.
WHATCHA GOT?
OH, PEANUT BUTTER SANDWICH, HUH?
YEAH, WITH NO MILK.
WHAT'S SO CRAZY ABOUT THAT?
WAIT FOR IT.
HERE IT COMES.
WHAT'S THE FOURTH LARGEST CITY
IN MINNESOTA?
(mouth full) DULUTH.
DULUTH. DULUTH!
NO! ANDERSON,
I CAN'T OPEN MY MOUTH!
I'M SORRY.
CAN'T OPEN YOUR MOUTH?
NO!
YES. SO I WILL ENJOY
THE SWEET SOUNDS OF SILENCE
WHILE YOU ENJOY
THESE COMMERCIALS.
UHH!
AAH! OH!
WHOO! AAH!
MAYBE SOMEBODY COULD
GET HIM SOME MILK, HUH?
PLEASE?
(chuckles)
Before the tissue, help
defend with a wipe.
Before the cold & flu
season,
help prevent with Lysol.
Because when you have 10
times more protection
with each hand wash...
and kill 99.9% of germs around
the house with each spray...
Those healthy habits
start to add up.
This season, a good
offense is the best defense
and Lysol has your
family covered
because that's
our Mission For Health.
Every human being
is unique.
And there is one store
that recognizes it.
The Sleep Number Store.
The only place in the
world you'll find the
extraordinarily comfortable
Sleep Number Experience.
An exclusive collection of
innovations that totally
individualize your sleep.
Perfectly comfortable
pillows that adjust to
your size and shape.
Temperature-balancing
bedding.
Dual warmth comforters.
All designed around the
Sleep Number Bed: A bed
with dual-air technology
that allows you to adjust
to the support your
body needs.
Each of your bodies.
In the name of human
individuality: The Sleep
Number Collection.
Discover how our sleep
professionals can
individualize your sleep
experience.
Exclusively at one of our 400
Sleep Number Stores nationwide.
Sleep Number.
Comfort Individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
♪
WE ARE BACK
ON WINTER "WIPEOUT."
THANKS SO MUCH
FOR STICKING AROUND WITH US.
YEAH, AND IF YOU'RE JUST TUNING
IN, WELCOME FOR THE FIRST TIME.
YOU'VE MISSED A LOT...
MM-HMM. YEP.
BUT HERE'S A QUICK RECAP.
UH... UH, PEOPLE FELL DOWN.
THAT IS
AN EXCELLENT SUMMATION.
YEAH, THANKS.
FELT PRETTY GOOD ABOUT IT.
GLAD YOU ARE HAPPY, AND I HOPE
WE CAN SAY THE SAME NOW
FOR OUR NEXT CONTESTANT.
JOE VAUX IS AT
THE TOP OF THE COURSE.
(ominous music playing)
ARMS LIKE THE EAGLE!
CLAWS LIKE THE MONKEY!
THE IMAGERY OF DARKNESS
IS AT MY FINGERTIPS!
(thunderclap,
electricity hums)
WOW, HE IS INTENSE!
I WILL PAINT THEE!
(music warps)
WHOO!
DID HE SAY "PAINT"?
YEAH, JOHN. JOE'S AN ARTIST.
THAT'S UN-TENSE.
WELL, HE CHANNELS THE INTENSITY
INTO HIS WORK.
(thriller music playing)
WHOA! I CAN'T PUT MY FINGER
ON IT,
BUT THERE'S SOMETHING ABOUT THIS
I REALLY LIKE.
(Vanessa) THIS IS
HENSON EATING ANDERSON?
I ACCENTED HIS TAIL,
WHICH YOU DON'T SEE ON TV MUCH,
BUT I KNOW HE'S GOT ONE.
YEAH.
AND THEN POOR ANDERSON--
ARE YOU NOT A SPORTS FAN?
OR WHAT'S GOING ON THERE?
YOU KNOW, PART OF THAT WAS
I JUST RAN OUT OF ROOM
ON THE PAPER.
BUT RIGHT NOW, UH, YOU KNOW,
HENSON'S, UH, THE BIG FISH.
(air horn blows)
(John H.) AND I GOT THE GILLS
TO PROVE IT, JOHNNY.
JOHN, DO YOU THINK JOE'S ART
WILL BE WORTH MORE POSTHUMOUSLY?
(John A.) WHAT EXACTLY
ARE YOU IMPLYING?
AAH!
OHH!
OH, HO HO!
VAN GOGHING, GOING, GONE!
AAH!
HE BURIED HIS HEAD
IN HIS SKI, JOHN.
THAT'S A COMMITMENT
TO DARKNESS.
DARK ARTIST JOE--
A BRUSH WITH THE SKI BOOT.
OH, HO! YEAH!
AND HE MADE AN IMPRESSION.
OHH!
WELL DONE!
(whooshing)
WOW! SHOWING A LITTLE
PERFORMANCE ART.
HE IS ON A ROLL, MAN.
IF HE GRABS THAT PENGUIN,
HE MIGHT WIN 500 BUCKS WORTH
OF DARK ART SUPPLIES.
HERE WE GO!
OH! EE, YAH!
OHH! OH, HO HO HO!
OH, I LOVE IT WHEN LIFE IMITATES
DARK ART.
(crunch)
HEY, IF YOU DON'T WANNA
GET EATEN,
DON'T SWIM IN A POND
WITH A BIG FISH AND BIG BALLS
AND BIG SNOWFLAKES.
UHH!
AH!
OH, HO HO!
HEY! LOOK AT THE CUTE,
LITTLE FLUFFY BUNNY TAIL.
I'M BEGINNING TO QUESTION
HIS COMMITMENT TO DARK ARTS.
WELL, I THINK THE DARK ARTIST
IS GONNA LOVE ARCTIC CIRCLE.
'CAUSE, YOU KNOW,
IT'S DARK UP THERE, LIKE,
24 HOURS A DAY
DURING WINTER.
YAH!
OH, HO! AND EVEN DARKER WHEN
YOU'RE HEAD IS DUNKED IN CHILI.
THIS CHILI SMELLS AWFUL.
ARE YOU SURE?
IT COULD BE GARY.
HE'S GOT A LITTLE
PERSPIRATION PROBLEM.
(chuckles nervously)
(roars)
OHH! OH!
OH! ON THE CANVAS!
SLIDING...
HOLD IT!
WOW!
NICE RECOVERY! BUT I'D WATCH OUT
FOR AQUATIC POP ART.
OH!
OHH!
OOH! RIGHT IN HIS WARHOL!
(Vanessa) OH!
THAT IS NOT A PRETTY PICTURE.
OH, MY GOD!
THE DARK ARTIST
WITH A TERRIFIC TIME OF...
UHH! STUPID!
WELL, IT'S GONNA BE
UNDER 3 MINUTES.
MAMA MIA!
NOW SCALING THE SKI BOOT
IS SONIA ALCAZAR...
OKAY, HERE WE GO, RED BALLS!
WHO APPARENTLY THINKS
SHE'S AT THE BIG REALLY BALLS.
OVER THE RED BALLS!
JOHN, YOU THINK MAYBE
WE SHOULD TELL HER
SHE'S NOT AT THE BIG BALLS?
OVER THE RED BALLS!
NOW WHERE IS THE FUN
IN THAT?
OVER THE RED BALLS! AH!
WHOOPS!
AFTER ALL, THE VERY BEST GIFTS
ARE A SURPRISE.
AAH!
YA, HA HA!
OH, HO HO!
(singsongy) SURPRISE!
(air horn blows)
JOHN, PERHAPS 20 YEAR OLD
LINDSAY WEGLARZ
WILL HAVE BETTER LUCK
ON THE COURSE.
OH, MY GOD. I HATE SKIING.
COME ON, LINDSAY.
THERE'S NOTHING TO IT.
IT'S ALL ABOUT FORM.
YOU JUST LEAN FORWARD.
NO, BACK! NO, FORWARD!
MM. AH!
WAIT! BACK!
OH, NOPE, IT'S FORWARD.
OH, NO! OH, NO!
OH, HO HO!
YA!
NO, NO, NO, NO!
OH, HER BODY SAYS "AGONY,"
BUT HER FACE SAYS...
YEAH, "AGONY."
WASN'T ALWAYS.
VANESSA SPOKE WITH LINDSAY
PRECRASH-LANDING.
OHH! WHAT IN THE WORLD?!
LOOK HOW CUTE, WITH YOUR
SOFT HAIR AND YOUR LITTLE BOW!
(laughs)
YOU'RE SO CUTE.
I STOLE THIS FROM
THE GIRL I NANNY FOR.
YOU STOLE THAT FROM THE KID
YOU NANNY FOR?
YEAH.
(gasps)
YOU WON'T NOTICE.
SHE HAS PLENTY OF STUFF.
(John H.) WOW!
WHEN SHE HOLDS UP A BABY,
SHE LITERALLY
HOLDS UP A BABY.
AAH! UHH!
AH, HA HA!
OH, HO HO!
THAT'S WHAT YOU GET
FOR STEALING A KID'S CLOTHES.
AND SHE STOLE
MY FAVORITE ROPE!
AAH!
(rips)
I'M SORRY FOR STEALING
THE HEADBAND.
UGH.
WHAT ABOUT ROPE?
(laughs)
WELL, IT'S TOO LATE NOW,
LINDSAY,
BECAUSE WITH THIS SKI BOOT...
OH!
OH, HO HO!
"SORRY" JUST ISN'T ENOUGH.
OKAY.
IS NO ONE SAFE
FROM THE AGONY OF DE FEET?
GET IT? "DE FEET"?
AH. GREAT. LOVE IT.
ESPECIALLY NOT THIS GUY.
HE'S CHEWING GUM
ON THE COURSE, JOHN.
(air horn blows)
YEAH, THAT'S BRIAN AYA,
WHO SAYS HE CHEWS GUM
EVERYWHERE HE GOES.
HE EVEN SHOWED VANESSA HOW
HE GETS 40 PIECES IN HIS MOUTH.
DON'T WORRY.
THAT'LL DIGEST IN 7-10 YEARS.
SO HERE'S A GUY WITH
40 PIECES OF GUM IN HIS MOUTH,
AND HE'S AT THE SKI BOOT.
ANYBODY KNOW THE HEIMLICH?
WHOO! AAH!
OHH!
OHH, HO HO! OH, HO HO!
BALLSY KNOWS THE HEIMLICH,
BUT HE'S HAD ZERO SAVES, JOHN.
(Brian groans)
VERY SHORT ARMS.
UH, NO ARMS. HANDS.
(gags)
ALL RIGHT, WELL,
GOOD LUCK WITH THAT, GUM GUY.
THAT'S MR. GUM TO YOU.
PENGUIN, I'M COMING.
HIKING UP TO THE BIG BALLS NOW
IS 34-YEAR-OLD BARBER
STEFAN ROBERTS.
GOING FOR THE PENGUIN CASH...
AH!
OHH!
THIS DUDE IS NOT GOING
ANYWHERE NEAR MY HAIR.
DID HE REALLY THINK HE COULD
REACH THE PENGUIN FROM THERE?
AAH!
I PREFER A BARBER WITH A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF DEPTH PERCEPTION.
QUACK.
BUT THAT IS
A PRETTY SICK MULLET.
BACK AT THE SKI BOOT IS
FRESHLY RINSED JASON WISHNOV.
WHOO!
HE'S A VOICE ACTOR.
(high-pitched voice)
AAH! OH, MY!
OW!
D'OH!
WELL, HE'S GOT THE ROLE OF
SCREAMING LITTLE GIRL DOWN PAT.
(high-pitched voice)
AAH! OH, MY!
JUST A TIP, JOHN--
VANESSA DISCOVERED THE FULL
RANGE OF HIS VOICE TALENTS.
(normal voice)
THAT AIN'T NOTHING!
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE TO DO
BETTER THAN THAT!
I'M A VOICE ACTOR. I DO IT
FOR ANIME AND VIDEO GAMES.
I TEND TO PLAY THE DEEPER,
VILLAINOUS KINDA ROLES.
UH...
OKAY, SO GIVE ME
YOUR VILLAINOUS VOICE.
(deep voice) IS THIS WHAT
YOU WANT TO HEAR, VANESSA?
(John H.) HUH.
DOESN'T HAVE THE SAME EFFECT
WITHOUT A CARTOON SCAR
AND A GRUMPY HUMPBACK BUTLER.
(Vanessa) UM, WHAT ELSE YOU GOT?
(normal voice) I HAVE
A SMOOTH, DEBONAIR KINDA GUY.
OF COURSE, THIS IS WHAT I WOULD
USE IF I WERE, YOU KNOW,
ASKING YOU OUT ON A DATE.
(John H.) HUH.
I WONDER WHAT KIND
OF A VOICE VANESSA
WOULD USE TO SAY NO.
(John A.) YEAH,
HOPEFULLY THE VOICE ACTOR
WILL BE SLIGHTLY SMOOTHER
ON THE BIG BALLS.
OH! HE LANDED THAT BETTER
THAN ANY VOICE ACTING WORK.
YEAH, PERHAPS HE CAN GET
500 BUCKS WORTH
OF VOICE ACTING LESSONS.
(penguin squawks,
fanfare plays)
HEY, HE GOT IT!
WELL DONE.
YEAH, BUT HE'LL PROBABLY
HAVE TO STRETCH OUT THAT MONEY
FOR A WHILE. NOT A LOT OF VOICE
ACTING WORK OUT THERE.
QUACK.
I KNOW!
TELL ME ABOUT IT.
YEAH!
(high-pitched muffled speaking)
GOOD LUCK!
(air horn blows)
OUR FINAL CONTESTANT
OF THE DAY
IS 51 YEAR OLD SCUBA INSTRUCTOR
TIM OSWALD.
(muffled voice) I GOT THIS.
WOW, HE'S GOT THE LOOKS
AND THE CRAZY OF GARY BUSEY.
DIVER DOWN! WHOO!
YOU CALLED IT.
UHH!
MM!
OHH!
NO, SEE "DIVER DOWN"
IS WHAT SCUBA DIVERS SAY.
TIM HUNTS FOR SUNKEN TREASURE.
IS THAT RIGHT? YOU KNOW, I WENT
TREASURE HUNTING IN A LAKE ONCE.
(firing)
ALL I FOUND WAS ALGAE
AND A HUMAN SHIN.
AH!
OHH!
OH, HO!
(clank)
WOW!
OHH, HO HO!
TWO CONTESTANTS ALREADY BEAT HIM
TO THE FIRST TINY TREASURE.
WHOO! AAH!
(clank)
IF TIM MAKES IT PAST
THE CANNONBALLS...
OHH!
OHH! HE'D BE THE THIRD
PENGUIN-HOPPER TODAY.
DIVER DOWN!
WHOA, HO HO!
OH, WELL, TECHNICALLY,
IT WAS DIVER DOWN, DIVER UP,
THEN DIVER DOWN.
WELL, THE TREASURE HUNTER'S
AT THE SNOWFALL,
AND I KNOW WHICH DIRECTION
HE'S HEADED.
UHH!
YA, HA HA!
AH!
HEADFIRST INTO THE WATER.
JOHN, DO I SEE A TREASURE
DOWN THERE?
NOPE. THAT'S THE DOOR TO
MY PRIVATE UNDERWATER BATHROOM.
I MAKE SURE IT'S IN
EVERY CONTRACT I SIGN.
AAH!
OH, HO!
OHH, ANOTHER FLIP!
AND THE TREASURE HUNTER'S
IN THE CHILI.
UHH!
HE DEFINITELY DOESN'T WANT
TO TAKE HOME
THE BULLION THAT'S IN THERE.
(roaring)
OOH, HOO! HE IS ROMANCING
THAT POLAR BEAR.
OOH!
CAN HE MAKE THE FINAL LEAP?
(Vanessa) COME ON, TIM!
WHOO!
YEAH!
TIM OSWALD MAKES
THE FINISH PLATFORM.
YEAH!
AND HIS TREASURE HUNT'S GONNA
CONTINUE IN ROUND TWO.
AND JOINING HIM, WE HAVE
KATIE "GAGA" HELMUTH,
THE WEDDING SINGER
RICKY LaCORTE,
AND THE DARK ARTIST JOE VAUX.
ALSO IN THE MIX, LINDSAY
"THE CRADLE ROBBER" WEGLARZ,
"MR. GUM" BRIAN AYA,
AND VOICE ACTOR JASON WISHNOV.
AAH!
STICK AROUND
BECAUSE THE FISH ARE BITING...
AAH!
OUR CONTESTANTS.
♪
WELCOME BACK
TO WINTER "WIPEOUT,"
WHERE OUR CONTESTANTS ARE
BOLD IN THE COLD.
WELL, I, FOR.
HEM, JOHN.
MM-HMM.
I SHRINK FROM THE COLD.
BEFORE YOU ELABORATE, LET'S SEE
WHO'S STILL IN THE GAME
AFTER OUR QUALIFIER
SHRUNK THE FIELD FROM 24 TO 12.
WE HAVE KATIE "GAGA" HELMUTH,
LEONARD'S FRIEND
CHRIS WHITHORN,
AND WILD AND CRAZY
AIMEE REILLY.
(Aimee) I'M CRAZY!
ALSO STILL IN IT,
THERE IS LINDSAY
"THE CRADLE ROBBER" WEGLARZ...
(baby cries)
THE BLIND
BARBER STEFAN ROBERTS,
AND TREASURE HUNTER
TIM OSWALD.
YOU KNOW, JOHNNY, THIS NEXT
OBSTACLE HAS INSPIRED ME
TO TAKE UP A NEW WINTER HOBBY--
ICE FISHING.
OH, THAT SOUNDS FUN.
OH, IT IS! AND REWARDING.
TURNS OUT I'M AN EXCELLENT
ICE FISHERMAN.
MY FREEZER
IS COMPLETELY FULL.
LOT OF FISH, HUH? WHAT KIND?
FISH? (chuckles)
NO, JOHN, ICE.
ICE FISHING.
CATCHING FISH WOULD BE HARD.
YEAH. MM-HMM.
BOY, YOU'RE NOT REAL OUTDOORSY,
ARE YA?
WELL, CLEAR--CLEARLY NOT
YOUR CALIBER.
UH, WHY DON'T WE GO FISHING
FOR SOME WIPEOUTS
ON OUR NEXT OBSTACLE,
PAIN IN THE ICE?
TELL 'EM HOW IT WORKS, JOHNNY.
I GOT NO IDEA.
THAT'S WHY I'M HERE.
CONTESTANTS BEGIN
HIGH IN THE AIR,
PERCHED AROUND OUR ICE HOLE.
IT'S HARD TO RELAX UP THERE.
THEY WILL BRAVE
THE ARCTIC WATERS,
DROPPING THROUGH THE HOLE,
ONTO THE FISHING POLE
FOR A SPIN OVER TO
THE LANDING PLATFORM.
THEN IT'S A TRICKY BALANCING ACT
ATOP THE LUMBER TUMBLER,
AN ICE-SLICKED WALK ACROSS THIS
WOODEN PLANK TO THE OTHER SIDE.
THAT'S FOLLOWED BY
A PERILOUS TRIP ACROSS
THE FROSTY FOOTBRIDGE,
FEATURING A RELENTLESS FREEZING
RUSH FROM OUR ARCTIC WATERFALL.
FINALLY, THEY WILL MOVE IT
OR LUGE IT
WITH A BELLY SLIDE
DOWN THE SNOW CHUTE.
FIRST SIX COMPETITORS LANDING
SAFELY ON THE FINISH PLATFORM
ADVANCE TO THE NEXT ROUND.
LOTS OF ICE OUT THERE, JOHNNY.
I HOPE IT'S BITING.
WELL, WE'RE GONNA FIND OUT
RIGHT NOW.
(cheering)
(Katie) I'M A CHICKEN,
I'M A CHICKEN, I'M A CHICKEN.
I KNOW, KATIE GAGA.
WE ALL SAW YOU HATCH
FROM AN EGG AT THE GRAMMYS.
I'M SHAKING.
WELL, SURE. YOU'RE IN
THE PRESENCE OF GREATNESS.
(Lindsay) I'M NOT GOING FIRST.
I'M SORRY. I'M REALLY SCARED.
CRADLE ROBBER
JUST BEING A BABY.
TREASURE HUNTER TIM
WONDERING
WHERE TO FIND
THAT LUCRATIVE BOUNTY.
LET'S CHECK IN WITH VANESSA.
ALL RIGHT, GENTLEMEN,
IT IS THAT TIME AGAIN.
LET'S GET IT STARTED.
(air horn blows)
(man) OH, MY GOD.
FIRST UP IS
BLIND BARBER STEFAN.
OH, HO!
KING AIM... OH!
GIANT ROTATING BARS
CAN BE SO HARD TO SEE.
AND WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE
AIN'T SCARED.
OHH!
EE! YA!
THAT WAS A FACE-PLANT.
YEAH, IT WAS.
A CRAZY FACE-PLANT WITH NO MILK.
(man) SOMEBODY GO.
DARK ARTIST SUMMONS UP
HIS COURAGE
AND PROBABLY A DEMON OR TWO.
HANGING ON AND DROPS
AT THE PLATFORM.
WHOO!
I'M REALLY GROWING
TO LIKE HIM, JOHN,
AND NOT JUST BECAUSE HE MADE ME
IMMORTAL WITH ARTWORK.
AH!
OH, HO! DOWN INTO
THE WATERCOLOR.
MR. GUM CLINGING TO
THE FISHING POLE.
HE'S ON THE BUBBLE.
CAN HE MAKE IT?
AW, YEAH!
WHOO!
HE'S GOT THAT MINTY FRESH
FEELING AT THE PLATFORM.
(Tim) OKAY, HERE WE GO.
TREASURE HUNTER
GETTING INTO THE RACE.
AND VASCO DA GAMA,
HE DISCOVERS THE PLATFORM.
VOICE ACTOR JASON'S
LOOKING FOR A PAYCHECK.
(Jason) LET'S GO, GUYS!
MOVE IT!
OHH!
OHH, HO HO HO! IT IS
A CATTLE CALL AT THE PLATFORM.
CRADLE ROBBER LINDSAY DROPS.
OH, MY GOD!
LANGUAGE!
NOT IN FRONT OF THE CHILDREN...
THAT YOU'RE ROBBING.
YOW
OH, HO HO!
AAH!
SOMEONE IS A BAD GIRL.
WHERE'S THE SNOWBALLS?
TREASURE HUNTER ON THE LOOKOUT
FOR INCOMING ARTILLERY.
DARK ARTIST--A MILD RESEMBLANCE
TO THE BLACK SWAN UP THERE.
OHH!
OH, HO! VERY MOVING.
GAH! THE BLIND BARBER
GETS CLIPPED. WHO'S NEXT?
OOH!
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE...
OH, MY GOD, MY CROTCH!
THAT'S GONNA PUT A KINK IN HER
WILD AND CRAZY PLANS TONIGHT.
MM!
YA HA HA! AND FALLS OFF
THE WILD SIDE.
AS FOR THE TRULY CRAZY,
LEONARD'S FRIEND CHRIS
TUMBLING SOME LUMBER.
WHOO!
ALL RIGHT! IT'S A CROWD.
CHRIS AND LEONARD
ALONE AT THE FOOTBRIDGE.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?!
WHO'S HE TALKING TO,
THE GUY RIGHT THERE
OR THE GUY IN HIS HEAD?
OH, HELL, NO.
DON'T USE THAT TONE
WITH LEONARD.
TREASURE HUNTER TIM
HOT ON THEIR TRAIL.
WHOO-HOO!
HE REMINDS ME OF
THE GREAT TREASURE HUNTER
NICOLAS CAGE.
BLIND BARBER FINALLY
FIGURING OUT THE POLE.
AW, YEAH!
HE ENVISIONED SUCCESS, PEOPLE.
OH, HO HO!
YOU GO FIRST, MAN.
THOSE GUYS GIVING
TREASURE HUNTER PERMISSION
TO BE THE FIRST EXPLORER.
(Aimee) ALL RIGHT, EVERYBODY,
WATCH OUT.
DO NOT STAND IN THE WAY
OF WILD AND CRAZY.
SHE SHOVES TREASURE HUNTER
FORWARD.
SAFE!
OH, HO HO!
WILD AND CRAZY--
OH! FALLING AND SPLASHING.
OHH!
WHOO!
TREASURE HUNTER
BEATING HIS CHEST,
BUT STILL HAS TO MAKE IT DOWN
THE SNOW CHUTE.
AH, HA HA!
OHH!
NOW HE'S SUNKEN TREASURE HUNTER
DARK ARTIST
ON THE FOOTBRIDGE.
BY THE POWER OF GRAYSKULL,
HE'S GOT IT!
COMING UP FROM BEHIND--MR. GUM
AND VOICE ACTOR JASON.
HE IS HANGING ON
FOR ALL HE'S WORTH.
AND WILD AND CRAZY
MAKES IT A THREESOME.
OH, HO HO! PARTY'S OVER, KIDS.
OHH, HO HO!
THE BLIND BARBER WAY BEHIND,
TRYING TO FEEL, SMELL, OR TASTE
HIS WAY PAST THE LUMBER TUMBLER.
UHH! AAH!
I HOPE HE WASN'T HOLDING
SCISSORS.
DARK ARTIST DIVES
ONTO THE SNOW CHUTE.
OHH!
HE TOOK THE CAMERA WITH HIM,
AND YOU JUST KNOW
HE'S GONNA USE IT IN A WAY
THE F.C.C. WOULDN'T APPROVE.
(Jason) I AIN'T GETTING
LEFT BEHIND!
VOICE ACTOR JASON SLIDES TOWARDS
THE CASTING COUCH.
OHH!
AH! HIS WORDS WEREN'T ENOUGH.
(squawks)
SOUNDS LIKE TREASURE HUNTER TIM
SWALLOWED HIS PARROT.
JACKPOT!
YEAH!
TIM GOT IT!
TREASURE HUNTER TIM
THE FIRST TO MOVE ON...
NEXT IN LINE TO JOIN HIM
ARE KATIE GAGA
AND LEONARD'S FRIEND CHRIS.
YEAH, IT'S GETTING CROWDED
OUT THERE, JOHN--
JUST LIKE IN CHRIS' HEAD.
KATIE GAGA IS ON,
AND LEONARD'S FRIEND TALKS
HIMSELF INTO IT WAS WELL.
AHEAD OF THEM, VOICE ACTOR JASON
WITH A CHANCE TO STEAL THE SHOW.
OHH, NO!
OH, HO HO!
OH, HE'LL NEVER GET AN AGENT
THAT WAY.
THE DARK ARTIST SLIDING
TO DAYLIGHT.
BRAKES! WHOA!
OHH!
YEAH! WHOO!
USES THE DARK AND UNNATURAL
POWERS TO HANG ON
AND TAKE THE SECOND SPOT.
OUR BLIND BARBER STILL
STARING DOWN THE LUMBER TUMBLER.
AAH! YEAH!
AND HE MAKES IT INTO FOCUS.
STILL PLENTY OF ROOM FOR
THE BOLD. FOUR SPOTS LEFT, JOHN.
AT THE SNOW CHUTE, KATIE GAGA
READY TO GET COVERED IN BUBBLES.
ALEJANDRO!
AAH!
NO!
AH!
HERE'S A MATCH
MADE IN HEAVEN--
A VOICE ACTOR GUY
AND A GUY WHO HEARS VOICES.
ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT,
I DON'T LIKE YOU!
I'VE HAD ENOUGH OF THIS!
MAYBE THEY CAN ALL ROOM
TOGETHER, SAVE ON THE RENT.
VOICE ACTOR JASON MAKES
A DESPERATE ATTEMPT...
WHOO!
AND GETS DISCOVERED!
HE'LL HAVE ANOTHER CHANCE
TO SHINE IN THE NEXT ROUND.
(Vanessa) ALL RIGHT!
ONLY THREE SPOTS LEFT.
LEONARD'S FRIEND CHRIS
SLIDES...
OHH!
OUCH! A SHOT TO THE HEAD.
BOY, THAT'S THE LAST THING
HE NEEDS.
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE CHASING
THE CRAZY, AND...
YEAH!
AND YEAH! OH, HO HO!
YEAH! OUR FIRST GIRL
IS AIMEE.
FIRST GIRL
AND POTENTIALLY OUR LAST
'CAUSE ONLY TWO SPOTS REMAIN.
MR. GUM DOESN'T WANNA BLOW IT.
AND FOUR OUT OF FIVE DENTISTS
APPROVE!
HA!
YEAH! WHOO!
BUBBLICIOUS!
THAT MAN HAS
LONG-LASTING FLAVOR.
YEAH! WHOO!
WHO'S GONNA MAKE IT?
IF I KNEW, I COULD
EARN A LIVING AS A PSYCHIC
AND I WOULDN'T NEED
TO TALK TO YOU PEOPLE.
LEONARD'S FRIEND TRYING AGAIN.
WILL THESE TWO FIGURE IT OUT?
AH! OUT OF LUCK!
OH, HO!
IT'S A TIGHT BATTLE
FOR THE FINAL SPOT.
AT THE FOOTBRIDGE,
THE BLIND BARBER MAKES IT ACROSS
AND WALKS SMACK INTO A WALL.
WHOO!
THE NEXT ROUND
IN HIS SIGHTS...
OH, HE'S READY!
GO, STEFAN! GO!
HE'S... OH! KATIE GAGA
PUSHES IN FRONT!
HE DIDN'T SEE THAT COMING.
A SLICK MOVE.
(cheering)
SHE IS SLIDING INTO
THE TOP SIX.
OH! KATIE GOT IT!
AND THE BLIND BARBER
CLOSES SHOP.
SHAVE AND A WIPEOUT--
TWO BITS.
TOP SIX, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN.
MOVING ON, JOHN, WE HAVE
THE TREASURE HUNTER TIM OSWALD,
THE DARK ARTIST JOE VAUX...
(thunderclap)
AND VOICE ACTOR JASON WISHNOV...
(Jason, deep voice)
IS THIS WHAT YOU WANT TO HEAR?
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE REILLY,
MR. GUM BRIAN AYA,
AND KATIE "GAGA" HELMUTH.
THESE SIX ARE THAT MUCH CLOSER
TO $50,000.
THEY HAVE PLENTY MORE HOOPS
TO FALL THROUGH
BEFORE WE SIGN THE CHECK.
(Joe) THIS IS
SUCH A CRUEL EVENT!
♪
WE ARE BACK WITH MORE
WINTER "WIPEOUT" JUST FOR YOU.
YEAH, AND I'M GLAD
THERE'S MORE.
I WAS STARTING TO GET
THE SHAKES.
I NEED MORE WIPEOUTS,
AND PROBABLY A LATTE.
THERE ARE
ONLY SIX CONTESTANTS LEFT,
AND THEY ARE ALL WILLING, JOHN,
TO GIVE YOU YOUR FIX OF FALLS.
STILL IN IT, WE HAVE
TREASURE HUNTER TIM OSWALD,
THE DARK ARTIST JOE VAUX...
AHH!
VOICE ACTOR JASON WISHNOV,
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE REILLY...
(blows noisemaker)
MR. GUM BRIAN AYA,
AND KATIE "GAGA" HELMUTH.
(Katie) GAGA!
YOU KNOW, JOHN, A LOT OF PEOPLE
MAKE FUN OF THE GAGA...
HMM.
FOR THOSE OUTRAGEOUS OUTFITS.
BUT MEAT PRODUCTS ARE
SURPRISINGLY WARM.
I HAVE ALL OF MY JACKETS MADE
WITH A BOLOGNA LINING.
YOU SHOULD TRY IT.
NO.
ALL RIGHT. YOUR LOSS.
BY THE WAY, YOU WANT
SOME BEEF JERKY?
MY PANTS ARE LINED
WITH DRIED BEEF.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I FEEL CONFIDENT IN SAYING
THAT I WILL NEVER WANT FOOD
FROM YOUR TROUSERS.
(mouth full) YOUR LOSS.
LET ME KNOW
IF YOU CHANGE YOUR MIND.
PLENTY MORE
WHERE THAT CAME FROM.
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GET DOWN
TO OUR NEXT OBSTACLE--
THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE.
(exhales)
LOOK AT HIS BREATH, JOHN.
HE GETS MORE COLDHEARTED
THE FURTHER WE GET INTO WINTER.
(rattles)
WELL, HERE'S HOW
THIS ONE WORKS.
CONTESTANTS WILL FIRST FACE
OUR TWO SLITHERING,
SPINNING SNOW SWEEPERS.
AAH! YEAH!
MAKE THE PLATFORM, AND IT'S UP
TO PLUMMET SUMMIT--
THE ENORMOUS BELLY
OF THE SNAKE.
AAH!
AVOID DIGESTION, SLIDE DOWN
THE SERPENT'S SLIPPERY BACK.
WHEE!
(exhales)
THEN IT'S OVER TO
THE SHIVERING TIMBERS.
BOUNCE OFF A GIANT SNOWBALL,
MAKE IT TO THE FINISH PLATFORM,
AND YOU, MY FRIEND...
WHOO-HOO!
HAVE MADE IT
TO THE WIPEOUT...
(rattles)
"S-S-S-SONE."
"S-S-S-SONE," JOHN?
YESSS.
FIRST THREE
TO GET PAST THE SNAKE
WILL ENTER THE WIPEOUT ZONE.
S-S-S-SONE.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
LET'S GO DOWN TO THE UNTIED
TONGUE OF VANESSA LACEY.
S-S-S-SONE.
OKAY, GUYS, IT LOOKS LIKE
THE CONTESTANTS ARE IN POSITION,
AND THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE
IS READY TO STRIKE.
(exhales)
WHO WANTS TO--
WHO'S GONNA JUMP FIRST?
ANYONE WANT TO JUST SAY
THEY'RE GONNA JUMP FIRST?
(air horn blows)
HEY!
KATIE GAGA, IF YOU ASK FIRST,
YOU'RE GONNA END UP LAST.
TREASURE HUNTER TIM OSWALD'S
OUT FRONT...
(groans)
FOLLOWED BY THE VOICE ACTOR
JASON WISHNOV.
OH, HO HO!
OOH, HOO!
RIGHT IN HIS TREASURE CHEST.
GOOD LANDING.
GOOD FOR HIM
BECAUSE NORMALLY, YOU SEE--
OHH!
OH!
MM!
THAT.
AAH!
AH!
OOH, HOO HOO! AND THAT.
HOLY CRAP! AAH!
AH, HA HA!
YEAH. YEAH, SOME OF THAT.
LOOK OUT!
TREASURE HUNTER A GREAT CHANCE
TO EXTEND HIS EARLY LEAD.
WHOO!
HE SHOULD HAVE AN ADVANTAGE
HERE, JOHN.
THIS IS JUST LIKE DIVING
FOR SUNKEN TREASURE.
MM-HMM.
ONLY THERE'S NO WATER
AND IT'S MORE OF A SLIDE.
UHH!
OHH, HO!
OHH!
I SAID "SLIDE," MAN!
THAT'S A STROKE OF LUCK
FOR DARK ARTIST.
TAKES ADVANTAGE OF HIS
GOOD FORTUNE WITH AS ARTSY MOVE.
MR. GUM TRYING
TO CHEW AWAY AT HIS LEAD,
BUT HE IS IN A STICKY SITUATION
AT THE SWEEPER ARM.
MM-HMM.
HE BETTER SCRAPE HIMSELF OFF.
(Vanessa) OOH!
OHH!
OHH, HO HO!
DARK ARTIST ABOUT TO DRAW A LINE
DOWN PLUMMET SUMMIT.
WHOA!
(Vanessa) YEAH!
YEAH! PERFECT! FRAME IT.
WHOA!
WATCH OUT!
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE...
OH!
OH, HO HO!
DOING THE SAME THING
OVER AND OVER
AND EXPECTING
DIFFERENT RESULTS.
THE DARK ARTIST...
OH, GOD!
AH! JUST ERASED HIS LEAD.
OH, HOO!
THE TREASURE HUNTER
ACTUALLY SLIDING THIS TIME.
WOW!
YEAH, A LITTLE MORE GENTLE
WITH THE JUNK IN HIS TRUNK,
AND HE IS MAKING IT DOWN
THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE.
RIGHT BEHIND AND READY TO SOAR
IS KATIE GAGA.
(Vanessa) KATIE!
OH, MY GOSH!
YEAH!
SHE'S ON IT...
AH, HA HA!
(John H. and Vanessa) OHH!
SO I HAVE TO GO AGAIN?
SORRY. ONLY ACTUAL CELEBRITIES
GET CELEBRITY TREATMENT.
(man) OH, GOD!
THE DARK ARTIST
IS GOING AT IT AGAIN.
HE'S ON THE SNOWBALL.
(Vanessa) GO!
JUST ONE GIANT LEAP LEFT.
YES!
YEAH!
THE DARK ARTIST FIRST TO QUALIFY
FOR THE WIPEOUT ZONE.
AND LOOKING TO JOIN HIM
IS MR. GUM.
OOH! UHH!
OOH, HO HO!
(Vanessa) COME ON! (laughs)
AH!
BREAK A GUMBALL.
COME ON. (laughs)
(high-pitched voice) DAMN!
KATIE GAGA COMING AROUND.
HERE WE GO. KATIE AGAIN.
SHE'S A ROCK STAR.
WHOO!
IMPERSONATOR.
BUT KATIE GAGA TAKES
CENTER STAGE.
(Jason) GREAT JOB, KATIE!
(Aimee) YEAH, KATIE!
IS THE VOICE ACTOR SERIOUSLY
TRYING TO NETWORK FROM UP THERE?
GREAT JOB!
YOU KNOW,
THE KEY TO NETWORKING
IS TO MAKE
A GREAT FIRST IMPRESSION.
MM!
OOH!
(man) THAT ONE HURT.
AH, LOOK,
IT'S WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE.
IS SHE SEEKING ASYLUM
ON THAT OBSTACLE?
I'M SO OVER THIS. AAH!
NO, APPARENTLY NOT.
MR. GUM AIMING FOR A BETTER
RESULT THE SECOND TIME AROUND.
WILL HE GET IT?
OH, NO!
OHH, HO!
HEY! DID HE JUST STICK HIS GUM
UNDER THE OBSTACLE?
YOU KNOW, I GOTTA
CLEAN THAT UP LATER!
JOHNNY, CALL ME CRAZY,
BUT IT LOOKS LIKE AIMEE IS
COMING DOWN PLUMMET SUMMIT.
DOES THAT COUNT?
YEAH.
WELL, IF KATIE GAGA
SAYS SO...
AND I THINK KATIE GAGA
IS ABOUT TO TAKE CHARGE AGAIN.
OH, HO! THAT IS JUST
GAGA BEING GAGA.
OHH!
THE TREASURE HUNTER
RISING TO THE OCCASION.
OH! GONNA GIVE HIMSELF
A LITTLE RUNNING ROOM.
OH!
EE! AH! NO!
OHH!
LESS MUSCLE, TIM!
LOOK OUT FROM ABOVE!
IT'S MR. GUM.
AND THIS TIME,
HE STICKS THE LANDING.
YES!
HE DO.HE'S GOT SPEARMINT.
YES, HE DO.
HE'S GOT SPEARMINT.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
WHOO!
(man) THERE YOU GO, BABY!
TWO MORE SPOTS.
BRIAN, VANESSA PROMISED
TO KISS YOU IF YOU MAKE IT!
(boing)
IS THAT RIGHT?
ALMOST POSITIVE
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
JOHN, WOULD YOU BELIEVE
DULL AND BORING WINS THE RACE?
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE
COMING FROM WAY BACK.
A WIPEOUT ZONE SPOT
ONE DARING DIVE AWAY...
OH, YEAH!
WOW!
CRAZY AIMEE ACTUALLY MADE IT!
THAT'S NUTS.
ONLY ONE PRECIOUS WIPEOUT ZONE
OPENING REMAINS.
JOHNNY, EVEN THE VOICE ACTOR'S
GOT A SHOT.
COME ON!
I DON'T KNOW.
THAT MR. GUM IS
CHOMPING AT THE BIT.
IT AIN'T OVER YET!
I GOT IT. I GOT IT.
THERE IS A SHOWDOWN COMING,
AND MR. GUM IS CREATING
A WHOLE WAD OF TENSION.
I GOT IT!
PATIENCE.
(man) GO, GO, GO!
HE'S OFF AND HE'S...
(man) YES!
I GOT IT!
YEAH, GOT IT.
WAY TO GRAB THE BALL.
HOW'D YOU DO IT?
UH-OH, HE'S ASKING FOR HELP
FROM THE DARK SIDE.
HOW'D YOU DO IT?
DID YOU JUST JUMP?
GIVE IT A LITTLE BOUNCE.
JUMP!
JUST FEEL IT OUT.
FEEL A LITTLE BOUNCE.
JUMP! JUMP!
MR. GUM CAN END THE FINAL SPOT
SUSPENSE RIGHT HERE.
FEEL THAT BALL!
COME ON, SHAKE THE BALL!
GO! GO ON. GET HIM. GO GET HIM.
I CAN'T. HE'S ON THE BALL.
KNOCK HIM OFF.
UH-OH! LOOKS LIKE GAGA
DIDN'T GET TO THE TOP
WITHOUT KNOCKING A FEW PEOPLE
DOWN, JOHNNY.
KNOCK HIM OFF. GO!
YOU CAN'T KNOCK ME OFF!
I GOT IT!
MAYBE NOT HER, BUT KATIE GAGA
HAS OTHERS TO DO HER DIRTY WORK.
GET HIM OFF. GET HIM OFF.
GO. GO, GO! GO.
SHE'S TALKED THE VOICE ACTOR
INTO IT.
ATTACKS FROM BEHIND!
NO!
OH, HO HO!
THAT WAS CRUEL!
NOW KATIE GAGA SENDING IN
ANOTHER MINION.
UH-OH.
HERE COMES
THE TREASURE HUNTER.
(JoeBRIAN!
(Katie) JUMP! JUMP!
GET OUT OF THERE!
MR. GUM FORCED TO MOVE.
OH, HO HO!
OH, HO! NO!
JOHN, THE MEN SEDUCED AND RUINED
BY THE POWER OF KATIE GAGA.
THE COAST IS NOW CLEAR
FOR HER TO CLAIM VICTORY.
HOPPING ONTO THE SNOWBALL.
(Joe, high-pitched voice)
COME ON, KATIE, YOU CAN DO IT!
HER MISCHIEVOUS PLOT
A LEAP FROM COMPLETION.
AAH!
OH, HO HO!
OHH!
(Aimee)
THAT WAS STRAIGHT IN HER FACE.
(Joe) SHE WAS COMBING HER HAIR
WITH HER TOES!
REALLY? ONLY A DARK ARTIST
WOULD GO THERE.
(smack, crunch)
OH. NO, TECHNICALLY,
HE'S RIGHT.
AAH!
(Joe) OW!
WELL, WITH THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE
AND SLY TEMPTRESS
BOTH OUT OF HIS WAY,
TREASURE HUNTER CAN NOW CLAIM
THE FINAL SPOT.
SAFELY ON THE SNOWBALL.
(Joe and Aimee) YES! YES!
STILL VULNERABLE.
(Katie) KNOCK HIM OFF, DUDE.
UH-OH.
HE KNOCKED YOU OFF.
OH, BOY. MR. GUM IS LIKE
PUTTY IN HER HANDS, JOHNNY.
HERE HE GOES!
INCOMING!
OH, HO HO!
(Joe) USE HIS HEAD!
AH, HA!
OHH!
LOOK OUT!
THIS IS SUCH A CRUEL EVENT!
MR. GUM HAS BEEN IN A LOT
OF STICKY SITUATIONS BEFORE,
BUT I'M GUESSING
HE NEVER IMAGINED THIS.
(Brian, slo-mo voice) OW!
NOW THAT IS
SOME BURIED TREASURE.
(Joe) LOOK OUT!
AAH!
NOW MR. GUM BETTER HURRY,
BECAUSE THE MANIPULATIVE
KATIE GAGA
IS PREPARED TO DO
HER OWN DIRTY WORK.
HERE SHE COMES, JOHNNY!
(Joe) GET OUT OF THERE, BRIAN!
MR. GUM'S GOT TROUBLE
ON TWO FRONTS.
FLINGING HIMSELF
IN THE FINAL SPOT!
OHH! KATIE GAGA GOES DOWN!
OHH!
ALMOST!
YEAH! YEAH!
AND MR. GUM IT IS!
WHOO!
(Vanessa speaks indistinctly)
YEAH!
THIS IS IT!
NO, IT'S NOT.
THIS IS MY ONE SHOT.
NO, DUDE, IT'S--
IF I DON'T MAKE IT NOW,
IT'S OVER.
IT'S ALREADY OVER, VOICE ACTOR.
TOTALLY OVER.
YEAH. HE IS SO DRAMATIC.
HE FELL ON YOUR FACE!
KISS MY HELMET.
OKAY, WAIT.
AH! DON'T DO THAT, VANESSA.
REMEMBER WHERE IT'S BEEN.
AAH!
(Joe) WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!
USE HIS HEAD!
SO OUR FINALISTS ARE SET--
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE REILLY,
MR. GUM BRIAN AYA,
AND THE DARK ARTIST JOE VAUX.
STICK AROUND
FOR THE CRAZIEST, DARKEST,
GUMMIEST WIPEOUT ZONE EVER.
It's time to free ourselves
from the smell
and harshness of bleach.
And free ourselves from worrying
about the ones we love.
New Lysol Power & Free has more
cleaning power than bleach.
How?
The secret
is the hydrogen peroxide
formula.
It attacks tough stains
and kills 99.9% of germs.
New Lysol Power & Free.
Powerful cleaning that's
family friendly.
Another step forward
in our Mission for Health.
Every human being
is unique.
And there is one store
that recognizes it.
The Sleep Number Store.
The only place in the
world you'll find the
extraordinarily comfortable
Sleep Number Experience.
An exclusive collection of
innovations that totally
individualize your sleep.
Perfectly comfortable
pillows that adjust to
your size and shape.
Temperature-balancing
bedding.
Dual warmth comforters.
All designed around the
Sleep Number Bed: A bed
with dual-air technology
that allows you to adjust
to the support your
body needs.
Each of your bodies.
In the name of human
individuality: The Sleep
Number Collection.
Discover how our sleep
professionals can
individualize your sleep
experience.
Exclusively at one of our 400
Sleep Number Stores nationwide.
Sleep Number.
Comfort Individualized.
This holiday season, give
the gift that's magical:
the innovative AirFit
adjustable pillow at
special 30% savings.
♪
WE ARE BACK
ON WINTER "WIPEOUT"...
AFTER DARK.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE STARTED THIS BLUSTERY DAY
WITH 24 HOPEFUL CONTESTANTS.
NOW WE'RE DOWN TO JUST THREE
STILL DUKING IT OUT
FOR THAT $50,000 CHECK.
NEXT UP, THEY FACE DOWN
THE FINAL CHALLENGE--
OUR WINTER WIPEOUT ZONE.
AND THIS STUNNER STARTS
WITH A 7-STORY DROP
STRAIGHT DOWN KILLER LUGE.
FROM THERE, IT'S ON TO
THE PSYCHEDELIC SNOW GLOBE,
WHERE CONTESTANTS MUST
TAG THE CENTER
IN ORDER TO DROP
THE EXIT PLATFORM.
NEXT, IT'S AN UPHILL BATTLE
ON THE FROZEN FURY
TO MAKE IT TO THE OTHER SIDE.
AND FINALLY, ICED OVER.
NAVIGATE ACROSS THESE REVOLVING
DIAMONDS TO THE FINISH PLATFORM.
TIME TO FIND OUT
WHICH OF THESE FINAL THREE
WILL GO HOME AS OUR CHAMPION.
UP FIRST--WILD AND CRAZY
AIMEE REILLY.
WHOO! WIPEOUT ZONE!
LET'S LOOK BACK AT HOW SHE GOT
TO THE WIPEOUT ZONE.
I'M CRAZY!
AIMEE REILLY STARTED THE DAY
CLAIMING TO BE WILD AND CRAZY...
AAH!
SHOWING OFF
SOME INSANE WIPEOUTS.
UHH! AAH!
OVERCOMING EXPECTATIONS,
SHE PULLED HERSELF TOGETHER
ON PAIN IN THE ICE.
I'M CRAZY!
AND AFTER A WILD RIDE
ON THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE,
SHE IS ON HER WAY
TO THE WIPEOUT ZONE.
(man) OHH!
KILLER LUGE LOOKS
AWFULLY IMPOSING.
LLY IMPOSING.
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE--
SHE'S GOTTA BE HALF-MAD
TO SIT UP THERE.
OH. MY. GOD.
WHAT'S THE MATTER? NEVER DROPPED
7 STORIES AT 35 MILES PER HOUR
ON A KILLER LUGE BEFORE?
(beeping)
A BUNDLE OF NERVES.
HERE'S THE COUNTDOWN.
(beep)
AND WILD AND CRAZY GOES DOWN.
ONLY ONE WAY OFF.
AAH!
WHOA!
WHOA, HO HO!
THAT'S WHAT'S KNOWN
AS THE CALL OF THE WILD.
AAH!
ALMOST MORE OF
A SHRIEK OF THE WILD, REALLY?.
WOW, THAT WAS QUITE A HIT.
REALLY A TOUGH LANDING.
PSYCHEDELIC SNOW GLOBE
DOESN'T CARE.
STILL SHAKING OFF THE EFFECTS
OF THAT WATER LANDING,
BUT SHE HAS MADE IT
INTO THE GLOBE.
NICE FIRST MOVE, WORKING HER WAY
TO THE CENTER.
THE BUTTON RELEASES
THE EXIT PLATFORM.
REACHING AND JUST GETS
A PIECE OF IT.
OHH!
OH! GOT INTO THE ROTATION.
A MEAN DOUBLE HIT.
AAH!
DON'T THINK OF IT AS LOSING
YOUR BALANCE, WILD AND CRAZY.
THINK OF IT AS FINDING
YOUR IMBALANCE.
SO IT'S TWO ATTEMPTS, AT LEAST,
ON THE GLOBE.
HER TIME ALREADY HEFTY--
PAST THE 5-MINUTE MARK.
SHE'S STAYING HIGH THIS TIME,
EXIT PLATFORM IN PLACE.
AN EASY RIDE.
HERE COMES THE DISMOUNT.
UHH!
YES!
WILD AND CRAZY CAN MOVE UP
TO THE FROZEN FURY.
THERE'S ICE UP HERE.
YEAH, IT GIVES YOU AN IDEA
OF THE CONDITIONS TONIGHT.
IT IS BITTER COLD OUT.
OH, MY GOD.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
THAT IS A FREQUENT QUESTION.
PLATFORMS TILTED
TO MATCH THE TEMPERATURE--
ABOUT 30 DEGREES.
UHH!
OH! EARLY WIPEOUT, JOHN.
YEAH, THE FROZEN FURY
DECLARING
WILD AND CRAZY
INCOMPETENT...
UHH!
AND SHE TOOK A PLATFORM
TO THE TEETH.
AND AS SHE FINISHES
HER 18-FOOT CLIMB
BACK TO THAT
ICE-SLICKED PLATFORM,
HER TIME TRIPS
PAST 9 MINUTES.
FROZEN FURY
STILL IN FRONT OF HER.
UHH! OH, MY GOD.
AIMEE CLEARLY FEELING
THE FATIGUE
AFTER THOSE LONG COLD SWIMS.
SHE IS REALLY STRUGGLING
TO GET OVER THOSE BARS.
YEAH, JOHN, THAT COLD HURTS.
EXHAUSTION THE ENEMY,
BUT SHE KEEPS PUSHING FORWARD.
ONE MORE PLATFORM LEFT.
AIMEE JUST WILLING HERSELF
OVER THAT BAR.
YEAH!
NOW ONLY ICED OVER REMAINS,
AS WILD AND CRAZY AIMS
TO ESTABLISH
THE OPENING TIME TO BEAT.
WILD AND CRAZY GOING FOR IT.
WHAT WAS THAT?
AND LOOKING A LITTLE STARTLED.
OHH!
OH, HO! MAN!
AND THAT QUICKLY HALTS
THE PROGRESS ON THIS RUN.
WHAT WAS THAT?
YEAH, AIMEE LOSES HER GRIP,
AND WHAT FEW WITS SHE HAD LEFT,
SHE GETS TOSSED INTO THE DRINK.
AND DOWN THERE,
THAT SWIMMING YOU DON'T SEE
IS WHERE THE CLOCK
REALLY TAKES A BEATING.
SECOND ATTEMPT NOW.
TIME ALREADY
AT 14 MINUTES, 47 SECONDS.
UHH!
AIMEE IS RIGHT OUT
ON THAT FIRST DIAMOND,
MAKE MAKING A JUMP
FOR THE SECOND.
OH!
OH! GETS A FACE FULL OF PLATFORM
THERE, BUT SHE IS UP
AND QUICKLY OVER TO
THAT THIRD DIAMOND.
SHE HAS ONE MORE JUMP
TO THE FINISH. OH!
UHH!
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE
PULLING HERSELF UP.
WHOO!
PUTS UP A TIME
OF 15 MINUTES, 5 SECONDS.
AND NOW WE'LL SEE
IF IT STANDS UP.
WHOO!
YEAH, HOPING TO BEAT
THAT TIME--MR. GUM BRIAN AYA.
YEAH, LET'S DO THIS! ALL RIGHT!
YEAH! I GOT THIS ONE!
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT HIS DAY.
WHOO! "WIPEOUT"!
MR. GUM BRIAN AYA PULLED OUT
FROM THE PACK TODAY
WHEN HE EASILY COMPLETED
OUR QUALIFIER.
UHH! AAH!
HIS BUBBLE ALMOST BURST
AT PAIN IN THE ICE.
UHH!
THEN HIS MINTY FRESH ATTITUDE
PUSHED HIM THROUGH
THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE.
NOW HE'S FACING DOWN
THE ULTIMATE STICKY SITUATION
IN THE WIPEOUT ZONE.
YEAH!
MR. GUM READY TO GO
ATOP KILLER LUGE.
15 MINUTES, 5 SECONDS
THE TIME TO BEAT.
(beeping)
LIGHTS, CAMERA, GRAVITY!
(beep)
MR. GUM SHOVES OFF.
YEAH, AND THE PHYSICS OF FALLING
ARE NOW IN CHARGE.
I LOVE YOU, MOM!
(laughs) YEAH.
TAKE A LISTEN, JOHN.
IN THE MIDST OF
A 80-FOOT DROP,
HE USES THAT CLASSIC LINE...
I LOVE YOU, MOM!
AND GIVES A SHOUT-OUT
TO HIS MOM.
WHAT A GUY.
COME ON. I CAN DO IT.
REALLY? YOU CAN DO
THE PSYCHEDELIC SNOW GLOBE
AND CHEW GUM
AT THE SAME TIME?
OH, MY GOD!
HOW DO YOU DO THIS?
NOT SURE THERE'S A MANUAL.
OHH! THE GLOBE
SPITS HIM RIGHT OUT.
OH!
SO MUCH
FOR HIGH EXPECTORATIONS.
MR. GUM GUMMED UP THAT ENTRY
AND HAD NOTHING TO HOLD ON TO.
YEAH, BUT HE WANTS ANOTHER PIECE
OF THIS THING, JOHNNY.
CLOCK SHOWS 4:20.
THIS WAY.
OOH!
OH! TRYING SOMETHING
A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
HE'S GOTTA MAKE IT DOWN
TO THE CENTER AND TOUCH THE--
AAH!
OH, HO!
OHH! WOW!
BRIAN SLIPS UP AGAIN...
AAH!
AND JUST GOES FLAILING
INTO THAT BONE-CHILLING WATER.
I CAN DO THIS.
THIRD TRY.
CLOCK APPROACHING 7 MINUTES.
GIVING THE GLOBE
ANOTHER SHAKE.
STILL HASN'T GONE ANYWHERE NEAR
THE CENTER BUTTON
TO RELEASE
THAT EXIT PLATFORM.
OH! SMOOTH HE IS NOT.
OOH.
I HIT IT!
FINALLY!
I GOT IT! I CAN DO IT!
ALL RIGHT, NOW HE'S GOTTA TRY
AND RIDE--
OHH!
OHH, MAN!
MR. GUM
A LITTLE TOO CONFIDENT
AND JUST MISSED THAT STEP
COMPLETELY.
THIS IS HIS FOURTH ATTEMPT
ON THE PSYCHEDELIC SNOW GLOBE,
JOHN.
MIGHT BE A RECORD.
DOESN'T HAVE TO MESS
WITH THAT CENTER ANYMORE,
WHICH IS NICE.
JUST GET ON AND GET OFF.
MAKING SURE HE'S GOT BOTH FEET
FIRMLY PLANTED.
AND FINALLY,
HE IS ON TO THE FROZEN FURY.
WHOO! I DID IT!
THAT'S GOOD, BUT HE IS STILL
FAR OFF THE LEADER'S PACE.
HE'S PROBABLY GETTING COLD
RIGHT ABOUT NOW.
(laughs)
MY HANDS ARE FREEZING!
NOT JUST FIGHTING THE ELEMENTS,
JOHN. HE IS FIGHTING THE CLOCK.
MR. GUM NOW LESS THAN 5 MINUTES
TO FINISH THE ZONE.
YEP, AND FROZEN FURY--
OH, HO!
NO! HE'S DOWN AGAIN!
YEAH, THAT COLD WEATHER IS
STARTING TO AFFECT HIS REFLEXES
BECAUSE THAT WAS A CASE
OF TOO LITTLE, TOO LATE.
DON'T GIVE UP.
YEAH, AND ATTEMPT NUMBER TWO,
AND MR. GUM HAS LESS THAN
2 MINUTES TO FINISH THE COURSE.
CLEVER HOP OVER THE BAR THERE.
MR. GUM MAY BE GETTING
THE HANG OF THIS ONE.
AND HE BETTER, JOHNNY.
HE STILL HAS ONE OBSTACLE TO GO
AND NO TIME FOR WIPEOUTS.
AAH!
LUNGS BURNING, MUSCLES ACHING.
HIS BODY REALLY GETTING PUSHED
TO THE LIMIT HERE.
AAH!
UP AND OVER. ONWARD HE GOES.
MR. GUM--HE CAN MAKE A GAME
OUT OF THIS AFTER ALL.
HE COMPLETES THE FROZEN FURY.
DID IT.
TAKE YOUR TIME. IT'S OKAY.
(laughs)
BRIAN'S GOT LESS THAN 30 SECONDS
TO CLEAR ICED OVER, JOHN.
READY TO TRANSITION FROM
THAT FIRST TO SECOND DIAMOND.
OH!
AH! OVER!
MR. GUM JUST COULDN'T GET
BOTH LEGS UP ONTO THAT DIAMOND,
AND LOST HIS BALANCE
AND HIS CHANCE AT THE 50K.
(air horn blows)
THE SOUND OF THE HORN OFFICIALLY
SOUNDS THE END FOR MR. GUM.
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE REILLY
REMAINS OUR LEADER.
BUT IS HER TIME
OF 15 MINUTES, 5 SECONDS
GOOD ENOUGH TO HOLD UP AGAINST
THE DARK ARTIST?
WE'LL FIND OUT FOR SURE
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
.
♪
WELCOME BACK
TO WINTER "WIPEOUT,"
AND SOMEBODY'S ABOUT
TO GET PAID.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE ARE JUST ONE RUN AWAY FROM
HANDING OUT OUR $50,000 PRIZE.
WILD AND CRAZY AIMEE REILLY
HOLDS THE LEAD
LOOKING TO CHANGE THAT--
WOUR FINAL COMPETITOR,
JOE VAUX, THE DARK ARTIST.
(mouth full) I'M READY.
I CAN'T TALK, BUT I'M READY.
LET'S REVIEW HIS JOURNEY
TO THE ZONE.
(thunderclap)
WHOO!
JOE VAUX, THE DARK ARTIST,
CREEPED EVERYONE OUT
WITH HIS RUN ON THE QUALIF.
HE SHOWED US HIS DIABOLICAL
VISION ON PAIN IN THE ICE.
AND BROUGHT DARKNESS
TO THE COLDHEARTED SNAKE.
NOW AFTER A LONG DAY
OF WIPEOUTS,
HE'S HOPING TO COMPLETE
HIS SINISTER MASTERPIECE
IN THE WIPEOUT ZONE.
AAH! UHH!
KILLER LUGE OMINOUS-LOOKING
FROM DOWN BELOW.
(grunts and laughs)
AND FAR WORSE FROM UP TOP.
TOTALLY NERVE-RACKING.
15:05
THE $50,000 TIME TO BEAT.
(beeping)
(beep)
BRIGHT LIGHTS, DARK ARTIST.
AAH!
YEAH! THERE YOU GO!
WHOA, HO!
TURN HIM LOOSE
AND INTO THE NIGHT!
THE DARK ARTIST GOES FOR A RIDE
DOWN KILLER LUGE,
AND ALMOST DOES A 180...
OOH!
BEFORE ENTERING THE DARK WATERS
OF THE WIPEOUT ZONE.
QUICKLY OUT OF THAT WATER
AND UP THE LADDER.
PSYCHEDELIC SNOW GLOBE
SPINNING.
RIGHT INTO IT.
UP ON ENTRY BUT UNDETERRED
TO THE CENTER BUTTON.
(high-pitched laugh)
AND WITH A CREEPY CACKLE,
HE TAGS--
UH-OH!
OHH!
OH, NO!
OH, THE DARK ARTIST NO MATCH
FOR THE PSYCHEDELIC SNOW GLOBE,
JOHNNY.
AAH!
HE BETTER GET HIMSELF READY
FOR ROUND TWO.
EVERYBODY TAKING MULTIPLE TRIES
ON THE GLOBE TONIGHT.
3 MINUTES GONE BY.
JOE STAYING HIGH AS THE EXIT
PLATFORM IS ALREADY DOWN
AND IN THE READY POSITION.
JUMPS...
HEY! FINE THIS TIME.
OOH, HE'S KINDA BOOKING IT.
I'LL SAY.
HE IS OPENING UP A LEAD
ON THE PACE SET
BY WILD AND CRAZY.
AT THE FROZEN FURY NOW.
HE'S UP AND OVER--OHH!
OHH! WOW.
NO. DIDN'T SEE THAT COMING.
THE DARK ARTIST LOOKED LIKE
HE HAD IT,
BUT CAUGHT HIS LEG
AND LANDED HARD.
SO HE WILL TAKE A COUPLE OF
SHOTS AT FROZEN FURY AS WELL.
NO ISSUE
WITH THE FIRST BAR THERE.
DON'T FORGET THIS OBSTACLE
IS AT AN INCLINE, JOHNNY.
SO HE IS TRULY FIGHTING
AN UPHILL BATTLE.
HE'S ONLY 7 MINUTES IN, JOHN,
BUT YOU CAN GET ALL KINDS
OF WORN OUT IN A SHORT TIME
HERE IN THE ZONE.
SETTING HIMSELF UP IN
GREAT POSITION TO WIN THE CASH.
THE PATH IS CLEAR NOW.
STEPS SAFELY OFF FROZEN FURY,
AND ICED OVER ALL THAT'S LEFT.
OH, MY GOD.
I'M GETTING NERVOUS NOW.
THE DARK ARTIST FACING DOWN
THE FINAL OBSTACLE,
BUT THESE REVOLVING DIAMONDS
ARE BLING WITH A STING.
FALLS WEAKLY
ONTO THE OBSTACLE.
LOOKS LIKE TROUBLE.
OHH!
OH!
YEAH, THE DARK ARTIST HAD
DESIGNS ON A GOOD POSITION...
AAH!
BUT ICED OVER WAS NOT BUYING.
LOST A LOT OF TIME GETTING
HIMSELF BACK TO THE START
HERE AT ICED OVER.
SECOND TRY AND IT STARTS OUT
MUCH BETTER.
HE'S IN GOOD POSITION.
OVER TO THE SECOND DIAMOND.
THIS FAR DOWN THE LINE, HE CAN
NO LONGER AFFORD A WIPEOUT.
YEAH, REALLY MEASURING
HIS MOVEMENTS ON THE THIRD NOW.
UH-OH. (chuckles)
THIS ISN'T LOOKING RIGHT.
UGH!
HE'S IN TROUBLE.
AH, BUT HE CALMLY BACKTRACKS.
RISKY STRATEGY.
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
IF IT WORKS, HE BUYS HIMSELF
SOME TIME FOR THAT FINAL JUMP.
AH!
HOW GOOD IS THAT?
OH!
IN A WALK....
WOW.
I DID IT!
THE DARK ARTIST WINS IT.
VANESSA, GIVE THE MAN
THE GOOD NEWS.
CONGRATULATIONS!
YOU WON "WIPEOUT"!
YEAH!
THE DARK ARTIST, JOE VAUX...
WHOO!
OUR NEWEST
WINTER "WIPEOUT" CHAMPION.
YEAH!
AND NOW I AM GONNA
HAVE THIS BABY FRAMED
AND HUNG OVER MY DESK.
SHAME TO SEE YOUR NAGEL PRINT
COME DOWN.
THAT'S GONNA DO IT FOR US.
BE SURE TO TUNE IN NEXT WEEK
WHEN 24 NEW CONTESTANTS
TAKE ON SOME CRAZY,
NEW WINTER OBSTACLES.
UNTIL THEN, AMERICA,
I'M JOHN ANDERSON...
THE LITTLE ONE HERE.
AND FOR OUR COHOST
VANESSA LACHEY,
I'M JOHN HENSON SAYING,
GOOD NIGHT AND BIG BALLS.
♪
OH! OH! OHH!
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
AAH!
DIVER DOWN!
UHH!
OH! OH!
KATIE!
OH, MY GOD!
YEAH!
AAH!
OH! AAH!
(growling)
BRAVEHEART!
(laughs)
"WIPEOUT"!
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>>> THE FOLLOWING IS A
PRESENTATION OF ESPN ON ABC.
>>> WELCOME TO ESPN SPORTS
SATURDAY.
>>> HI, EVERYONE.
I'M YOUR HOST ROBERT FLORES.
WE'LL GET YOU TO S.E.C. STORY
CREW.
IN JUST A MOMENT.
BUT FIRST, THE COUNTRY
ESPECIALLY THOSE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, CONTINUE TO MOURN
AND REMEMBER THE VICTIMS OF THE
FAMILIES AFFECTED BY YESTERDAY'S
SHOOTINGS.
ATHLETES TAKING TO TWITTER TO
EXPRESS THEIR THOUGHTS.
THIS FROM SAINTS QUARTERBACK
DREW BREES -- MY HEART BREAKS
FOR THE FAMILIES OF THOSE KILLED
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.