HEY, KATHRYN. YOU LOOK GREAT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> YEAH!
Meredith: TALK ABOUT THE
PRESSURE ON YOU TO GET THAT
BROADWAY QUESTION RIGHT.
>> I KNOW, I KNOW. I MEAN, I--
CONSIDERING THE FACT THAT I HAVE
A DEGREE IN THEATER, IF I GET
WRONG, HA HA!
Meredith: OH, YOU DO HAVE
A DEGREE IN THEATER?
>> I DO, YEAH.
Meredith: OK, THAT'S GREAT.
>> WHICH MEANS THAT IT'S EVEN
MORE PRESSURE.
Meredith: EXACTLY. AND RIGHT
NOW, YOU ARE WAITING TABLES TO
MAKE SOME ENDS MEET?
>> YEAH, YEAH. TO KIND OF FIGURE
OUT WHERE I WANT TO GO WITH
A CAREER.
Meredith: WELL, RIGHT NOW WE'RE
GLAD THAT YOU'RE HERE WITH US
BECAUSE YOU'RE DOING A GOOD JOB.
YOU GOT $11,000. YOU'RE 11 AWAY
FROM THE MILLION, 7 AWAY FROM
ROUND TWO, AT WHICH POINT YOU
GET TO KEEP ALL THE MONEY IN
YOUR BANK, AND YOU STILL HAVE
ONE LIFELINE REMAINING.
ARE YOU READY?
>> I'M READY.
Meredith: AUDIENCE, ARE YOU
READY?
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
THEN LET'S PLAY "MILLIONAIRE."
[FANFARE PLAYS]
BESIDES URANUS, WHICH OF THESE
OTHER PLANETS HAS AN ELEMENT--
[LAUGHTER]
REALLY. JUST A LITTLE DECORUM,
PLEASE.
[LAUGHTER]
BESIDES URANUS, WHICH OF THESE
OTHER PLANETS HAS AN ELEMENT
NAMED AFTER IT? [CHUCKLES]
SATURN, NEPTUNE, MARS, JUPITER.
>> SO, UM, MY DAD IS--BASICALLY,
HE'S A CHEMIST, AND I ACTUALLY,
SHOCKINGLY, FAILED CHEMISTRY IN
HIGH SCHOOL.
Meredith: REALLY?
>> YEAH, WHICH--IT'S NOT THAT I
DIDN'T STUDY. I JUST THINK THAT
I DIDN'T CARE ENOUGH TO STUDY
HARD. SO THE FACT THAT I'M
GETTING A QUESTION ABOUT
ELEMENTS, IT'S MORE ABOUT THE
ELEMENTS--THAN THE PERIODIC
TABLE--THAN THE PLANETS. UM...
AND I'M TRYING TO, LIKE, ADD,
YOU KNOW, SATURNIUM OR SOMETHING
OR NEPTUNIUM, LIKE, AND NONE OF
IT SOUNDS RIGHT. UM...
I GUESS MY MOTHER WAS RIGHT WHEN
SHE TOLD ME I SHOULD HAVE
STUDIED MORE.
Meredith: HEH HEH HEH!
>> [SIGHS] IT JUST DOESN'T MAKE
SENSE FOR ME TO GUESS ON THIS
ONE BECAUSE I REALLY, I JUST--
I DON'T KNOW.
Meredith: OK. DO YOU WANT TO
JUMP IT, THEN?
>> [SIGHS]
I DON'T WANT TO, BUT I HAVE TO,
SO LET'S JUMP THE QUESTION.
Meredith: GONNA JUMP THE
QUESTION? OK, QUESTION'S OUT OF
PLAY. YOU DON'T HAVE TO ANSWER
IT. LET'S SEE THE CORRECT
ANSWER.
NEPTUNE. NEPTUNIUM, ACTUALLY.
>> AND I SAID NEPTUNIUM.
Meredith: WELL, YOU WERE RIGHT
AND DIDN'T EVEN KNOW IT. LET'S
SEE WHAT YOU JUMPED OVER.
HOPEFULLY NOT TOO MUCH. LAST
TIME IT WAS $15,000. THIS TIME
IT'S $5,000.
>> OK.
Meredith: OK.
BY JUMPING THE QUESTION, YOU'RE
NOW 10 AWAY FROM A MILLION.
YOU STILL HAVE THAT $25,000 UP
THERE, SO THERE'S STILL GOOD
MONEY TO BE HAD.
>> YES.
Meredith: "OVER EATING" IS THE
CATEGORY. A COMMON TERM IN THE
COMPETITIVE EATING WORLD, THE
CONDITION OF PROFUSELY SWEATING
DUE TO OVERCONSUMPTION IS KNOWN
AS WHAT?
MEAT SWEATS, VEGETABLE SWEATS,
BREAD SWEATS, DAIRY SWEATS.
>> UM, IT'S...IT'S "A,"
MEAT SWEATS, FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: YEAH. THAT ONE YOU
KNEW. MEAT SWEATS. OK, LET'S PUT
SOME MONEY IN YOUR BANK. HOW
MUCH IS BEHIND THIS QUESTION?
$2,000. UP TO $13,000, AND THIS
NEXT QUESTION COMING UP IS YOUR
BROADWAY QUESTION.
>> HERE WE GO.
Meredith: THEATER MAJOR. IN A
SMASH BROADWAY HIT THAT OPENED
IN 2001, MATTHEW BRODERICK
PERFORMED THE SONG "I WANNA BE
A" WHAT?
SPAMALOT, MAMMA MIA!
MAN OF LA MANCHA, PRODUCER.
>> HE WANTS TO BE A PRODUCER AND
HAVE HISAR IN LIGHTS.
FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: FINAL?
>> FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: IT IS PRODUCER.
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT. ALL RIGHT,
FIRST LET'S SEE HOW MUCH MONEY
IS BEHIND THIS QUESTION.
$100. OK. $13,100, BUT BY
ANSWERING THAT QUESTION
CORRECTLY, YOU ARE GONNA GO TO
"MARY POPPINS" TONIGHT, ALONG
WITH ONE ROW IN THIS AUDIENCE.
PICK A NUMBER BETWEEN ONE
AND 23.
>> UM...
[DRUM ROLL]
I WILL GO WITH, UH, 5.
Meredith: 5.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
ALL RIGHT. WAY UP AT THE TOP.
ALL OF YOU HAVE TICKETS TO "MARY
POPPINS" TONIGHT, SO CANCEL ANY
OTHER PLANS YOU MIGHT HAVE MADE.
VERY NICE. AND YOU'RE NOW 8 AWAY
FROM THE MILLION, 4 AWAY FROM
ROUND TWO, AT WHICH POINT YOU
GET TO KEEP ALL THE MONEY IN
YOUR BANK, OK? LIFELINES ARE
GONE. "POETIC PAYBACK"--
CATEGORY.
IN AN ACT OF POETIC REVENGE,
WHAT ITALIAN POLITICIAN WROTE AN
EPIC WORK IN WHICH HIS ENEMIES
WERE CONVENIENTLY PLACED
IN HELL?
DANTE ALIGHIERI,
LORENZO de MEDICI,
FRANCIS OF ASSISI,
CARLO COLLODI.
>> UH, WELL, I KNOW THAT IT IS
"DANTE'S INFERNO," WHICH IS--
THERE ARE THE 7 CIRCLES OF HELL,
OR I THINK THERE ACTUALLY MIGHT
BE 9 CIRCLES OF HELL IN IT.
UM, YEAH, "A," DANTE. FINAL
ANSWER.
Meredith: YEAH, "A," DANTE IS
RIGHT, ABSOLUTELY. "THE DIVINE
COMEDY." ALL RIGHT, KATHRYN.
YOU HAVE $13,100 IN YOUR BANK.
TO THAT, WE'RE GONNA ADD HOW
MUCH MORE MONEY? LET'S PUT IN
ANOTHER...$500. OK. $13,600,
3 QUESTIONS LEFT IN ROUND TWO.
$25,000 IS STILL UP THERE.
CATEGORY--"GREAT NAMES."
WHICH OF THE FOLLOWING IS THE
NAME OF KATE MIDDLETON'S SISTER
AND NOT A PRODUCT SOLD AT IKEA?
[L
>> AHEM.
Meredith: KLIPPEN, PIPPA,
VRETA, KULLA.
>> KATE MIDDLETON'S SISTER,
WHICH WE ALL FAIRLY PROBABLY
KNOW MORE THAN WE WANT TO KNOW
ABOUT NOW, HER NAME IS PIPPA, SO
KATE MIDDLETON'S SISTER'S NAME
IS PIPPA, NOT A PRODUCT AT IKEA.
"B," FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: PIPPA IS RIGHT.
ALL RIGHTY, COMPUTER, PLEASE
SHOW US THE MONEY. LET'S HOPE
FOR THE $25,000.
$7,000. UP TO $20,600. GONNA
TAKE A BREAK. WE'LL BE BACK WITH
MORE "MILLIONAIRE" RIGHT AFTER
THIS.
Don't judge me!
Whatever it takes, get to
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
Meredith: WELCOME BACK TO
"BROADWAY GIVEAWAY WEEK."
KATHRYN SHRADER, WORKING HER WAY
THROUGH ROUND ONE. TWO QUESTIONS
LEFT. ONE OF THEM IS WORTH
$25,000. AS I SAID TO YOU IN THE
BREAK, WE'RE MAKING YOU WORK FOR
THAT MONEY, BABY.
>> SERIOUSLY WORK.
Meredith: THE LIFELINES ARE GONE
AT THIS POINT, BUT YOU DO HAVE
$20,600 IN YOUR BANK, AND LIKE I
SAID, JUST TWO AWAY FROM ROUND
TWO. AT THAT POINT, YOU GET TO
KEEP ALL OF THAT MONEY, AND YOU
GOT A LOT OF SUPPORT HERE AMONG
EVERYBODY IN THE AUDIENCE, AND
MOST OF ALL, YOUR BUDDIES BACK
THERE, WHO ARE ROOTING YOU ON.
SO WHAT DO YOU SAY? YOU READY TO
KEEP PLAYING?
>> I'M READY.
Meredith: THEN LET'S PLAY.
[FANFARE PLAYS]
WHAT SPORT WAS DAVID LETTERMAN
TALKING ABOUT WHEN HE SAID THAT
HE MISSED "THE PINE TAR, THE
RESIN, THE GRASS, THE DIRT--AND
THAT'S JUST IN THE HOT DOGS"?
BASEBALL, FOOTBALL,
BASKETBALL, SOCCER.
>> UM, WELL, HOT DOGS IS
ASSOCIATED WITH BASEBALL, UH,
SO I'M NOT A SPORTS PERSON, BUT
"A," BASEBALL, FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: ABSOLUTELY, IT IS
BASEBALL. OK, THIS IS WORTH
EITHER $3,000 OR $25,000.
>> I'M HOPING.
Meredith: LET'S SEE.
$3,000. OK.
>> MAN.
>> $23,600. THIS IS YOUR LAST
QUESTION IN ROUND ONE. YOU GET
THIS RIGHT, YOU'RE GONNA GET
$25,000 MORE PUT IN YOUR BANK.
THAT BANK WILL BE YOURS, AND
WE'LL SEE THE QUESTION FOR
$100,000. GOOD LUCK.
>> THANK YOU.
Meredith: "FAMOUS SITTERS."
WHAT FUTURE MUSIC STAR WAS PAULA
ABDUL'S BABYSITTER WHEN SHE WAS
7 YEARS OLD?
KENNY LOGGINS, GENE SIMMONS,
MICHAEL BOLTON, PRINCE.
>> I DON'T KNOW WHY GENE SIMMONS
IS STICKING OUT TO ME.
FOR SOME REASON, IT IS. I KNOW
THAT'S NOT HIS REAL NAME. UM...
OOH. SO IT'S $11,000.
Meredith: IF YOU WALK, YOU'LL
WALK WITH $11,800. YOU GET THIS
RIGHT, YOU'LL ADD ANOTHER
$25,000 TO YOUR BANK, WHICH
WOULD PUT YOU UP AT $48,600,
WHICH WOULD BE YOUR MONEY AND
YOU'D SEE THE QUESTION FOR
$100,000. BUT IF YOU GUESS THIS
AND YOU'RE WRONG, YOU LOSE
YOUR BANK.
>> RIGHT.
[SIGHS]
OK, I'M GONNA...
I'M GONNA...WALK AWAY.
[APPLAUSE]
FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: FINAL ANSWER?
>> YEAH. FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: YOU KNOW WHAT? IT'S A
GOOD THING YOU'RE WALKING AWAY
BECAUSE THE CORRECT ANSWER WAS
MICHAEL BOLTON.
>> REALLY?
Meredith: YEAH. SHE SAID HE
WASN'T EVEN THAT GOOD A SITTER.
HE ENDED UP BEING A VERY GOOD
SINGER, HOWEVER, BUT YOU'RE
WALKING AWAY WITH $11,800.
THANK YOU, AND YOU DID A GREAT
JOB. THANK YOU, SWEETIE.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
AND JOINING ME NOW IS ALEX
GRANOVSKY FROM NEW YORK CITY.
HEY, ALEX. NICE TO MEET YOU,
SWEETIE. ALEX IS AN ATTORNEY
THAT STARTED HIS OWN LAW FIRM
ONE YEAR AGO TODAY.
>> THAT IS RIGHT.
Meredith: HOW IS IT GOING?
>> SO FAR SO GOOD. IT'S
EXCITING, IT'S SCARY, BUT IT'S
GOING WELL.
Meredith: AND IT INDICATES THAT
YOU ARE A RISK-TAKER OF SORTS,
SO YOU'RE PROBABLY A GOOD
CANDIDATE FOR THIS SHOW, A GOOD
CONTESTANT.
>> I HOPE SO. I'M GONNA DO
MY BEST.
Meredith: WELL, WE'LL FIND OUT.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT THE MONEY
IN YOUR ROUND ONE. OK,
COMPUTER, PLEASE RANDOMIZE THE
MONEY AND LET'S RANDOMIZE THE
QUESTIONS AS WELL, SEE WHERE
YOUR BROADWAY QUESTION IS--WAY
UP, ALMOST AT THE TOP THERE, SO
WE'VE GOT SOME WORK TO DO.
YOU READY TO PLAY?
>> I AM READY.
Meredith: LET'S PLAY
"MILLIONAIRE."
[FANFARE PLAYS]
IN 2011, QUENTIN TARANTINO SUED
HIS NEIGHBOR, SCREENWRITER
ALAN BALL, OVER THE "OBNOXIOUS
PTERODACTYL-LIKE SCREAMS" OF
WHAT PETS?
MACAWS, PIT BULLS,
HAMSTERS, FERRETS.
>> OK. ONE WOULD THINK IT'S
EASY.
I'M GONNA GO WITH MY FIRST
INSTINCT, WHICH IS "A"...
MACAWS, FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: FIRST INSTINCT WAS
RIGHT. IT IS MACAWS. LET'S START
BUILDING YOUR BANK. HOW MUCH
MONEY IS BEHIND THIS QUESTION?
WE'RE GONNA START OUT WITH
$5,000. OK.
>> ALL RIGHT.
Meredith: 13 AWAY FROM A
MILLION.
"CRAFTY NASA" IS THE CATEGORY.
NASA SUGGESTS KIDS COVER AN
INFLATED BALLOON WITH PAPER AND
GLUE, LET IT DRY, AND THEN CUT
HOLES IN IT TO MAKE A PAPER
MACHE WHAT?
ROCKET SHIP, FLIGHT JACKET,
SPACE HELMET, MOON BOOT.
>> OK. IT'S A BALLOON, SO IT'S
ROUND. THINKING OUT LOUD.
Meredith: YEP.
>> MY GUT SAYS SPACE HELMET.
IT'S THE ONLY THING THAT SEEMS
TO MAKE SENSE.
INFLATED BALLOON. OK. YOU KNOW,
IT'S A LOT EASIER TO GUESS WHEN
YOU'RE WATCHING THIS.
Meredith: HA HA!
>> BUT I'M GONNA GO WITH "C,"
SPACE HELMET, FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: YES, SIR. IT IS SPACE
HELMET.
PUT SOME MORE MONEY IN YOUR
BANK. HOW MUCH IS BEHIND THIS
QUESTION? WE'RE TALKIN'...
$15,000. UP TO $20,000 TWO
QUESTIONS IN, ALEX. GONNA GIVE
YOU A MINUTE TO BREATHE. WE'LL
BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
"MILLIONAIRE" RIGHT AFTER THIS.
Meredith: WELCOME BACK TO
"BROADWAY GIVEAWAY WEEK."
TODAY WE'RE GIVING AWAY TICKETS
TO "MARY POPPINS." ALEXSKY FROMI
GRANOVSKY FROM NEW YORK CITY,
A FEW QUESTIONS TO GO BEFORE YOU
REACH THAT BROADWAY QUESTION,
BUT SO FAR DOING A GREAT JOB--
$20,000 IN YOUR BANK, 12 AWAY
FROM A MILLION. JUST TWO
QUESTIONS IN AND YOU STILL HAVE
ALL YOUR LIFELINES. READY TO
KEEP PLAYING?
>> I AM READY.
Meredith: THEN LET'S PLAY.
[FANFARE PLAYS]
WHAT BELOVED "SO YOU THINK YOU
CAN DANCE" JUDGE REFERS TO THEIR
FAVORITE CONTESTANTS AS HAVING
TICKETS TO "THE HOT TAMALE
TRAIN"?
NIGEL LYTHGOE, MIA MICHAELS,
MARY MURPHY, ADAM SHANKMAN.
>> OK. I'M NOT A DANCER.
Meredith: NO? YOU LOOK LIKE YOU
COULD BE A DANCER.
>> I DO, I DO. I KNOW THAT.
THANK YOU. HA HA! I AM NOT A
WATCHER OF DANCE PROGRAMS.
IN FACT, AT FIRST, I WAS
THINKING "DANCING WITH THE
STARS," BUT I THINK THIS
AUDIENCE, LOVELY AUDIENCE WHO
I'M TOTALLY PANDERING TO, MIGHT
KNOW THIS AND I WOULD LIKE TO
PLEASE ASK THE AUDIENCE.
Meredith: ALL RIGHT. AUDIENCE,
ALEX NEEDS YOUR HELP.
ON YOUR KEYPADS, VOTE NOW.
OK, 45% BELIEVE IT IS MARY
MURPHY, 32% FOR NIGEL LYTHGOE
AND DOWNHILL FROM THERE.
>> THAT'S TOUGH.
Meredith: YEAH.
>> OK. NIGEL--NOW I GOT TO THINK
A LITTLE BIT. SO I GUESS IT'S
BETWEEN NIGEL LYTHGOE AND MARY
MURPHY. NIGEL LYTHGOE, I KNOW,
IS THE PRODUCER OF THE SHOW.
I THINK HE'S, IN ANY CASE, THE
SORT OF RUDE BRITISH MAN ON IT.
"HOT TAMALE TRAIN." DO I GAMBLE?
WELL, WE CAME TO PLAY. I CAN'T
BELIEVE I'M DOING THIS.
"C," MARY MURPHY, FINAL ANSWER.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
Meredith: IT'S MARY MURPHY.
YOU GOT IT RIGHT.
THE AUDIENCE CAME THROUGH FOR
YOU, FOR SURE, ON THAT ONE.
LET'S SEE HOW MUCH MONEY IS
BEHIND THIS QUESTION. COMPUTER,
SHOW US THE MONEY. WE'RE TALKING
$1,000. OK, $21,000, 7 AWAY FROM
ROUND TWO. AT THAT POINT, YOU
GET TO KEEP ALL THE MONEY IN
YOUR BANK.
>> RIGHT.
Meredith: EMPLOYED BY THE
FEDERAL RESERVE IN 2011,
"OPERATION TWIST" WAS A PROGRAM
MEANT TO LOWER WHAT?
INTEREST RATES, OIL CONSUMPTION,
VOTING AGE, HEALTHCARE COSTS.
>> VOTING AGE, OIL CONSUMPTION.
[SIGHS]
I'M GONNA HAVE TO JUMP THE
QUESTION.
Meredith: NO PROBLEM.
>> I HAVE A HUNCH...
BUT I'M GONNA JUMP IT.
Meredith: OK, QUESTION'S OUT OF
PLAY, BUT WHAT IS YOUR HUNCH?
>> "A," INTEREST RATES.
Meredith: INTEREST RATES? LET'S
SEE THE CORRECT ANSWER. IT WAS
INTEREST RATES. OK.
[SCATTERED APPLAUSE]
NOW, THERE IS SOME BIG MONEY ON
THAT BOARD, INCLUDING THE
$25,000. THERE'S ALSO A LOT OF
LOWER NUMBERS, LIKE A HUNDRED,
SO LET'S SEE HOW MUCH IS
BEHIND...
$10,000.
>> SERVES ME RIGHT.
Meredith: DOESN'T SERVE YOU
RIGHT. BY JUMPING THAT QUESTION,
YOU'RE NOW ONE QUESTION CLOSER
TO THE MILLION. WE'RE GONNA TAKE
A LOOK AT YOUR NEXT QUESTION
RIGHT AFTER THIS BREAK. WE'LL BE
RIGHT BACK WITH MORE OF
"MILLIONAIRE."
THANK YOU, CURÉL.
CURÉL ULTRA HEALING LOTION
INSTANTLY RELIEVES AND
PREVENTS DRY SKIN.
YOUR SEARCH FOR DRY
SKIN RELIEF IS OVER.
Meredith: HERE'S YOUR
"MILLIONAIRE" QUESTION OF THE
DAY. IN A 2006
INTERVIEW WITH A GERMAN
REPORTER, GEORGE W. BUSH SAID
THAT HIS BEST MOMENT AS
PRESIDENT OCCURRED WHILE DOING
WHAT? STAY TUNED FOR THE ANSWER,
WHEN WE COME BACK.Meredith: WELA
Meredith: WELCOME BACK. THE
ANSWER TO THE "MILLIONAIRE"
QUESTION OF THE DAY IS
FISHING.
WE ARE BACK WITH ALEX GRANOVSKY
FROM NEW YORK CITY, AN ATTORNEY,
JUST STARTED HIS OWN LAW FIRM
ABOUT A YEAR AGO. $21,000 IN
YOUR BANK, ALEX, AT THIS POINT,
10 AWAY FROM THE MILLION. YOU
STILL HAVE ONE LIFELINE LEFT,
AND BEFORE I START YOU PLAYING
AGAIN, I WANTED TO GIVE A BIG
HELLO TO YOUR FIANCEE, NEETI,
WHO'S THERE IN THE AUDIENCE,
ROOTING YOU ON. A LOT OF FIRSTS
IN YOUR LIFE: MARRIAGE AND THE
LAW FIRM AND THE WHOLE THING.
AND, HOPEFULLY, FIRST TIME
WINNING A MILLION DOLLARS ON
A GAME SHOW.
>> I'M VERY LUCKY.
Meredith: YES, YOU ARE. YOU
READY TO KEEP PLAYING?
>> I AM READY.
Meredith: LET'S PLAY.
[FANFARE PLAYS]
WHAT POET'S 1816 LETTER IS
CONSIDERED THE FIRST DOCUMENTED
USE OF THE WORD "MILLIONAIRE" IN
ENGLISH?
SIR WALTER RALEIGH,
LORD TENNYSON,
MARQUIS de SADE, LORD BYRON.
>> IT'S GOOD TO KNOW WHAT YOU
DON'T KNOW.
Meredith: HA HA HA!
>> I DON'T KNOW THIS.
I CAN'T EVEN BEGIN TO GUESS.
I'M GOING TO...
I'M GONNA JUMP THE QUESTION.
>> OK. QUESTION IS OUT OF PLAY.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO ANSWER IT.
LET'S SEE WHAT THE ANSWER IS.
LORD BYRON WAS THE CORRECT
ANSWER. THE LAST TIME YOU
JUMPED, YOU JUMPED OVER $10,000.
THIS TIME, LET'S SEE HOW MUCH IS
BEHIND THE QUESTION.
$3,000. THAT'S A LOT LESS
PAINFUL THAN $10,000, FOR SURE.
BY JUMPING THE QUESTION, NOW
JUST 9 AWAY FROM A MILLION.
YOU STILL HAVE THE BIG MONEY ON
THE BOARD. THAT $25,000 IS
STILL THERE.
>> [SIGHS]
Meredith: DESIGNED FOR SELF-
PRESERVATION, VARIOUS TREES HAVE
LEAVES THAT FEATURE "DRIP TIPS,"
THAT HELP PROTECT THE TREES
FROM WHAT?
EARTHQUAKES, TORNADOES,
WILDFIRES, RAINSTORMS.
DRIP TIPS.
>> ONE WOULD THINK IT'S EASY.
I THINK IT'S THIS--SHOULD BE
OBVIOUS. I'M NOT GONNA OVER-
THINK IT. I'M JUST GONNA OVER-
READ IT.
Meredith: HA HA HA!
>> "D," RAINSTORMS, FINAL
ANSWER.
Meredith: YES, IT IS RAINSTORMS.
OK, ALEX, YOU PUT SOME MORE
MONEY IN YOUR BANK. HOW MUCH IS
BEHIND THIS QUESTION?
$100. OK. $21,100. 4 QUESTIONS
AWAY FROM ROUND TWO. AT THAT
POINT, YOU KEEP ALL YOUR MONEY
IN THE BANK.
NOT TO BE CONFUSED WITH A FRUIT,
WHICH OF THESE WORDS COULD BE
USED TO DESCRIBE A COMPLETE
SENSE OF CONFIDENCE?
CHARY, APLOMB, DAPPLE, IMPEACH.
COMPLETE SENSE OF CONFIDENCE.
>> I FEEL FAIRLY CONFIDENT THAT
I'M GONNA SAY "B," APLOMB,
FINAL ANSWER.
Meredith: YOU SHOULD FEEL VERY
CONFIDENT. IT IS APLOMB.
ALL RIGHT, ALEX. LET'S PUT MORE
MONEY IN THE BANK. HOW MUCH IS
BEHIND THIS QUESTION?
THERE YOU GO!
>> THAT'S IT!
Meredith: $46,100. HA HA HA!
[HORN SOUNDS]
AH! THAT IS A PERFECT TIME TO
HEAR THAT BUZZER. THAT HORN
MEANS THAT OUR TIME IS UP FOR
TODAY, BUT YOU'VE GOT $46,100 IN
YOUR BANK. GONNA PLAY FOR A
MILLION WHEN WE COME BACK
TOMORROW. UNTIL THEN, FOLKS,
FROM NEW YORK, EVERYBODY,
BYE-BYE.
I have high blood pressure.
And when I get a cold I take
Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
Announcer: CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED BY...
[ Female Announcer ] A CLASSIC
MEATLOAF RECIPE FROM STOUFFER'S
STARTS WITH GROUND BEEF,
UNIONS, AND PEPPERS
BAKED IN A KETCHUP GLAZE
WITH SAVORY GRAVY
AND MASHED RUSSET POTATOES.
WHAT MAKES STOUFFER'S MEATLOAF
BEST OF ALL?
THAT MOMENT YOU ENJOY IT
AT HOME.
STOUFFER'S. LET'S FIX DINNER.
[CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
DISNEY-ABC DOMESTIC TELEVISION]
[CAPTIONED BY THE NATIONAL
CAPTIONING INSTITUTE]
Captioned y
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
THIS IS "JEOPARDY!"
INTRODUCING
TODAY'S CONTESTANTS--
AN INVESTMENT CONSULTANT
FROM MONROVIA, CALIFORNIA...
A NURSING TUTOR
FROM BROOKLYN, NEW YORK...
AND OUR RETURNING CHAMPION--
A TUTOR FROM
HIGHLAND PARK, NEW JERSEY...
WHOSE 2-DAY CASH WINNINGS
TOTAL...
AND NOW HERE IS
THE HOST OF "JEOPARDY!"--
ALEX TREBEK!
THANK YOU, JOHNNY.
HELLO, EVERYONE AND WELCOME.
AT THE END OF LAK,
AN EASY VICTORY FOR JASON.
YESTERDAY, A CLOSE CALL.
WHAT WILL TODAY BRING AS HE
DEFENDS FOR THE SECOND TIME?