>>> IT'S ALMOST CHRISTMAS AND
THERE IS STILL SO MUCH TO DO.
GOOD THING WE HAVE OUR SAMSUNG
GALAXY NOTE 2s.
>> I DON'T KNOW HOW TO BUILD THE
BABY.
>> HERE I SHOW YOU.
I SHARE WITH YOU USING S-BEAM.
>> OKAY.
NOW I GET IT.
CHRISTMAS IS SAVED!
>> NOT YET.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE I'M GOING.
I HAVE TO PLAN MY ROUTE.
THE BIG SCREEN MAKE IT SO MUCH
EASIER.
>> YOU GO TO FREEWAY, 101 FROM
SANITY YEAH GO TO MEXICO.
>> I'M GOING OUT FOR A TEST RUN,
OKAY?
>> OKAY.
>> GOOD LUCK.
>> [ SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAG  ]
LANGUAGE ].
>> TIME TO MAKE A NOTE WITH THE
SAMSUNG S-10.
GET BIGGER REINDEER.
NOW CHRISTMAS IS SAVED THANKS TO
THE SAMSUNG GALAXY NOTE 2.
>> THE SAMSUNG GALAXY NOTE II.
PHONE, TABLET, BEST OF BOTH.
THE NEXT BIG THING IS HERE.
>> "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE" LIBACK I
TWO MINUTES WITH HUGH JACKMAN,
JENNA FISCHER AND MUSIC FROM 2
CHAINZ.
This season, give Craftsman
tools and give the gifts that
keep on giving.
CRAFTSMAN. GUYS'
FAVORITES GUARANTEED.
FIND IT AT SEARS.
THAT'S THE GUY WHO GETS
HIS SALSA FROM NEW YORK CITY.
NEW YORK CITY?
[ alarm chirps ]
[ Male Announcer ]
'ROUND HERE, THERE'S ONLY
ONE WORD FOR SALSA: PACE.
MADE THE RIGHT WAY
FOR THAT BIG BOLD KICK.
GRAB THE SOUTHWEST
BY THE BOTTLE.
KEEPING UP WITH THE KIDS
IS TOUGH, SO I DRINK EMERGEN-C.
WITH VITAMIN C
FOR IMMUNE SUPPORT
AND B VITAMINS
FOR NATURAL ENERGY,
I'M READY
FOR WHATEVER THEY GET INTO.
GET YOUR FREE SAMPLE
AT MYEMERGENC.COM.
STAY HEALTHY AND FEEL THE GOOD.
>> Announcer: FROM HOLLYWOOD,
IT'S "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE"!
TONIGHT HUGH JACKMAN.
JENNA FISCHER.
AND MUSIC FROM 2 CHAINZ.
WITH CLETO AND THE CLETONES.
AND NOW, HERE'S JIMMY KIMMEL!
>> Cleto: JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> I'M JIMMY.
MIAMI THE HOST OF THE SHOW.
THANKS TO ALL OF YOU COMING OUT
TONIGHT.
I APPRECIATE THAT.
I'M GLAD THAT YOU CAME OUT.
I HOPE WE CAN LAUGH A BIT
TONIGHT AFTER A HORRIBLE
WEEKEND.
AND -- I HAVE TROUBLE
CONTROLLING MY EMOTIONS BUT IT'S
WEIRD TO DO A SHOW WITH SO MUCH
SADNESS.
I THINK THE PRESIDENT SAID WHAT
NEEDED TO BE SAID LAST NIGHT ON
TELEVISION.
I THINK HE SPOKE BEAUTIFULLY.
I JUST WANT THE PEOPLE IN
CONNECTICUT TO KNOW THAT WE DO
NOT TAKE WHAT YOU'RE GOING
THROUGH LIGHTLY AND WE ARE
THINKING ABOUT YOU A LOT ALL OF
US EVEN THOUGH WE ARE AT A TALK
SHOW.
SO MY JOB TONIGHT IS TO GIVE YOU
A LITTLE BREAK FROM BEING SAD.
AND I WILL TRY MY BEST TO DO
THAT, ALL RIGHT?
SO -- YOU WANT TO SEE SOME
CHRISTMAS LIGHTS SHAPED LIKE A
PENIS?
WE HAVE VIDEO HERE.
THIS IS A CRIST MAT LIGHT
DISPLAY IN BRIGHTON ENGLAND.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THIS HAPPENED
OR IF IT WAS ACCIDENTAL OR
INTENTIONAL.
BUT IT WOULD APPEAR THAT IF YOU
STAND DIRECTLY UNDER THE LIGHTS
A VERY FAMILIAR SHAPE APPEARS.
I KNOW YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO KISS
UNDER MISTLETOE WHAT DO YOU DOE
UNDER THAT?
I HAVE A SERIOUS QUESTION, HOW
DO YOU TIP YOUR GARBAGE MA
SOMEONE I HAVE THREE TRUCKS, ONE
FOR TRASH, ONE FOR RECYCLE AND
ONE FOR YARD CLIPPINGS.
AM I SUPPOSED TO WAIT OUTSIDE MY
HOUSE AT 5:30 EVEN MORNING.
I THOUGHT ABOUT TAPING AN
ENVELOPE TO THE CONTAINER BUT
WHAT IF THEY DON'T SEE IT.
I WAS THE VICTIM OF A THEFT THIS
WEEKEND.
ON SATURDAY NIGHT BETWEEN THE
HOURS OF 2:00 AND 3:00 A.M.
SOMEONE STOLE THE COVER OFF MY
DAUGHTER'S PRIUS.
MY DAUGHTER IS AWAY AT COLLEGE.
AND SATURDAY NIGHT I GOT HOME,
SUNDAY MORNING, GONE.
NOW, I HAVE SECURITY CAMERAS AT
MY HOUSE.
I WENT THROUGH THE TAPE.
THIS IS THE CAR THAT DID IT.
A GMC YUKON DEAL Y. THE CAR
DIDN'T DO IT.
THE PEOPLE IN THE CAR.
I HAVE VIDEO OF IT COMING AND
SHOTS OF IT GOING.
I CAN'T MAKE OUT THE LICENSE
PLATE AT ALL.
I NEED ONE OF THOSE GUYS FROM
EVERY FBI SHOW, WHERE IS THAT
TECHNOLOGY IN THE REAL WORLD?
ON TV THEY ZOOMED IN.
THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS WHEN WE
ZOOM IN TO TRY TO GET IT.
NOTHING.
I'M DETERMINED TO CATCH THESE
GUYS.
I'M CHECKING ON CRAIGSLIST.
WHO STEALS THE COVER OFF A CAR?
LIKE STEALING THE CAP OFF THE
PEN.
AT LEAST STEAL THE CAR.
IF YOU ARE WATCHING RIGHT NOW I
WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT MY NAME IS
JIMMY KIMMEL AND YOU STOLE THE
COVER OFF MY DAUGHTER'S PRIUS
AND I WILL NOT REST UNTIL YOU
ARE BROUGHT TO JUSTICE.
I WILL REST.
BUT -- I NEVER FELT MORE LIKE
LIAM NEESON THAN I DID A MOMENT
AGO.
MAKE THEY DON'T REALIZE I WORK
FOR ABC.
CASTLE WILL TRACK YOU DOWN AND
LOOK GREAT DOING IT, YOU JERKS.
>>> CHRISTMAS IS A WEEK AWAY.
TO GET YOU IN THE CHRISTMAS
SPIRIT WE BOOKED A RAPPER BY THE
NAME OF 2 CHAINZ WHO REMINDS ME
OF A YOUNG BING CROSBY.
ALSO JENNA FISCHER AND HUGH
JACKMAN ARE HERE.
AFTER EIGHT NIGHTS, HANUKKAH
ENDED.
I FEEL LIKE IT WENT ON LONGER
THAN THE HOBBIT THIS YEAR.
ONE OF OUR WRITERS WENT TO HIS
KID'S HEBREW SCHOOL.
HE WENT TO THE LUNCHEON AND THE
KIDS SANG HANUKKAH SONGS FOR THE
PARENTS AND HE SWEARS THESE ARE
THE LYRICS.
TAKE A POTATO, PAT, PAT, PAT,
SHAPE IT AND MAKE IT FLAT, FLAT,
FLAT.
NOT EXACTLY HAVE YOURSELF A
MERRY LITTLE CHRISTMAS.
HOW EXCITED CAN KIDS GET ABOUT
MAKING A POTATO FLAT, FLAT,
FLAT?
EVERYONE GETS BAD GIFTS AROUND
THE HOLIDAYS.
BUT THE WORST PART IS NOT THE
GIFT BUT PRETENDING YOU LIKE THE
GIFT.
YOU GIVE THEM YOUR BEST IT'S
PERFECT AND I LOVE IT THING.
BUT THAT IS THE MOST IMPORTANT
CHRISTMAS KILL TO HAVE.
TODAY WE ASKED PEDESTRIANS TO
SHOW US THEIR FALSE ENTHUSIASM
AND SHOW US HOW THEY REACT WHEN
THEY GET A LAWSY GIFT.
THIS IS A CITY FULL OF ACTORS.
THEY SHOULD BE GOOD AT THIS.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU KNOW ME SO WELL.
THIS IS BEAUTIFUL.
I LOVE IT.
>> OH, MY GOD.
GREAT, THANKS, PERFECT.
>> OH, WOW.
THANKS.
>> OH, THAT'S SO NICE.
>> IT'S SO NICE.
SO WONDERFUL.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> OH, WOW.
I ABSOLUTELY LOVE IT.
WHERE DID YOU FIND IT?
>> WOW!
NO!
I LIKE IT.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU KNOW, I APPRECIATE THAT.
>> OH, MY GOD THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I WANTED.
HOW DID YOU KNOW?
>> WOW, HONEY THIS IS GREAT.
>> I DON'T LIKE TEDDY BEARS.
THANK YOU, THOUGH.
>> THANKS, THIS IS AWESOME.
HURRAY.
>> WHOA.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> OH, THANK YOU.
>> I ALWAYS WANTED THIS AND I'LL
KEEP IT AND LOOK AFTER IT FOR
ALWAYS.
>> YOU'RE A LIAR.
>> I AM A LIAR.
>> WOW.
IT'S SO PERFECT.
>> I LOVE IT.
AND I WILL DEFINITELY USE IN THE
FUTURE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THAT.
>> OH, MY GOD.
I LOVE THIS GIFT.
>> OH, WOW.
THAT'S SO NICE.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S REALLY COOL.
I LOVE IT.
DEFINITELY I'M GOING TO WEAR
THIS CHRISTMAS IN MY DINNER.
>> GOING TO WEAR THIS CHRISTMAS
IN MY DINNER.
A LOT OF PEOPLE WON'T WEAR THEIR
CHRISTMAS IN THEIR DINNER.
>>> "THE HOBBITS HAD THE BIGGEST
OPENING WEEKEND EVER FOR A MOVIE
IN DECEMBER.
IT'S A THREE HOUR MOVIE ABOUT
DWARVES EATING BREAKFAST.
IT'S 169 MINUTES LONG.
THE LONGEST MOVIE EVER MADE
ABOUT SHORT PEOPLE.
>>> THERE IS A BIG POWER BALL
DRAWING LAST WEEK FOR $59
MILLION AND IT WAS PURCHASED BY
A COUPLE IN NEW JERSEY.
>> THEY HAVE 50 MILLION REASONS
TO SMILE.
SHE WANTS TO SHARE HER FORTUNE
WITH HER KIDS AND GRANDCHILDREN.
>> AND HE SAYS HE WOULD LIKE TO
GET A NEW SET OF TEETH.
>> THAT IS QUITE A NEW SET OF
TEETH.
>> Jimmy: ABC TELEVISION NETWORK
HAS A DEAL WITH JUSTIN BIEBER TO
DEVELOP A SITCOM BASED ON HIS
LIFE.
HOW IS IT ALL CONDUCIVE TO
SITUATION COMEDIES?
I CAN'T BELIEVE I CRASHED MY
FERRARI AGAIN.
MOM'S GOING TO KILL ME.
JUSTIN WILL NOT BE THE STAR BUT
IT WILL BE BASED ON HIS
UNCONVENTIONAL UPBRINGING HIS
PREVIOUS TELEVISION EXPERIENCE
INCLUDES A HOSTING GIG AND HE
PLAYED A MOP ON A PINE SOL
COMMERCIAL.
>>> LAST NIGHT, THE WETTING OF
ASHLEY AND HER FIANCE J.P., NO
ONE TOLD THEM BATHEY WERE SUPPOD
TO BREAK UP.
THEY GOT MARRIED INSTEAD.
THE BEST PART WAS NOT THE
WEDDING BUT THE PROMO FOR THE
NEW SEASON OF THE BACHELOR.
THIS TIME AROUND IT'S SHAWN
LOWE.
AND BASED ON THIS PROMO IT LOOKS
LIKE THIS WILL BE THE MOST
DRAMATIC SEASON YET.
>> I'M NOT GOING TO LET ANY GIRL
STOP ME FROM BEING WITH SHAWN.
>> OH, MY GOD.
>> I CAN'T BELIEVE THEY DID THIS
TO ME.
>> I HOPE THE GIRLS GOT WHAT
THEY WANTED.
>> THIS IS REALLY CRAZY.
>> I'M JUST STUNNED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> IT BLIND SIDED ME SO BADLY.
>> WHAT A LUCKY BREAK.
DID THEY HAPPEN TO HAVE A CAMERA
SITTING ON THE FLOOR SLOW
THROWING IT RIGHT AT THE STOP
WHERE THAT ROSE FELL.
WHAT ARE THE ODDS?
IT'S ALMOST AS IF THEY KNEW IT
WAS GOING TO HAPPEN.
AND ONE MORE THING.
WE SPEND A LOT OF TIME COMBING
THE TELEVISION AND THE INTERNET
TO FIND THE BEST CLIPS.
WE CHOOSE THE BEST OF THE BEST
AT THE END OF THE YEAR AND NOW
IT'S TIME TO PRESENT THE AWARD
FOR 2012 CLIP OF THE YEAR.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THE NOMINEES FOR CLIP OF THE
YEAR ARE DIABOLICAL CAT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: BIG-ASS SHARK.
>> GOT NO LINE.
>> OH.
[ BLEEP ] OH!
[ BLEEP ].
>> IT'S ALL MINE.
IT'S ALL MINE.
GET IT!
[ BLEEP ].
>> IT'S A SHARK!
A SHARK!
IT'S A BIG-ASS SHARK!
>> Jimmy: SWEET BROWN.
>> GO GIVE ME A COLD POP.
THEN I THOUGHT SOMEBODY WAS
BARBECUING AND I SAID LORD JESUS
IT'S A FIRE.
I RAN OUT AND DIDN'T GRAB NO
SHOES OR NOTHING, JESUS AND I
RAN FOR MY LIFE AND THEN THE
SMOKE GOT ME.
I GOT BRONCHITIS.
I DON'T GOT TIME FOR THAT.
>> Jimmy: THAT WAS NOT A
COUNTDOWN.
>> THERE WE GO.
>> [ BLEEP ].
>> HERE WE GO.
>> CAN YOU GIVE ME A
COUNTDOWN --
>> THAT WAS NOT A COUNTDOWN WHAT
KIND OF COUNTDOWN WAS THAT?
>> Jimmy: MOM OF THE YEAR.
>> A WOMAN IS IN TROUBLE FOR
ALLEGEDLY TAKING HER
FIVE-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER INTO A
TANNING BOOTH IN A SALON.
>> I'M GOING TO BRING MY
DAUGHTER INTO A 90-DEGREE BED.
THAT'S NOT NORMAL.
>> Jimmy: AND BIRTHDAY WISHES.
>> YOU CAN'T FORGET FIRST
BIRTHDAYS.
HAPPY FIRST BIRTHDAY.
>> Jimmy: AND THE WINNER IS FOR
CLIP OF THE YEAR 2012, SWEET
BROWN!
LOOK AT THIS.
CONGRATULATIONS.
PERHAPS YOU'D LIKE TO SAY A FEW
WORDS, SWEET BROWN.
CONGRATULATIONS.
>> OH, MY GOSH!
MAN, THIS IS SO WONDERFUL.
THANK YOU Y'ALL SO MUCH.
THANK Y'ALL.
I LOVE Y'ALL SO MUCH AND JIMMY
THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME ON YOUR
SHOW.
>> HAPPY HANUKKAH TO YOU.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> SWEET BROWN THE CLIP OF THE
YEAR WINNER.
>> WE HAVE A GOOD SHOW TONIGHT.
FROM "THE OFFICE," JENNA FISCHER
IS HERE.
WE HAVE MUSIC FROM 2 CHAINZ.
AND WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH
HUGH JACKMAN.
SO STICK AROUND.
♪
[Spider-Man]
WE GOT THIS.
♪
[Mom]
THIS HERO STUFF IS EASY!
I CAN'T BREATHE,
SO I CAN'T SLEEP.
AND THE NEXT DAY I PAY FOR IT.
I TRIED DECONGESTANTS...
I TOSSED AND TURNED...
I EVEN VAPORIZED.
AND THEN I FOUGHT BACK
WITH DRUG-FREE BREATHE RIGHT.
THESE NASAL STRIPS
INSTANTLY OPEN MY NOSE,
LIKE A BREATH OF FRESH AIR.
I WAS BREATHING
AND SLEEPING BETTER.
[ Female Announcer ] EXERCISE
YOUR RIGHT TO BREATHE RIGHT.
GET TWO FREE STRIPS
AT BREATHERIGHT.COM.
HEY IT'S YOUR RIGHT
TO BREATHE RIGHT.
GET TWO FREE STRIPS
AT BREATHERIGHT.COM.
GO OLIVE GARDEN'S 2 FOR $25.
AN ITALIAN DINNER FOR 2.
START WITH ALL THE FRESH SALAD
AND WARM BREADSTICKS YOU WANT.
CHOOSE AN APPETIZER
MADE FOR SHARING.
THEN TWO DELICIOUS ENTREES
FROM FIVE OF OUR FAVORITES.
CLASSICS LIKE
EGGPLANT PARMAGIANA.
OR NEW FAVORITES LIKE
SMOKED MOZZARELLA CHICKEN.
THREE COURSES,
TWO PEOPLE, JUST $25
BUT ONLY FOR A LIMITED TIME.
GO OLIVE GARDEN.
AND TRY OUR UNLIMITED
HOMEMADE SOUP, CRISP SALAD,
AND WARM BREADSTICKS
LUNCH, JUST $6.95.
HO
HOBBIT HOB
.
>> Jimmy: HI, THERE.
TONIGHT ON THE PROGRAM
FROM "THE OFFICE" THE DELIGHTFUL
JENNA FISCHER IS HERE.
SHE'S A LOT OF FUN AND THEN WITH
MUSIC FROM THIS GRAMMY NOMINATED
ALBUM "BASED ON A TRUE STORY"
2 CHAINZ FROM THE BUD LIGHT
STAGE.
THERE ARE TWO CHAINS ON THE CD.
TOMORROW NIGHT WE'LL BE JOINED
BY SAMUEL L. JACKSON.
AND THE CAST OF JERSEY SHORE.
SO I HOPE YOU LIKE CURSING!
AND WE'LL HAVE MUSIC FROM
ED SHEERAN.
AND A QUICK PROGRAMMING NOTE
TUESDAY, JANUARY 8TH WILL BE OUR
FIRST NIGHT IN OUR NEW TIMESLOT
AT 11:35.
OUR GUESTS THAT NIGHT WILL BE
JENNIFER ANISTON AND NO DOUBT.
WHETHER HE'S BELTING OUT SHOW
TUNES ON A BROADWAY STAGE OR
RIPPING A VILLAIN APART WITH
FOOT-LONG KNUCKLE-BLADES, OUR
FIRST GUEST IS A MIGHTY SHOW
BUSINESS FORCE HIS NEWEST FILM
FOR WHICH HE EARNED A GOLDEN
GLOBE NOMINATION THE EPIC
MUSICAL "LES MISERABLES," OPENS
IN THEATERS CHRISTMAS DAY,
PLEASE SAY HELLO TO
HUGH JACKMAN.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: HOW ARE YOU?
>> GOOD.
VERY GOOD TO SEE YOU.
>> Jimmy: GOOD TO SEE YOU, AS
ALWAYS.
THIS WEEK -- IN THIS WEEK YOU
GOT A GOLDEN GLOBE NOMINATION, A
S.A.G. NOMINATION AND YOUR STAR
ON THE HOLLYWOOD WALK OF FAME
RIGHT ACROSS THE STREET FROM US.
THAT'S A DECENT WEEK.
>> GOING TO BE HARD TO GET A
GOOD CHRISTMAS PRESENT.
GOING TO BE HARD FOR MY FAMILY.
AND THEY EXPECT ME TO BUY A
LOTTERY TICKET.
>> Jimmy: YOU KNOW HOW MUCH
PEOPLE WOULD HATE YOU IF YOU WON
THE LOTTERY.
YOU WOULD GO FROM A FAVORITE TO
A LEAST FAVORITE.
ARE YOU SHOOTING THE NEW
WOLVERINE MOVIE?
>> JUST FINISHED.
>> Jimmy: WHERE DID YOU SHOOT
THAT?
>> WE SHOT IT IN SYDNEY BUT THE
WHOLE THING TAKES PLACE IN
JAPAN.
IT'S A JAPAN SAGA FROM THE COMIC
BOOKS.
AND WE SHOT MOST OF IN THE
SYDNEY AND IT'S WEIRD.
THERE ARE ONLY 100 JAPANESE
PEOPLE WHO LIVE IN THE COUNTRY
OF AUSTRALIA AND THEY PLAY 15
ROLES EACH.
IF YOU WATCH CAREFULLY THEY ARE
ALL ROTATING.
BUT WE DID SHOOT IN JAPAN.
>> Jimmy: PART OF IT?
>> A MONTH WE SHOT IN JAPAN.
THAT IS AN EXPERIENCE I WILL
NEVER FORGET.
WE HAD ABOUT TWO DAYS OFF.
I CLIMBED MOUNT FUJI WITH MY
SON, OSCAR.
HE IS ONLY 12 AND IT'S A SERIOUS
CLIMB WITH OXYGEN TANKS.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT UNTIL WE GOT
UP THIS.
THEY WERE SELLING THEM UP THERE
FOR $3,000.
>> Jimmy: DID HE MKNOW?
HOW LONG DOES IT TAKE?
>> TEN DAYS.
EACH STATION IS A COUPLE HOURS
CLIMB AND WE STAYED ON THE
EIGHTH STATION.
THAT'S CLOSE.
WE HAD BEEN GOING SIX HOURS.
AND YOU THEN SLEEP UNTIL 1:30 IN
THE MORNING AND CLIMB THE REST.
IN JAPAN THEY GIVE YOU A MEAL
AND YOU GO TO SLEEP IN THESE
SHELVES.
THERE ARE SHELVES LAID OUT AND
THEY ALL JUST PILE IN LIKE
SARDINES AND ALL THE JAPANESE
PEOPLE LIKE THIS IS NORMAL AND
IT'S FINE AN THEY CLIMB IN AND
THEY GIVE YOU A PACT OF RICE AS
A PILLOW.
>> Jimmy: WHAT?
AS A PILLOW.
>> IF YOU IMAGINE THAT'S THE
AISLE AND THAT'S THE WALL AND
THEY ARE ON THEIR iPHONES LIKE
THIS.
AND THEY LITERALLY ALL JUST
GO --
>> Jimmy: THEY'RE DINING RIGHT?
>> RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU.
THE WESTERNER.
YOU ARE ON A TATAMI MAT.
>> Jimmy: YOU'RE TOO BIG.
>> IT'S VERY UNCOMFORTABLE.
I'M WALKING UP AND DOWN THE
WHOLE TIME.
I WALK PAST.
1:30 IN THE MORNING WE GET UP
AND THEY JUST LITERALLY GO --
AND UP THEY GO.
WE CLIMB UP THE NEXT FOUR HOURS.
IT'S A LONG STORY.
>> Jimmy: GO AHEAD.
>> WE GET TO THE TOP OF THE
MOUNTAIN AND ARRIVE TEN MINUTES
BEFORE SUNRISE.
IT'S GETTING BRIGHTER AND THE
SUN IS COMING UP.
THERE IS A SEAT THERE AND WIRE
MESH FENCE THAT YOU DON'T FALL
DOWN AND EVERYONE IS SITTING
THERE.
AS THE SON CAME UP AND MY SON IS
LIKE THIS --
>> Jimmy: OSCAR DIDN'T SLEEP
WELL EITHER?
>> NO.
NO RECOLLECTION OF THE ENTIRE
THING.
>> Jimmy: HOW OLD IS HE?
>> 12.
>> Jimmy: I DON'T THINK YOU
APPRECIATE NATURAL BEAUTY AT
THAT AGE UNLESS IT'S A NAKED
WOMAN.
>> A GOOD POINT.
HE IS ONLY INTERESTED IN THIS
BIT RIGHT NOW.
>> Jimmy: YOU GO FROM THERE.
>> IT'S BIZARRE HOW -- OH, YEAH.
WE'VE JUST BEEN ON A TOUR --
>> Jimmy: OF WHAT?
>> OF "LES MIS."
AND MY SON IS LIKE --
>> Jimmy: OH, YEAH, RIGHT.
>> YOU'RE AN INCREDIBLE ACTRESS.
>> Jimmy: AND WHEN YOUR NAME IS
OSCAR.
>> DO NOT ENCOURAGE HIM.
ANYWAY.
IT'S AN AMAZING EXPERIENCE.
>> Jimmy: THE BEST THING MY DAD
AND I DID TOGETHER.
>> YOU ARE CLIMBING WITH HIM.
AND YOU LOOK BACK AND THE VIEW
OF TOKYO RIGHT DOWN TO THE
WATER, AMAZING.
IS IT ANY BETTER FOUR HOURS
LATER WHEN YOU ARE A LITTLE
HIGHER?
NO.
>> Jimmy: AND THE HELICOPTER
TAKES YOU UP THERE NOW.
YOU HAVE BEEN GETTING GREAT
REVIEWS FOR "LES MISERABLES."
AND YOU GOT THE GOLDEN GLOBE
KNOCK NATION.
I ASSUME YOU HAD SEEN THE PLAY
BEFORE.
IS IT SOMETHING YOU HAD
COMMITTED TO MEMORY?
>> I WAS EXPOSED TO IT BY MY
MATE GRUBBY.
>> Jimmy: WHAT?
>> HE'S NAME IS BRIAN BUT HIS
NICKNAME IS GRUBBY.
THE NICKNAMES ARE CRUEL.
>> Jimmy: LIKE WHAT?
>> A KID AT OUR SCHOOL HAD A CAR
ACCIDENT.
IT WAS TOUCH AND GO FOR A WHILE.
HE WAS IN A COMA AND THERE WERE
PEOPLE PRAYING AND DOING THIS
THING AND WILL HE COME BACK?
HE CAME BACK AND WE WERE NOT
SURE IF HE WAS COMING BACK IN
THE SAME SHAPE THAT HE LEFT.
WHEN HE CAME BACK SIX MONTHS
LATER.
IT APPEARED HE WAS GETTING
BETTER.
BUT FROM THE MOMENT HE ARRIVED
BACK AT SCHOOL HE WAS CALLED
DAMAGE.
>> Jimmy: IT COULD HAVE BEEN
WORSE.
DAMAGE, HUH?
>> DAMAGE, WELCOME BACK.
IT WAS WORSE FOR ME.
>> Jimmy: WHAT IS YOUR NAME?
>> DO YOU REMEMBER THE SHOW "V"?
>> AND THEY TRIED TO BRING IT
BACK HERE AT ABC.
>> I GOT IN A HOT SWEAT WHEN I
SAW IT.
THEY HAD A MARK HERE IN THE
SHAPE OF THE V.
THAT DISTINGUISHED THEM AS
ALIENS.
I WOKE UP AT THE AGE OF 14 WITH
ACNE IN THE SHAPE OF A V FOR A
MONTH EVERY DAY.
COULD NOT GET RID OF IT AS THE
SHOW IS PEAKING AND EVERYONE IS
YELLING YO, V, WELCOME TO SCHOOL
MAN.
WHAT UP, ALIEN.
>> Jimmy: WHY DID YOU CALL HIM
GRUBBY?
>> HE WAS VERY SLICK.
>> Jimmy: AN OPPOSITE THING.
LIKE WHEN YOU CALL A FAT GUY
SLIM.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE A BREAK AND
COME BACK AND SEE A CLIP FROM
YOUR NEW FILM "LES MISERABLES."
HUGH JACKMAN IS HERE.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
Introducing
Grey Goose Cherry Noir
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
PREPARE YOURSELF
FOR THE FEELING OF MORE WATER
WITHOUT USING MORE WATER.
WITH THE UNIQUE WAVE PATTERN
OF Delta H2Okinetic Technology.
ANOTHER WAY Delta
IS MORE THAN JUST A SHOWER.
SEE WHAT Delta CAN DO.
ANOTHER WAY Delta
IS MORE THAN JUST A SHOWER.
>>> YOUR TIME IS UP AND YOUR
PAROLE'S BEGUN.
YOU KNOW WHAT THAT MEANS.
>> YES, MEANS I'M FREE.
>> NO.
FOLLOW TO THE LETTER YOUR I
TINRY YOUR BADGE WILL SHOW YOU
UNTIL YOU DIE.
IT WARNS YOU'RE A DANGEROUS MAN.
>> I STOLE A LOAF OF BREAD.
MY SISTER'S CHILD WAS CLOSE TO
DEATH.
WE WERE STARVING.
>> YOU WILL STARVE AGAIN UNLESS
YOU LEARN THE MEANING OF THE
LAW.
>> THE MEANING OF THOSE 19
YEARS.
>> A SLAVE OF THE LAW.
>> THAT IS HUGH JACKMAN AND
RUSSELL CROWE IN "LES
MISERABLES."
IT OPENS CHRISTMAS DAY.
IT'S FUN TO SEE YOU GUYS ARGUING
IN SONG.
>> VERY NATURAL.
>> REAL AUSTRALIANS DO THAT.
>> ♪ I HATE YOU JIMMY KIMMEL.
>> I WAS THERE AND I DIDN'T DO
THAT.
FOR A MOVIE LIKE THIS.
YOU HAVE SEEN THE MUSICAL.
DO YOU BOTHER TO DO RESEARCH FOR
IT?
>> THERE IS THAT 1600 PAGE BOOK
WITH WHICH I WILL GET AROUND TO
READING ANY MINUTE.
I HEAR IT'S GREAT.
BUT I ACTUALLY WENT TO UNUSUALLY
LONG AND DEEP LENGTHS TO MAKE
SURE I HAD EVERYTHING RIGHT.
THIS IS A FAMOUS FRENCH TALE.
ISAAC FACED MYSELF FOR THE LAST
SUMMER BY GOING TO FRANCE.
NO, NO.
WAIT.
I DID A ROAD TRIP RIGHT THROUGH
THE WINE REGION AND RIGHT TO THE
SOUTH OF FRANCE AND I HAD A
HOUSE FOR A MONTH IN PROADVANCE.
DAY IN AND DAY OUT, FRENCH,
FRENCH, FRENCH.
>> ALL WRITE OFFS RIGHT?
ALL TAX DEDUCTIBLE.
THAT'S RESEARCH FOR THE ROLE.
YOU REALLY DID THAT.
>> I REALLY DID THAT.
I'M A SERIOUS ACTOR.
>> Jimmy: WAS ANYONE CONVINCED
YOU WERE DOING THIS FOR THE
ROLE?
>> NOBODY.
BUT AFTER THE THIRD BOTTLE OF
WINE I WOULD SING A LOT.
BUT IT WAS EMBARRASSING.
I WENT ON THIS ROAD TRIP RIGHT
DOWN TO ST. TROPEZ AND I WAS
DRIVING IN A CAR WITH A GPS.
AND SOME OF THEM HAVE THE NAME
OF THE STREET YOU ARE ON.
WE TURN ON THIS TOWN AND GOING
DOWN THE MAIN STREET AND WE'RE
ON AVENUE VICTOR HUGO.
THIS IS AMAZING.
THIS -- LET'S FIND THE STREET
SIGN.
I'M LIKE COME ON, KIDS.
WE TAKE A PHOTO.
AND VICTOR HUGO.
GET BACK IN THE CAR AND SECOND
TOWN, AVENUE VICTOR HUGO.
THIS IS INCREDIBLE.
THIS IS WHY WE DO THE RESEARCH.
I'M FEELING HIM IN MY BONES.
THIRD DOWN I REALIZE THAT MAIN
STREET IN EVERY TOWN IN FRANCE
IS AVENUE VICTOR HUGO.
BUT NEXT TIME I WILL DO THE
SLIDE SHOW OF MY TRIP.
53 PICTURES.
>> YOUR POOR KIDS THROUGHOUT THE
WHOLE THING.
DAD AND HIS VICTOR HUGO.
>> DAD, THIS IS INCREDIBLE.
>> Jimmy: CONGRATULATIONS ON THE
MOVIE.
I KNOW IT WILL BE A GOOD MOVIE.
>> Jimmy: HUGH JACKMAN!
"LES MISERABLES" OPENS IN
THEATERS CHRISTMAS DAY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH
JENNA FISCHER.
♪
First rule of taking the
world by surprise?
Do something the world
will actually notice.
Introducing the entirely
new Ford Fusion.
With a turbo-charged EcoBoost
engines and a hybrid that
doubles the fuel economy of
the average vehicle.
It's an entirely new idea of
what a car can be.
HOME OF THE MEATY, MELTY
MCDOUBLE YOU LOVE.
AND OTHER AMAZING TASTES
FOR JUST A DOLLAR EACH.
EVERY DAY, AS ALWAYS,
THERE'S A LOT TO LOVE
FOR A LITTLE
ON MCDONALD'S DOLLAR MENU.
♪
ON MBWe need to leave our.
contract plan
and make the move to
Net10 Wireless.
What???
Oh nice, let's just have our
calls drop all the time.
Net10 uses the same cell towers
as the top carriers,
but for half of what we pay now.
Half?
Don't worry.
Confusion is normal.
But, I...
It's better this way.
But what if...what if...
Shhh...
Welcome to the next generation
of family plans.
Fifty dollars the first line,
40 dollars each new line
with unlimited everything.
Visit Net10Wireless.com
HI.
DELUXE DREAM VILLAGE.
THAT'S MY FAVORITE.
[ Male Announcer ] SOME PEOPLE
REALLY LOVE THEIR JOBS.
OK.
HAVE A SUPER SPARKLY DAY!
AND SOME PEOPLE
JUST LOVE TO SAVE MONEY.
SEE HOW YOU CAN SAVE
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
AND SOME PEOPLE
JUST LOVE TO SAVE MONEY.
This season, give Craftsman
tools and give the gifts that
keep on giving.
CRAFTSMAN. GUYS'
FAVORITES GUARANTEED.
FIND IT AT SEARS.
THAT THERE'S THE GUY WHO GETS
HIS SALSA FROM NEW YORK CITY.
NEW YORK CITY?!
[ Male Announcer ] ONLY PACE
HAS THAT BIG, BOLD KICK.
ANYTHING ELSE JUST AIN'T RIGHT.
PACE. GRAB THE SOUTHWEST
BY THE BOTTLE.
[ sneezes ]
[ sniffles ]
[ Female Announcer ]
FOR EVERYTHING YOUR FACE
HAS TO FACE.
FACE IT
WITH PUFFS FACIAL TISSUES.
PUFFS HAS AIR-FLUFFED PILLOWS
FOR 40% MORE CUSHIONY
THICKNESS.
FACE EVERY DAY
WITH PUFFS SOFTNESS.
A LOWER PRICE ON YOUR GIFTS.
GETTING THEM HOME?
WOW.
YEAH.
THAT'S ANOTHER STORY.
CITI PRICE REWIND.
SEE HOW YOU CAN SAVE
AT CITI.COM/PRICEREWIND.
AS PAM THE PERSON, NOT THE
COOKING SPRAY ON THE
LONG-RUNNING AND VERY FUNNY
SHOW, "THE OFFICE."
ITS FAREWELL SEASON CONTINUES
THURSDAY NIGHTS ON NBC.
PLEASE WELCOME JENNA FISCHER.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: YOU LOOK GREAT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> Jimmy: HOW'S EVERYTHING.
I THINK YOU WERE PREGNANT THE
LAST TIME I SAW YOU.
>> U.S. WAS THAT TRUE?
>> Jimmy: WITH A BABY.
>> I WAS PREGNANT WITH A BABY.
THAT'S GOOD.
>> Jimmy: THAT'S WORKED OUT
NICELY?
>> NOW WE HAVE THE BABY AND HE
IS A YEAR OLD.
>> Jimmy: WOW.
WAS THAT THE LAST TIME -- I
HAVEN'T SEEN YOU FOR A WHILE.
>> IT WAS A WHILE.
THAT WAS OUR BIG NIGHT OUT
BEFORE I HAD THE BABY.
>> Jimmy: MINE AND YOURS.
>> YOU HAVEN'T GOT OUT MUCH
EITHER.
>> Jimmy: YOU ARE HALF WAY
THROUGH THE FINAL SEASON OF "THE
OFFICE."
HAVE YOU STARTED TO FEEL
NOSTALGIC ABOUT THAT?
>> YEAH.
WE FILMED HALF OF THE FINAL
SEASON.
HASN'T AIRED YET BUT WE FINISHED
FILMING IT.
AND WE WERE ON SET TALKING ABOUT
HOW FAR WE'VE COME.
THE SHOW HAS CHANGED ALL OUR
LIVES.
WE HAVE CAREERS WHERE WE DIDN'T
HAVE CAREERS BEFORE AND TRADING
STORIES ABOUT OUR FIRST JOBS.
>> Jimmy: WHAT WAS YOUR FIRST
JOB?
>> VERY DIFFERENT THAN THE
OFFICE.
MY FIRST PAID ACTING JOB WAS AS
A BACKGROUND PERSON.
THE PEOPLE WHO STAND IN THE
BACKGROUND OF THINGS THAT ARE --
>> Jimmy: RIGHT.
>> NO LINES OR ANYTHING.
AND WAS A BACKGROUND PERSON FOR
THE "JURASSIC PARK RIDE" A
COMMERCIAL.
I HAD JUST GOT HERE AND HAD BEEN
HERE THREE DAYS AND MY
GIRLFRIEND FROM COLLEGE WAS A
CASTING DIRECTOR WHO CAST THE
BACKGROUND PEOPLE AND SHE ASKED
IF I WANTED TO BE IN THIS
COMMERCIAL AS A BACKGROUND
PERSON AND I WAS LIKE YES.
THEY WERE GOING TO PAY ME $100
TO RIDE THE RIDE AT ALL DAY AND
FILM ME.
I THOUGHT THIS WAS THE GREATEST
THING.
WE SIGNED UP AND PULL ON TO THE
UNIVERSAL STUDIOS LOT.
I'VE BEEN HERE THREE DAYS AND
I'M ON THE LOT.
>> Jimmy: IT'S A FUN LOT.
>> YOU SEE THE "BACK TO THE
FUTURE" STUFF AND THAT -- I
THINK THAT'S RIGHT.
>> Jimmy: "JAWS" IS THERE.
>> AND ARNOLD SCHWARZENEGGER IS
WALKING TO HIS CAR SMOKING A
SKB
CIGAR.
WE WOULDN'T BELIEVE IT.
AND IT WAS ALL DOWNHILL FROM
THERE.
LITERALLY DOWN MANY HILLS.
BECAUSE IT'S -- IT'S A WATER
RIDE.
IT'S A WATER ROLLER COASTER
AND I'M AN EXTRA ON IT NOW ALL
DAY.
>> Jimmy: OKAY.
>> AND SO, YOU RIDE THE RIDE BUT
YOU RIDE IT IN SECTIONS FOR THE
COMMERCIALS.
SO YOU RIDE THE FIRST SECTION
AND A GUY COMES OUT AND SUPPOSED
TO SPIT WATER AND THEY DECIDED
IT WASN'T ENOUGH WATER.
SO THEY GOT GUYS WITH BUCKETS OF
WATER AND THEY WOULD PUSH THE
BOAT AND THROW BUCKETS OF WATER
ON US, COLD ICY WATER AND WE'RE
GETTING DRENCHED.
AND THEN THEY DECIDED IT WASN'T
GIVING THEM THE IMPACT THEY
WANTED ON CAMERA AND PULLED OUT
WHAT IS CALLED A WATER CANNON.
>> Jimmy: OKAY.
>> YOU KNOW, REGULAR CANNON,
SHOOT CANNON BALLS.
THIS SHOOTS CANNON BALLS OF
WATER.
>> Jimmy: A BALL OF WATER.
>> A BALL OF WATER SHOOTING AT
YOU.
>> Jimmy: HOW HARD DOES IT COME
AT YOU?
>> SO HARD.
SO HARD.
>> Jimmy: AND SOMEONE FIRING
THESE?
>> THERE'S A GUY LIKE YOU KNOW
HE'S GOT AN INTENSE LOOK ON HIS
FACE AND THE BOAT'S ABOUT TO
COME UP TO HIM.
>> Jimmy: AND YOU HAVE TO
PRETEND YOU DON'T KNOW IT'S
HAPPENING.
>> OH -- AND YOU ARE HIT WITH
THIS WATER.
SO AS A BACKGROUND PERFORMER YOU
ARE NOT TREATED REALLY WELL.
>> Jimmy: NO.
>> I DON'T REMEMBER EATING ANY
FOOD OR USING THE RESTROOM OR
LEAVING THIS BOAT.
I WAS JUST IN THIS BOAT THE
WHOLE TIME.
AND I HAD TO GO TO THE BATHROOM
SO BAD.
>> Jimmy: OH, NO.
>> AND I'M DRENCHED AND COLD AND
IT'S THE LAST SHOT AND THE GUY
SITTING NEXT TO ME I GUESS HE
HAD BEEN GETTING HIT WITH THE
WATER CANNON INTENSELY.
AND HE HAD HAD ENOUGH.
SO ON THE LAST ROUND I NOTICE AS
THE WATER CANNON GOES OFF THE
GUY NEXT TO ME GOES LIKE THIS
AND I GET THE FULL BRUNT OF THE
CANNON RIGHT IN MY CHEST.
AND -- I'M NOT -- LET ME JUST
SAY I'M NOT SAYING I PEED MY
PANTS BUT I CAN'T HAVE TO GO TO
THE BATHROOM ANY MORE.
>> Jimmy: WATER BEGAT WATER.
WERE YOU EXCITED WHEN YOU SAW IT
ON TELEVISION?
>> OH, JIMMY.
NO.
>> Jimmy: WHY?
>> WELL, I DID MANAGE TO TAPE
IT.
AND THIS WAS BACK WHEN THERE
WERE VCRs AND YOU COULD GO FRAME
BY FRAME AND I WAS IN TWO FRAMES
UP IN THE CORNER.
AND AT CHRISTMAS TIME I MADE THE
ENTIRE EXTENDED FAMILY GATHER
AROUND THE TELEVISION AND SHOWED
THEM MY TWO FRAMES.
>> Jimmy: YOU SHOULD FIND
WHOEVER DIRECTED THAT VIDEO AND
PUNISH HIM.
>> I HAVE RIDDEN THE RIDE SINCE.
14 YEARS LATER I WENT BACK AND
TOOK MY NEPHEW.
AND YOU DON'T GET WET AT ALL.
IT'S LIKE A SPRINKLE OF NOTHING.
IT'S LIKE MISTING OF WATER.
THERE'S NO WATER ON THIS RIDE AT
ALL.
>> Jimmy: THAT'S FALSE
ADVERTISING.
>> THERE ARE PEOPLE IN THOSE
CLEAR RAIN PARKAS IN LINE.
THEY ARE ALL LIKE AFRAID THEY
WILL BE DRENCHED ALL DAY.
>> Jimmy: WHAT ARE YOU DOING FOR
THE HOLIDAYS?
WHAT'S THE PLAN?
>> GOING HOME TO ST. LOUIS.
TO SEE MY FOLKS.
MY HUSBAND AND THE BABY --
>> Jimmy: I HAVE BEEN TO ST.
LOUIS A BUNCH OF TIMES.
YOUR MOM WAS MY FIANCE'S
TEACHER.
SHE IS ONLY 14 YEARS OLD, MY
FIANCE.
IT'S A JOKE.
BUT IT'S -- THAT'S A WEIRD
THING.
AND DO YOU HAVE SPOTS YOU GO TO
THE EAT?
>> EMO'S PIZZA.
>> Jimmy: CAN I SAY SOMETHING?
IT'S THE MOST DISGUSTING PIZZA
EVER.
IT'S THE WORST PIZZA I HAVE EVER
HAD IN MY LONG -- ILLUSTRIOUS
PIZZA EATING CAREER.
AND EVERYONE FROM ST. LOUIS
LOVES IT.
WHY?
>> I HOPE YOU HAD IT DELIVERED.
IT GETS PLASTICY AND THAT'S WHEN
IT IS THE BEST.
>> Jimmy: REALLY?
THAT'S A GREAT SLOGAN.
IT WAS PLASTICY.
>> THAT'S WHAT MAKES IT GOOD.
>> Jimmy: NO.
BUT IT WAS PLASTICY.
IT'S A WEIRD THING.
EVERY TIME I GO THERE, THE
PROVOLONE VERSION OF VELVEETA.
>> I LOVE IT SO MUCH.
WE HAD THANKSGIVING DINNER AND I
ORDER PIZZA AT MIDNIGHT.
I HAD ONE DAY IN TOWN.
>> Cleto: I LIKE THE FROZEN
CUSTARD.
>> SURE.
>> Jimmy: A PLACE CALLED RED
LION.
AND PAPPY'S SMOKE HOUSE.
>> THEY'RE ALL GOOD.
BUT IF YOU ONLY GET ONE THING I
GOT HAVE THAT PIZZA.
>> Jimmy: WINSLOW'S HOME IS A
GOOD PLACE.
JUST GIVE ME OTHER OPTIONS.
MERRY CHRISTMAS TO YOU.
AND THIS IS THE LAST SEASON.
IT'S BEEN ON A LONG TIME.
YOU HAVE BECOME A PART OF OUR
LIVES.
NEW EPISODES OF "THE OFFICE"
RETURN JANUARY 10TH ON NBC.
JENNA FISCHER, EVERYBODY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH 2
CHAINZ.
>> Jimmy: THIS IS HIS DEBUT AND
GRAMMY NOMINATED ALBUM.
IT'S CALLED "BASED ON A TRU
STORY."
HERE WITH THE SONG "I'M
DIFFERENT" 2 CHAINZ.
YEAH!
WHO DIFFERENT?
♪ I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT ♪
♪ I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING ♪
♪ PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING
PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING ♪
♪ PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING
MIDDLE FINGER UP
TO MY COMPETITION ♪
♪ I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT ♪
♪ I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING ♪
♪ PULL TO THE SCENE
WITH MY ROOF GONE
WHEN I LEAVE THE SCENE
BET YOUR BOO GONE ♪
♪ AND I BEAT THE
LIKE A NEW SONG
2 CHAINZ BUT I GOT
ME A FEW ON ♪
♪ EVERYTHING HOT
SKIP LUKEWARM
TELL SHAWTY TO BUST IT OPEN
UNCLE LUKE ON ♪
♪ GOT THE PRESENT
FOR THE PRESENT
AND A GIFT WRAPPING
I DON'T FEEL GOOD ♪
♪ BUT MY TRIGGER HAPPY
BUT THE STRIPPER HAPPY
BUT THEY WISH HAD ME
AND I WISH A WOULD ♪
♪ LIKE A KITCHEN CABINET
AND ME AND YOU ARE CUT
FROM A DIFFERENT FABRIC
HER SO GOOD ♪
♪ IT'S A BAD HABIT
SIT DOWN YOU GOT
A BAD ATTI'
GAVE HER THE WRONG NUMBER ♪
♪ AND A BAD ADDY
YOU AIN'T GOING NOWHERE
LIKE A BAD NAVI
SO BIG ♪
♪ I TOLD HER
TO LOOK BACK AT IT
LOOK BACK IT
LOOK BACK IT ♪
♪ THEN PUT A FAT RABBIT
ON THE CRAFTMATIC
I AM SO HIGH ATTIC
I AM SO HIGH ♪
♪ LIKE AN ADDICT
I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
I'M DIFFERENT ♪
♪ YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
PULL UP TO THE SCENE ♪
♪ WITH MY CEILING MISSING
PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING
PULL UP TO THE SCENE ♪
♪ WITH MY CEILING MISSING
PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING
MIDDLE FINGER UP ♪
♪ TO MY COMPETITION
I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
I'M DIFFERENT ♪
♪ YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
PULL UP TO THE SCENE ♪
♪ WITH MY CEILING MISSING
2 CHAINZ GOT YOUR GIRL
ON THE CELLY
AND WHEN I GET ♪
♪ OFF THE CELLY
I MADE HER MEET AT THE TELLY
WHEN SHE MEET AT THE TELLY ♪
♪ I PUT IT STRAIGHT
IN HER BELLY
WHEN IT GO IN THE BELLY
IT AIN'T YOU CAN TELL ME ♪
♪ HAIR LONG MONEY LONG
ME AND BROKE
WE DON'T GET ALONG
HAIR LONG MONEY LONG ♪
♪ ME AND BROKE
WE DON'T GET ALONG
I PAID A THOUSAND DOLLARS
FOR MY SNEAKERS ♪
♪ YE TOLD YA
A 100K FOR A FEATURE
EEEERR EEEERR
SOUND OF THE BED ♪
♪ BEAT IT UP
BEAT IT UP
THEN I GET SOME --
WELL I MIGHT GET SOME -- ♪
♪ THEN I BEAT IT UP
I DON'T GIVE A
SWITCH IT UP
LIVE IT UP ♪
♪ YEAH IT'S GOING DOWN
SO GET UP
MY VALET PARKS
THE BRINKS TRUCK ♪
WHO DIFFERENT?
ONE, TWO, THREE, WHO DIFFERENT?
♪ I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT ♪
♪ I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING ♪
♪ PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING
PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING ♪
♪ PULL UP TO THE SCENE
WITH MY CEILING MISSING
MIDDLE FINGER UP
TO MY COMPETITION ♪
♪ I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT
I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT ♪
♪ I'M DIFFERENT
YEAH I'M DIFFERENT