HER SKIN IS JUST AMAZING.
AND SO, I FEEL LIKE
NOW I HAVE A CHANCE.
>> WHAT'S CINDY'S BEAUTY SECRET?
WE'RE ABOUT TO FIND OUT.
♪
>> THE FIRST TIME
I SAW CINDY IN PERSON,
SHE TURNED AROUND,
I WENT "WHOA!"
THAT WOMAN'S GORGEOUS.
AND SHE DOESN'T HAVE
A DROP OF MAKEUP ON.
WHATEVER SHE HAS,
I WANT IT BOTTLED
AND I WANT TO USE IT.
>> CINDY CRAWFORD IS
ONE OF THE MOST BEAUTIFUL
WOMEN ON EARTH.
SHE'S ICONIC AND THE BUZZ IS
LIKE, "WHAT IS SHE DOING?"
>> I WANT TO HAVE WHAT CINDY HAS
BECAUSE SHE GETS THE SUPER
SECRET INFO THAT WE DON'T GET.
>> WHAT IS CINDY'S SECRET?
>> AFTER MORE THAN
TWO DECADES ON THE JOB,
CINDY REMAINS ONE OF THE MOST
VISIBLE FACES AND SOUGHT AFTER
SUPER MODELS IN THE WORLD.
>> YET HER SKIN STILL
LOOKS REMARKABLY YOUTHFUL
AND GORGEOUSLY WRINKLE-FREE.
>> EVERYBODY WANTS TO KNOW
"WHAT IS CINDY USING?"
BECAUSE WE ALL KNOW WE WANT
TO LOOK LIKE CINDY CRAWFORD.
>> CHECK OUT THESE PHOTOS.
ON THE LEFT, CINDY AT AGE 28.
AND ON THE RIGHT, AT 41.
HERE'S ANOTHER PICTURE OF CINDY
AT 28 AND ON THE RIGHT
AT AGE 43.
AND FINALLY, CINDY AT 28
AND TODAY AT AGE 45.
>> HOW DOES CINDY DO IT?
>> HER SECRET IS RENOWNED
FRENCH ANTI-AGING SPECIALIST,
DOCTOR JEAN-LOUIS SEBAGH.
>> HE'S BEEN CALLED
"THE WONDER DOCTOR,"
"A MIRACLE WORKER,"
AND "THE YOUTH GURU."
>> DOCTOR JEAN-LOUIS SEBAGH
IS A SUPER EXCLUSIVE
DOCTOR IN PARIS.
I WAS 28 WHEN I FIRST
WENT TO HIM,
AND I INSTANTLY NOTICED
THAT MY SKIN JUST CAME ALIVE.
AND THAT WAS IT, IT WAS
KIND OF LOVE AT FIRST SIGHT.
>> DOCTOR SEBAGH'S TREATMENTS
ARE IN SUCH DEMAND,
MODELS, CELEBRITIES,
AND EVEN VIP CLIENTS
WAIT MONTHS JUST TO GET
AN APPOINTMENT WITH HIM.
>> PEOPLE DON'T MIND WAITING
FOUR HOURS AT A TIME JUST
TO SEE HIM BECAUSE THEY KNOW
THAT AT THE END OF THE DAY
THEY COME OUT LOOKING FRESHER
AND HEALTHIER AND YOUNGER.
YOU KNOW, HE'S THE MAN.
>> HOW IS IT THAT DOCTOR SEBAGH
IS ABLE TO PRODUCE SUCH
POWERFUL ANTI-AGING ELIXIRS?
>> HIS SECRET LIES IN
A FABLED AND BEAUTIFUL PART
OF THE FRENCH COUNTRYSIDE.
>> HERE IN THIS SECLUDED FIELD
IN THE SOUTH OF FRANCE,
SCIENTISTS HAVE DISCOVERED
A RARE VINE-RIPEN MELON
WITH ASTONISHING YOUTH
PRESERVING PROPERTIES.
>> CHECK OUT THIS NEW
TIME-LAPSE VIDEO SHOWING
HOW AN ORDINARY MELON
WRINKLES, AGES, AND DECAYS.
>> WHILE THE REMARKABLE MELON
ON THE RIGHT STAYS
FRESH AND FIRM.
NO WONDER THEY CALL
DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
SIGNATURE INGREDIENT
"THE YOUTH MOLECULE."
>> YEAH, THAT'S PRETTY DRAMATIC
RIGHT THERE, WHEN YOU LOOK AT
THE TWO MELONS SIDE BY SIDE.
IT'S LIKE, "HM, WHAT'S IN THAT
MELON THAT'S MAKING IT NOT AGE?
I WANT SOME OF THAT."
>> IT'S BEEN A VERY
DIFFICULT PROCESS TO EXTRACT
THE ENZYME FROM THIS MELON.
AND WE'VE BEEN THE FIRST ONE
TO USE THIS MELON EXTRACT
IN A VERY HIGH CONCENTRATION,
WHICH IS EXCLUSIVE
TO MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
>> SINCE CINDY FIRST JOINED
WITH DOCTOR SEBAGH
TO BRING THE POWER
OF HIS MELON-BASED SERUMS
TO WOMEN LIKE US,
RUMORS OF THE AMAZING
VISIBLE RESULTS HAVE MADE IT
AN UNDERGROUND SECRET
IN HOLLYWOOD
AND AROUND THE WORLD.
>> YOU HAVE CINDY CRAWFORD;
SUPER MODEL,
AND DOCTOR SEBAGH;
INTERNATIONALLY RENOWNED
SKIN EXPERT.
THOSE TWO TOGETHER,
TO ME, THAT'S GOLD.
>> NOW, FOR 2013 AND BEYOND,
DOCTOR SEBAGH HAS RE-ENGINEERED
HIS MELON-BASED FORMULAS
AND ENHANCED THEM
WITH EVEN MORE REMARKABLE
AGE-FIGHTING INGREDIENTS.
INTRODUCING MEANINGFUL
BEAUTY ADVANCED.
THE ULTIMATE YOUTH ENHANCING
SYSTEM FROM CINDY
AND DOCTOR SEBAGH.
>> LITERALLY WITHIN SEVEN DAYS
I CAN SEE RESULTS.
>> USING MEANINGFUL BEAUTY
HAS BEEN AMAZING.
IT'S EVENED OUT MY SKIN TONE
AND IT REDUCED CIRCLES
AND PUFFINESS.
>> THIS STUFF IS AMAZING.
IT'S JUST A LITTLE MIRACLE
IN A BOTTLE.
>> MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED
IS A REVOLUTIONARY ANTI-AGING
SYSTEM THAT IS SO ADVANCED
AND SO PERFECTLY FORMULATED
WOMEN SURVEYED SAW VISIBLY
HEALTHIER, YOUNGER-LOOKING
SKIN IN JUST WEEKS.
>> CINDY'S SECRET IS
DEFINITELY THE REAL DEAL
BECAUSE I SEE IT.
I SEE IT IN MY SKIN.
I SEE THE DIFFERENCE.
>> TAKE A LOOK.
THAT'S NOT TRICK PHOTOGRAPHY.
IT'S NOT DRAMATIZATION
OR A SIMULATION.
THESE ARE REAL RESULTS.
AND THERE'S MORE.
>> TODAY, CINDY IS HERE
TO ANNOUNCE A GROUND-BREAKING
NEW INNOVATION
FROM DOCTOR SEBAGH.
THREE POWERFUL ANTI-AGING
FORMULAS COMBINE INTO
ONE LUXURIOUS SERUM.
IT'S CALLED CREME DE SERUM.
>> I WAS SOLD RIGHT AWAY
BECAUSE THIS ROCKS.
AND IT HAS SUCH A SILKY
GLIDE ON YOUR SKIN.
>> IN THE CREME DE SERUM,
AT THE END THEY MIX TOGETHER
AND YOU ACHIEVE CREAM.
THEN YOU GO THE BEST
OF THE BEST.
YOU CAN CREME DE LA CREME.
>> AS SOON AS YOU APPLY IT,
YOUR SKIN JUST INSTANTLY
FEELS TIGHTER AND IT FEELS
LIKE YOU CAN JUST FEEL
YOUR POURS SHRINKING.
AND IT IS AMAZING.
>> IN THE NEXT FEW MINUTES,
CORRESPONDENT, KATRINA SZISH
TAKES YOU DEEPER INSIDE
THE STORY OF CINDY
AND HER "WONDER DOCTOR."
>> AS CINDY SHARES HOW YOU
CAN GET ACCESS TO THE MAN
WHOSE AMAZING FORMULAS HAVE
WORKED THEIR WONDERS ON CINDY
FOR OVER 17 YEARS.
>> THERE'S PROBABLY NOTHING
IN MY LIFE THAT I DO
THAT'S MORE EXCLUSIVE
THAN SPENDING TIME
WITH DOCTOR SEBAGH.
>> AND WHAT IF YOU COULD
HAVE YOUR OWN PERSONAL VISIT
WITH DOCTOR SEBAGH?
>> WATCH AS ONE LUCKY
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY CUSTOMER
RECEIVES A SURPRISE
INVITATION FROM CINDY.
>> HI, THIS IS CINDY CRAWFORD.
>> OH, MY GOSH,
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
>> I AM SERIOUS.
>> AND A LITTLE LATER
IN THE SHOW, CINDY DOES
SOMETHING VERY SURPRISING.
HAND HELD CAMERA,
TOTALLY CANDID,
ZERO MAKEUP.
>> I STILL CAN'T BELIEVE
WHEN PEOPLE COME UP TO ME
AND ASK ME IF I REALLY
USE MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
I DO USE MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
AND I'M GONNA SHOW YOU
HOW I DO IT.
>> PLUS, IMAGINE IF YOU COULD
HAVE EVERY ONE OF CINDY'S
YOUTH-ENHANCING SECRETS
FOR YOURSELF AT MORE THAN
HALF OFF THE REGULAR PRICE.
>> IT'S NO JOKE.
JUST WATCH FOR THIS SPECIAL
COUPON CODE WHEN IT SHOWS UP
AGAIN LATER IN THE PROGRAM.
AND TAKE ADVANTAGE OF OVER 50%
IN INSTANT COUPON SAVINGS
THANKS TO CINDY.
>> JUST AHEAD, IT'S YOUR CHANCE
TO LOOK YEARS YOUNGER AS YOU
DISCOVER THE AGE-DEFINED MAGIC
OF MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED.
♪
>> YOU KNOW HER AS AMERICA'S
MOST CELEBRATED SUPER MODEL.
APPEARING ON OVER 600
MAGAZINE COVERS AND COUNTING.
HI, EVERYONE, I'M KATRINA SZISH
HERE TODAY WITH ONE OF THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL WOMEN IN THE WORLD.
PLEASE JOIN ME FOR THIS VERY
SPECIAL CLOSE-UP INTERVIEW
WITH CINDY CRAWFORD.
NICE TO SEE YOU, CINDY.
I AM SO EXCITED TO SIT DOWN
AND REALLY TALK TO YOU
ABOUT MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
>> THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE TOO.
>> PEOPLE ARE TALKING
ABOUT IT EVERYWHERE.
WOMEN'S WEAR DAILY EVEN
RECENTLY TALKED ABOUT IT
AS ONE OF THE TOP TEN
FASTEST GROWING SKIN CARE
BRANDS IN THE U.S.
THIS IS HUGE.
WHY IS IT CATCHING ON LIKE THIS?
>> IT'S DELIVERING RESULTS.
I MEAN, WOMEN ARE GETTING
GREAT RESULTS AND THEY'RE
TELLING THEIR FRIENDS
OR THEY'RE TWEETING ABOUT IT
OR BLOGGING ABOUT IT.
WITH MEANINGFUL BEAUTY
YOUR SKIN LOOKS AMAZING.
IT HAS THAT GLOW.
IT LOOKS GREAT
AND IT JUST FEELS LIKE
THAT YOUTHFUL, LUSH SKIN.
EVERYONE LIKE
"SO, WHAT'S THE TRICK?
WHAT'S THE TRICK?"
OR "WHAT'S THE SECRET?"
AND REALLY, THE TRICK
IS MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
>> TELL ME ABOUT THE MAN
YOU WORK WITH TO CREATE
THIS INCREDIBLE LINE.
EVERYBODY IN THE BEAUTY
INDUSTRY KNOWS
JEAN-LOUIS SEBAGH.
HE'S BEEN CALLED BY VANITY FAIR
"THE WORLD EXPERT
IN MEDICAL ANTI-AGING."
HE'S GOT A LONG LIST
OF CELEBRITIES, MODELS,
SOCIALITES, POLITICIANS
WHO WAIT FOR MONTHS
TO COME TO HIM.
WHAT MAKES HIM SO EXTRAORDINARY?
>> WELL, JEAN-LOUIS SEBAGH IS
LIGHT YEARS AHEAD OF EVERYBODY,
AND JUST HOW HE'S THINKING
ABOUT THE WAY THAT SKIN AGES.
AND I HAVE BEEN WORKING WITH HIM
SINCE I WAS 28 YEARS OLD.
A MAKEUP ARTIST ACTUALLY
SUGGESTED THAT I SEE HIM.
SO, I WENT.
I MADE AN APPOINTMENT.
AND HIS OFFICE IS IN THIS
APARTMENT BUILDING IN PARIS.
IT'S NOT MARKED, YOU KNOW.
IT'S LIKE YOU HAVE
TO KNOCK THREE TIMES
AND KNOW THE SECRET CODE
AND ALL THAT.
AND AFTER THE VERY
FIRST TIME I SAW HIM,
I SAW LIKE IMMEDIATE RESULTS.
MY SKIN JUST FELT
RADIANT LOOKING.
IT WAS JUST LIKE A NEW ME.
AND I WAS LIKE, "OKAY,
HE'S THE REAL DEAL."
AND I WAS SOLD RIGHT AWAY.
YOU KNOW, HE'S BEEN
MY GUY EVER SINCE.
>> RIGHT.
>> WITH MEANINGFUL BEAUTY
YOU DON'T HAVE TO GO
TO PARIS TO SEE HIM.
YOU CAN STILL HAVE ACCESS
TO DOCTOR SEBAGH
THROUGH MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
>> THE SECRET TO MEANINGFUL
BEAUTY ADVANCED
IS DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
GROUND-BREAKING SERUMS
FEATURING A RARE MELON ENZYME
DISCOVERED BY SCIENTISTS
IN THE SOUTH OF FRANCE.
>> THIS MELON PRODUCES A LARGE
QUANTITY OF AN ANTIOXIDANT
ENZYME CALLED S.O.D.
THE ENZYME KEEPS THIS
UNIQUE MELON FROM DECAYING
AND IN THE SKIN,
HELPS PREVENT CELLS FROM AGING
AS FAST AS THEY NORMALLY WOULD.
>> WHAT'S UNIQUE WITH
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY IS
WE USE THIS VERY POWERFUL
SUPER ANTIOXIDANTS
AND WE ARE ONE OF THE FIRST
IN AMERICA TO USE IT
IN A SKIN CARE.
>> I TALK TO A LOT OF PEOPLE
ABOUT A LOT OF DIFFERENT
SKIN CARE AND WHEN I SEE
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY,
PEOPLE SAY "WHAT IS IT
ABOUT THAT SECRET MELON,
THAT ANTIOXIDANT?"
I THINK OF IT AS
THE MAGIC MELON
AT THE CORE OF THIS STORY.
>> MEANINGFUL BEAUTY IS BASED
AROUND THIS SPECIAL MELON
THAT IS GROWN ONLY
IN THE SOUTH OF FRANCE.
IT HAS THIS VERY SPECIAL
AND VERY POTENT ANTIOXIDANT.
IN THE BEGINNING IF YOU PUT IT
NEXT TO A REGULAR MELON,
YOU WOULDN'T SEE
THAT MUCH DIFFERENCE.
BUT OVER TIME THIS MELON
DOESN'T DECAY AS FAST.
IT STAYS FRESHER
AND FIRMER LONGER.
>> THAT'S AMAZING.
>> AND I ALWAYS JOKE.
I'M LIKE, "I WANT TO BE
FRESHER AND FIRMER."
AND DOCTOR SEBAGH AND HIS
CHEMISTS FIGURED OUT A WAY
TO EXTRACT THIS VERY SPECIAL
AND VERY POTENT ANTIOXIDANT
THAT'S BEEN CALLED
THE YOUTH MOLECULE.
>> THAT MELON EXTRACT
CLEARLY WORKS.
I'VE BEEN USING DOCTOR SEBAGH
AND CINDY'S FORMULAS FOR
THREE YEARS AND IT IS AMAZING
HOW GREAT MY SKIN LOOKS.
>> I ACTUALLY WENT TO MY
DERMATOLOGIST AND SHE SAID
"YOUR SKIN LOOKS FANTASTIC.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?"
AND I THOUGHT THAT IT
MIGHT BE LIKE CANDID CAMERA.
I LOOKED AROUND
BECAUSE I THOUGHT,
"YOU'RE KIDDING ME, RIGHT?"
AND SHE'S LIKE,
"NO, YOUR SKIN TONE
LOOKS BETTER.
YOUR PORES LOOK SMALLER.
EVERYTHING'S BETTER."
AND I WAS LIKE,
"IT'S MEANINGFUL BEAUTY."
>> I'VE HAD THE OPPORTUNITY
TO REVIEW BEFORE
AND AFTER PHOTOGRAPHS,
WHICH WERE TAKEN OF SUBJECTS
USING MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
AND WHAT WE SEE HERE
IS THE APPEARANCE
OF THE CROW'S FEET
ARE VISIBLY DIMINISHED.
WE SEE THE DRAMATIC IMPROVEMENT
IN THE REDNESS OF THE CHEEKS,
IN ADDITION TO A REDUCTION IN
THE SIZE OF THE VISIBLE PORES.
AND FINALLY A REMARKABLE
IMPROVEMENT IN THE APPEARANCE
OF THESE DEEP FOREHEAD WRINKLES.
♪
>> THINK ABOUT IT.
YOU'VE GOT THIS AMAZING
SKIN DOCTOR FROM FRANCE
AND HE HAS THIS SECRET WEAPON.
AND YOU'VE GOT THE WORLD'S
MOST BEAUTIFUL SUPER MODEL.
AND THEY'VE DEVELOPED
THIS BEAUTY SYSTEM.
NOW, WOULDN'T YOU
WANT TO TRY IT?
>> IMAGINE IF WITH ONE PHONE
CALL YOU CAN GET SOME OF
THAT SAME MAGIC THAT'S KEPT
CINDY CRAWFORD'S SKIN LOOKING
SO YOUTHFUL FOR OVER 17 YEARS.
WELL, NOW YOU CAN.
INTRODUCING MEANINGFUL
BEAUTY ADVANCED.
THE ULTIMATE YOUTH ENHANCING
SYSTEM FROM CINDY
AND DOCTOR SEBAGH.
>> CALL NOW AND GET STARTED
WITH CINDY'S LUXURIOUS
SKIN SOFTENING CLEANSER.
>> THIS UNIQUE FORMULA CAN BE
USED WITH WATER OR DRY
TO CLEANSE AND REMOVE MAKEUP,
LEAVING YOUR SKIN SOFT,
DEWY, AND REFRESHED.
>> NEXT, YOU'LL GET
DOCTOR SEBAGH'S INCREDIBLE
ANTI-AGING DAY CREAM
FOR A BEAUTIFUL GLOW
THROUGHOUT YOUR DAY.
>> COMPLETE WITH BROAD SPECTRUM
SPF20 AND DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
RARE MELON EXTRACT.
>> YOU'LL ALSO RECEIVE HIS NEW
ADVANCED LIFTING EYE CREAM
TO REDUCE THE LOOK OF
PUFFINESS, DARK CIRCLES,
AND CROW'S FEET.
>> YOU'LL BE IMPRESSED
HOW YOUR EYE AREA APPEARS
MORE FIRM AND LIFTED WITH
THIS NEW SUPER TREATMENT.
>> MY MAKEUP ARTIST
ON THE MENTALIST NOTICED
THAT WHEN I STARTED USING
THE LIFTING EYE CREAM
WITHIN TWO WEEKS THERE WAS
A REDUCTION IN THE DARKNESS
UNDERNEATH MY EYES
AND THE PUFFINESS.
I MEAN, THAT'S PRETTY AMAZING.
>> YOU'LL ALSO GET
DOCTOR SEBAGH'S NEWLY ADVANCED
DECOLLETE AND NECK TREATMENT.
>> THIS SKIN BRIGHTENING SUPER
CREAM HELPS SMOOTH THE LOOK OF
SUN DAMAGED SKIN AND MINIMIZES
THE APPEARANCE OF AGE SPOTS
IN THIS EYE-CATCHING AREA
THAT OFTEN SHOWS
PREMATURE AGING.
>> AND FOR NIGHT TIME,
YOU'LL GET DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
GROUND-BREAKING NEW
CREME DE SERUM, WHICH FEATURES
THREE POWERFUL AGE-FIGHTING
FORMULAS SWIRLED INTO ONE.
>> YOU'LL BE AMAZED HOW THIS
DECADENT SUPER SERUM NOURISHES,
FIRMS, AND FIGHTS THE SIGNS
OF WRINKLES WHILE YOU SLEEP.
>> THE CREME DE SERUM
IS MAGIC IN A BOTTLE.
I PUT THIS ON AT NIGHT
BEFORE I GO TO SLEEP,
EVERY SINGLE NIGHT,
AND EVERY MORNING I WAKE UP
AND MY SKIN LOOKS
REFRESHED AND HAPPY.
IT'S FANTASTIC.
>> DOCTOR SEBAGH HAS BEEN
CALLED "THE WONDER DOCTOR,"
"A MIRACLE WORKER,"
AND "THE YOUTH GURU."
>> HIS PATIENTS WAIT MONTHS
FOR AN APPOINTMENT
AND OFTEN PAY THOUSANDS
OF DOLLARS FOR A SERIES
OF TREATMENTS CONTAINING
HIS RARE MELON DISCOVERY.
>> THAT'S WHY THE REGULAR
PRICE OF ONLY $119 FOR
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED
IS ALREADY A TOTAL BARGAIN.
BUT BECAUSE CINDY IS USING
HER UNIQUE POSITION
TO BRING DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
ELITE FORMULAS DIRECT TO YOU
THROUGH TV WITHOUT
EXCESSIVE RETAIL MARKUPS,
YOU CAN SAVE BIG ON
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED.
>> JUST MENTION THIS
SPECIAL COUPON CODE WHEN
YOU CALL TOLL-FREE NOW
AND YOU'LL RECEIVE OVER 50%
IN INSTANT COUPON SAVINGS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
ALL YOU'LL PAY IS JUST $59.95
FOR THE COMPLETE NEW
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED.
>> SOMETHING IS HAPPENING
AND IT'S CHANGING YOUR SKIN,
WHICH IS WONDERFUL.
>> IN FRANCE AT THE HIT
PARIS BOUTIQUE, COLETTE
WOMEN HAVE LINED UP
TO BUY MEANINGFUL BEAUTY,
PAYING 275 EUROS FOR A KIT.
>> THAT'S NEARLY $350 U.S.
BUT ALL YOU'LL PAY
IS JUST $59.95.
>> I CAN'T IMAGINE YOUR SKIN
NOT JUST LOVING IT.
MY SKIN LOOKS YOUNGER,
MORE YOUTHFUL.
THE LINES DON'T SHOW AS MUCH.
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY IS
THE BEST PRODUCT I'VE
EVER USED ON MY SKIN.
>> AND CINDY HAS A SPECIAL
PROPOSITION FOR YOU.
BE AMONG THE FIRST
FIVE HUNDRED CALLERS RIGHT NOW
AND SHE'LL SEND YOU $45 WORTH
OF PERSONAL GIFTS
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
>> YOU'LL GET DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
MODEL SECRET,
HIS INCREDIBLE GLOWING SERUM,
A FAVORITE OF
HOLLYWOOD INSIDERS.
>> THIS IS MY RED CARPET
SECRET FOR MY CELEBRITIES.
IT WILL REFIRM, HYDRATE,
AND IT WILL GIVE YOU
AN INSTANT GLOW TO YOUR FACE.
>> AND WE'LL ALSO SEND YOU
DOCTOR SEBAGH'S ENHANCED
WRINKLE SMOOTHING CAPSULES.
NAMED A BEST NEW ANTI-AGING
PRODUCT BY ALLURE MAGAZINE.
>> YOU'LL LOVE HOW IT TARGETS
THE LOOK OF FROWN LINES,
CROW'S FEET, AND EVEN
EXPRESSION LINES
AND LIP LINES.
>> IT'S JUST LIKE SILK
IN LITTLE CAPSULES.
YOU CAN APPLY IT HERE, UP HERE,
AND HERE ON THOSE SMILE LINES.
THEY'RE JUST AMAZING.
>> IMAGINE YOU GET ALL THESE
AGE DEFINING SUPER TREATMENTS
FOR JUST $59.95.
THAT'S AN INCREDIBLE STEAL.
>> BUT WHAT IF WE COULD
GO EVEN LOWER.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> TODAY, CINDY IS OFFERING
A SPECIAL ONE TIME REWARD
FOR SMART SHOPPERS
WHO ACT QUICKLY.
>> ORDER IN THE NEXT 10 MINUTES
AND USE TODAY'S SPECIAL COUPON
CODE AND YOU WON'T PAY $59.95,
NOT $49.95, BUT JUST $39.95
FOR EVERYTHING YOU SEE HERE.
>> PICK UP THE PHONE,
TRY IT.
IT'S GONNA MAKE YOU
FEEL BEAUTIFUL.
FEEL MORE CONFIDENT.
IT'S GONNA MAKE YOU
FEEL REVITALIZED.
YOU'RE GONNA BE THRILLED,
I PROMISE YOU.
>> REMEMBER TO MENTION
TODAY'S SPECIAL COUPON CODE
WHEN YOU CALL TO LOCK IN
ALL YOUR DISCOUNTS
AND FREE GIFTS.
>> WE'LL EVEN FAST TRACK YOUR
SHIPMENT WITH A FREE UPGRADE
TO PRIORITY SHIPPING.
>> BUT SUPPLIES ARE LIMITED,
SO CALL NOW AND START LOOKING
YOUNGER LIKE CINDY WITH
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED.
>> IMAGINE YOU'RE SITTING
AT HOME, THE PHONE RINGS,
AND IT'S CINDY CRAWFORD
INVITING YOU TO SPEND
THE DAY WITH HER.
SOUND IMPOSSIBLE?
WELL, THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT HAPPENED TO THIS
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY CUSTOMER.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> THIS IS SO EXCITING.
>> HELLO?
>> SHANNON?
>> YES?
>> HI, THIS IS CINDY CRAWFORD.
>> NO, IT'S NOT.
>> IT IS.
HOW CAN I PROVE IT?
>> OH, MY GOSH.
I'M SHAKING RIGHT NOW.
>> WELL, LISTEN, I AM GOING
TO NEW YORK THIS WEEK
AND I WAS WONDERING IF YOU
WANTED TO FLY UP ON FRIDAY
TO HANG OUT WITH ME
AND YOU KNOW, GO ON SOME
APPOINTMENTS WITH ME.
>> OH, MY GOSH, ARE YOU SERIOUS?
>> I AM SERIOUS AND ACTUALLY
ONE OF THE APPOINTMENTS
THAT I'M DOING IS
WITH DOCTOR SEBAGH.
AND IF YOU WANTED TO MEET HIM,
HE IS IN NEW YORK.
>> I WOULD LOVE TO, THANK YOU.
YES, YES.
>> SO, IF YOU THINK YOU
CAN GET OFF FROM WORK,
COME OUT AND HAVE A MEANINGFUL
BEAUTY DAY WITH ME.
>> THAT SOUNDS WONDERFUL.
OH, I'M SO EXCITED.
I WON'T BE ABLE TO SLEEP.
>> SHE'S IN.
♪
I ALWAYS LOVE COMING
BACK TO NEW YORK.
IT'S JUST SUCH A GREAT CITY
AND THE THING THAT'S INCREDIBLE
ABOUT NEW YORK IS THE ENERGY.
I THINK THAT'S WHAT I MISS MOST.
AND THIS VISIT IS
ESPECIALLY FUN BECAUSE
I'M GONNA MEET ONE OF MY
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY CUSTOMERS
FOR THE VERY FIRST TIME.
HI, SHANNON.
>> HI!
>> HOW ARE YOU?
>> OH, HOW ARE YOU?
IT'S SO NICE TO MEET YOU.
>> NICE TO MEET YOU.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR COMING UP.
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
I'M SO EXCITED.
>> YOU'RE A KINDERGARTEN
TEACHER, RIGHT?
>> I AM A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER.
>> AND YOU'RE FROM TEXAS.
>> FROM HOUSTON, THAT'S RIGHT.
>> IT'S EXCITING FOR ME
AND DOCTOR SEBAGH TO MEET YOU
AND GET TO EXPERIENCE
WHAT IT'S REALLY LIKE TO BE
ONE OF HIS PATIENTS.
>> THAT IS SO EXCITING.
>> SO, ON THAT NOTE,
LET'S BRING HIM IN.
DOCTOR SEBAGH.
>> HELLO, HOW ARE YOU?
PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
>> THIS IS SHANNON.
THIS IS JEAN-LOUIS.
>> YOU LOOK GREAT.
>> THANK YOU, THANKS TO YOU.
THANK YOU.
I HAD A TRIP TO NEW YORK
WHERE I WAS ABLE TO MEET
DOCTOR SEBAGH AND CINDY ALSO.
>> IT'S AMAZING.
IT'S REALLY NICE.
>> HE'S CHECKING
THE ELASTICITY NOW.
>> THE ELASTICITY IS VERY GOOD.
BECAUSE SHE'S USING MEANINGFUL
BEAUTY ON A DAILY BASIS,
SHOWS SUCH WONDERFUL RESULTS.
>> HE WAS INSPECTING MY SKIN.
WAS GIVING ME TIPS,
AND HE WAS VERY KNOWLEDGEABLE
ABOUT WHAT WAS GOING ON.
THAT REALLY IMPRESSED ME.
>> YOU NEED TO FEED YOUR
SKIN ON A DAILY BASIS.
IT'S QUIT ESSENTIAL
THE SAME WAY YOU FEED YOUR BODY.
SO, MEANINGFUL BEAUTY
WILL ALLOW YOU TO ACHIEVE
WHAT EVERYBODY WANTS.
GLOW RADIANCE AND AT THE END,
A YOUTHFUL APPEARANCE.
GIVING BACK THE CONFIDENCE
TO A WOMAN, THAT'S THE BEST
THING I CAN DO.
>> I WANT TO THANK
DOCTOR SEBAGH AND CINDY
SO MUCH BECAUSE WHEN YOU
FEEL BETTER ABOUT YOURSELF,
IT IS A LIFE CHANGING
EXPERIENCE.
I LOVE MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
LOVE IT.
>> LET'S TALK ABOUT THE NEW
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY SYSTEM.
AT THE CORE OF THIS THERE'S THIS
AMAZING CREME DE SERUM PRODUCT.
>> YES, DOCTOR SEBAGH,
REALLY HE TALKS ABOUT IT,
IT IS CREME DE LA CREME.
>> RIGHT.
>> THIS IS AS GOOD AS IT GETS.
AND SERUMS ARE THE HOT
THING IN SKIN CARE.
I KNOW YOU KNOW THAT FROM
ALL THE WORK THAT YOU DO.
BUT THEN YOU NORMALLY HAVE
TO USE A MOISTURIZER
ON TOP OF THAT.
SO, THIS TAKES OUT THAT STEP.
AND WHAT'S REALLY UNIQUE
IS WE COMBINED REALLY
THREE DIFFERENT PRODUCTS
IN ONE BOTTLE.
AND WHEN YOU PUMP IT OUT
ONTO YOUR HAND, RIGHT THEN
THEY'RE BLENDED TOGETHER
AND RIGHT AWAY YOU PUT IT
ONTO YOUR FACE.
AND THIS IS THE NEW NIGHT CREAM.
WE LOVED OUR OLD NIGHT CREAM.
THIS ROCKS.
AND IT HAS SUCH A SILKY
GLIDE ON YOUR SKIN.
AND THEN IN THE MORNING
YOU WAKE UP AND IT'S LIKE
YOUR SKIN JUST DRANK IT IN.
>> THIS HAS A REALLY
UNIQUE LOOK.
IT KIND OF IS FUTURISTIC,
BUT IT'S A COMBINATION
OF A CREAM AND A SERUM.
>> EXACTLY, INSIDE HERE
WE HAVE THE MELON COLORED,
WHICH IS OF COURSE OUR
SUPER ANTIOXIDANT,
THE MELON COMPLEX.
THE CLEAR IS HYALURONIC.
AND WHAT THAT DOES,
IT KIND OF ACTS LIKE
A SPONGE ON YOUR SKIN
AND IT HELPS YOUR SKIN GRAB
MOISTURE AND HOLD MOISTURE.
SO, IT GIVES IT THAT DEWY, LUSH,
HYDRATED, MOISTURIZED LOOK.
THEN THE WHITE IS
ANTI-AGING PEPTIDES.
AND THOSE HELP WITH
THE DEEP LINES,
THE FINE LINES.
HELP THE VOLUME IN YOUR SKIN.
NORMALLY YOU WOULD USE
A SERUM ALONE AND THEY'RE
USUALLY VERY EXPENSIVE.
>> RIGHT.
>> I MEAN, EVEN THIS SERUM,
DOCTOR SEBAGH SAID,
YOU KNOW, WE ASKED,
"WELL, WHAT PRICE COULD IT BE?"
AND HE SAID, "$200, $300."
>> THAT AMAZING.
>> AND IT'S FUN FOR ME
TO TRY NEW THINGS.
AND WHEN I NOTICE A DIFFERENCE
THEN I'M REALLY EXCITED TO SHARE
THAT WITH EVERYBODY ELSE.
>> THAT CREME DE SERUM
IS SO GOOD.
IT FEELS SO SILKY.
IT FEELS LIKE YOU'RE DOING 500
GREAT THINGS FOR YOUR SKIN.
>> YEAH, THIS IS AMAZING STUFF.
WHEN YOU PUT IT ON YOUR SKIN,
IT IMMEDIATELY FEELS YOUNGER.
I USE IT MORNING AND NIGHT.
I'M GREEDY.
>> UP NEXT: DISCOVER HOW
YOU CAN GET DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
NEW CREME DE SERUM DELIVERED
RIGHT TO YOUR DOOR FAST.
>> AND STILL TO COME:
CINDY TAKES THE MAKEUP OFF
TO GIVE YOU A PRIVATE,
PERSONAL DEMONSTRATION
OF HOW SHE USES
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY EVERYDAY.
>> IMAGINE THAT WITH ONE PHONE
CALL YOU COULD GET SOME OF
THAT SAME MAGIC THAT'S KEPT
CINDY CRAWFORD'S SKIN LOOKING
SO YOUTHFUL FOR OVER 17 YEARS.
>> WELL, NOW YOU CAN.
BECAUSE WITH THE NEW
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED,
DOCTOR SEBAGH IS MAKING HIS
AMAZING FRENCH MELON EXTRACT
AVAILABLE DIRECTLY TO YOU.
>> JUST WATCH AS OVER TIME
AN ORDINARY MELON WRINKLES,
AGES, AND DECAYS.
>> WHILE THE REMARKABLE
MELON ON THE RIGHT
STAYS FRESH AND FIRM.
>> CALL NOW AND GET STARTED
WITH CINDY'S LUXURIOUS
SKIN-SOFTENING CLEANSER.
>> THIS UNIQUE FORMULA CAN BE
USED WITH WATER OR DRY
TO CLEANSE AND REMOVE MAKEUP,
LEAVING YOUR SKIN SOFT,
DEWY, AND REFRESHED.
>> NEXT, YOU'LL GET
DOCTOR SEBAGH'S INCREDIBLE
ANTI-AGING DAY CREAM
FOR A BEAUTIFUL GLOW
THROUGHOUT YOUR DAY.
>> COMPLETE WITH BROAD SPECTRUM
SPF20 AND DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
RARE MELON EXTRACT.
>> YOU'LL ALSO RECEIVE HIS
NEW ADVANCED LIFTING EYE CREAM
TO REDUCE THE LOOK OF
PUFFINESS, DARK CIRCLES,
AND CROW'S FEET.
>> WHEN I'M TIRED
AND OVER-WORKED
IT SHOWS IN MY EYES.
SO, I LOVE, LOVE, LOVE
CINDY'S EYE CREAM.
THE LIFTING ONE.
THIS ONE.
THIS LITTLE MAGICAL
LITTLE BOTTLE.
IT TIGHTENS, IT LIFTS,
IT MAKES THE WRINKLES
LOOK LIKE THEY'RE GONE.
IT'S AMAZING.
>> YOU'LL ALSO GET
DOCTOR SEBAGH'S NEWLY ADVANCED
DECOLLETE AND NECK TREATMENT.
>> THE SKIN BRIGHTENING SUPER
CREAM HELPS SMOOTH THE LOOK OF
SUN DAMAGED SKIN AND MINIMIZES
THE APPEARANCE OF AGE SPOTS
IN THIS EYE-CATCHING AREA THAT
OFTEN SHOWS PREMATURE AGING.
>> AND FOR NIGHT TIME,
YOU'LL GET DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
GROUND-BREAKING NEW
CREME DE SERUM, WHICH FEATURES
THREE POWERFUL AGE-FIGHTING
FORMULAS SWIRLED INTO ONE.
>> MY SKIN FEELS SO SOFT
AND SMOOTH ONCE IT'S ON.
IT'S AN INCREDIBLE PRODUCT.
>> THIS STUFF IS AMAZING.
IT JUST GIVES YOUR SKIN
JUST A REAL SMOOTH FINISH.
IT'S LIKE VELVET.
>> DOCTOR SEBAGH HAS BEEN
CALLED "THE WONDER DOCTOR,"
"A MIRACLE WORKER,"
AND "THE YOUTH GURU."
>> HIS PATIENTS WAIT MONTHS
FOR AN APPOINTMENT
AND OFTEN PAY THOUSANDS
OF DOLLARS FOR A SERIES
OF TREATMENTS CONTAINING
HIS RARE MELON DISCOVERY.
>> THAT'S WHY THE REGULAR
PRICE OF ONLY $119 FOR
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED
IS ALREADY A TOTAL BARGAIN.
BUT BECAUSE CINDY IS USING
HER UNIQUE POSITION
TO BRING DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
ELITE FORMULAS DIRECT TO YOU
THROUGH TV WITHOUT
EXCESSIVE RETAIL MARKUPS,
YOU CAN SAVE BIG ON
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED.
>> JUST MENTION THIS
SPECIAL COUPON CODE WHEN
YOU CALL TOLL-FREE NOW
AND YOU'LL RECEIVE OVER 50%
IN INSTANT COUPON SAVINGS.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
ALL YOU'LL PAY IS JUST $59.95
FOR THE COMPLETE NEW
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED.
>> AND CINDY HAS A SPECIAL
PROPOSITION FOR YOU.
BE AMONG THE FIRST
FIVE HUNDRED CALLERS RIGHT NOW
AND SHE'LL SEND YOU $45 WORTH
OF PERSONAL GIFTS
ABSOLUTELY FREE.
>> YOU'LL GET DOCTOR SEBAGH'S
MODEL SECRET,
HIS INCREDIBLE GLOWING SERUM,
A FAVORITE OF HOLLYWOOD
INSIDERS THAT DOCTOR SEBAGH
NORMALLY RESERVES ONLY FOR HIS
EXCLUSIVE VIP CLIENTS.
>> AND WE'LL ALSO SEND YOU
DOCTOR SEBAGH'S ENHANCED
WRINKLE SMOOTHING CAPSULES.
NAMED A BEST NEW ANTI-AGING
PRODUCT BY ALLURE MAGAZINE.
>> YOU'LL LOVE HOW IT TARGETS
THE LOOK OF FROWN LINES,
CROW'S FEET, AND EVEN
EXPRESSION LINES
AND LIP LINES.
>> THE WRINKLE SMOOTHING
CAPSULES.
THESE ARE MAGIC.
YOU OPEN IT UP,
YOU SQUEEZE IT OUT ON YOUR HAND
AND WHEN YOU PUT IT ON
IT FEELS VELVETY.
I THINK THIS IS MY FRIEND.
>> IMAGINE YOU GET ALL THESE
AGE DEFYING SUPER TREATMENTS
FOR JUST $59.95.
THAT'S AN INCREDIBLE STEAL.
>> BUT WHAT IF WE COULD
GO EVEN LOWER.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> TODAY, CINDY IS OFFERING
A SPECIAL ONE TIME REWARD
FOR SMART SHOPPERS
WHO ACT QUICKLY.
>> ORDER IN THE NEXT 10 MINUTES
AND USE TODAY'S SPECIAL COUPON
CODE AND YOU WON'T PAY $59.95,
NOT $49.95, BUT JUST $39.95
FOR EVERYTHING YOU SEE HERE.
>> WHAT'S MORE,
YOU CAN LOCK IN THIS
ONE TIME DISCOUNT PRICE
AND INSURE YOU'LL NEVER
PAY A PENNY MORE.
>> THANKS TO CINDY'S
CONVENIENT HOME DELIVERY,
YOU'LL RECEIVE A FRESH SUPPLY
OF MEANINGFUL BEAUTY
EACH NEW SEASON.
>> ALWAYS AT OUR LOWEST
PRICE EVER, GUARANTEED.
>> AND YOUR ORDER IS RISK FREE,
THANKS TO A 60 DAY
MONEY BACK GUARANTEE
FROM TRUSTED GUTHY RENKER.
>> WITH MEANINGFUL BEAUTY
YOU WILL FEEL THE DIFFERENCE
IN YOUR SKIN IMMEDIATELY.
THE VERY FIRST TIME I USED
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY I WAS HOOKED,
AND MY SKIN HAS NEVER
LOOKED BETTER.
>> REMEMBER TO MENTION
TODAY'S SPECIAL COUPON CODE
WHEN YOU CALL TO LOCK IN
ALL YOUR DISCOUNTS
AND FREE GIFTS.
>> WE'LL EVEN FAST TRACK YOUR
SHIPMENT WITH A FREE UPGRADE
TO PRIORITY SHIPPING.
>> BUT SUPPLIES ARE LIMITED,
SO CALL NOW AND START LOOKING
YOUNGER LIKE CINDY WITH
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED.
>> I STILL CAN'T BELIEVE
WHEN PEOPLE COME UP TO ME
AND ASK ME IF I REALLY
USE MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
I DO USE MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
AND I'M GONNA SHOW YOU HOW
I USE IT AT HOME EVERY DAY.
IN THE MORNING,
THE ONE STEP I WOULD NEVER
SKIP IS THE DAY CREAM.
DURING THE DAY YOU HAVE
TO PROTECT YOUR SKIN
AND YOU CAN DO THAT IN
A COUPLE DIFFERENT WAYS.
YOU CAN DO THAT WITH
ANTIOXIDANTS, WHICH WE HAVE
OUR SPECIAL MELON IN HERE,
BUT ALSO WE HAVE SPF.
IT GOES ON SUPER LIGHT,
IT'S NOT GREASY,
IT'S GREAT UNDER MAKEUP.
SO, NEXT I USE THE EYE CREAM,
AND I HAVE FOUND,
NOW THAT I'M GETTING ON
IN MY 40S,
I HAVE THIS WHOLE NEW
BEAUTY CONCERN OF PUFFINESS.
SO, WE REFORMULATED
THE EYE CREAM
AND THIS EYE CREAM
REALLY IS ACTION PACKED.
AND IT ADDRESSES
UNDER-EYE CIRCLES, PUFFINESS,
AND THE APPEARANCE
OF FINE LINES.
SINCE THE BEGINNING OF
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY WE'VE BEEN
TALKING TO YOU ABOUT TAKING
CARE OF YOUR NECK AND CHEST.
SO MANY WOMEN FORGET
ABOUT THIS AREA,
AND IT REALLY SHOWS YOUR AGE.
EVERYONE SEES IT,
ESPECIALLY IF YOU WANT
TO WEAR SOMETHING LOW CUT.
SO, OUR NEW DECOLLETE TREATMENT
HAS SPF IN IT AND WE PUT IN
SOME BRIGHTENING INGREDIENTS.
IT JUST GIVES YOUR SKIN
THAT DEWY LUSHNESS THAT
HAS VIBRANCY TO IT.
OKAY, NOW LET'S TALK ABOUT OUR
NEW PRODUCT THE CREME DE SERUMS.
THIS IS JEAN-LOUIS' LATEST BABY
AND IT'S TOTALLY INNOVATIVE.
IT'S THREE DIFFERENT PRODUCTS
SWIRLED INTO ONE.
YOU'RE GETTING HYDRATION,
YOU'RE GETTING PROTECTION,
YOU'RE GETTING
ANTI-AGING PEPTIDES.
IT'S ALL IN THIS
ONE GREAT PRODUCT.
WHEN YOU PUT IT ON
IT'S SO SILKY.
AND WHEN YOU WAKE UP YOU
HAVE THAT GREAT FRESH GLOW.
WITH MEANINGFUL BEAUTY
I KNOW MY SKIN IS GETTING
EVERYTHING IT NEEDS
TO FIGHT THE GOOD FIGHT.
FIGHT THAT AGING PROCESS.
AND IT REALLY FEELS LIKE
NUTRITION FOR MY SKIN
AND THAT'S WHAT I WANT.
>> I FEEL EVERY DAY
WITH MEANINGFUL BEAUTY
LIKE I HAVE EXACTLY WHAT MY
SKIN NEEDS TO KEEP IT LOOKING
YOUNG AND FRESH AND NATURAL.
>> WITH MEANINGFUL YOU LOOK
YOUTHFUL, YOU LOOK YOUNGER,
AND YOUR SKIN LOOKS GREAT.
>> YOU'VE GOT TO TRY THIS STUFF.
I REALLY CAN'T TELL YOU ENOUGH
HOW GREAT MEANINGFUL BEAUTY IS.
>> I'M SUPER THANKFUL FOR CINDY
FOR BRINGING MEANINGFUL BEAUTY
TO US BECAUSE I FEEL LIKE
NOW I HAVE A CHANCE.
>> WITH MEANINGFUL BEAUTY YOU
ACTUALLY SEE FANTASTIC RESULTS,
AND THAT'S SO EXCITING
BECAUSE I'VE BEEN SEARCHING.
>> IT IS TAKING ALL
THE BLOTCHINESS AWAY.
IT IS EVEN OUT MY SKIN TONE.
I AM SO HAPPY THAT I TRIED
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY.
I'M SO GLAD I DID.
>> THERE'S STILL TIME.
ORDER NOW AND SEE HOW
AGELESS AND BEAUTIFUL
YOUR SKIN CAN LOOK WITH
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED.
>> IF I WERE YOU
I WOULDN'T WAIT.
CALL NOW, AND IF OPERATORS
ARE BUSY, KEEP ON TRYING.
>> YOU HAVE TO GO
AND GET THIS STUFF.
YOU HAVE TO TRY IT
FOR YOURSELF TO SEE.
>> THIS HAS BEEN
A PAID PRESENTATION FOR
MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED
BY CINDY CRAWFORD.
BROUGHT TO YOU BY GUTHY RENKER.
♪
>>> THIS MORNING, A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA" AS THE PRESIDENT
PREPARES TO VISIT A SHATTERED
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT,
CONNECTICUT, WHERE WE ARE
LEARNING MUCH MORE ABOUT THE MAN
BEHIND THE WORST ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN AMERICAN
HISTORY.
>> HE ALWAYS CARRIED A BRIEFCASE
AND THAT'S WHAT STICKS OUT IN MY
MIND.
>> DID HIS MOTHER, THE FIRST
VICTIM, GIVE HIM TARGET
PRACTICE?
>>> ALSO THIS MORNING FOR THE
FIRST TIME WE ARE HEARING THE
SURVIVAL STORY FROM INSIDE HIS
SCHOOL.
>> THE FIRST WORDS SHE TELLS WAS
MOMMY, I'M OKAY, BUT ALL MY