THE WAY THEY CAN PROCESS IT
AND HANDLE IT, I FEEL HORRIBLE
FOR FAMILY, FOR THEM.
>> YOUNG JACK WAS A NEW YORK
GIANTS FOOTBALL FAN.
WIDE RECEIVER VICTOR CRUZ
VISITED HIS GRIEVING FAMILY
AND WROTE IS HE MY CHEERO ON
HIS CLEATS.
THIS IS WHERE MOURNERS HUGGED
AND CRIED.
A SCENE PLAYING OUT MORE THAN
TWO DOZEN TIMES IN THE
COMMUNITY THAT IS JUST
STARTING TO HEAL.
>> NEWTOWN IS FOREVER CHANGED.
AND WE CAMES A COMMUNITY THAT,
IS WHO WE ARE.
WE'RE HERE FOR THE PINTOS.
>> WE'RE BACK LIVE, YOU CAN
SEE OUTPOURING OF EMOTIONS.
AND SUPPORT FOR THIS
COMMUNITY.
FOLKS HERE COMING ALL DAY ALL
NIGHT, AND A STREAM OF CARS
HERE SINCE WE'VE BEEN HERE.
TO GIVE YOU A PERSPECTIVE,
AGAIN THIS IS THE CENTER OF
TOWN.
LOOKING UP STREET WE'RE
SHOWING YOU THERE IS÷19z A LINF
POLICE.
THAT IS THE STREET THAT IS
WHERE THIS SCHOOL IS LOCATED.
YOU CAN SEE THEY HAVE POLICE
HERE AND A LINE OF COLUMNS
GOING UP THE STREET.
THEY'RE ALLOWING THE PUBLIC TO
WALK UP TO THE AREA THERE.
THE FIRE HOUSE WHERE THE KIDS
RAN TO IS THAT ANOTHER LARGE
PUBLIC MEMORIAL.
TONIGHT HOW A CALIFORNIA
FAMILY REACHED ALL THE WAYQGme=T
HERE TO PAY THEIR RESPECTS AND
GIVE SOME SUPPORT TO THIS
COMMUNITY, AGAIN, TONIGHT AT
6:00.
LIVE IN SANDY HOOK, ABC 7
NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
>> WELL, THERE WILL BE A
MEMORIAL FOR THE VICTIMS OF
THE TRAGEDY TONIGHT HERE IN
THE BAY AREA ON THE PENINSULA.
A SERVICE OF REMEMBRANCE
GETTING UNDERWAY IN
BURLINGAME.
THIS SERVICE BEGINS AT 7:00
P.M.yI?V
ON THE CHURCH ON EASTON KRIF.
>> SHOOTING PROMPTED TWO STATE
AGENCIES TO REVIEW THEIR PLANS
FOR SCHOOLS AND WORK PLACE AS
CROSS CALIFORNIA.
NANNETTE MIRANDA JOINS US LIVE
NOW.
NANNETTE?
>> THIS PLAN JUST DOESN'T
INCLUDE SHOOTINGS BUT SUPPOSED
TO INCLUDE RESPONSES FOR
EARTHQUAKES, FIRES AND OTHER
SITUATIONS.
ONCE STATE LAWMAKER SAYS SELF
REPORTING ISN'T WORKING.
EVERY JULY, HOW THEY EVACUATE
STURD YENTS, WHETHER THEY HAVE
LOCKED DOORS, WHICH PEOPLE DO
THEY LET IN?
ARE SECURITY CAMERAS IN PLACE?
ARE THE STAFF TRAINED?
ONE SENATOR IS UPSET THAT THE
LAST NUMBERS HE CAN FIND
INDICATE THAT OVER HALF DID
NOT COMPLY IN 2009.
>> AND BECAUSE WE DON'T KEEP A
GOOD TRACK, WE DON'T KNOW IN
TWO YEARS WHETHER SITUATION
HAS GONE GOTHEN WORSE OR
BETTER.
>> IN LIGHT OF THE SHOOTING
STATE ASKED ALL CALIFORNIA
SCHOOLS... TO REVIEW THEIR
SAFETY PLANS.
AFTER COLUMBINE, LAWMAKERS
ALLEGEO INDICATED $90 MILLION
FOR IMPROVEMENTS.
BUT AS RECESSION ROLLED ON,
AND SQUEEZED STATE BUDGET,
FINANCE CONSULTANTS SAY LEADER
AS LOUED FLEXIBILITY IN HOW
MONEY IS SPENT.
>> THAT MEANSa      "s IT'S
UNRESTRICTED FUNDING NOW.
>> SCHOOLS SUPERINTENDENT SAYS
CALIFORNIA SCHOOLS ARE SAFE.
THERE ARE LESSON BUZZ WE CAN'T
GO TO EXTREME.
>> WE CAN'T LIVE IN FEAR AND
TURN OUR SCHOOLS INTO FOR
TRESS WAS BARBED WIRE.
THERE COULD BE COST TO THAT,
CHANGING ATMOSPHERE OF THE
SCHOOLS.
WE WANTío TO FIND THE BALANCE.
>> THE STATE SENATOR THINKS
CALIFORNIA SCHOOLS SHOULD
START WITH BASICS OF HAVING A
SAFETY PLAN IN PLACE.
AND REINTRODUCING A BILL FROM
SCHOOLS IF THEY DON'T HAVE ONE
IN PLACE IN CASE A SHOOTING
HAPPENED HERE ITS SO TRAGIC.
I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE IN
CALIFORNIA THAT WE TAKE STEPS
TO PRY TRI TO PREVENLT FUTURE
TRAGEDIES.
>> SUPERINTENDENT SAYS A
PROPOSED BOND FOR 2014 WILL
LIKELY MANDATE THAT ALL NEW
SCHOOLS BUILT BE INCLUDE
SAFETY MEASURES IN PLACE LIKE
LIMITED ACCESS.
FLIF SACRAMENTO, ABC 7 NEWS.
>> THANK YOU.
A NEW ABC NEWS WASHINGTON POST
POLL SHOWS SUPPORT FOR
STRICTER GUN CONTROL AT A
FIVE-YEAR HIGH.
54% WANT STRICTER LAWS.
59% SUPPORT A BAN ON
AMMUNITION CLIPS AND 52% WANT
A BAN ON SEMI AUTOMATIC
HANDGUN AUTOS CLASSES RESUMED
IN TWO SOUTH BAY SCHOOLS SHUT
DOWN BECAUSE OF A BOMB THREAT
DIRECTED AS A TEACHER.
CLASSES RESUMED ATMONTA VISTA
HIGH SCHOOL.
KEPT THEM CLOSED ON FRIDAYhMzXñ,
AND THEY HAD A CALL TO REOPEN
FOLLOWING THE ARREST OF THE
16-YEAR-OLD SUSPECT.
PARENTS FACE DIFFICULT TIME
EXPLAINING THING OWES TO THEIR
KIDS.
>> THIS IS A VERY DELICATE.
HAVE YOU TO EXPLAIN IT TO
KIDS.
THEY CANNOT UNDERSTAND THE
DETAILS THAT, YOU KNOW?
IN THEIR MINDS.
SO IN A WAY THAT SAFETY IS
NECESSARY.
THEY HAVE BEEN DOING GOOD
WORK.
>> POLICE SAY THE 16-YEAR-OLD
CONFESSED TO CLAIMING A BOMB
WAS BLAIS PLAISED ON CAMPUS.
NO DEVICE WAS FOUND.
THE TEENAGER FACES FELONY
CHARGES IN JUVENILE COURT.
>> NOW, ABC 7 NEWS WILL
CONTINUE TO COVER THE SHOOTING
TRAJ DMI NEWTOWN AS IT
UNFOLDS.
AT 5:30 ON WORLD NEWS A CLOSER
LOOK AT THE TWO ADUT SURVIVORS
PLAYING A KEY ROLE INTO THE
INVESTIGATION.
AND YOU CAN EXPRESS YOUR
SYMPATHYES BY POSTING THIS
BADGE TO YOUR FACEBOOK WALL IN
A SHOW OF SUPPORT FOR EVERYONE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> AND STUDENTS AND STAFF ARE
MOURNING LOSS OF ONE OF THEIR
SENIOR FOOTBALL PLAYERS.
THE 17-YEAR-OLD SHOT AND
KILLED SATURDAY NIGHT.
ABC 7 NEWS IS LIVE FOR US IN
CONCORD TONIGHT.
>> STUDENTS TELL US THERE WAS
A MOMENT OF SILENCE FOR
MONTREAL BLAKELY.
BLAKELY PLAYED OFFENSE AND
DEFENSE FOR THE FOOTBALL TEAM
POLICE SAY HE WAS SHOT AND
KILLED SATURDAY NIGHT IN SAN
FRANCISCO BAY VIEW DISTRICT.
AROUND 10.
A FRIEND TOOK HIM TO THE
HOSPITAL WHERE HE WAS PRO
DOWNSED -- PRONOUNCED DEAD
NCHL ADDITION TO MOMENT OF
SILENCE, STUDENTS SAY MANY
WORE BLACK TODAY. THEY FOUND
OUT ABOUT HIS DEATH YESTERDAY.
SLEEA SOCIAL MEDIA.
THERE IS A VIGIL YIL PLANNED
FRIDAY EVENING ON THE FOOTBALL
FIELD, PARENTS WEARY OF WHAT
FEELS LIKE UNRELENTDING
VIOLENCE.
>> THERE IS NO VALUE PUT ONLY.
EVERY DAY YOU READ ABOUT
SOMETHING, HEARING ABOUT
SOMETHING WHERE TAKING
SOMEONE'S LIFE SEEMS TO BE THE
MOST IMMEDIATE, SIMPLE WAY TO
ADDRESS A PROBLEM.
>> IT WAS SHOCKING.
VERY TRAGIC.
I HEARD HE WAS A GREAT GUY.
I DIDN'T -- I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT
TO THINK.
>> PEOPLE HAVE BEEN SAYING ON
TWITTER, FACEBOOK.
PEOPLE POSTING PICTURES.
AND HE WAS A GOOD PERSON.
>> STUDENTS HERE SAYING THEY
HAVE NO IDEA WHY WOE HAVE BEEN
IN SAN FRANCISCO ON SATURDAY
NIGHT.
ALSO, POLICE ARE?÷B> REVEALING
VERY FEW DETAILS ABOUT THIS
CASE AND THEY ARE ASKING FOR
HELP IN SOLVING THIS MURDER.
>> SO SAD.
THANK YOU.
>> THE POLICE CHIEFS OF
OAKLAND ASK SAN FRANCISCO
CALLING A WEEKEND GUN BUY BACK
A SMALL VICTORY IN THE FACE OF
THE RAMPAGE.
THE BUY BACK TOOK 600 GUNS OFF
THE STREET.
300 IN OAKLAND, 300 IN SAN
FRANCISCO.
HELD ON SATURDAY NIGHTS JUST
HOURS AFTER THE NAS MASA KER.
>> WE WANT TO CONTINUE
PARTNERSHIP IN THESE GROUPS ON
THE HEELS OF WHAT TOOK PLACE
FRIDAY SHOWS THE COMMUNITY
VERY CONCERNED ABOUT VISHLGS
PEOPLE BEGINNING TO TAKE
ACTION TO REDUCE VIOLENCE IN
THIS CITY.
>> OAKLAND MAYOR SAYS SHE'S
HOPING TO HOLD ANOTHER BUY
BACK SOON BECAUSE MANY PEOPLE
SHOWED UP ON SATURDAY, THEY
RAN OUT OF MONEY.
>> THERE WAS JUST ENOUGH RAIN
z÷ UMBRELLAS
OPEN AND PUDDLE DODGING GOING
ON NEAR UNION SQUARE THIS
AFTERNOON.
SANDHYA PATEL IS HERE NOW TO
LET US KNOW.
>> I WOULD HANG ONTO IT.
LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD SHOWING YOU
WE DO HAVE SHOWERS LEFT,
REALLY HOST OF THESE WINDING
DOWN.
THERE IS MOUNTAIN VIEW AREA IS
JUST STARTING TO WIND DOWN.
NOW, INTO5u
ROUTE 88 AND 4.
80 NOT REQUIRING CONTROLS,
WINTER STORM WARNING IS GOING
UNTIL MIDNIGHT TONIGHT.
SO JUST KEEP THAT IN MIND.
COUPLE MORE INCHES EXPECTED SO
xM
INCHES HAVE FALLEN.
AND THERE WILL BE MORE COMING.
SO MORE STORMS DMU THIS WEEK.
WHEN WILL YOU NEED UMBRELLAS?
WHAT WILL CHRISTMAS EVE LOOK
LIKE?
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WITH PROLIFERATION OF HOME
SOLAR SYSTEMS, WARN GOINGING
OUT ABOUT COLD SNAP SANDHYA IS
TALKING ABOUT.
CRACKED PIPES ARE A
POSSIBILITY.
ABC 7 NEWS IS LIVE IN SAN JOSE
TO EXPLAIN WHAT TO DO.
DAVID?
>> RISING RIVERS AND CREEKS
ARE HAS YARDS WHEN STORMS HIT.
BUT FREEZING TEMPERATURES CAN
CAUSE THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS OF
DAMAGE.
FLOODING HAS BECOME PART OF
THE NORM WHEN HIGH TIDES
COINCIDE.
BUT THE FREEZING TEMPERATURES
EXPECTED LATE TUESDAY NIGHT
POSE A THREAT.
DAMAGE TO LANDSCAPINvI< AND ROF
TOP SYSTEMS.
ANNIE IS A POOL AND LANDSCAPE
CONTRACTOR.
>> IF YOU HAVE SOLAR PLUMBING,
LIKE SOLAR FOR SWIMMING POOLS
HAVE YOU TO EMPTY ALL OF THE
PANELS TO MAKE SURE THATáU@0HEY
DON'T FREEZE HE WARN THAT'S A
THIN LAYER CAN FORM IN POOLS,
AS ICE EXPANDS CAN CRACK TILE
WORK IN OLDER POOLS.
A COLD SNAP CAN BE HAZARDOUS.
THIS CENTER IS ONE OF THREE
OPERATED BY THE EHS LIFE
BUILDERS.
THE CAPACITY HERE IS 250 BUT
104 FLOOR MATS ARE SET OUT.
>> WATERING SYSTEM IN PLACE IS
NOT A FACTOR DURING THESE
EXTREME COLD WEATHER MONTHS
LIKE THIS.
OR THES⌟♪ NIGHTS WEX TRIED TO
SERVE THAT IN BETTER SEEKING
SHELTER FOR THE NIGHT.
>> BLANKETS, TOWELS AND SOAP
PROVIDED WITH HOT MEALS.
HOMELESS CAN WASH, DRY THEIR
OWN CLOTHING DURING THEIR
STAY.
CLIENTS SAY THE OPPORTUNITY TO
ESCAPE FREEZING WEATHER IS A
LIFE SAVER SINCE HOSTILE
CONDITIONS CAN LEAD TO
SICKNESS, MARK WHEELER KNOW
THAT'S FROM PERSONAL
EXPERIENCE.
>> IT TAKES A LITTLE BIT OF
RAIN TO GET CLOTHES WET.
THEN, YOU'RE FREEZING.
HYPE THERMA. THERE ARE PEOPLE
THAT DIE OUT THERE.
IT'S SAD.
>> THERE ARE ARMRIES IN
SUNNYVALE GOING TO BE OPEN
TOMORROW NIGHT AS COLD WEATHER
SHELTERS.
IN SAN JOSE, ABC 7 NEWS.
>> GOOD INFORMATION, THANK
YOU.
>> COMING UP, DOG THAT COULD
BE KEY TO HELPING POLICE IN
THE EAST BAY SOLVE A RAPE
CASE.
>> AND A MAJOR MEDICAL GROUP
GIVES OKAY NOW TO A
CONTROVERSIAL INGREDIENT
BANNED FROM CHILDREN VACCINES.
>> PLUS, EVENTS THAT FOUND A
DUCHESS OF CAMBRIDGE STEPPING
OUT PUBLICLY FOR THE FIRST
TIME SINCE BEING HOSPITALIZED
WITH SEVERE MORNING SICKNESS.
>>> PLIS LOOKING FOR LEADS IN
THE SEARCH FOR A RAPIST THAT
TACKED A WOMAN THAT WAS HIKING
IN THE REGIONAL WILDERNESS
WHEN SWAULTDED ON WEDNESDAY BY
A MAN WALKING HIS DOG.
SHE DESCRIBED THE MAN BEING
FIVE FEET, 10 INCHES TALL.
SHE SAID THE DOG WAS BROWN AND
WHITE, MEDIUM SIZED WITH ONE
EAR UP, ONE DOWN, SHE CANNOT
TELL THE BREED F YOU CAN HELP
YOU'RE ASKED TO CALL THE ALAMO
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
>> IN SAN FRANCISCO,
FIREFIGHTERS CAME TO THE
RESCUE OF A MAN SNUCK A
CHIMNEY OVERNIGHT.
THE RESCUE CAUSED QUITE A
COMMOTION FOR PEOPLE LIVING IN
THIS APARTMENT APARTMENTING
NEAR CLAY STREET AND PRESS
INDIVIDUAL YIDO AVENUE.
INVESTIGATORS AREN'T SURE WHY
HE WAS INSIDE OF THE CHIMNEY.
CREWS HAD TO LOOSEN SEVERAL
BRICKS TO GET HIM OUT.L
>> AND A BODY WASH ADD SHORE
YESTERDAY HAS BEEN IDENTIFIED
AS A MAN WHO WENT MISSING LAST
WEEK FROM A TUG BOAT.
THE CONTRA COSTA COUNTY
CORONER SAYS A 77-YEAR-OLD
BROWNED HE WAS REPORTED
MISSING DECEMBER 9th HELPING
CLEAN DEBRIS FROM A SHIP
DOCKED IN VALLEJO.
THE WOD BODY FOUND BY A HIKER
IN POINT PINOLE YESTERDAY.
>> A LEADING DOCTOR'S GROUP
SAYS A CONTROVERSIAL
PRESERVATIVE USED IN CHILDHOOD
VACCINES SHOULD NOT BE BANNED
BY 9 UNITED NATIONS.
SAYING IT IS NOT A HASUS
SOURCE OF MERCURY N 19999
GROUP HELPED TO GETócLy THIMERL
REMOVED BUT TWO STUDIES FOUND
NO EVIDENCE IT CAN CAUSE
AUTISM.
MEANTIME, FDA HAS GIVEN A NOD
TO THE FIRST FLU VACCINE
INTENDED TO PROTECT AGAINST
FOUR STRAINS OF THE VIRUS.
THE DRUG MAKER SAYS IT WILL BE
AVAILABLE FOR 2013, 2014 FLU
SEASON.
UNLIKE CURRENT VACCINES IT
WILL INCLUDE TWO STRAINS OF
THE FLU B AS WELL AS TWO
STRAINS OF A.
PANELS SAYS VACCINES HAVE BEEN
MANUFACTURED TO INCLUDE
STRAINS.
>> TECHNOLOGY NEWS, APPLE
TODAY IS REPORTING BRISK SALES
OF THE iPHONE 5 IN CHINA
DURING ITS FIRST THREE DAYS ON
THE MARKET THERE.
APPLE SAYS IT SOLD MORE THAN
TWO MILLION PHONES IN CHINA
SINCE FRIDAY.
AND EXPERTS SAY IT CAN BE
AVAILABLE IN MORE THAN 100
COUNTRIES.
>> THE DUCHESS OF CAMBRIDGE
STEPPED UT FOR HER FIRST
PUBLIC APPEARANCE SINCEMENT
HOSPITALIZED FOR ACUTE MORNING
SICKNESS PRESENTING TWO AWARDS
AT THE BBC SPORTS PERSONALITY
OF THE YEAR, SHE SEEMED
HEALTHY WEARING A GREEN DRESS.
THE DUCHESS APPEARED WITH OUT
HER HUSBAND, PRINCE WILLIAM
WHO HAD A PREVIOUS COMMIT NMT
A MOVIE PREMIER.
>> NASA TWIN PROBES ENDED
THEIR GRAVITY MAPPING MISSION
TODAY.
THE SPACE AGENCY INTENTIONALLY
CRASHED DISH WASHER SIZED
CRAFTS INTO THE SIDE OF A
CRATER NEAR THE NORTH POLL.
THIS MISSION LAUNCHED IN
SEPTEMBER, 20116789 NASA SAYS
THEY PRODUCE THE HIGHEST
RESOLUTION FIELD MAP OF ANY
CELESTIAL BODY TO DATE.
PROVIDING A BETTER
UNDERSTANDING OF HOW THEY
FORMED OVER THE IONS.
>> MAZING.
>> YES. SIT.
>> WE'RE EXPECTING MORE RAIN
AND VERY COLD TEMPERATURES.
>> YES.
>> THIS IS MILD IN COMPARISON
IT IS GOING TO BE CHILLY
TONIGHT.
WE MAY SEE FROST.
>> SO SNOW JUST ENDED IN THE
LAKE TAHOE AREA, JUST MINUTES
AGO. YOU'RE LOOKING AT THIS
VIEW RM.
YOU CAN SEE SKIES CLEARING OUT
MEANING CHILL WILL BE SETTLING
IN, AS WE HEAD INTO TOMORROW
MOSHING.
SO YOU'LL NEED TO BUNDLE UP.
TRACKING JUST ISOLATED SOURCE
WE HAVE OUR OWN RADAR.
A LOT OF THE STORMS HAVE BEEN
COMING IN FROM THE NORTH,
NORTHWEST.
WE HAVE MONTEREY BAY NATIONAL
WEATHER SERVICE RADAR TRACKING
SHOWERS DOWN.
YOU CAN SEE THEM AROUND THE
MONTEREY BAY.
SO 22/100ths IN SAN FRANCISCO.
SANTA ROSA AIRPORT JUST OVER A
HALF INCH.
LIVERMORE VALLEY DIDN'T PICK
UP MUCH.
7/100ths.
MOFFETT FIELD, 1300.
SAN JOSE, 15/100ths.
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS OVER AN
INCH OF RAIN IN 24 HOURS.
TEMPERATURESCó9f[ NOW, INTO 50s.
HIGH SO FAR HAVE BEEN IN THE
MID-50s.
TO MID-60s AROUND PLACES LIKE
MONTEREY.
THAT IS LIGHT CHANCE OF
SHOWERS FREEZING CONDITIONS
COMING YOUR WAY.
SO THIS IS A FRONT THAT
BROUGHT US RAIN, MAKING FOR A
SLOPPY COMMUTE.
NOW, WE'RE WATCHING THIS COLD
AIR, THIS LOW PRESSURE SYSTEM
FROM THE GULF OF SKA SKARKS
THIS IS WHAT IS GOING TO
PRODUCE SLIGHT CHANCE OF
SHOWERS TOMORROW AND CERTAINLY
BRINGING US A POSSIBILITY OF
FROST BY WEDNESDAY MORNING.
LOOKINGÑWw0s ACROSS PRA PACIFICE
DO HAVE AN ACTIVE PATTERN,
HANG ON TO RAIN GEAR, YOU'LL
NEED UMBRELLAS HEADING INTO
NEXT WEEK.
SO HERE, STARTING AT 7:00 P.M.
TONIGHT, YOU CAN SEE SKIES
CLEARING AROUND THE BAY AREA.
AND THEN, WE'LL SEE HIT OR
MISS SHOWERS ALONG THE COAST.
IT'S GOING TO BE A SLIGHT
POSSIBILITY.
COLD LOW PRESSURE SYSTEM JUST
PARALLELS THE COAST.
NOT MAKING IT OVER LAND.
TOMORROW MORNING MAKE SURE
HAVE YOU A JACKET OR SWEATER,
SIT GOING TO BE COLD.
CLOSE TO FREEZING IN SANTA
ROSA.
34 DEGREES NOT QUITE AS COLD
AROUND SAN FRANCISCO.
45.
43 OAKLAND.
36 DEGREES BY MORNING IN
LIVERMORE.
TOMORROW AFTERNOON, IT WILLPç E
COOL.
TEMPERATURES INTO LOW TO
MID-50s UNDER PARTLY CLOUDY
SKIES.
YOU'LL NOTICE MID-40s AROUND
CLOVER DALE, 47 DEGREES.
SO ON THE CHILL EYE SIDE
TORTDZ THE NORTH.
53 IN SAN FRANCISCO.
PALO ALTO AND SAN JOSE.
A SLIGHT SHOWERS, MORE OF COLD
AIR YOU'RE GOING TO START TO
FEEL.
AROUND THE MONTEREY BAY, 54 IN
N SANTA CRUZ AND WATSONVILLE.
HERE IS THE ACCU-WEATHER
FORECAST AND WHAT IS COMING.
SLIGHT CHANCE OF SHOWERS
TOMORROW, LOW TO MID-50s FOR
HIGHS.
GOING TO BE FREEZING COLD IN
VALLEYS WEDNESDAY MORNING.
WE'LL SEE FROST, LOW TO
MID-50s FOR HIGHS.
IT'S A DRY DAY.
MAKE SURE YOU COVER YOUR PLANS
IF YOU HAVE FROST SENSITIVE
PLANTS.
RAIN RETURNING THURSDAY WITH
ANOTHER SYSTEM MID TO UPPER
50s, WITNESS, WINDY FRIDAY.
ANOTHER SYSTEM COMING THROUGH
HERE, RAIN FOR THE WEEKEND.
TURNING INTO SHOWERS ON
SUNDAY.
AND BY CHRISTMAS EVE, I THINK
YOU'LL GET A CHANCE TO GET RID
OF THE UMBRELLAS AND DRY OUT,
TEMPERATURES IN MID-50s SO
LOOKING AT ACCU-WEATHER
FORECAST, I KNOW IT LOOKS LIKE
A LOT OF RAIN.
DON'T PANIC.
THE STORMS WE'RE LOOKING AT
LIVE WITH THE LATEST KMOOUTER
MODELS LOOK LIKE ONE STORM
BRINGS US RAIN, ANOTHER STORM
RAINFALL TOTALS OVER FOUR DAYS
WE'RE LOOKING AT THREE AND A
HALF TO FOUR AND A HALF INCHES
OF RAIN BUT THAT IS OVER FOUR]s
DAYS INTO THE WETTEST
LOCATIONS.
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS AND NORTH
BAY.
DON'T PANIC YET.
>> YOU'LL LET US KNOW WHEN?
>> RIGHT.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> STILL TO COME TWO SAN
FRANCISCO OFFICERS RECOGNIZED
FOR HELPING SAVE A NEWBORN
DESCRIBING HOW THEY SWUNG INTO
ACTION.
>> THEN, A HOLLYWOOD WHO DONE
IT?
POLICE AND ABC 7 VIC LEE TRY
TO FIND OUT WHO STOLE AN
UNRELEASED MOVIE.
IT'S A STORY ONLY ON ABC 7
ñT'S A STORY ONLY ON ABC 7
>> I CAN SEE THEM AND HEAR HIM,
CRYING TALKING WITH THE BABY
JUST TELLING THE BABY COME
BACK, BREATHE.
SO YOU KNOW THAT, IS SOMETHING
I'LL NEVER FORGET.
>> BABY NASH IS DOING BETTER.
SAN FRANCISCO GENERAL.
HIS MOTHER WILL BE ARRAIGNED
ON SEVERAL CHAIMPBLGS
INCLUDING WELLFUL CRUELTY.
>>u:Rqu SKATING STAR RUDY GALINO
HAS BEEN NAMED TO U.S. FIGURE
SKATING HALL OF FAME WINNING
TITLES IN 1989 AND
199067891996 WON THE U.S.
SINGLES TITLE IN FRICHBT CROWD,
REMEMBER AT HP PAVILION?
RETURNING AFTER EARNING A
BRONZE MEDAL AT WORLD
CHAMPIONSHIPS.
THE 43-YEAR-OLD NOW COACHES
SKATING IN SAN JOSE.
>> WHAT A CAREER.
>> YES OO. COMING UP NEXT A
3,000 ITEMS YAUSED TOo17k DECORE
THIS TREE.
>> YES.
THEY'RE ALL VERY FRAGILE.
>>> COMING UP A CASE OF VERY
BAD TIMING TONIGHT A GUN STORE
ABOUT TO OPEN ITS KOOR DOORS
OVER OCCASIONS OF NEIGHBOR
AUTOS PLANTING A DREAM.
THE EAST BAY CAMPUS HOPING TO
WIN A GRANT BY BECOMING A
LITTLE SCHOOL THAT COULD.
>> A BIG MOVE FOR SAN
FRANCISCO EXPLORATORIUM,
PACKING UP THE PAST, PREPARING
FOR THE FUTURE, THOSE STORIES
AND MORE COMING UP AT 6:00.
>> AND FINALLY HERE HOLIDAY
SPIRIT CLIMBING TO NEW HEIGHTS
IN ONE CITY.
>> YES.
>> NICKNAMED CITY OF TASTE.
IT'S FITTING THE CHRISTMAS
FREE TREE IS MADE OF DINING
WARE.
>> CHECK THAT OUT.
MADE OF 3,000 FLAITS PLAITS,
CUPS AND CROCKERY DONATED BY
THE PEOPLE.
SYMBOLIZES STAPLES SHARED BY
FAMILY AND FRIENDS, A SPECIAL
RECOGNITION FOR THOSE THAT
COULDN'T BE THERE.
>> AND YOU DON'T HAVE
>>> THIS IS "WORLD NEWS."
TONIGHT, WE TAKE YOU TO A SMALL
TOWN IN CONNECTICUT, WHERE SO
MANY FUNERALS HAVE BEGUN.
A DAY AFTER THE PRESIDENT'S
EMOTIONAL SPEECH.
>> WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE
THIS AS ROUTINE.
>> HE PROMISED TO TAKE ACTION.
TONIGHT, WHAT WILL HE DO FIRST?
>>> ALSO, NEW DETAILS TONIGHT
ABOUT THE YOUNG MAN CARRYING THE
RIFLE.
>> NANCY HAS ALWAYS INSTRUCTED
ME TO KEEP AN EYE ON HIM AT ALL
TIMES.
>>> AND PARENTS COME OUT OF THE
SHADOWS, SAYING THEY NEED HELP
WITH THEIR CHILDREN, TOO.
>> THIS IS A PROBLEM THAT WE'VE
KIND OF PUSHED TO THE MARGINS IN