>> Ama: GOOD EVENING, WE DO
BEGIN WITH BREAKING NEWS IN SAN
FRANCISCO.
ABC-7 NEWS REPORTER SERGIO QUINN
TAN   NICE ON CALIFORNIA AND
HYDE STREETS WERE POLICE ARE
SEARCHING FOR A GUNMAN.
REPORTER: AND ACTUALLY
CALIFORNIA JUST OPENED WITHIN
THE LAST TWO MINUTES.
IT HAD BEEN SHUT DOWN TO TRAFFIC
SINCE 6:30 THIS EVENING.
LET'S SHOW YOU SOME VIDEO WE
JUST SHOT.
A LITTLE LESS THAN AN HOUR AGO,
A MAN AND WOMAN WERE BROUGHT OUT
IN AUCTION, POLICE TELL US THIS
WAS A DOMESTIC VIOLENCE
SITUATION AND THEY WERE CALLED
HERE BY NEIGHBOR OF THE COUPLE.
THE NEIGHBOR TOLD POLICE HE
HEARD THE COUPLE WERE ARGUING IN
THEIR APARTMENT.
HE KNOCKED ON THEIR DOOR, AND
THE MAN SAID HE HAD A GUN, AND
THAT PROMPTED THIS RESPONSE BY
POLICE.
NOW AFTER THREE AND A HALF HOURS
OF NEGOTIATIONS, THE COUPLE DID
COME OUT UNHARMED.
AND THEY HAVE BEEN TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY.
POLICE TELL US THEY HAVE NOT YET
FOUND A FIREARM BUT THEY ARE
SEARCHING THAT APARTMENT.
REPORTING LIVE IN SAN FRANCISCO,
SERGIO QUINN TAN   FASHION ABC-7
NEWS.
>> Ama: AN EMOTIONAL OUTPOURING
FOR THE VICTIMS OF THE DEADLY
SHOOTING IN CONNECTICUT.
PEOPLE GATHERED FOR A
CANDLELIGHT VIGIL AT THE HOME
TOWN OF TEACHER VICTORIA SOTO.
AS THE COMMUNITY MOURNS WE NOW
KNOW THE NAMES OF THE YOUNGEST
VICTIMS.
REPORTER: TONIGHT WE'RE HEARING
A FATHER'S ANGUISH, ROBBY PARKER
LOST HIS DAUGHTER EMILY.
SHE WAS SIX.
>> I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU GET
THROUGH MICHIGAN LIKE -- THROUGH
SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
>> AND THIS EVENING A PORTRAIT
OF THE GUNMAN.
IN ONE CLASS, EVERY STUDENT BUT
ONE SHOT AND KILLED.
15 FIRST GRADES IN THAT ONE ROOM
ALONE LOST IN AN INSTANT IN
ANOTHER CLASSROOM, FIVE OF THE
VICTIMS WERE CHILDREN.
A LITTLE BOY WHO HAD A TWIN
SISTER, HE DIED.
HIS TWIN IN ANOTHER CLASSROOM,
HIDING IN THE BATHROOM WITH HER
TEACHER, SURVIVED.
THE SCHOOL PRINCIPAL IS AMONG
THE DEAD.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG AND SHE MIGHT
HAVE TURNED ON THE P.A. SYSTEM
SO THE EACHERS COULD BE WARNED.
MARY SHER HAWK.
HER FAMILY SAYING MARY FELT LIKE
SHE WAS DOING GOD'S WORK,
ANOTHER TEAMER, VICTOR YEAH
SOTO, HER BODY FOUND SHIELDING
HER STUDENTS.
>> HER LIFE'S DREAM WAS TO BE A
TEACHER, AND HER INSTINCTS
KICKED IN.
>> AND TONIGHT SOME OF THE
YOUNGEST FACES, KATHERINE
HUBBARD, SIX YEARS OLD, HER
FAMILY SAYING, WE'RE GREATLY
SADDENED BY THE LOSS OF OUR
BEAUTIFUL DAUGHTER, KATHERINE
VIOLET.
ANNA GREEN WAS SEVEN.
SHE GREW UP IN A HOME WITH JAZZ.
HER BROTHER SURVIVED IN THE
SCHOOL.
HER FATHER SAYING THEY'RE
STRUGGLING TO WORK THROUGH THE
NIGHTMARE, AND JESSE LEWIS, SIX,
HIS FATHER WAS ON THE WAY TO THE
COOL TO WATCH HIM MAKE A
INGERBREAD HOUSE, AND WE HEARD
FROM ONE OF THE FIRST RESPONDERS
WHO WERE INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
>> IT WAS LOOK WAWCHG SOMETHING
THAT WAS UNREAL.
>> SHE WATCHED AS IT DAWNED ON
PARENTS AS OTHER ONES LEFT.
>> THEY'RE GOING IN THAT ROOM TO
PICK UP THEIR KIDS, AND THEN
SEEING THEM LEAVE, THEY'RE
DISTRAUGHT, AND FROM THE
POSITION RIGHT HERE, TRYING TO
HELP AND BEING HELPLESS.
>> SHE SAID SOME NEEDED HUGS,
OTHERS SIMPLY NEEDED SOMEONE TO
HOLD THEIR HAND.
>> NEW DETAILS ARE EMERGING
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
AUTHORITIES SAY ADAM LANZA
FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> Ama: LANZA SHOT 20 FIRST
GRADERS.
>> I BELIEVE EVERYBODY WAS HIT
MORE THAN ONCE WEAPON DID NOT
BRING THE BODIES AND THE
FAMILIES INTO CONTACT.
WE TOOK PICTURES OF THEM, OF
THEIR FACIAL FEATURES.
YOU HAVE -- IT'S EASIER ON THE
FAMILIES WHEN YOU DO THAT.
>> Ama: POLICE ENTERED THE
SCHOOL AND FOUND LANZA DEAD,
APPARENTLY BY HIS OWN HAND.
PEOPLE WHO KNEW LANZA IN HIGH
SCHOOL DESCRIBE A VERY SHY,
SOCIALLY AWKWARD INDIVIDUAL.
HE WAS AN HONOR STUDENT AND
MEMBER OF THE PEP CLUB.
HIS AUNT SAID SHE TALKED WITH
LANZA'S MOM ABOUT HIS TROUBLES.
>> SHE HAD ISSUES WITH THE
SCHOOL.
SHE EVENTUALLY WOUND UP
HOME-SCHOOLING HIM.
I'M NOT CERTAIN IF IT WAS
BEHAVIOR OR LEARNING DISABILITY.
>> LAB SA'S FATHER ISSUED A
STATEMENT THAT READS IN PART.
I-UNDER DO.
>> ALSO LEARNING ABOUT THE HEROS
IN THE LINE OF FIRE.
ONE PREGNANT TEACHER SPRANG INTO
ACTION WHEN SHOTS WERE FIRED.
>> SHE LOCKED THE DOOR AND PUT
OUR -- TAPED A PIECE OF WHITE
TAPE OVER THE WINDOW OF THE
DOOR, AND THEN SHE TOLD TO US GO
IN THE CORNER.
19 PEOPLE IN OUR CLASS.
AND SHE SAVED ALL OF US.
>> THIRD GRADER TORI CAME HOME
SAFELY TO HER MOTHER, THANKS TO
HER TEACH RER'S RAPID RESPONSE.
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON THE HEROES.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL ATTEND A
MEMORIAL SERVICE TOMORROW NIGHT
IN NEWTOWN IN HIS SATURDAY RADIO
ADDRESS, THE PRESIDENT CALLED
FOR ACTION.
>> WE HAVE TO COME TOGETHER AND
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO TAKE
MEANINGFUL ACTION TO PREVENT
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING.
>> VIGILS HONORING THOSE KILLED
ARE BEING HELD AROUND THE
NATION, INCLUDING RIGHT HERE IN
THE BAY AREA.
CORNELL BERNARD IS LIVE AT GRACE
CATHEDRAL.
>> THE CHOIRS HAVE BEEN
PERFORMING HOLIDAY CONCERTS HERE
FOR DECADES, BUT TONIGHT THE
CONCERTS HAVE BECOME A SOLEMN
DEDICATION TO THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING VICTIMS.
♪.
REPORTER: THE SPECIAL
ARRANGEMENT OF SILENT NIGHT HAD
A NEW MEANING, DEDICATED TO THE
VICTIMS OF THE SHOOTING AND SO
WAS THE ENTIRE HOLIDAY CONCERT
AT THE CATHEDRAL.
>> THE SONGS AND THE BEAUTY OF
THEM ECHOS AND MAKES YOU THINK
ABOUT LIFE AND IT'S VERY
PRECIOUS AND THE THINGS YOU NEED
TO DO.
>> MAY GOD BE WITH YOU.
>> BISHOP MARK ANDREWS WANTED TO
CHANNEL THE GRIEF SO MANY PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN FEELING.
HE SAYS GUN VIOLENCE MUST STOP.
>> THE SIMPLE SOLUTION ABOUT GUN
CONTROL IS NOT ENOUGH.
IT'S SOMETHING WE MUST ADDRESS.
BUT WE ALSO MUST ASK WHAT IS
BEHIND THE VIOLENCE?
REPORTER: AT ST. MARY'S CATHOLIC
CHURCH, A PRAYER FOR THE
VICTIMS.
WORDS OF COMFORT.
[INAUDIBLE]
>> AND TONIGHT'S LIGHTING OF THE
MEN MENORAH, THEY LOOKED FOR
ANSWERS.
BUT WE HAVE TO START WITH SIMPLE
ACTS.
HOW DO YOU RESPOND TO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS?
YOU JUST DON'T NOPE WHAT TO DO,
HOW TO -- JUST DON'T KNOW WHAT
TO   DO HOW TO REACH OUT.
SO YOU HAVE TO REACH OUT
STARTING ON THE HOME FRONT, WITH
YOUR FAMILIES FAMILY.
REPORTER: AND TRYING TO FIND
LIGHT DURING A DARK TIME.
♪.
REPORTER: AND THE REMAINING
CONCERTS HERE AT GRACE CATHEDRAL
WILL BE DEDICATED TO THE
SHOOTING VICTIMS.
ACROSS THE BAY AREA, OTHER
VIGILS ARE TAKING PLACE, SERGIO
QUINTANA HAS THAT.
>> OLIVIA ENGLE.
BORN, JULY 18, 2006.
>> AT A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL ON THE
FRONT STEPS OF PAY TON
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN ALAMEDA,
THE NAMES OF THOSE KILLED IN
CONNECTICUT WERE READ.
>> THESE CHILDREN WERE FIVE AND
SIX YEARS OLD.
WE ALL KNOW FIVE AND
SIX-YEAR-OLD WHICH IS PART OF
WHY IT WAS SO IMPORTANT TO
GATHER ON THE FRONT STEPS OF AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> AMONG THOSE HERE, THE
REVEREND LAURA ROSE, SHE LED THE
GROUP IN PRAYER AND SHARED THE
FAMILY RESIDE PAIN.
HER COUSIN HAD TWO CHILDREN AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WHO
ESCAPED.
>> THEY SHUT THE PHONE OFF BUT
BASICALLY I'M GETTING A POST
FROM FACEBOOK, AND I'LL PROBABLY
TALK TO THEIR GRANDMOTHER IN THE
NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS.
>> THEY HELD THEIR VIGIL FOR AN
HOUR, WHICH WAS LONGER THAN THE
ORGANIZER EXPECTED.
>> MY HUSBAND COUNTED 49 PEOPLE,
WHICH RAIN AND COLD AND JUST
FOUND OUT ABOUT IT A FEW HOURS
AGO.
>> ACROSS THE BAY IN SAN
FRANCISCO, ANOTHER GROUP BRAVED
THE EXPLAIN THE COLD.
CHILDREN HELD SIGNS SPELLING OUT
THEIR CALLS FOR ACTION.
THESE VIGILS THAT HAVE SPRUNG
ACROSS THE BAY AND THE COUNTRY
HAVE A SIMILAR TEAM.
PEOPLE SHOWING SUPPORT FOR THE
FAMILY FAMILIES OF THOSE LOST
AND TO CALL FOR CHANGE.
>> WE HAVE HAD UNFORTUNATELY A
NUMBER OF SHOCKING SHOOTINGS
WITHIN THE LAST YEAR.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IT TAKES TO
REACH A TIPPING POINT.
I'LL BE CURIOUS TO SEE IF THIS
IS A TIPPING POINT.
>> Ama: STAY WITH AN ANSWER --
ABC-7 NEWS FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE.
YOU CAN GET UPDATES ANYTIME AL
ABC7.com.
>> WE HAD A LITTLE BIT OF A
BREAK TONIGHT, BUT IT WAS A WET
START TO THE WEEKEND, THIS VIDEO
SHOT EARLIER TODAY AS THE RAIN
CAME DOWN IN SAN FRANCISCO.
YOU CAN SEE PEOPLE WITH
UMBRELLAS HURRYING THROUGH THE
RAIN.
LET'S HEAD TO LEIGH GLASER.
>> Leigh: BOY, COLD RAIN MOVING
ACROSS MUCH OF THE BAY AREA
TODAY.
LIVE DOPPLER 7HD SHOWING YOU
JUST A LITTLE BIT OF LIGHT
SPRINKLE ACTIVITY, MAYBE SOME
HEAVY MIST AND DRIZZLE.
YOU CAN SEE FOR YOURSELF, NOT A
LOT OUT THERE RIGHT NOW.
BUT WE ARE ANTICIPATING A FEW
MORE SHOWERS TO INTENSE TIE --
INTENSIFY.
SONOMA, A LITTLE LIGHT RAIN, AND
SAN JOSE, SARATOGA, MORGAN HILL.
NEXT WEEK LOOKS WET, WITH A
SERIES OF RAIN STORMS HEADED
TOWARDS THE BAY AREA.
WE'LL LOOK AT THE
AccuWeather SEVEN-DAY
FORECAST COMING UP.
>> Ama: STILL TO COME AT 11:00,
NEW DEVELOPMENTS IN THE MURDERS
OF TWO TEENAGE GIRLS IN OAKLAND,
WHAT AUTHORITIES LEARNED
TONIGHT.
>>> AN ARREST IN THE BOMB THREAT
THAT SHUT DOWN TWO SCHOOLS IN
THE SOUTH BAY THIS WEEK.
>>> THE COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS
IS ON.
THE HOLIDAY CRAZINESS THAT'S
UNDERWAY IN THE BAY
>> Ama: TWO ADULTS AND A
JUVENILE HAVE BEEN ARRESTED IN
CONNECTION WITH THE SHOOTING
DEATHS OF TWO TEENS IN OAKLAND A
MONTH AGO.
A 15-YEAR-OLD AND HER BEST
FRIEND WERE GUNNED DOWN ON A
QUIET STREET CORNER SUNDAY
MORNING.
THE GIRLS WERE STAND ON THE
STREET WHEN A CAR DROVE BY AND
FIRED 36 SHOTS.
>> A 16-YEAR-OLD BOY IS ACCUSED
OF SPRAY PAINTING BOMB THREATS
THAT SHUT DOWN TWO SCHOOLS IN
THE SOUTH BAY.
THIS GRAFFITI NAMED A TEACHER.
WE BLURRED HIS NAME TO PROTECT
HIS IDENTITY.
ALMOST IDENTICAL MESSAGES WERE
SPRAYED ON THE WALLS IN TWO
OTHER SCHOOLS.
>>> A SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA MALL
WAS LONGED DOWN TONIGHT AFTER A
MAN FIRED AT LEAST 50 SHOTS INTO
A DEPARTMENT STORE PARKING LOT.
HAPPENED OUTSIDE MACY'S AT THE
FASHION ISLAND MALL IN NEWPORT
PEOPLE.
POLICE TOOK A MAN INTO CUSTODY.
A ROBOT INVESTIGATED THE CAR TO
MAKE SURE NOTHING DANGEROUS WAS
INSIDE.
>> THE HOLIDAY FRENZY IS ON.
A CHILLY DAY AND SOGGY WEATHER
COULDN'T KEEP PEOPLE FROM
SHOPPING IN SAN FRANCISCO,
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE WERE IN
UNION SQUARE, OVERALL SALES ARE
UP MORE THAN 2% OVER LAST YEAR.
AMERICANS SPENT MORE THAN 659
BILL SINCE LAST SATURDAY.
>> SANTA HAD A SPECIAL ESCORT
WHEN HE DELIVERED GIFTS TO SICK
KIDS.
THESE BIKERS FROM THE GOLDEN
GATE HARLEY CLUB RODE WITH HIM
FROM SOUTH SAN FRANCISCO TO THE
HOSPITAL.
THE RIDERS PLACED THE GIFTS
UNDER THE HOLIDAY TREE IN THE
MAIN LOBBY AND THEY WILL BE
DISTRIBUTED TO CHILDREN WHO HE
CARE AT THE MEDICAL CENTER OVER
THE HOLIDAYS.
>> SEE THESE KIDS, THEY'RE EYES
LIGHT UP, AND COME DOWN HERE AND
GET EXCITED ABOUT THIS, IS JUST
OVERWHELMING.
>> THE BIKERS ALSO HASN'T OVER A
CHECK FOR $1,200.
THE 23rd YEAR THEY MADE THE
TOY RUN.
>> MORE CLAIM DELIGHT AT THE
HOLIDAY PARTY AT THE ALLEN
TEMPLE BAPTIST CHURCH.
THEY HAD TOYS TO HAND OUT AND
EXPECT 900 CHILDREN TO ATTEND.
>>> WE HAVE A LITTLE MORE THAN A
WEEK UNTIL CHRISTMAS, AND A LOT
OF WET WEATHER COMING OUR WAY.
>> ESPECIALLY MID-TO LATTER PAST
OF NEXT WEEK.
STILL A FEW SHOWERS OUT THERE.
LIVE LOOK NOW FROM THE HIGH
DEFINITION EAST BAY CAM LOOKING
WEST TOWARDS THE BAY BRIDGE, SAN
FRANCISCO.
ALSO WANT TO CAUTION YOU WITH
THIS MOISTURE OUT THERE, WE ARE
ALSO LOOKING AT THE POSSIBILITY
OF SOME OF THAT DENSE FOG
DEVELOPING OVERNIGHT.
FOLKS, HERE A LOOK AT LIVE
DOPPLER 7HD, VERYING A TITHE
FIVE HOURS AGO.
SINCE THEN THAT BAND OF RAIN HAS
PUSHED TO THE SOUTH.
WE'LL TAKE YOU TO NORTH BAY
WHERE WE'RE PICKING UP A LITTLE
LIGHT PRECIPITATION, TOWARDS
SONOMA, A LINE HEADING DOWN
TOWARD NOVATO, EVEN A LITTLE TO
THE EAST OF SANTA ROSA, ALSO
FROM SAN JOSE, MORGAN HILL,
LITTLE ACTIVITY SCOTTS VALLEY,
SANTA CRUZ.
THIS IS VERY, VERY LIGHT, AND
IT'S CONTINUING TO PUSH FROM THE
NORTH TO THE SOUTH.
SO, WE WILL DEFINITELY SEE MORE
SHOWERS DEVELOP OVERNIGHT, BUT
NEEDLESS TO SAY WE'RE IN A NICE
BREAK RIGHT NOW.
TEMPERATURES, COLD THIS HOUR IN
THE 40s.
48, SAN FRANCISCO 44 IN ANTIOCH,
AS WELL AS SANTA ROSA, SAN JOSE
RIGHT NOW, WITH CLOUDS OVERHEAD,
48 DEGREES, FEW LIGHT SHOWERS IN
YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD.
SO TONIGHT WE'LL GO WITH COLD
SHOWERS OVERNIGHT.
SHOWERS AND SUN BREAKS EXPECTED
FOR SUNDAY.
TOMORROW, A NICE BREAK BEFORE
MORE RAIN MOVES IN SUNDAY NIGHT
AND MONDAY, AND, YES, LOOKS LIKE
AN ACTIVE WEATHER WEEK NEXT WEEK
WITH OFF AND ON RAIN SHOWERS
THROUGHOUT THE WEEK.
HIGHER ELEVATIONS MAY SEE A FEW
FLAKES OVERNIGHT TONIGHT.
TEMPERATURES IN THE NORTH BAY IN
THE 30s.
WE'LL LOOK FOR 40s ELSEWHERE
FOR OVERNIGHT LOWS.
HERE'S A LOOK AT THE COLD FRONT.
YOU CAN SEE IT STRETCHING LIVE
HERE ACROSS THE BAY AREA.
THIS IS WHAT CAME IN EARLIER
THIS AFTERNOON.
BRINGING WITH IT SHOWERS.
YOU CAN SEE HOW QUICKLY IT HAS
PUSHED INTO SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
A LITTLE BIT OF A BREAK HERE,
ALREADY UPSTREAM WE'RE STARTING
TO SEE MOISTURE DEVELOP.
SO THIS IS WHAT IS ANTICIPATED
TO MOVE IN OVERNIGHT TONIGHT.
NOW, A FORECAST MODEL KIND OF
OVERDOING IT A LITTLE BIT FOR
THIS TIME FRAME BUT AT LEAST YOU
GET A SENSE OF THE SHOWERS WILL
CONTINUE TO BE ACROSS THE BAY
AREA.
THIS IS SUNDAY.
10:00, 11:00, 12:00, 1:00, 2:00,
AND WE THIS WILL SEE A LITTLE B,
AND THE NEXT SYSTEM IS POISED TO
MOVE IN HERE BY 10:00 TOMORROW
NIGHT IN THE NORTH BAY, AND
DEFINITELY SET THE STAGE FOR A
WET COMMUTE MONDAY MORNING.
HERE'S A LOOK AT THE HIGHS FOR
SUNDAY.
A COOL DAY, ALTHOUGH A LITTLE
SUNSHINE WILL HEAT US UP.
LOOK FOR MID-TO-LOW 50s ACROSS
MUCH OF THE BAY AREA,
WATSONVILLE, 53, HOLLISTER.
THE AccuWeather SEVEN-DAY
FORECAST, A MIXTURE OF SUN
BREAKS AND SHOWERS FOR SUNDAY.
RAIN LIKELY ON MONDAY.
A FEW SHOWERS TUESDAY.
WEDNESDAY WILL BE DRY.
LARGEST STORM, HEAVY RAIN AND
WIND BY THURSDAY AND FRIDAY SO
VERY UNSETTLED.
>> Ama: SHU IS HERE IN SPORTS.
>> Mike: THE 49ers TRAVEL TO
NEW ENGLAND TO PACE THE PATRIOTS
TOMORROW NIGHT, AND TOM BRADY
WILL GIVE THE NINERS' DEFENSE
ALL THEY CAN HANDLE.
CARVES UP DEFENSES LIKE A
HOLIDAY TURKEY.
>> Mike: THE 49ers ARE
PREPARING FOR TOMORROW NIGHT'S
ANTICIPATED MATCHUP WITH THE
PATRIOTS.
IF THE NINERS WIN, THEY TAKE THE
TOP SPOT.
TOM BRADY, THAT'S WHERE ALVIN
SMITH COMES IN.
IF THE NINERS CAN'T PRESSURE
BRADY IT'S GOING TO BE A LONG
NIGHT.
HE TOOK APART THE DEFENSE OF
HOUSTON TEXANS.
IT WILL BE THE TOUGHEST MATCHUP
FOR THE 49ERS' DEFENSE.
>> HE IS SO GOOD WITH EVERY
DETAIL OF HIS GAME.
HIS THROWING MOTION, HIS
UNDERSTANDING OF THE GAME,
PROTECTION, DEFENSES, SO IT'S A
BIG TASK, AND I THINK WE'RE UP
FOR IT AND OUR GUYS ARE EXCITED
TO PLAY THIS GAME.
>> Mike: TO HIGH SCHOOL
FOOTBALL.
STATE CHAMPIONSHIPS, De La
SALLE FACING CORONA CENTENNIAL.
NOW, CENTENNIAL HAS THE STATE'S
LEADING OFFENSE, AVERAGING
542 YARDS AND TWO 1,000-YARD
RUSHERS.
BOB LATTICE TALKED ABOUT
RETIRING AFTER 24 YEARS AT THE
HELM.
21-0, SPARTS.
AND THEN AUSTIN LONESTAR.
13535-14 SPARTANS.
CENTENNIAL HAS A GREAT OFFENSE
BUT COULDN'T GET ANY CLOSER THAN
14.
De La SALLE, DIVISION STATE
CHAMPIONS FOR THE FOURTH
STRAIGHT YEAR, 48-28 YOUR FINAL.
>> DIVISION III MARKS REIN
CATHOLIC AND MADDISON.
THE QUARTERBACK HEADED TO CAL.
OUT TO HANDLEY, WILDCATS UP
35-31, MADDISON ANSWERS, PREAIR
CORMIER, AND THIS KID IS STRONG.
79 YARDS.
MAD -- MAD DISSON WITH THE VIC.
>> WE'LL TAKE A BRIEF TIME-OUT.
THE WARRIORS RETURN WITH A
FRANCHISE RECORD NUMBER OF
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>> Mike: THE WARRIORS' LONGEST
ROAD TRIP IN THE YEAR.
THEY WON THE FIRST FIVE,
INCLUDING A WIN OVER THE MIAMI
HEAT.
A LOSS IN ORLANDO AND A WIN OVER
ATLANTA COMING HOME.
OFF TO BEST START SINCE THE
92-91 SEASON, ROOKIE HARRISON
IMPROVING EVERY GAME.
19 IN THE GAME.
CARL LANDRY OFF THE BENCH.
THE FOLLOWUP, 'ONE-HASN'T --
ONE-HASN'T JAM.
WARRIORS MOST EFFECTIVE WHEN
EVERYBODY GETS INVOLVED.
DAVID LEE, AVERAGING A DOUBLE
DOUBLE IN EVERY GAME ON THE
TRIP.
THIS STEAL AND THE SLAM.
18 POINTS FOR CURRY, WAR YORE
6-1 ON THE ROAD TRIP, 115-93
YOUR FINAL.
>> TO CONDITIONAL HOOPS.
STANFORD FACING UC DAVIS.
A LITTLE NONCONFERENCE MATCHUP
AFTER A COUPLE WEEKS OF EXAM.
THE ONLY AGGIE PLAYER TO SHOW
UP.
23 OF THE TEAM'S 52 POINTS.
ONLY TWO DAVIS PLAYERS HIT
DOUBLE DIGIT.
JOSH HITS THE DUMPER AND A FOUL.
HE HAD 14.
CARDINAL LEFT AT THE HALF.
CARDINAL WITH THE 75-52 VICTORY.
>> OUR DEFENSE IS -- I BELIEVE
IN OUR GUYS.
I KNOW WE HAVE GOOD SHOOTERS.
WE KEEP DEFENDING LIKE WE'RE
DEFENDING RIGHT NOW,LL TAKE IT.
THE WAY WE'RE DEFENDING, GIVE
OURSELVES A CHANCE TO WIN
AGAINST EVERYONE, EVERY NIGHT.
AS LONG AS WE STAY CONFIDENT,
BELIEVE IN OURSELVES, THAT'S
GOING TO TURN AROUND AND WE'RE
GOING TO SHOOT THE BALL WELL.
>> Mike: CAL HOSTING CREIGHTON.
JUSTIN COBB, 18.
BUT THEY WERE NO MATCH FOR
CREIGHTON0S DOUG McDERMOTT.
10-13 FROM THE FIELD.
MONSTER GAME FOR THE BLUE JAYS.
CAL FOLLOWS TO 6-3 WITH STRAIGHT
CREIGHTON'S VICTORY.
THIS SPORTS REPORT BROUGHT 0 TO
YOU BY RIVER ROCK CASINO.
MICHAEL CRABTREE SURPRISED SOME
KIDS FROM THE SAN FRANCISCO BOYS
AND GIRLS CLUB.
THIS COULD BE A PREVIEW OF THE
SUPER BOWL.
THEY HAVE TO GET TO TOM BRADY OR
IT'S GOING TO BE A LONG NIGHT.
AND COLLIN CAP PER --
KAEPERNICK, GOING TO BE
INTERESTING.
>> Ama: GETTING GUNS OFF THE
STREETS.
HUNDREDS TURN OUT FOR A BAY AREA
GUN BUYBACK PROGRAM, FUELED IN
PART BY YESTERDAY'S TRAGEDY.
>>> A MESS ON HIGHWAY 1.
WHY THE ROAD CLOSED AFTER THIS
MONTH'S STORM COULD STAY CLOSED
INDEFINITELY.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
>> Ama: GOOD EVENING.
IN TONIGHT'S HEADLINES, A MAN
AND WOMAN WERE TAKEN INTO
CUSTODY AFTER THREE AND A HALF
HOUR STANDOFF IN SAN FRANCISCO.
POLICE SAY IT WAS A DOMESTIC
VIOLENCE SITUATION.
THE MAN TOLD A NEIGHBOR HE HAD A
GUN.
POLICE HAVE YET TO FIND A
WEAPON.
>> TWO ADULTS AND A JUVENILE
HAVE BEEN ARRESTED IN CONNECTION
WITH THE SHOOTING DEATH OFFICE
TWO TEENAGE GAILS IN OAKLAND
LAST MONTH.
THEY WERE KILLED ON MINER AVENUE
THANKSGIVING WEEKEND.
>> A 16-YEAR-OLD CUPERTINO BOY
IS ACCUSED OF THREATENING TO
KILL A TEACHER AND HAS BEEN
ARRESTED.
THE THREAT WAS SPRAY PAINTED ON
THE WALL AT THE HIGH SCHOOL.
BOTH AT THE TEACHER AND THE BOY
WERE AT HOSPITAL VISTA HIGH
SCHOOL.
>> AUTHORITIES IN CONNECTICUT
SAY THE GUNMAN BEHIND THE
MASSACRE FORCED HIS WAY INTO THE
BUILD SOMETHING SHOT 20 CHILDREN
TWICE.
TODAY POLICE RELEASED THE NAMES
AND AGES OF THE VICTIMS.
THE YOUNGEST SIX YEARS OLD,.
TONIGHT AS THE NATION COMES TO
GRIPS WITH THE TRAGEDY, WE'RE
HEARING ABOUT THE HEROES WHO
PREVENT MORE DEATHS.
REPORTER: FOR THE LAST TWO
YEARS, DAWN CHICAGO SPRUNG
INFUSED SANDY HOOK WITH HER OWN
MAGIC.
SHE WOULD TWEET AND ORGANIZE
HAPPY HOURS FOR THE TEACHERS TO
SHARE THE BEST iPAD APPS FOR
THE CLASSROOM.
SHE SHARED THIS PHOTO ON
TWITTER.
SHE SAID, WELCOMING OUR KINDERS
THIS MORNING, 74 NEW
OPPORTUNITIES TO INSPIRE
LIFE-LONG LEARNING, AND
INTRODUCED THE SANDY HOOK BOOK
FAIRLY, AND -- FAIRY, AND SHE
AND HER TEACHERS WERE THERE WHEN
THEY NEEDEDDED THEM MOST.
>> I NEEDED TO KNOW I LOVE YOU
ALL VERY MUCH, AND THAT IT'S
GOING TO BE OKAY BECAUSE I
THOUGHT THAT WAS THE LAST TIME I
WOULD EVER SEE THEM.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
REPORTER: SHE TAUGHT HER
TEACHERS AND STUDENTS WHAT TO DO
IN AN EMERGENCY.
HER TWEET IN OCTOBER SHOWS US
WHAT HELPED SO MANY PREPARE FOR
AN UNIMAGINABLE MORNING.
THAT TRAINING BROUGHT THIRD
GREATER TORII CHAP HOME SAFE TO
HER MOTHER.
>> SHE LOCKED THE DOOR AND PUT
UP PIECE OF WHITE TAPE OVER THE
WINDOW OF THE DOOR.
AND THEN SHE TOLD US TO GO IN
THE CORNER.
19 PEOPLE IN OUR CLASS.
AND SHE SAVED ALL OF US.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE IN
NEWTOWN TOMORROW EVENING TO
ATTEND A MEMORIAL SERVICE FOR
THE VICTIMS.
YOU CAN EXPRESS YOUR SYMPATHY BY
POSTING A BADGE TO YOUR FACEBOOK
WALL IN SILENT SUPPORT OF
EVERYONE IN CONNECTICUT.
WE WILL HAVE LIVE REPORTS FROM
CONNECTICUT TOMORROW STARTING
WITH THE MORNING NEWS, AND YOU
CAN GET UPDATES ANYTIME AT
ABC7NEWS.COM.
>> A PREVIOUSLY SCHEDULED GUN
BUYBACK PROM FOR OAKLAND AND SAN
FRANCISCO TODAY GOT A BOOST
AFTER YESTERDAY'S TRAJECTORY --
YESTERDAY'S TRAGIC EVENTS.
HERE'S THE STORY.
>> I DECIDED TO GIVE UP MY GUNS.
I DON'T NEED THEM.
>> MICHELLE, WAS ONE OF MORE
THAN 200 PEOPLE WILLING TO SELL
THEIR GUNS TO SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE.
MANY WHO STOOD AND WAITED IN
THIS ALONG LINE AT THE SAN
FRANCISCO OMEGA CLUB WERE
BROUGHT HERE BY THE SAME
TRAGEDY.
THE MASS MURDER OF 20 CHILDREN
IN CONNECTICUT.
>> HIT ME PRETTY STRONG.
I NEVER THOUGHT ABOUT GETTING
RID OF THEM BEFORE.
>> HE IS A VIETNAM VET AND SAYS
HE AND HIS WIFE SOBBED WHILE
WATCHING THE NEWS.
DAN WAS TURNING IN HER GUN SO IT
COULD NEVER BE USED TO TAKE A
LIFE.
>> IF THIS IS SOMETHING THAT
MIGHT HURT SOMEBODY SOME DAY,
THEN I WOULD FEEL TERRIBLE ABOUT
THAT.
REPORTER: THE GUN BUYBACK WAS
FUNDED BY AN ANN ANONYMOUS
DONOR.
THE DIRECTOR OF THE BOYS CLUB
SAYS THE TURNOUT SHOWS BOTH
COMMUNITIES CARE ABOUT GUN
VIOLENCE.
>> WHEN THE COMMUNITY SAYS
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH, YOU GOT A GOOD
CHANCE FOR SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
REPORTER: IN OAKLAND, PEELED
LINED UP IN CARS STARTING AT
6:00 A.M. TO TURN IN GUNS AT
ST. BENEDICT'S CHURCH, THIS IS
WHERE HOLA SIMMONS WERE BUYING
THE GUNS.
>> WE HAVE EVERY EXPECTATION IT
WILL EXCEED OUR EXPECTATIONS,.
>> THE INITIAL TARGET WAS 500
GUNS.
A FINANCIAL INCENTIVE HELPED
BRING PEOPLE OUT.
>> MONEY, MONEY.
>> $200 WAS PAID FOR EACH
HANDGUN OR RIFLE.
A LIMIT OF THREE WEAPONS FOR
EACH RESIDENT, AND PEOPLE HAD TO
PROVE THEY RESIDED THE IN THE
CITY BUYING THE GUNS.
>> OAKLAND AND SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE DEPARTMENTS ARE GOING TO
BE ASKING THE GOVERNOR TO SEE IF
HE CAN MAKE THIS A GUN BUYBACK A
STATE PROGRAM.
>> SAN RAFAEL POLICE IDENTIFIED
THE MAN WANTED FOR ATTEMPTED
MURDER IN YESTERDAY'S TRANSIT
CENTER SHOOTING.
TONIGHT THEY RELEASED THIS
PICTURE OF 24-YEAR-OLD LA DRAKE
SUNNY DEAN.
POLICE SAY DEAN SHOT A
22-YEAR-OLD MAN AT CLOSE RANGE
ON PLATFORM D AT THE TRANSIT
CENTER AT 1:00 P.M. FRIDAY.
THE 22-YEAR-OLD VICTIM IS IN THE
HOSPITAL AND IS EXPECTED TO
SURVIVE.
>>> FIREFIGHTERS RESCUED A
77-YEAR-OLD MAN WHOSE CAR
PLUNGED DOWN A RAVINE IN MARIN
COUNTY THIS AFTERNOON.
THE CAR WAS 150 PEOPLE OFF THE
ROAD AND THE DRIVER, ANOTHER
50 FEET BELOW THE VEHICLE.
FIREFIGHTERS WERE ABLE TO HOIST
HIM TO SAFETY.
HE WENT TO MALIN GENERAL
HOSPITAL WITH HYPOTHERMIA.
>> A SECTION OF HIGHWAY 1
THROUGH SONOMA YA COUNTY WILL
REMAIN CLOSED INDEFINITELY.
THE HIGHWAY WAS CLOSED JUST
NORTH A JENNER.
A SMALL SECTION OF THE ROAD
COLLAPSED THIS MONTH WHEN A
SERIES OF STORMS HIT THE AREA.
OFFICIALS ORIGINALLY HOPED TO
OPEN THE HIGHWAY THIS WEEK BUT
ENGINEERS DETERMINED THE WORK
WILL TAKE LONG THAN EXPECTED.
>> NOT JUST MADE IN AMERICA BUT
MADE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THE COMPANY MAKING ITEMS FOR 112
YEARS AND COULD BE AROUND FOR
ANOTHER CENTURY.
>> Leigh: HI THERE AGAIN, I'M
LEIGH GLASER.
MORE RAIN IS IN MY SEVEN-DAY
FORECAST.
WE'LL LOOK AT THAT, PLUS A
LITTLE
>>> WE KNOW HOW AMERICANS DON'T
MANUFACTURE PRODUCTS ANYMORE BUT
WE FOUND A CONTRADICTION IN OUR
OWN BEAK YARD.
IN CONJUNCTION WITH THE MADE IN
AMERICA SEARCH, WE'RE SEARCHING
FOR LOCAL EXAMPLES AND FOUND AN
ITEM THAT EVERYONE USES.
>> ON ONE OF SAN FRANCISCO ROZ
PROUDEST STREETS, HERE'S A VEN
EASTERLY NAME FOR YOU, A
MATTRESS COMPANY HAS THAT
SURVIVED DESPITE BEING AROUND
LONGER THAN ALL OF US.
>> WHERE IN CHINA DO YOU MAKE
YOUR MATTRESSES?
>> WE'RE IN CHINA?
I DON'T THINK SO.
REPORTER: ROBIN, THE THIRD
GENERATION, HER GRANDFATHER,
EDWARD, WAS A MATTRESS EQUIPMENT
SAYSMAN FROM CHICAGO WHO CAME TO
SAN FRANCISCO IN 1898 WITH HIS
BROTHER, LEONARD.
IF THEY WERE TO VISIT THE
FACTORY ON MINNESOTA STREET
TODAY THEY WOULD BE PROUD TO SEE
THE COMPANY THEY OFFEND STILL --
THEY FOUNDED STILL GOING STRONG.
>> THE BENEFIT IS WE'RE IN
CHARGE OF THE QUALITY.
>> EASY TO SAY.
NOT SO EASY TO DO.
WHEN THEY SAY THEY MAKE THEIR
MATTRESSES FROM SCRATCH IN
AMERICA, THEY MEAN IT.
BEGINNING WITH THE COTTON, THEY
BLEND AND MACHINE INTO BATTING.
TO THE COILS, WHICH THEY WIRE,
MANUFACTURED IN CALIFORNIA, THEN
TURN, BENT, TW TWISTED BY
MACHINE, AND FINISHED BY A
FORMER STREET SWEEPER.
>> ALL HAND-MADE.
>> BY YOUR HAND.
>> BY MY HAND, YEAH, ALL OF OUR
HAND.
>> THEY BUILD MATTRESSES THE
OLD-FASHIONED WAY, SAME TAGS
THEY ALWAYS HAVE AS REFLECTED
THROUGH ALMOST A CENTURY'S WORTH
OF ORDERS AND RECEIPTS THAT
REMAIN ON FILE.
THE SYSTEM IS DEFINITELY OLD
SCHOOL BUT IT WORKS.
WHEN A CUSTOMER CALLS ASKING FOR
INFORMATION ON A SALE, ALL THEY
DO IS CONSULT THESE CATALOGUES.
THEY HAVE EVERYTHING IN 15
SECONDS.
WHEN DID THEY GOOD TO COMMUTER
AND.
>> WE STARTED IN 1998.
>> NOT THE NORMAL FINANCIAL
WHIZ.
ACCORDING TO THE VICE-PRESIDENT,
ROB BURKE, WHILE SOME MATTRESS
COMPANIES MIGHT TURN OUT 1500
UNITS EVERY 24 HOURS.
>> WE VARY A LOT.
IT WILL BE ANYWHERE FROM SEVEN
TO 12 A DAY.
IT'S NOT A LOT OF MATTRESSES.
REPORTER: THOUGH THEY CAN COST
UPWARDS OF $5,000 EACH AND
CUSTOMERS MAY HAVE TO WAIT THREE
WEEKS FOR DELIVERY, BUT THE
MATTRESSES HAVE A TEN-YEAR
WARRANTY.
>> OTHER PRODUCTS DON'T LAST AS
LONG.
>> AREN'T YOU GOING TO PUT
YOURSELF OUT OF BUSINESS FOR
MAKING A MATTRESS THAT LASTS TOO
LONG?
>> WE COULD.
>> WE COULD MAKE IT IN A LESS
EXPENSIVE MANNER.
BUT WE BELIEVE IN THE PRODUCT
AND BELIEVE IN THE FAMILY NAME.
>> SO IN A HURSH UP, BUILD IT
OVERSEAS TYPE OF WORLD, HERE'S
YOUR LOCAL CONTRADICTION, 113
YEARS OLD, 31 EMPLOYEES, STILL
SUCCEEDING THE OLD WAY.
>> YOU LEARNED A LOT TODAY.
ISSUE IN ISSUE -- MORE THAN YOU
THOUGHT.
>> IN SAN FRANCISCO, WAYNE
FREEDMAN, ABC-7 NEWS.
>> Ama: TONIGHT IS A NICE NIGHT
TO BE CUDDLED UP INURE BED.
IT'S COLD OUT THERE.
>> Leigh: IT'S BEEN COLD ALL DAY
LONG.
THE SHOWERS MOVING ACROSS THE
BAY AREA.
WANT TO SHOW YOU HONOR HONOR
HONOR ONE MORE TIME.
YOU CAN SEE MUCH OF THE HEAVY
SHOWERS PASSING THROUGH THE
SOUTH.
WE'LL SEE SOME STRAY SHOWERS
HERE AND THERE AND THROUGHOUT
THE DAY TOMORROW, AND ALSO SOME
SUN BREAKS.
IF YOU'RE TRAVELING TOMORROW,
HEADED BACK EAST, FROM NEW YORK
DOWN TOWARD D.C., ATLANTA, NEW
ORLEANS, WE HAVE A LINE OF
SHOWERS THAT WILL CONTINUE TO
PUSH TOWARDS THE SOUTH AND EAST.
MAYBE SOME IMBEDDED
THUNDERSTORMS.
THE SNOW IN THE ROCKIES AND LOOK
FOR A NEW BATCH OF RAIN TO MOVE
INTO THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST AND
THAT WILL MOVE INTO THE BAY AREA
AS WE HEAD INTO THE MIDDLE PART
AND LATTER PART OF THE WORK
WEEK.
IF YOU'RE TRAVELING ACROSS THE
STATE, FEW LINGERING SHOWERS
EXPECTED.
L.A. TOWARDS SAN DIEGO, WATCH
OUT FOR FRESNO, AND POCKETS OF
DENSE VALLEY FOG THERE AND IF
YOU'RE HEAD TOLLING TAHOE, A
LITTLE LIGHT SNOW EXPECTED.
37 DEGREES.
HERE'S A LOOK AT THE
AccuWeather SEVEN-DAY
FORECAST.
SOME SCATTERS SHOWERS AND SUN
BREAKS EXPECTED FOR US TOMORROW.
THEN THICKENING CLOUDS SUNDAY
NIGHT, RAIN LIKELY FOR MONDAY.
ON TUESDAY, WE GET A FEW
LINGERING SHOWERS.
WEDNESDAY LOOKS DRY, AND THEN A
MUCH STRONGER STORM SYSTEM IS
DUE IN HERE BY THURSDAY NIGHT,
THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT, THROUGH
FRIDAY MORNING, AND THE FORECAST
MODELS ARE SUGGESTING MODERATE
RAIN OUT OF THE STORM SYSTEM ON
THURSDAY AND GUSTY WINDS.
WE'LL'LL KEEP YOU UPDATED.
>> Ama: WINTER IS COMING.
>> Leigh: WINTER ON FRIDAY,
YOU'RE RIGHT.
>> Ama: MIKE IS HERE WITH
SPORTS.
>> Mike: THE NINERS FACING THE
PATRIOTS TODAY, AND MICHAEL
CRABTREE WORKING ON HIS DANCE
MOVES.
WE HAVE IT NEXT IN
>> Mike: THE 49ers-PATRIOTS
MATCHUP HAS THE MAKINGS OF A
GREAT GAME.
TOM BRADY AGAINST THE 49ers
DEFENSE, AND THE PATRIOT DEFENSE
TRYING TO CONFUSE COLIN
KAEPERNICK, MICHAEL CRABTREE HAS
66 CATCHES, 761 YARDS, AVERAGING
ALMOST 12 YARDS PER CATCH.
BIGGEST IMPROVEMENT THIS YEAR
HAS BEEN WHAT HE DOES WITH THE
BALL EVERYWARDS ACCORDING TO HIS
COACH.
>> HIS YARDS AFTER CATCH, HE HAS
BEEN DOING THAT THE ENTIRE YEAR.
HE IS -- PLAYING AS WELL AS
ANYBODY IN THE GAME RUNNING WITH
THE BALL AFTER THE CATCH, YARD
AFTER CATCH, YARDS AFTER
CONTACT.
AS GOOD AS ANYBODY IN THE
LEAGUE.
>> Mike: GOING TO NEED A LOT OF
THOSE TOUCHDOWNS.
>> PLAYERS GET DAYS OFF.
THEY REST OR TAKE CARE OFFER
RANS BUT MR. CRABTREE IS HELPING
KID THAT REMIND HIM OF HIMSELF
GROWING UP IN TEXAS.
>> VIDEO GAME PUBLISHER WAS
DEMONSTRATING ITS LATEST GAME
THIS WEEK, HIP-HOP DANCE
EXPERIENCE, TO THE LOCAL BOYS
AND GIRLS CLUB OF SAN FRANCISCO.
THIS GAME USES NFL PLAYERS AND
ALL OF A SUDDEN IT CAME TO LIFE
AS 49er WIDE RECEIVER MICHAEL
CRABTREE SHOWED UP.
>> IT WAS AMAZING.
HE WAS LIKE REALLY NICE.
>> MICHAEL GOT INVOLVED AND NOW
DONATES $1,000 FOR EVERY
TOUCHDOWN HE CATCH THOAZ BOYS
AND GIRLS CLUB OF SAN FRANCISCO,
WITH HIS CRAB-SHAKE TOUCHDOWN
DANCE WHICH HE DOM MOAN
STRAIGHTED.
>> I WAS LIKE, MAN, AND THE BOYS
CLUB CAME TO MIND, AND DANCE
MOVES, AND I'VE ALWAYS BEEN A
BIG DANCER WHEN I WAS YOUNG, AND
ALL TIED INTO ONE.
>> MICHAEL GOT INVOLVED WITH THE
BOYS AND GIRLS CLUB DATING BACK
TO HIS CHILDHOOD.
>> I WAS THERE EVERY DAY.
PLAYING BASKETBALL, FOOTBALL,
AND ALL THE ABOVE, AND I JUST
FELT LIKE --
>> IT MEANT A LOT TO THESE KIDS.
>> GIVES THE KID AN OPPORTUNITY
TO SEE SOMEBODY WHO IS ON TV WHO
IS REAL, AND THE MESSAGE HE
BROUGHT OUT IS SOMETHING WE
PREACH EVERY DAY.
>> THAT'S A GOOD DEAL.
I GET TO DANCE AND GIVE BACK AT
THE SAME TIME.
YOU CAN'T BEAT THAT.
>> HOPEFULLY A LOT OF THOSE
DANCES TOMORROW WITH TOUCHDOWN
CATCHES.
>> TO HIGH SCHOOL FOOTBALL.
STATE CHAMPIONSHIPS, De La
SALLE FACING CENTENNIAL FOR THE
OPEN DIVISION CROWN.
SPEARNT HEAD COACH HAS BEEN
TALKING ABOUT RETIREMENT AFTER
34 YEARS AT THE HELM.
46 YARDS FOR THIS.
SPARTZ UP 21-0.
SECOND HALF.
De La SALLE QUARTERBACK
CHRIS WILLIAMS, GUNS IT TO A
GOW, I LOVE HIS LAST NAME,
AUSTIN LONESTAR.
CENTENNIAL HAS A GREAT OFFENSE
BUT COULDN'T GET CLOSER THAN 14.
THE LEAD IS EXTENDED ONCE AGAIN.
De La SALLE DIVISION STATE
-- OPEN DIVISION STATE
CHARMS FOR THE FOURTH YEAR.
>> WARRIORS, ROAD TRIP ENDED IN
ATLANTA TODAY.
THEY WON THE FIRST FIVE,
INCLUDING A WIN OVER THE MIAMI
HEAT.
A LOSS IN ORLANDO AND ENDED WITH
A WIN IN ATLANTA, COMING HOME
6-1, THE BEST START SINCE THEN
91-2 SEASON.
HARRISON BARNES IMPROVING EVERY
GAME, 19 FOR THE GAME.
CONTRACTOR LANDRY, THE FOLLOWUP.
ONE-HAND SLM.
62-49 WARRIORS AT THE HALF.
THIS TEAM IS MOST EFFECTIVE WHEN
EVERYONE GETS INVOLVED.
JACKS, 13.
DAVID LEE, 20 POINTS, 11 BOARDS,
AVERAGED A DOUBLE DOUBLE EVERY
GAME ON THIS TRIP.
STEPH CURRY, ALL.
WARRIORS 6-1 IN ON THE ROAD
TRIP.
>> LET'S MOVE OVER TO COLLEGE
HOOPS.
STANFORD MEN FACING UC DAVIS.
NONCONFERENCE MATCHUP.
OF TWO WEEKS OF CAMES -- EXAMS
THEY'RE LOOKING FORWARD TO
PLAYING FOOTBALL.
DESPITE THE LAYOFF, STANFORD NO
RUSH.
THE JUMPER AND THE FOUL.
AND DWIGHT POWELL LED ALL
CARDINALS.
CARDINALS WITH THE 75-52
VICTORY.
>> CAL HOSTING CREIGHTON.
CRABTREE LED THE NATION IN
SCORING BUT ON TWO IN THE FIRST
HALF.
THEY WERE NO MATCH FOR
CREIGHTON'S DOUG McDERMOTT.
34 POINTS.
A MONSTER GAME NOR THE BLUE
JAYS.
CAL FALLS TO 6-3 WITH
CREIGHTON'S 74-64 VICTORY.
>> AND THIS ABC-7 SPORTS REPORT
BOOTH TO YOU BY RIVER LIKE
CASINO.
RAIDERS HOSTING KANSAS CITY.
THE GAME OF THE NIGHT IS THE
49ers AND PATRIOTS SO IT'S
GOING TO BE EXCITING.
>> Ama: THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THAT'S IT FOR THIS EDITION OF
ABC-7 COOPS.
Captioned by Closed Captioning
Services Inc.
HOW TO THINKING ABOUT
HOW TO KILL PEOPLE--PSYCHOPATHS
AND MYSTERY WRITERS.
I'M THE KIND THAT PAYS BETTER.
WHO AM I?
I'M RICK CASTLE.
CASTLE.