IT'S VERGA AND EXPECT SPRINKLES
NORTHWARD RIGHT NOW.
THROUGH 7:00 IT WILL BE CHILLY
AROUND THE BAY WITH TEMPERATURES
IN THE LOW 40s.
MOSTLY SUNNY BY AFTERNOON.
WE'LL HAVE A SMALL CHANCE OF A
SCATTERED SHOWER DURING THE
AFTERNOON HOURS.
FROSTY INLAND VALLEYS THROUGH
7:00.
CLOUDS WILL BE ON THE INNER
CREASE UNTIL NOON BUT 45 AROUND
LUNCH HOUR AND MID TO UPPER 40s
BY 4:00.
GRAB THAT HEAVIER COAT FOR THE
EVENING HOURS.
40-45 DEGREES.
OVER AT THE COAST.
LIGHT RAIN AND LOW TO MID 40s.
IT WILL BE TAPERING IN THE
AFTERNOON.
>> RIGHT NOW.
IT'S PRETTY LIGHTED.
THAT IS HOW WE LIKE IT.
THIS IS LOOK LIVE FROM THE SAN
MATEO BRIDGE TOLL PLAZA IN
WESTBOUND DIRECTION.
A FEW BRAKE LIGHTS MAKING YOUR
WAY OVER TO THE HIGH-RISE BUT
OTHER THAN THAT, A SMOOTH RIDE
FROM HAYWARD OVER TO SAN MATEO.
EAST SHORE FRIDAY FRAI, BUNCH
CAN WHERE 580 MERGES INTO 80.
GOLDEN GATE FIELD AND ON INTO
MacARTHUR MAZE.
NO DELAYS AT BAY BRIDGE.
680, 16 ITSELF AND EMBARCADERO A
STALL BLOCKING THE OFF-RAMP.
580 WHERE IT CONTINUES, THREE
RIGHT LANES UNTIL 9:00 THIS
MORNING, WESTBOUND SLUGGISH OUT
OF TRACY UP OVER THE ALTAMONT
PASS AND DEFINITELY SLOW THROUGH
PLEASANTON.
>>> DEVELOPING NEWS WE'RE
FOLLOWING FROM OVERNIGHT, TWO
EARLY MORNING EARTHQUAKES OFF
THE COAST OF SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
FIRST QUAKE REGISTERED 6.3, A
STRONG ONE THAT HIT AT 2:36 THIS
MORNING.
SECOND A QUAKE PROBABLY AN
AFTERSHOCK HIT ROUGHLY THE SAME
AREA 15 MINUTES LATER AND
MEASURED 4.7.
BOTH OF QUAKES HIT 150 MILES
SOUTHWEST OF CATALINA ISLAND.
A TSUNAMI WARNING HAS NOT
ISSUED.
>>> STUDENTS RETURNING THIS
MORNING TO TWO CUPERTINO SCHOOLS
AFTER A BOMB SCARE YESTERDAY
WILL NOTICE EXTRA SECURITY IN
PLACE.
TERRY McSWEENEY IS LIVE AT
MONTEVISTA HIGH SCHOOL WITH
DETAILS FOR US.
>> IT APPEARS THAT THIS ENTIRE
THING THAT WENT ON YESTERDAY WAS
A HOAX BUT SHERIFF'S DEPUTIES
NOT TAKING ANY CHANCES.
THEY ARE GOING TO HAVE
ADDITIONAL DEPUTIES AT
MONTEVISTA HIGH AND ALSO AT
LINCOLN ELEMENTARY SOMETHING
THAT BEGIN FOUR MILES FROM HERE
IN SAN JOSE.
TAKE A LOOK AT MESSAGE THAT
STARTED THIS ENTIRE THING, AT
LINBROOK HIGH SCHOOL A
SPRAY-PAINTED THREAT ABOUT A
BOMB AND THREAT ABOUT A TEACHER.
THAT THREAT LED TO SANTA CLARA
COUNTY SHERIFF'S DEPUTIES
CLOSING DOWN MONTEVISTA AND
LINCOLN ELEMENTARY.
BOMB-SNIFFING DOGS WERE CALLED
OUT.
THEY CHECKED OUT THE CAMPUS.
A ROOM BY ROOM SEARCH WENT ON.
SHORTLY AFTER THE 11:00, IT WAS
THE ALL CLEAR, JUST A HOAX BUT
THE SHERIFF'S OFFICE IS ALSO
INTERESTED IN PROTECTING THE
TEACHER IN CASE THERE MIGHT BE
SOME TRUTH TO THIS.
>> A COUPLE DEPUTIES ARE
PROVIDING PROTECTION.
>> IT WON'T BE A LAUGHING MATTER
IF THEY FIND THE PERSONS THAT
SPRAY PAINED THAT MESSAGE.
THAT PERSON OR PERSONS COULD BE
FACING A FELONY.
THIS MORNING, BOTH MONTE VISTA
HIGH AND LINCOLN ELEMENTARY WILL
BE OPEN FOR BUSINESS BUT AS I
MENTIONED ADDITIONAL SHERIFF'S
DEPUTIES WILL BE ON CAMPUS JUST
IN CASE.
TERRY McSWEENEY, "ABC 7 NEWS."
>>> FIRE INVESTIGATORS HOPE THEY
CAN GET THEIR FIRST LOOK INSIDE
A GUTTED BUSINESS TO SEE WHAT
STARTED A MASSIVE FIRE IN
FREMONT.
FAST MOVING FLAMES ENGULFED THE
BUSINESS NEAR 680.
THEY DO METAL FABRICATION WORK
FOR THE SEMI CONDUCTOR INDUSTRY.
NOBODY WAS HURT.
THEY URGED PEOPLE TO SHELTER IN
PLACE.
WE'LL HEAR FROM A MAN THAT TRIED
TO PUT ON A FIRE IN A LIVE
REPORT FROM AMY HOLLYFIELD
COMING UP AT 6:30.
>> SAN JOSE POLICE HAVE REVEALED
THE IDENTITY OF A YOUNG MAN WHO
WAS SHOT TO DEATH EARLIER THIS
WEEK.
18-YEAR-OLD JOHN CODY SONNE BRG
WAS FOUND SHOT INSIDE A PICKUP.
IT FIRST IT APPEARED HE WAS HURT
IN AN ACCIDENT BECAUSE THE TRUCK
JUMPED A CURB.
HE DIED AT THE SCENE.
DETECTIVES DON'T KNOW WHY
SOMEONE WHO WANT TO KILL HIM BUT
THEY ADD HIS DEATH IS NOT
GANG-RELATED.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, A FEDERAL
COURT WILL HEAR BARRY BONDS'
APPEAL OF OBSTRUCTION OF
CONVICTION EARLY LAST YEAR.
THEY HAVE SET ORAL ARGUMENTS FOR
FEBRUARY 13th.
A JURY CONVICTED OF HIM ONE
COUNT TO GIVE EVASIVE ANSWERS
WHEN HE WAS ASKED WHETHER HE
RECEIVED DRUGS THAT REQUIRED A
SYRINGE.
THEY DEADLOCKED ON THREE OTHER
CHARGES.
HIS LAWYERS THE ANSWER WAS
ACCURATE AND NOT MEANT TO
OBSTRUCT JUSTICE.
>> THE CITY OF SAN FRANCISCO IS
JUDGE TO DISMISS A LAWSUIT.
THEY FILED A MOTION TO THREAT
DEBATETHROUGHOUT IN MORNING.
ON THEY EXPECT IT TO DISMISS THE
CASE.
NUDITY BAN TAKES PLACE IN
FEBRUARY 1st AND ONLY ALLOWS
NUDITY ALLOWS IN BAY TO BREAKERS
AND CERTAIN FUNCTIONS.
>> FIND OUT HOW HIGH THEY WILL
HAVE TO TURN ON THE CAR HEATERS
THIS MORNING.
WE'LL HAVE SUE HALL.
LIVE LOOK AT SAN FRANCISCO AND
EMBARCADERO AREA, JUST GORGEOUS.
>> A MYRIAD OF REIGNS REASONS TO
TUNE IN.
>> SAFETY WARNING FOR PARENTS,
COMMON HOUSEHOLD APPLIANCE THAT
COULD BE PUTTING YOUR KIDS AT
RISK.
>> THAT IS WHERE IT IS STAYING
IN THE AIR AND EVAPORATING
BEFORE IT REACHES THE GROUND.
THE AIR IS SO DRY UNDERNEATH IT
IS TAKING IT AWAY.
THE AIR IS SO COLD, WE ARE STILL
UNDER A FROST ADVISORY FROM 2:00
TO 8:00.
TEMPERATURES IN MID 30s TO 40
INLAND AND UPPER 30s AROUND THE
BAY.
>> PRETTY LIGHT OUT THERE FOR A
FRIDAY MORNING.
THAT IS HOW WE LIKE IT.
WE HAVE A LIVE LOOBLG FROM THE
BAY BRIDGE, METERING LIGHTS HAVE
JUST BEEN FLIPPED ON.
CARPOOL LANES ARE GETTING BY AND
MINIMUM DELAY TO THE WEST GRAND
OVERCROSSING.
BART, MUNI, CALTRAIN, EVERYBODY
IS RUNNING ON SCHEDULE.
A GREAT WAY TO GET AROUND.
SAN FRANCISCO'S CITY STREETS
WHERE WAZE TRAFFIC APP.
THIS IS VAN NESS AND EARLIER
ACCIDENT AT FELL.
THAT HAS BEEN CLEARED ACCORDING
TO THE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
DEPARTMENT BUT IT LOOKS LIKE
SLOW TRAFFIC FROM BROADWAY ALL
THE WAY TO FELL IN SOUTHBOUND
DIRECTION.
YOU CAN NAVIGATE YOUR COMMUTE BY
DOWNLOADING A FREE APP OR GOOGLE
PLAY.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, A SAFETY
WARNING FOR ALL PARENTS OUT
THERE ABOUT THE DANGERS ABOUT
THAT TIP OVER.
RECORD NUMBER OF THE KIDS ARE
GETTING HURT BY FALLING
TELEVISION IN THEIR HOMES.
43,000 KIDS ARE INJURED THIS
YEAR AND THE FALLS LAST YEAR
WERE ACTUALLY DEADLY.
84% OF THE INJURED CHILDREN ARE
NOW NINE YEARS OLD ARE YOUNGER.
AS FAMILIES SWAP OUT OLDER TVs
THE OLD TVs ARE MOVED TO OTHER
PARTS OF THE HOME WITHOUT A
PROPER STAND.
>> NEW THIS MORNING OUT OF
VALLEJO EXAMPLE TO SEE MORE
POLICE OFFICERS WHILE YOU ARE
OUT DOING HOLIDAY SHOPPING.
VALLEJO POLICE DEPARTMENT WILL
BE CONDUCTING SPECIAL HOLIDAY
PERHAPS AT SHOPPING CENTERS AND
DOWNTOWN.
THEY WILL BE WALKING AROUND OR
RIDING BIKE.
THEIR GOAL IS TO MAKE THEMSELVES
MORE VISIBLE SO CUSTOMERS FEEL
SAFER.
>> STILL AHEAD, CABS WILL FACE
TOUGHER REGULATIONS, HOW IT WILL
KEEP PASSENGERS FROM TAKEN FOR A
RIDE.
>> A POLITICAL SHUFFLE IS ON
AFTER A KEY CANDIDATE FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE DROPS OUT OF
RUNNING.
>> AND IMPORTANT DEADLINE FOR
THE HEALTHCARE INITIATIVE.
WITH SOME STATES ARE CHOOSING
>>> WELCOME BACK.
LIVE LOOK AT DOPPLER.
CLOUDS ARE TAKING OVER AND RADAR
GETTING ACTIVE.
AS WE ZOOM IN NOTICE THIS CIRCLE
AROUND LIVE DOPPLER.
EVEN WITH THE RADAR RETURNS
RIDING ACROSS IT.
IT SHOWS ME IT'S NOT REACHING
THE GROUND.
WATER IS EVAPORATING BEFORE IT
REACHES THE GROUND.
RAIN IS STILL POSSIBLE THROUGH
7:00.
MID 40s AND ISOLATED SHOWER
POSSIBLE BY 4:00 AND HIT THE LOW
50s.
BETTER CHANCE OF MEASURABLE RAIN
TOMORROW WITH SCATTERED SHOWERS
SUNDAY INTO MONDAY.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING,
CELEBRATIONS ARE CONTINUING IN
NORTH KOREA AFTER THE COUNTRY'S
FIRST SUCCESSFUL SATELLITE
LAUNCH.
THIS IS VIDEO FROM THE STATE
ORGANIZED RALLY HELD IN NORTH
KOREAN CAPITAL.
THEY FILLED THE PUBLIC SCHOOL
PRAISING THE LAUNCHING OF
MISSILE CARRYING THE SATELLITE.
THEY HAVE BEEN TARGET OF
BLISTERING OUTRAGE FROM WORLD
LEADERS.
IT REACHED A RESOLUTION BARRING
THE COUNTRY FROM HAVING ANY
MISSILES.
>> FAMILIAR NAMES ARE BEING
BANTERED AROUND.
KATIE MARZULLO IS LIVE N THE
NEWSROOM WHAT HAPPENS NOW THAT
SUSAN RICE HAS TAKEN HERSELF OUT
OF THE RUNNING FOR SECRETARY OF
STATE.
>> THEY ARE MEETING WITH SUSAN
RICE IN PRIVATE.
PUBLICLY HE HAS RELUCTANTLY.
ALL SIGNS POINT TO JOHN KERRY OF
MASSACHUSETTS.
HE HAS HAD NO COMMENT ON THAT.
ON F KERRY GETS THE JOB HIS
SENATE SEAT BECOMES AVAILABLE.
IT'S LIKELY EXPECTED OUTGOING
SENATOR SCOTT BROWN WOULD RUN IN
THAT SPECIAL ELECTION.
AMBASSADOR RICE HAS BEEN A
CONTROVERSIAL FIGURE BECAUSE SHE
MADE STATEMENTS THAT THE DEADLY
TERRORIST ATTACK IN LIBYA WAS A
SPONTANEOUS REACTION TO AN
ANTI-MUSLIM MOVIE.
SHE SAYS SHE IS STEPPING ASIDE
BECAUSE HER NOMINATION PROCESS
WOULD BE A DISTRACTION THE
COUNTRY DOES NOT NEED RIGHT NOW.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS SAYING HE
WON'T LET RICE GO FAR.
>> AN OUTSTANDING JOB, SHE WILL
CONTINUE TO BE ONE OF TOP
MEMBERS OF MY NATIONAL SECURITY
TEAM.
>> Reporter: OTHER OPENINGS,
SECRETARY OF DEFENSE, FORMER
SENATOR CHUCK HABELGEL SEEMS TO
HAVE THE EDGE THERE.
C.I.A. DIRECTOR, ACTING DIRECTOR
MICHAEL MORALE AND JOHN BRENNAN
ARE CONSIDERED TOP CONTENDERS.
ONE LAST NOTE ON SENATOR KERRY.
SOME SAY HE IS A SHOO-IN FOR
SECRETARY OF STATE BUT HE WILL
LIKELY FACE QUESTIONS ABOUT PAST
SUPPORT FOR SYRIAN PRESIDENT
ASSAD.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, TODAY IS
DECISION DAY FOR STATES TO
NOTIFY WASHINGTON IF THEY WILL
RUN THEIR OWN INSURANCE MARKETS
UNDER HE'LL OVERHAUL.
19 STATES HAVE TURNED DOWN THE
ADMINISTRATION'S INVI STATION TO
SET UP HEALTH INSURANCE
EXCHANGES.
THAT LEAVES THE FEDS WITH A HUGE
TASK OF DOING IT FOR THEM.
ON THE OTHER SIDE, 17 STATES
INCLUDING CALIFORNIA,
WASHINGTON, D.C. SAY THEY WANT
TO SET UP THEIR OWN MARKETS.
>> WALGREEN'S DRUGSTORES HAVE
AGREED TO PAY A HUGE FINE TO
SETTLE A LAWSUIT FILED IN IN
ALAMEDA COUNTY.
THEY ARE GOING TO PAY $16.5
MILLION AFTER THEY SAY THEY
ILLEGALLY DUMPED DUMPED WASTE
INTO TRASH BINS.
THEY DUMPED PATIENTS' RECORDS
WITHOUT SHREDDING THEM FIRST.
THEY WERE FOUND TO BE VIOLATION
OF THE LAW.
THIS SETTLEMENT COVERS MORE THAN
HALF THE COUNTIES IN CALIFORNIA.
>>> NEW YORK CITY LEADERS ARE
TRYING TO PROTECT CAB PASSENGERS
TO BE TAKEN FOR A RIDE.
THE MAYOR HAS SIGNED A MEASURE
INTO LAW FACING OPERATORS TO
MAKE TIMERS CLEARLY VISIBLE TO
PASSENGERS AND CHARGE BY THE
MINUTE.
THEY SAY SOME CAB OPERATORS
CHARGE BY THE BLOCK AND PASS ON
TO SURCHARGES.
A TEXAS FAMILY PAID MORE THAN
$400 TO GO 14 BLOCKS.
>>> ABC7 HONORED RECIPIENTS OF
PROFILES EXCELLENCE AWARDS LAST
NIGHT.
THEY HAVE CELEBRATED THE BAY
AREA'S RICH CULTURAL DIVERSITY.
CHERYL JENNINGS HOSTED THE EVENT
RIGHT HERE AT ABC7.
EACH OF THE 15 PEOPLE HONORED
MADE IMPORTANT CONTRIBUTIONS TO
OUR COMMUNITY.
YOU ARE INVITED TO VIEW RECENT
EPISODES OF PROFILES OF
EXCELLENCE AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
>> SO INSPIRING AND CHECK IT
OUT.
WF 18.
WHO IS COLDEST.
>> THAT INSPIRES YOU TO WEAR A
HEAVIER COAT.
WE'LL TAKE A LOOK AT THAT AND
ALSO TAKE A LOOK WHERE THE RAIN
IS SHOWING UP ON LIVE DOPPLER
7-HD.
IT IS DRY HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
AS WE LOOK FROM VALLEJO STREET
DOWN THE EMBARCADERO TOWARDS THE
FERRY BUILDING ALL THE WAY TO
THE BAY BRIDGE.
TWEET ME WHAT IS GOING ON IN
YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD.
ASK MIKE NICCO AND CHECK OUT
LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD.
NOT A LOT OF RADAR RETURNS BUT
MOST OF IT NOT REACHING THE
GROUND.
AIR IS TOO DRY AND GREENS OUT
OVER THE OCEAN.
THAT IS WHERE WE HAVE LIGHT RAIN
FALLING AND THAT IS WHERE WE'RE
GOING TO HAVE THE BEST CHANCE OF
MEASURABLE PRECIPITATION IS NEAR
THE OCEAN.
COUPLE OF CHANCES, ONE MOVING
THROUGH RIGHT NOW AND ANOTHER
WITH THAT WEAKENING LOW PRESSURE
ON UP TO THE NORTH, RADAR
RETURNS IS DISSIPATING.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THOSE
TEMPERATURES.
WITH THE CLOUDS ROLLING IN.
THEY ACTUALLY GONE UP A FEW
DEGREES.
34 IN LIVERMORE.
EVERYBODY ELSE IN THE LOW TO MID
40s.
MONTEREY BAY, MID TO UPPER 30s
TO 41 IN MONTEREY.
CHECK OUT THAT FROSTY 32 IN
GILROY RIGHT NOW.
TODAY'S RAIN BEST OVER THE
OCEAN.
BETTER CHANCE OF US SEEING
MEASURABLE RAIN TOMORROW AND A
COUPLE MORE CHANCES NEXT WEEK.
AS FOR TODAY.
HERE IS A LOOK AT THE COLD
FRONT.
YOU SEE IT COMING ON DOWN
TOWARDS US, LIMITED IN MOISTURE
AS WE TALKED ABOUT.
THERE IS OUR BREAK.
CHILLY NIGHT WITH POSSIBLE FROST
IN INLAND VALLEYS.
NEXT STORM COMING IN FOR
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
THEN BEHIND THAT, YOU CAN SEE
ONE MORE STORM COMING IN.
NEXT STORM COMING IN, A LITTLE
FARTHER TO THE SOUTH.
WE WILL SEE TEMPERATURES
MODERATE AS WE HEAD THROUGH THE
WEEKEND AND INTO NEXT WEEK.
CLOUD COVER THIS MORNING.
A CHANCE OF SPRINKLES TO SOME
VERY LIGHT RAIN THROUGH THE NOON
HOUR.
THEN LOOK AT THAT AT THAT
SCATTERED SHOWER.
OVERNIGHT CLOUDS CLEAR, IT WILL
BE COLD AGAIN TONIGHT AS WE GET
MORE CLOUDS AROUND 7:00 OR 8:00
TOMORROW MORNING.
BY 11:00 YOU CAN SEE THE
SCATTERED RAIN START TO MOVE IN
TO OUR NEIGHBORHOODS AND JUST BE
SCATTERED RAIN THROUGHOUT THE
AFTERNOON AND EVENING HOURS.
NOT ENOUGH TO CANCEL ANY PLANS.
IT'S NOT GOING LAST HOPEFULLY
VERY LONG AND DEFINITELY WON'T
DROP HEAVY AMOUNTS LESS THAN A
TENTH OF AN INCH.
FOR SUNDAY, VERY SCATTERED AND
VERY LIGHT RAIN.
NOTICED THE TEMPERATURES IN THE
FORECAST, MID TO UPPER 50s.
AFTER BARELY ESCAPING THE 40s
TODAY.
UP TO 60 ON MONDAY.
>> 80 FREEWAY AND 80 EAST SHORE,
AS YOU MAKE YOUR WAY PAST GOLD
GATED FIELDS, THIS IS EASTBOUND
DIRECTION, YOU FIND BUNCHING UP
AROUND 580 AND THEN THINGS PICK
UP AS YOU MAKE YOUR WAY TO AGO
ARTHUR MAZE.
WE HAVE A STALLED TRUCK IN LANE
NUMBER TWO FARTHER EAST TOWARD
THE FAIRFIELD AREA.
METERING LIGHTS ON THE BAY
BRIDGE TOLL PLAZA.
CARPOOL IS GETTING BY NO DELAYS,
BUT BACKED UP TO THE 8080
OVERCROSSING AND A LITTLE
SLUGGISH AS YOU MAKE YOUR WAY
WESTBOUND.
THIS IS 280 IN THE NORTHBOUND
DIRECTION, PAST THE 17
INTERCHANGE AND TO THE CUPERTINO
AREA.
EVERYBODY IS AT THE LIMIT AT YOU
MAKE YOUR WAY IN THE NORTHBOUND
DIRECTION.
WE'LL GO BACK TO A STALL AT 16th
AVENUE STILL BLOCKING THE
OFF-RAMP.
EASTBOUND 24 BEFORE THE
CALDECOTT TUNNEL, YELLOW SENSORS
WE HAVE A STALL THERE BLOCKING
LANE NUMBER TWO, SECOND LANE
FROM THE LEFT.
NORTH 101 PAST TULLY THIS IS AN
ACCIDENT CLEAR TO THE SHOULDER
NO INJURIES INVOLVED HERE.
>>> STILL AHEAD, A NEW DEAL THAT
COULD ALLOW AN HISTORIC PLATES
IN MOUNT DIABLO TO SHINE
BRIGHTER.
>> SHOOTING STARS DURING THE
GEMINID METEOR SHOWERS.
>> THE END OF AN ERA, SIX
SEASONS.
CLOUDS ARE SET OKAY A JERSEY
SHORE.
A POP CULTURE SENSATION THE SHOW
HAS BECOME.
TODAY LAUNDRY AND KATIE.
THEY ARE ALL HERE AND WE WILL BE
ASSESSING THE SITUATION, AS
WELL.PAULA FARI
>> FRIDAY MORNING, WE HAVE
SUNSHINE DURING THE AFTERNOON
HOURS, AND TEMPERATURES IN THE
40s TO LOW 50s.
DEFINITELY WELL BELOW AVERAGE.
COUPLE CHANCES OF RAIN, MOVING
DOWN TOWARD US AND SOME MOUNTAIN
SNOW.
IN TAHOE WE HAVE A CHANCE OF
SNOW SHOWERS TODAY BUT A COUPLE
OF INCHES OF FRESH POWDER FOR
YOU ON SUNDAY.
ENJOY THAT.
WE HAVE RAIN IF YOU ARE HEADED
THAT WAY.
DRIER TOMORROW AND BETTER CHANCE
OF RAIN ON SUNDAY.
>>> LOOK CLOSELY AT THIS SHOT OF
THE STARS FROM NASA.
IT SHOWS LAST NIGHT'S GEMINID
METEOR SHOWERS, IT WAS AT PEAK
LAST NIGHT.
THE EVENT HAPPENS AROUND THIS
TIME AS THE EARTH PASSES THROUGH
THE TAIL OF AN ASTEROID THAT
CREATES A SHOOTING STAR.
THAT WAS APPEARING BEFORE DAWN.
>> YOU STILL HAVE A CHANCE TO
GET OUT AND SEE IT.
>> AND CONSERVATION GROUP IS
GOING TO RESTORE THE PEAK THAT
SITS IN THE EAST BAY AFTER
SIGNING AN AGREEMENT.
THEY REPORT THE GROUP SAVE MOUNT
DIABLO THEY WANT TO FIX THE
LIGHT ON THE PEAK THAT OVERLOOKS
LARGE SECTIONS OF THE BAY AREA
AND CENTRAL VALLEY.
IT'S LIT ONCE A YEAR.
DECEMBER 7th TO HONOR PEARL
HARBOR VICTIMS BUT IT IS
SUFFERING FROM AGE AND LACK OF
MAINTENANCE MONEY.
IT WAS BUILT IN 1928 DESIGNED TO
NINE SHOO INHIGH ENOUGH TO HELP
SHIPS AND AIRPLANES NAVIGATE.
>> STUDENT RETURN AFTER A BOMB
THREAT.
>> AND A MOTHER WHO LEFT HER
NEWBORN ON A COLD SAN FRANCISCO
STREET IS DUE IN COURT TODAY.
CRIMINAL CHARGES SHE IS FACING.
>> PLUS A NEW CRIME FIGHTING
STRATEGY, TWO BAY AREA CITIES
ARE HOPING TO TAKE FIREARMS
>>> GOOD MORNING, 6:30.
WE MADE IT TO FRIDAY.
IF YOU CAN'T CLIMB TO THE EAST
BAY HILLS TO LOOK HOW THE BAY
LOOKS, WE'LL GIVE YOU A LIVE
PICTURE TO AVOID ALL THE
TROUBLE.
>> AND THE COLD.
>> AND COLD CONDITIONS.
THAT IS BIG STORY THIS MORNING.
GOOD MORNING, I'M KRISTEN SZE.
>>> I'M ERIC THOMAS.
TELL US MORE ABOUT THE COLD.
>> 30s INLAND AND EVEN 30s ON
THE PENINSULA TO LOW 40s AROUND.
ONE OF OUR COOLER MORNINGS.
CLOUDS ARE COMING IN AND REACHED
THE MAXIMUM COOLING.
WE SEE SOME STUFF FALLING FROM
THE CLOUDS ON LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD
BUT IT'S NOT MAKING IT DOWN INTO
OUR NEIGHBORHOODS.
IF IT DOES FEW SPRINKLES IN THE
MORNING.
TEMPERATURES IN THE 30s AND 40s.
IT WILL BE SUNNY BY NOON.
STILL CLOUDS OUT THERE AND
SCATTERED SHOWERS POSSIBLE IN
THE AFTERNOON HOURS.
CLOUDS ARE ON THE INCREASE RIGHT
NOW.
THEY WILL START TO DECREASE, A
QUICK MOVING STORM.
WE'LL HAVE PARTLY CLOUDY
CONDITIONS WITH SOME CHILLED
SUNSHINE AND TEMPERATURES IN THE
MID TO UPPER 40s.
DOWN AT THE COAST, BEST CHANCE
OF SEEING MEASURABLE RAIN.
LOW TO MID 40s THERE.
TAPERING BY NOON.
MID TO UPPER 40s AND STRAY
SHOWER AND MID TO UPPER 40s BY
4:00 HOUR.
>> LOOKING WEST FROM THE SAN
MATEO BRIDGE TOLL PLAZA, YOU CAN
SEE TRAFFIC IS GETTING BUSIER ON
THE SAN MATEO BRIDGE WITH BRAKE
LIGHTS HAPPENING WESTBOUND UP
TOWARDS THE HIGH-RISE.
EVERYTHING IS MOVING.
WE'RE LOOKING AT ABOUT 15 MINUTE
RIGHT FROM EAST BAY TO THE
PENINSULA.
STALL ON EASTBOUND 24 BEFORE THE
CALDECOTT TUNNEL, BOTTLING THE
RIGHT LANE, NON-COMMUTE
DIRECTION WE HAVE A STALLED
PICKUP TRUCK AND WESTBOUND 37 AT
LAKEVILLE, AN ACCIDENT ON THE
SHOULDER AND TO SAN JOSE NORTH
101 PAST JULIAN THAT ONE IS ALSO
ON THE SHOULDER.
>> MORE ON DEVELOPING NEWS WE'VE
BEEN FOLLOWING THIS MORNING, A
STRONG EARTHQUAKE OFF THE COAST
OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
6.3 QUAKE HIT AT 2:36 THIS
MORNING, 160 MILES WEST OF
CATALINA ISLAND.
IT WAS FOLLOWED BY AN AFTERSHOCK
AND THESE NUMBERS HAVE BEEN
REVISED AND THOSE ARE THE
LATEST.
NO REPORTS OF DAMAGE OR
INJURIES.
PEOPLE SAID THEY FELT IT ACROSS
ORANGE COUNTY.
ONE MAN SAID THE QUAKE ROLLED
FOR ABOUT 25 SECONDS.
>> EMPLOYEES AT A SITE OF RAGING
INDUSTRIAL FIRE IN FREMONT.
IT GUTTED C AND H ENTERPRISES A
METAL FABRICATION PLANTED NEAR
680.
AMY HOLLYFIELD JOINS US WITH A
LOOK WHAT IS LEFT BEHIND TODAY.
>> RIGHT NOW THE GOAL IS TO KEEP
PEOPLE OUT OF THE BUILDINGS.
THEY HAVE A SECURITY GUARD HERE
MAKING SURE THAT NO ONE GETS IN.
IT'S JUST NOT SAFE.
SO FIREFIGHTERS ARE WAITING FOR
AN ENGINEER TO COME AND CHECK IT
OUT ONES IT IS DAYLIGHT BEFORE
FIREFIGHTERS GO IN AND LOOK FOR
A CAUSE.
IT CAUGHT FIRE AROUND 1:45
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON.
FIREFIGHTERS SAY IT WAS AN
INTENSE FIRE.
THE ROOF COLLAPSED AND THEY
WEREN'T ABLE TO GO INSIDE.
THERE WERE ABOUT 60 EMPLOYEES IN
THE BUILDING WHEN THE FIRE
STARTED AND ONE TRIED TO PUT OUT
ZBLEIRTD I TRIED TO HELP BUT IT
CAUGHT ON TOO FAST.
THERE WAS NOTHING I COULD DO.
>> IT WAS FULLY INVOLVED WHEN WE
ARRIVED.
WE HAD FIRE THROUGH THE ROOF AND
OUT THE.
>> Kristen: NO ONE WAS HURT.
EVERYONE GOT OUT OKAY.
FIREFIGHTERS DID ASK PEOPLE IN
THE AREA TO SHELTER IN PLACE AS
A PRECAUTION.
THEY WANTED TO TRY TO KEEP THE
FIRE JUST TO BUILDING BUT THEY
WANTED TOW BE CAREFUL.
THEY WORRIED ABOUT POSSIBLE
HAZARDOUS MATERIALS BURNING IN
THE FIRE.
EVERYTHING WAS FINED AND KEPT IT
CONTAINED TO THE BUILDING.
THEY DO PRECISION WELDING AND
FABRICATING.
THERE IS A SIGN THERE IS
COMBUSTIBLE AND FLAMMABLE
MATERIALS INSIDE.
THE DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS FOR
THE COMPANY SAYS THAT THE
COMPANY HAS GOOD INSURANCE AND
IT WILL COVER THE LOST WAGES AND
SALARIES OF THE EMPLOYEES.
>>> THERE WILL BE EXTRA SECURITY
AT TWO SOUTH BAY SCHOOLS WHEN
THEY REOPEN THIS MORNING.
SHERIFF'S DEPUTIES WILL BE ON
CAMPUS AT MONTEVISTA AND LINCOLN
ELEMENTARY.
GRAFFITI CALLED ON A WALL AT
DIFFERENT CAMPUS IN SAN JOSE
CLAIMED THERE WAS A BOMB AT
MONTEVISTA AND THREATENED TO
KILL A TEACHER THERE.
NO DEVICE WAS FOUND.
AUTHORITIES SAY THEY ARE ALSO
MAKING SURE THAT SPECIFIC
TEACHER NAMED IN THE THREAT
REMAINS UNDER PROTECTION.
>>> WOMAN ACCUSED OF ABANDONING
HER NEWBORN BABY IN SAN
FRANCISCO IS EXPECTED TO BE
ARRAIGNED TODAY ON CHARGES OF
CHILD CRUELTY.
AS WE FIRST TOLD YOU ON
WEDNESDAY MORNING, A MAN FOUND
THE BABY BOY LYING ON THE STREET
IN THE CITY'S BAYVIEW DISTRICT.
THEY FOUND THE MOM NEARBY
COVERED IN BLOOD.
SHE IS IDENTIFIED AS 39-YEAR-OLD
NANEKKA NASH.
THEY PERFORMED CPR WHILE RUSHING
HIM TO SAN FRANCISCO GENERAL
HOSPITAL.
DOCTORS FOUND TRACES OF COCAINE
IN THE NEWBORN'S SYSTEM.
>> A SIXTH SUSPECT OF DUMPING
BOTH OF THEM ON SAN FRANCISCO
STREET AFTER SHOOTING THEM.
STEVEN READ DIED MONDAY AT A
HOSPITAL AFTER HOURS HE AND HIS
GIRLFRIEND WERE FOUND TIED UP IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE STREET.
POLICE BELIEVE THEY WERE VICTIMS
OF A BRUTAL HOME INVASION ON
SUNDAY BY A GROUP AIR QUAINT
ANSWERS IN THE VISITACION
VALLEY.
FOUR OTHER SUSPECTS THREE OF
WHICH ARE WOMEN ARE ALSO
EXPECTED AT THAT HEARING.
>> A STATE APPEALS COURT HAS
REJECTED A CLAIM FROM A FORMER
ADMINISTRATOR THAT SHE WAS FIRED
ILLEGALLY BY THEN MAYOR RON
DELLUMS.
SHE LOST HER JOB IN 2008.
SHE CLAIMS DELLUMS FIRED HER
BECAUSE SHE QUESTIONED THE
SPENDING OF CITY MONEY BY THE
MAYOR AND HIS WIFE.
HE SAYS SHE WAS DISMISSED
BECAUSE OF A TIP-OFF OF AN
IMPENDING POLICE RAID.
>> THE OAKLAND AND SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE DEPARTMENTS ARE TRYING
TAKE BACK THE STREETS BY KEEPING
GUNS OFF THEM.
BOTH DEPARTMENTS WILL HOLD GUN
BUY-BACK PROGRAMS.
PARTICIPANTS WILL GET $200 CASH
BUT A LIMIT OF THREE.
THE PROGRAM IS SPONSORED BY THE
BOYS CLUB AND YOUTH UPRISING.
IN OAKLAND THE PROGRAM WILL BE
HELD AT ST. BEEN DIGITS CHURCH.
IN SAN FRANCISCO IT'S AT THE
BOYS CLUB.
BOTH RUN FROM 10:00 IN THE
MORNING UNTIL 3:00 IN THE
AFTERNOON.
FOR MORE INFORMATION GO TO OUR
WEBSITE AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
>>> TRAFFIC AND WEATHER TOGETHER
HERE IS A LIVE LOOK OUTSIDE.
WE'VE GOT THE BAY BRIDGE TOLL
PLAZA.
TRAFFIC BACKING UP.
ROADS ARE DRY.
MIKE NICCO WILL HAVE FULL
ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST AND CHECK
IN WITH SUE HALL IN THE TRAFFIC
CENTER.
>> ALSO NEW DETAILS ON THE DEATH
OF MEXICAN-AMERICAN SUPERSTAR
JENNI RIVERA, WHY THE PLANE
CRASH HAS SPARKED THE
>>> WELCOME BACK.
HERE IS A LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER
7-HD.
WE HAVE RADAR RETURNS AND STILL
NO PROOF IT IS REACHING THE
GROUND.
IF IT DOES, A FEW SPRINKLES OUT
THERE.
TEMPERATURES RUNNING IN SOME OF
THE HIGHER ELEVATIONS NEAR
FREEZING A FLURRY ON TOP OF
MOUNT DIABLO OR HAMILTON.
LET'S TALK ABOUT WHAT IS GOING
TO HAPPEN.
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE A STRAY
SHOWER AND TEMPERATURES RUNNING
POSSIBLY IN THE UPPER 40s INLAND
TO NEAR 50.
>> WE'VE GOT A LIVE LOOK AT BAY
BRIDGE TOLL PLAZA.
WE SHOWED YOU A MINUTE AND
TRAFFIC IS REALLY JAMMED, BACK
TO THE WEST GRAND AND 880
OVERCROSSING.
I WANTED TO SHOW YOU LIVE LOOK
MacARTHUR MAZE.
BERKELEY CURVE, NO PROBLEMS WITH
THE MAZE AS FAR AS THAT GOES.
A LITTLE BIT OF TRAFFIC HEADED
IN THE EASTBOUND DIRECTION,
COMING INTO THE BAY BRIDGE NO
PROBLEM, LEVY RIDGE ON-RAMP
REMAINS CLOSED AND WESTBOUND IS
SLOW OUT OF ANTIOCH.
>>> TWO POLICE OFFICERS IN
MEXICO HAVE BEEN ARRESTED FOR
STEALING EVIDENCE FROM THE SITE
WHERE SINGER JENNI RIVERA'S
PLANE CRASH HAPPENED IN MEXICO.
THEY WON'T SAY WHAT THEY WERE
BUT THEY WERE FOUND AT OFFICER'S
HOMES.
IN ANOTHER NEW DEVELOPMENT THE
DRUG ENFORCEMENT ADMINISTRATION
AGENCY IS ALSO INVESTIGATING THE
COMPANY THAT OWNS THE LUXURY JET
THAT CRASHED AND KILLED THE
MEXICAN POP SUPERSTAR AND SIX
OTHERS ON SUNDAY SAYING THEY
WILL TO PLANES SEIZED THIS YEAR.
>>> PORTLAND MALL WHERE A GUNMAN
TOOK THREE LIVES IS SET TO
REOPEN AT NINE THIS MORNING.
A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL IS SET FOR
TONIGHT.
POLICE ARE STILL TRYING TO
FIGURE OUT WHY 22-YEAR-OLD JAKE
ROBERTS WALKED INTO THE TOWN
CENTER ON TUESDAY WEARING A
HOCKEY MASK AND OPENED FIRE.
A TEENAGE GIRL WAS ALSO WOUNDED.
ROBERTS EX-GIRLFRIEND HE HAD
QUIT HIS JOB AND SOLD EVERYTHING
HE OWNED IN DAYS BEFORE THE
ATTACK BUT SO FAR INVESTIGATORS
HAVE NOT REVEALED A CLEAR MOTIVE
FORFEITURE SHOOTING.
>> COMING UP, WE HAVE VIDEO OF
THE MOST STUNNING STORY.
A DIE-HARD APPLE FAN, A MOTHER
ENDS UP BEING TASED AT THE MALL.
>> AND TROUBLE AT PG&E,
IMPORTANT INSPECTIONS THAT WERE
NOT DONE AND IT
>>> OUR BEST CHANCE OF SPRINKLES
AS WE HEAD INTO THE AFTERNOON
HOURS, STRAY SHOWER, LOOK HOW
COLD.
UPPER 40s TO LOW 50s.
SYSTEM IS FALLING APART AS IT IS
HEADING TOWARD THE BAY AREA.
SO A STRAY SHOWER POSSIBLE
TODAY.
LOOK AT TAHOE, ABOUT 33 DEGREES
WITH SNOW SHOWERS AND COUPLE OF
INCHES OF POWDER FOR YOU ON
SUNDAY.
>>> LET'S CHECK IN WITH JOSH
ELLIOT FOR A PREVIEW WHAT IS
COMING UP ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA" AT 7:00.
>>> GOOD FRIDAY MORNING.
COMING UP HERE BARBARA WALTERS
TO TALK ABOUT HER EXCLUSIVE SIT
DOWN WITH PRESIDENT OBAMA AND
MICHELLE OBAMA.
THIS IS THE COUPLE'S FIRST
INTERVIEW.
ALSO FOR YOU TODAY, WE'VE BEEN
COUNTING DOWN THE PLAYS OF THE
YEAR ALL WEEK.
TODAY IT IS NUMBER ONE.
TO WRING IT IN WE HAVE A VERY
SPECIAL GUEST.
DON'T MISS IT ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA."
>> NEW THIS MORNING, PG&E IS
RUSHING TO INSPECT MORE THAN
1500 PIECES OF UNDER GROUND
ELECTRICAL EQUIPMENT IN THE BAY
AREA FOR POSSIBLE SAFETY
HAZARDS.
THIS COMES AFTER REQUIRED
INSPECTIONS MAY NOT HAVE
ACTUALLY BEEN PERFORMED.
PG&E HAS EXPERIENCED EXPLOSIONS
AND FIRES IN UNDER GROUND VAULTS
IN THE CITY INCLUDING ONE IN
UNION SQUARE THAT SENT A MANHOLE
COVER INTO THE AIR AND INJURING
A PASSERBY.
THEY FIRED EMPLOYEES WHO CLAIMED
TO HAVE INSPECTED EQUIPMENT WHEN
THEY ACTUALLY HAD NONE ZBLOT A
JUDGE RECEIVED A PUBLIC
ADMONISHMENT STEMMING FROM
COMMENTS HE GAVE.
DEREK JOHNSON GOT HIMSELF IN HOT
WATER I'M NOT A GYNECOLOGIST BUT
I CAN TELL YOU SOMETHING, IF
SOMEONE DOESN'T WANT TO HAVE
SEXUAL INTERCOURSE, THE BODY
SHUTS DOWN.
WHEN HE SEND THE IQ BOYFRIEND
BACK IN 2008, PROSECUTORS WANTED
A 16 YEAR SENTENCE.
>>> YOU'VE GOT TAKE A LOOK AT
THIS STORY.
A WOMAN IN NEW ENGLAND SAYS
POLICE USE ADD TASER GUN TO
KEEPER FROM KEEP HER BY BUYING
TOO MANY iPHONES.
SHE SUFFERED SEVERAL INJURIES
AFTER A CONFRONTATION WITH
POLICE.
IT SHOWS LEE ON THE GROUND.
SHE HAD A BOUGHT TWO iPHONES
FROM THAT STORY.
THE TROUBLE STARTED WHEN SHE
RETURNED TO THE STORE AFTER
BUYING TWO MORE ONLINE.
THE STORE CLAIMS THEY HAD A STAY
AWAY ORDER AGAINST LEE AND SHE
VIDEOTAPED OTHER PEOPLE THEY
WERE BUYING MORE THAN THEIR
LIMIT OF TWO.
WOW!
>> YOUR KIDS GOING WELL IN
SCHOOL MAY NOT BE THE BEST IDEA.
>> AND LOT OF PEOPLE ARE PUTTING
OFF THEIR HOLIDAY SHOPPING.
LET'S GO TO JANE KING LIVE FROM
THE NEW YORK STOCK EXCHANGE.
>> ALMOST HOLIDAY SHOPPING
CRUNCH TIMING.
TEN DAYS TO CHRISTMAS EVE AND
THEY SAY, 6% OF CONSUMERS WILL
WAIT UNTIL THREE DAYS TO START
SHOPPING.
THEY ALSO SAY 58% HAS STARTED
SHOPPING AS OF YESTERDAY.
INVESTORS ARE KEEPING AN EYE ON
RETAIL INDUSTRY.
IT SHOWED NO INFLATION OUT
THERE.
SO IT'S BEEN A CONCERN OF SOME
BUT SO FAR, LOOKS LIKE INFLATION
NOT AN ISSUE FOR THE ECONOMY.
THE DOW AND S&P 500 AND NASDAQ
LOOK LIKE THIS MORNING, VERY
QUIET.
IT CONTINUES TO BE ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF AND IF THERE IS ANY
PROGRESS BEING MADE IN
WASHINGTON.
SILICON VALLEY INDEX, DOWN MORE
THAN HALF A PERCENT.
SEARS AND ADOBE HAVING SOME LUCK
OFFERING WEB BASED SUBSCRIPTIONS
TO THE SIDE SHIP FLEET PRODUCT.
AND IF YOU ARE TRYING TO GET
YOUR CHILD TO DO BETTER IN
SCHOOL, ONE MAY NOT MAKE THE
GRADE PAYING CHILDREN TO GET
GOOD GRADES.
OFFERING MONEY CAN DISCOURAGE
KIDS FROM WORKING HARD AND CAUSE
FRUSTRATION AND RESENTMENT AMONG
SIBLINGS.
THEY THINGS LIKE
SELF-REMEMBERING LIAGS AND GRIT
AND RESILIENCE.
BUT SOME PARENTS PAYING KIDS FOR
GRADES BUT AND ONE ANALYST SAY
IT'S A WAY OF PREPARING THEM FOR
LIFE.
>> IT'S OKAY.
JANE, I ACTUALLY DON'T USE MONEY
TO BUY THEM.
I SHAME THEM.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> SHAME THEM?
>> WHY, YOU DON'T GET SHAMED AND
THAT IS FORM OF BRIBERY IN
ITSELF.
>> AND LADY WITH A GIFT OF BEING
SHAMED.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> NO SHAME IN THE FORECAST,
BUNDLING UP TODAY.
FROM BAD TO WORSE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> NOT LIKE YOU TO DO THAT.
YOU CAN DO THAT LIKE I NORMALLY
DO.
GOOD MORNING TO YOU.
YOU DON'T SHAME THEM THAT MUCH.
WE ALL DO THAT A LITTLE BIT.
FROSTY OUT THERE THIS MORNING,
YOU MAY NEED AN ICE SCRAPE
WHEARND A BEAUTIFUL PICTURE FROM
MOUNT TAMALPAIS.
YOU NOTICE YOU DON'T SEE ANY
RAIN.
WE LOOK DOWN TO THE SOUTH THIS
MORNING.
LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD, MOST OF THAT
IS STAYING MOUNTAIN CLOUDS OR
WHEN IT IS FALLING IT IS RUNNING
INTO A LAYER OF DRY AIR AND IT'S
EVAPORATING ALL THIS RAIN THAT
IS TRYING TO MAKE IT TO THE
GROUND THIS MORNING.
WE HAVEN'T HAD A SINGLE REPORT
OF A EVEN A SPRINKLE FALLING YET
THIS MORNING.
THE SYSTEM STILL HAS TWO PARTS
TO IT.
A SECOND SYSTEM YOU SEE IT
FALLING APART TO THE NORTH.
THAT IS ONE COMING IN LATER
TODAY AND BRING US A CHANCE OF A
STRAY SHOWER.
USE THE ICE SCRAPE THEY ARE
MORNING AND IT WAS DEFINITELY
COLD AT ONE POINT.
THE CAR GOT DOWN TO 29 DEGREES
DURING THROUGH THE EAST BAY
HILLS.
MID TO UPPER 30s AND HILLS AND
NORTH BAY, 39 AT SAN JOSE AND 36
IN LOS GATOS.
A LOT OF 3.30s AROUND THE BAY.
BETTER CHANCE TOMORROW AND MORE
RAIN AS WE HEAD TOWARDS NEXT
WEEK.
WHAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT TODAY,
A COLD FRONT, A PASS FAGS MOVING
ONE, VERY NARROW BAND AND CLEAR
AIR BEHIND IT TONIGHT.
FROSTY AND THIS IS TOMORROW AND
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY.
THEN ONCE WE GET PAST THAT WE'VE
GOT ANOTHER SYSTEM THAT WILL
COME IN ON MONDAY.
EACH ONE WILL PROGRESSIVELY GET
A LITTLE WARMER.
LIGHT RAIN MAINLY OVER THE OCEAN
AND STRAY SHOWER IN THE
AFTERNOON.
TONIGHT CLEAR, A BETTER CHANCE
OF SCATTERED, LIGHT RAIN
SATURDAY AND SUNDAY BUT IT'S SO
LIGHT, DO NOT CANCEL YOUR PLANS.
LOW TO MID 50s TOMORROW.
UPPER 50s TO NEAR 60 BY MONDAY.
>> EASTBOUND SAN JOSE BRIDGE,
REVERSE COMMUTE.
WE ARE GETTING REPORTS OF A
STALL COMING OFF THE HIGH RIGHT
RIES IN THE RIGHT LANE.
HEADLIGHTS HEADED TOWARDS
HAYWARD MOVING AT THE LIMIT.
A LITTLE SLOW ON THE FLAT
SECTION AS YOU MAKE YOUR WAY
OVER FOSTER CITY.
GETTING BUSIER PAST LUCAS VALLEY
ROAD INTO CENTRAL SAN RAFAEL.
SERVICING AT THE LIMIT.
NO DELAYS ON GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE.
ALL MASS TRANSIT CHECKING IN ON
TIME.
LIVE CRIMES THERE IS SAN JOSE
BRIDGE.
15 MINUTES AND 101 OUT OF SANTA
ROSA AND OUT OF SAN JOSE.
>> AHEAD FIVE THINGS TO KNOW
BEFORE YOU GO.
>>
>>> FIVE THINGS TO KNOW BEFORE
YOU GO.
NUMBER ONE, C AND H ENTERPRISES
EMPLOYEES WILL LEARN HOW THE
COMPANY PLANS TO REBUILD AFTER A
MAJOR FIRE YESTERDAY.
NOBODY WAS HURT.
INVESTIGATORS HOPE TO GET THEIR
FIRST LOOK INSIDE THE GUTTED
BUILDING TODAY AS THEY SEARCH
FOR THE CAUSE OF THE FIRE.
>> NUMBER TWO, EXTRA SECURITY AT
MONTEVISTA HIGH SCHOOL AND
LINCOLN ELEMENTARY.
A BOMB THREAT FORCED THE CLOSURE
OF BOTH SCHOOLS YESTERDAY.
NO DEVICE WAS FOUND.
>> NUMBER THREE, PG&E IS RUSHING
TO INSPECT MORE THAN 1500 PIECES
OF UNDER GROUND ELECTRICAL
EQUIPMENT IN THE BAY AREA FOR
POSSIBLE SAFETY HAZARDS.
UTILITY SAYS IT HAS FIRED OR
SUSPENDED EMPLOYEES AND CONTRACT
WORKERS WHO CLAIM TO HAVE
INSPECTED EQUIPMENT.
>>> THE WOMAN ACCUSED OF
ABANDONING HER NEWBORN BABY WILL
BE IN COURT TODAY.
39-YEAR-OLD NANEKKA NASH FACES
CHARGES OF CHILD CRUELTY.
HER BONE BOY WAS FOUND ON A
STREET NOT BREATHING.
>> MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR JOHN
KERRY APPEARS TO BE AT THE TOP
OF THE LIST FOR THE JOB OF
SECRETARY OF STATE.
U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE HAS
TAKEN HERSELF OUT OF THE
RUNNING.
HER NOMINATION WOULD BE TOO
DISTRACTING BECAUSE OF THE
CONTROVERSY SURROUNDING THE
SEPTEMBER 11th TERROR ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI.
>> IT IS COLD OUT THERE.
ONE CHECK ON THE TEMPERATURES
WITH MIKE.
>> WE'LL TALK ABOUT 30s AND 40s.
IT FEELS COOLER AFTER WE LOOK AT
LIVE DOPPLER AND SEE THE RADAR
RETURNS, NOTHING MAKE CAN IT TO
THE GROUND.
LOOK AT YOUR TEMPERATURE IN YOUR
CITY.
36 AT NAPA.
34 IN LIVERMORE.
36 IN LOS GATOS.
40 IN SAN JOSE.
A LITTLE BIT OF WIND CHILL THREE
TO FIVE DEGREES COOLER.
LOW 50s AND STRAY SHOWERS THIS
AFTERNOON.
>> BACK TO THE BAY BRIDGE,
METERING LIGHTS REMAIN ON AND
TRAFFIC BACKING TOWARD THE 880
INTERCHANGE AND SLUGGISH ON THE
INCLINE.
HERE IS A LOOK AT MAZE, 80
COMING IN NICELY, 580 AND WE DO
HAVE A STALL EASTBOUND 24
APPROACHING THE CALDECOTT.
LEFT LANE BLOCKED THERE.
WE HAVE SLOW TRAFFIC OUT OF
CENTRAL VALLEY AND EASTBOUND
ROAD WORK UNTIL 9:00 ON 580 THIS
MORNING.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MORNING NEWS CONTINUES IN 25
MINUTES WITH NEWS A, WEATHER
DURING "GOOD MORNING AMERICA."
>> WE'RE ALWAYS ON AT
ABC7NEWS.COM.
HAVE A GREAT DAY AND GREAT
WEEKEND.
>>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
BREAKING RIGHT NOW, TWO, LARGE
OFF CALIFORNIA, WAKE UP
THOUSANDS ALONG THE WEST COAST
OVERNIGHT.
NOW REGISTERING 6.3.
WE'LL HAVE THE VERY LATEST ON
THIS BREAKING STORY.
>>> UNDER FIRE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA'S TOP CONTENDER
TO REPLACE HILLARY CLINTON DROPS
OUT, MAKING A SUDDEN WITHDRAWAL,
SAYING SHE WANTS TO SPARE HIM
THE FIGHT.
A MAJOR CABINET SHAKEUP ROOMING
AS RICE HEADS TO THE WHITE HOUSE
FOR A FACE-TO-FACE.
>>> CAUGHT ON TAPE.
THE REMARKABLE STORY BEHIND THIS
VIDEO.
LOOK CLOSELY AT THAT PICKUP
TOSSED BY A TORNADO.