MICHAEL WALTRIP.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
GO!
[ ENGINE REVS ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WELL, I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
THE HOUSE
IS COMING TOGETHER AWESOME,
AND WE'VE GOT
LANDSCAPING GOING IN,
SIDING, DOORS, WINDOWS ARE IN.
WHAT'S REALLY IMPORTANT
TO UNDERSTAND, TOO,
IS FOR THE FRIDAY FAMILY,
THEIR OLD HOUSE,
IT WAS SO SMALL,
THEY TRIED TO MAKE MORE SPACE
BY CONVERTING THEIR GARAGE
INTO ROOMS FOR THE KIDS.
WELL, NOW
WE'VE CHANGED ALL THAT.
WE'VE GIVEN THEM A SPACE FOR
NOT ONLY THE FAMILY TO GROW,
BUT WE'RE
GIVING THE KIDS
SOMETHING THEY'VE NEVER HAD
BEFORE -- ROOMS OF THEIR OWN.
UP HERE ON THE SECOND FLOOR,
THIS IS THE HUB.
IT'S SORT OF THE NUCLEUS
OF THE WHOLE UPSTAIRS.
IT'S THE LEARNING CENTER.
I'M TAKING CARE OF THIS ROOM.
I LOVE THIS.
IT'S GOT A COLUMN
IN THE MIDDLE.
THERE'LL BE DESKS
ALL THE WAY AROUND.
THEY'LL HAVE THEIR OWN
COMPUTERS, TONS OF STORAGE.
YOU KNOW WHAT I LOVE,
THOUGH, IS THAT THIS
IS IN THE MIDDLE,
BUT THEN THE BOYS
ARE WAY OVER THERE
AND THE GIRLS
ARE WAY OVER HERE.
AS IT SHOULD BE.
I'M GOING
TO THE GIRLS' SIDE.
Woman:
HELLO! HOW ARE YOU?
HELLO!
OH, MY GOSH.
I KNOW WHO YOU GIRLS ARE.
YOU GUYS ARE THE BOGER CITY
STEELERS CHEERLEADERS.
AND MISS DEVONDA IS YOUR
CHEERLEADING COACH, RIGHT?
YEAH? AND,
SO WHO'S BEEN COACHING YOU?
NOBODY.
NOBODY?
IF I PULL A FEW STRINGS,
I MIGHT BE ABLE TO FIND
SOMEBODY PRETTY COOL
TO FILL IN FOR HER.
WOULD YOU GUYS
LIKE THAT?
All: YEAH.
OKAY.
SO, DEVONDA'S
THE HEAD COACH
FOR THE BOGER CITY STEELERS
CHEERLEADING TEAM.
SHE'S VERY PASSIONATE ABOUT IT.
THE GIRLS ARE VERY PASSIONATE
ABOUT THEIR CHEERLEADING.
SO I HAVE TO MAKE SURE
THAT THEY DON'T LOSE THEIR ZEST
WHILE SHE'S GONE.
OKAY, GIRLS. HERE WE GO!
[ ALL SCREAMING ]
SO, I THOUGHT TO MYSELF,
WHY DON'T WE DO SOMETHING
REALLY SPECIAL WHILE SHE'S GONE
AND GET SOMEBODY PRETTY COOL
TO FILL IN HER SHOES?
Man:
PLEASE WELCOME THE LADY CATS!
[ ALL SCREAMING ]
WHO BETTER TO FILL IN
DEVONDA'S SHOES
THAN THE OFFICIAL NBA DANCERS
FOR THE BOBCATS?
WHEN THE LADY CATS CAME IN,
WE WERE SO EXCITED.
WE JUMPED AND CLAPPED.
IT WAS SO MUCH FUN.
THIS IS BRANDY.
SHE'S THE HEAD COACH
FOR THE LADY CATS.
ALL RIGHT, WE'RE GONNA PUMP
OUR ARMS ON 1. PUMP OUR ARMS.
2.
Girl: WE GOT TO CHEER
WITH THE LADY CATS,
AND IT WAS SO MUCH FUN.
I NEED TO SEE THOSE SMILES.
STEP AND PUNCH
AND DO YOUR ARMS UP IN THE AIR.
CAN YOU SINK THIS?
All: GO, LADY CATS!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Paige:
THIS LOOKS AMAZING.
OKAY, SO, WE'RE MISSING
AN ENGINE, BUT THAT'S OKAY,
BECAUSE
IT'S NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
THEY'RE JUST GONNA BE SITTING
WATCHING MOVIES.
Paige:
WE GOT A CHALLENGE FROM TY
TO RE-CREATE
A DRIVE-IN MOVIE THEATER
IN THE FRIDAYS' BACKYARD.
WE WANT THE SEATING
FOR THIS DRIVE-IN THEATER
TO BE BASED ON, KIND OF,
A RETRO FEEL
AND BE IN OLD, CLASSIC CARS.
IF WE DO THIS RIGHT, WE'RE
GONNA CREATE THIS EXPERIENCE
THAT IS GONNA CREATE MEMORIES
FOR YEARS TO COME
FOR THE FRIDAY FAMILY.
SO, YOU HANDLE THE HARDWARE.
I'LL HANDLE THE SOFT STUFF.
PETE?
YES, SIR.
PETE BURGESS.
HOW ARE YOU?
NICE TO SEE YOU.
GLAD TO MEET YOU, MIKE.
SO, THIS IS THE SPACE
WE'RE TALKING ABOUT, RIGHT?
YES, IT IS.
COME ON IN.
LET ME SHOW YOU AROUND.
DEVONDA AND JAMES,
THEY HAVE AN ORGANIZATION
CALLED "HOUSE OF HOPE."
AND ESSENTIALLY WHAT IT IS
IS IT'S A PLACE WHERE
NEWLY ADOPTIVE OR FOSTER PARENTS
CAN GO AND JUST GET THE BASICS.
NOT ONLY ARE WE GONNA BUILD
A BEAUTIFUL HOME THIS WEEK,
WE'RE GONNA HELP OUT
WITH THE HOUSE OF HOPE.
WE'RE GONNA FIND THEM
A NEW LOCATION,
A PLACE WHERE THEY CAN DO
WHAT THEY DO BEST,
WHICH IS HELPING OTHER PEOPLE.
THIS IS PERFECT.
WE'RE HAPPY TO HELP
ON SOMETHING LIKE THIS.
SUZANNE, YOU'RE THE ONE
WHO'S BEEN WORKING
WITH ALL THE FOSTER KIDS
AND SORT OF, LIKE,
EVERYBODY WHO'S SORT OF
COME THROUGH
THE FRIDAY HOUSE, RIGHT?
YES. YES.
OKAY.
AND I BROUGHT SOME
OF THESE FOLKS WITH ME TODAY.
OH, REALLY?
YES.
HEY, EVERYBODY.
THIS IS TY.
HI!
All: HI.
WHAT KIND OF IMPACT DO YOU THINK
THEY HAD IN YOUR LIFE?
A POSITIVE IMPACT.
YES.
THEY ENCOURAGED ME
TO GO TO COLLEGE
AND BECOME
A SUCCESSFUL ENGINEER.
OH, AWESOME.
CONGRATS.
DEVIN, HOW OLD ARE YOU?
5.
SO, YOU WERE A FOSTER
KID WITH THE FRIDAYS,
AS WELL, RIGHT?
YES.
IS IT PRETTY COOL THAT YOU HAVE
YOUR MOM AND DAD NOW?
YES, SIR.
I BET.
IT WAS SO EASY
TO ADOPT HIM,
'CAUSE THEY HAD SHOWN HIM
SO MUCH LOVE
THAT HE COULD JUST FREELY
SHOW IT TO US.
WOW. I'VE HEARD THAT
THEY ENDED UP FOSTERING,
LIKE, OVER THE YEARS,
LIKE, OVER LIKE 30 KIDS.
YES.
THAT'S PRETTY INCREDIBLE,
DON'T YOU THINK?
MM-HMM.
I THINK THAT IS
INCREDIBLE.
OKAY, SO, RIGHT NOW,
YOU KNOW
THE FRIDAY FAMILY
IS ON VACATION IN JAMAICA,
AND THEY DON'T EVEN KNOW
YOU GUYS ARE HERE HELPING OUT.
BUT I TELL YOU WHAT.
WE SHOULD LET 'EM KNOW, RIGHT?
YES!    YES!
YES!                        YES!
[ HORN HONKS ]
James:
THERE HE GOES.
Devonda: WHOO!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
James:
A CARIBBEAN ISLAND VACATION,
ESPECIALLY
FOR THE FAB FIVE...
HI, OLIVIA.
...TO LIVE ON AN ISLAND
AND VACATION
AND BE CATERED
TO FOR A WHOLE WEEK,
I DON'T THINK THEY EVER
WOULD HAVE IMAGINED
BEING ABLE TO DO THAT.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE HEAVEN.
WE TRIED TO ABSORB IT ALL.
IT WAS AMAZING.
Ty:
HELLO, FRIDAY FAMILY.
HI, TY!     HI, TY!
HI, TY!                  HI, TY!
SO, THIS
IS THE CHRISTMAS SEASON.
I HAVE TO SAY, ONE
OF MY FAVORITE THINGS ABOUT IT
IS ALL THE CHRISTMAS STORIES
WE GET TO HEAR EVERY YEAR.
AND ONE OF MY FAVORITES
IS "A CHRISTMAS CAROL."
YOU KNOW, THE ONE
ABOUT SCROOGE, WHO'S VISITED
BY THE GHOSTS OF CHRISTMAS
PAST, PRESENT, AND FUTURE?
YEAH.
WELL, IT GOT ME THINKING
ABOUT YOU GUYS
AND HOW YOUR DECISION
TO FOSTER AND ADOPT THESE KIDS
HAS MADE SUCH AN IMPACT
THAT WILL SPAN
THEIR PAST, THEIR PRESENT,
AND THEIR FUTURE.
WELL, RIGHT NOW, I'VE GOT A FEW
OF THOSE KIDS YOU FOSTERED.
SAY "HI," EVERYBODY!
HI!     HI!
HI!                         HI!
HI!         HI!
HI!                          HI!
JAMES AND DEVONDA,
YOU IMPACTED MY LIFE...
MADISON.        MADISON.
...MY GRADES, ENCOURAGING ME
TO ALWAYS MAKE A's AND B's
SO I CAN GO TO COLLEGE
AND MAKE SOMETHING OF MYSELF.
I'M AN HONORS STUDENT,
AND I HAVE A JOB
AT THIS PLACE CALLED
"THE GIRLS CLUB."
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU GO, GIRL!
THANK YOU FOR GIVING ME
THE CONFIDENCE
THAT I NEVER HAD
THAT I HAVE TODAY.
WE'RE PROUD OF YOU, BABY.
BECAUSE OF YOU GUYS,
MY LIFE HAS CHANGED
IN MANY WAYS.
I'VE NOW OPENED MY HEART
TO MANY PEOPLE AT SCHOOL.
I'M MORE FRIENDS
WITH EVERYBODY NOW.
WOW.
THANK YOU.
DEVIN!
[ LAUGHTER ]
LOOK AT HIS NEW HAIRDO.
I WANT TO JUST THANK Y'ALL
FOR EVERYTHING YOU DO,
FOR GIVING US
THIS PRECIOUS LITTLE BOY.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
Ty:
SO, YOU GUYS CAN SEE
HOW THE PAST
YOU PROVIDED FOR THESE KIDS
REALLY IS HAVING A HUGE IMPACT
IN THEIR LIVES.
BUT REMEMBER, THESE KIDS
REPRESENT THE CHRISTMAS PAST.
BUT THERE'S ALSO THE CHRISTMAS
PRESENT AND CHRISTMAS FUTURE.
CHECK THIS OUT.
Jillian:
HEY, FRIDAY FAMILY!
DEVONDA, I KNOW THAT YOU'RE
THE HEAD CHEERLEADING COACH
FOR THE BOGER CITY STEELERS.
NOW, WHILE YOU'RE AWAY,
THINK OF ME
AS YOUR
DESIGNER OF CHRISTMAS PRESENT,
BECAUSE WE'VE BROUGHT IN
THE PROS
TO FILL IN FOR YOU
AS HEAD CHEERLEADING COACH.
I AM HERE AT THE
CHARLOTTE BOBCATS HOME ARENA.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
CHECK THIS OUT.
Man:
WELCOME THE LADY CATS
WITH SPECIAL GUESTS --
THE BOGER CITY CHEERLEADERS!
[ ALL CHEERING ]
Woman: 5, 6, 7, 8.
[ DANCE MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
LOOK AT ALL THOSE STEPS.
WHOO!
WAY TO GO, STEELERS!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
HOW COOL IS THAT?
[ ALL CHEERING ]
OKAY, FRIDAY FAMILY,
I KNOW THAT YOU GUYS
HAVE NEVER ACTUALLY
BEEN TO AN NBA GAME.
WE'RE ACTUALLY GONNA BRING
YOU HOME A LITTLE BIT EARLY,
SO YOU GUYS
ARE GONNA BE WATCHING
YOUR VERY FIRST GAME HERE --
BOBCATS VERSUS THE MIAMI HEAT!
[ ALL CHEERING ]
AND, CHRIS AND JDIAH,
YOU GUYS ARE ACTUALLY GONNA BE
HONORARY BALL BOYS.
OH, MY GOODNESS!
LONDON, KAMAYA,
CARLY, AND OLIVIA,
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA BE
HONORARY LADY CATS.
[ ALL CHEERING ]
AND IF THAT WASN'T COOL ENOUGH,
THE CHARLOTTE BOBCATS OWNER
AND NBA LEGEND MICHAEL JORDAN
WOULD LIKE YOU TO SIT
IN HIS SUITE
WHILE YOU ENJOY THE GAME.
[ ALL CHEERING ]
SO, YOU GUYS KNOW WHAT
YOU'RE DOING THIS CHRISTMAS,
BUT YOU ARE NOT GONNA BELIEVE
WHAT YOUR
CHRISTMAS FUTURE HOLDS.
CHECK THIS OUT.
WELL, JAMES AND DEVONDA...
HEY, PAIGE!
PAIGE!
...I'M ABOUT TO SHARE
WITH YOU
SOME PRETTY INCREDIBLE NEWS
ABOUT YOUR CHRISTMAS FUTURE.
I'M RIGHT DOWN THE STREET
FROM YOUR HOUSE,
AT BELMONT ABBEY
COLLEGE.
OH.
SAY HI, EVERYONE.
HI!         HI!
HI!                          HI!
HI!              HI!
HI!                        HI!
YOU GUYS
ARE NOT GONNA BELIEVE THIS.
BELMONT ABBEY COLLEGE HAS
OFFERED FULL-RIDE SCHOLARSHIPS
TO ALL SEVEN OF YOUR CHILDREN!
[ ALL CHEERING ]
ALL TOGETHER, THESE FOUR-YEAR
FULL-RIDE SCHOLARSHIPS
FOR ALL SEVEN OF YOUR KIDS
IS WORTH OVER $1 MILLION.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
James: SINCE WE FOSTERED
AND ADOPTED THE FAB FIVE,
THEY'VE HAD TO HAVE
A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF COURAGE
TO DO WHAT THEY'VE DONE
AND TO MAKE SOME OF THE PROGRESS
THAT THEY'VE MADE
SINCE THEY'VE BEEN WITH US,
IN SCHOOL.
[ SOBS ]
OH, YOU KNOW
WHAT THAT MEANS.
AND YOU KNOW MY WIFE AND I
JUST TRY TO HELP THEM REACH
THAT FULL POTENTIAL.
SO, WHEN WE LEARN
THAT BELMONT ABBEY COLLEGE
WERE GIFTING ALL SEVEN OF OUR
CHILDREN FOUR-YEAR SCHOLARSHIPS,
ANOTHER PRAYER ANSWERED,
ANOTHER BURDEN LIFTED,
BECAUSE WE KNOW THE VALUE
OF A GOOD QUALITY EDUCATION.
IT'S A BLESSING.
THAT WAS THE BEST GIFT
JAMES AND I COULD EVER RECEIVE.
YOU HAVE TO HAVE AN EDUCATION.
THAT'S WHAT WE ALWAYS INSTILL
IN EVERY CHILD
THAT COMES THROUGH OUR HOUSE.
[ SNIFFLES ]
[ Voice breaking ]
MY PRAYERS HAVE BEEN ANSWERED.
THIS IS THE PRESIDENT
OF THE SCHOOL, DR. BILL.
Dr. Bill:
DEVONDA AND JAMES,
WE'RE LOOKING FORWARD
TO WELCOMING
ALL OF YOUR CHILDREN HERE
IN THE FUTURE.
AND SO, MERRY CHRISTMAS
AND GOD BLESS YOU.
OH, GOD BLESS YOU.
THANK YOU.        THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.            THANK YOU.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
MERRY, MERRY CHRISTMAS.
YOU GUYS, HAVE A GREAT TIME
ON VACATION.
WE'LL SEE YOU WHEN YOU GET BACK.
BYE, GUYS!
BYE!    BYE!
BYE!                        BYE!
OH, GUYS.
THAT WAS GOOD.
YEAH!     YEAH!
YEAH!                   YEAH!
Hey buddy, I bet Mom
would love this, huh?
Jack?
Jaaack?
Jaaack?!
Jack?!
Looks good
ladies!
Jack!
Come on,
stop the car.
JACK!
No, no, no, no, no!
The only thing more surprising
than finding the
perfect gifts..
Niice.
...is where you find them.
How did you know?
I had a little help.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
with Lively Colombian.
It's a morning breeze
smooth as Black Silk.
With Folgers Gourmet Selections
K-Cup packs
You can turn any day gourmet.
New roasts, a new look...
available
where you buy groceries.
GIVES YOU 1% CASH BACK
ON ALL PURCHASES,
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS.
AND EVERYONE...BUT HER
LIKES 50% MORE CASH.
BUT I'M UPPING MY GAME.
DO YOU WANT A CANDY CANE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT THE PUPPY?
DO YOU WANT A TRICYCLE?
YES!
DO YOU WANT
50 PERCENT MORE CASH?
NO!
♪
FESTIVE.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE Capital One
Cash Rewards Card
GIVES YOU
1% CASH BACK
ON EVERY
PURCHASE
PLUS A 50% ANNUAL BONUS
ON THE CASH YOU EARN.
IT'S THE CARD FOR PEOPLE
WHO LIKE MORE CASH.
WHAT'S IN YOUR WALLET?
♪
[ chirping ]
[ bleating ]
[ meowing, barking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
UNLIMITED PHONE...
UNLIMITED DATA...
UNLIMITED GIFTS OF JOY.
BUY ONE SAMSUNG GALAXY PHONE...
GET THE SAME MODEL FREE.
VISIT A SPRINT STORE
OR SPRINT.COM/HOLIDAY TODAY.
[ "JINGLE BELLS" PLAYS ]
Michael: MICHAEL!
HELLO!
OH, WOW!
LOOK WHAT I GOT.
CHECK IT OUT.
IT'S YOUR SPECIAL DELIVERY
FROM TWO-TIME DAYTONA 500
CHAMPION MICHAEL WALTRIP.
HOW ARE Y'ALL?
WE TOOK A REAL NASCAR RACECAR
AND SHRUNK IT.
Michael:
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE OTHER
DESIGNERS HAVE GOT YET,
BUT I'M TELLING YOU, I THINK
THE MICHAEL SQUARED TEAM HERE
HAS ROCKED THE HOUSE.
[ LAUGHS ]
Ed: OKAY, GUYS.
THIS IS A FANTASTIC
BIT OF KIT BECAUSE BEFORE,
CHRISTOPHER USED TO PLAY
BASKETBALL DOWN IN THE DRIVEWAY.
THIS IS FANTASTIC.
NON-STICK RESISTANT, PROVIDING
HE'S WEARING THE RIGHT SHOES.
ALSO, THIS STUFF IS LOW IMPACT
ON THE JOINTS.
PLUS, HE'S GOT
HIS BASKETBALL V.I.P. ROOM.
WE'VE HOOKED HIM UP
WITH BASKETBALL HEAVEN! GAME ON!
IT'S SANDERS
WITH THE HOOK SHOT!
THIS WAY A LITTLE BIT.
COME ON OVER HERE.
YOU KNOW, FROM BACK HERE, IT
LOOKS SET AND -- MOVIE MAGIC --
BUT FROM AROUND HERE,
IT LOOKS LIKE A GREAT BIG TREE
FOR LONDON'S
LITTLE NEIGHBORHOOD.
THIS LOOKS FANTASTIC,
AND IT'S HUGE!
Jillian:
I THINK IT'S AT THE POINT
WHERE I REALLY WANT
YOU TO CHECK THIS OUT.
SO, KAMAYA -- DID YOU KNOW
THAT SHE'S WRITING
AN AUTO-BIOGRAPHY
OF HER OWN LIFE?
SHE READ IT TO ME,
AND IT IS AMAZING.
SO THE MAJOR HOOK
OF THIS ROOM IS,
RIGHT HERE,
THERE'S GONNA BE THIS BIG UNIT.
AND IT'S ALL GONNA LOOK LIKE
A BIG BOOKCASE.
THEN THERE'S GONNA BE
THIS SPACE
THAT LOOKS LIKE A BOOKCASE,
BUT IT SLIDES OVER.
IT'S LIKE A "SECRET NOOK"
THAT SHE CAN GO IN THERE
AND READ AND WRITE.
CONSIDERING WHAT SHE'S
BEEN THROUGH IN HER LIFE,
FOR HER TO FEEL LIKE SHE HAS
A SPACE OF HER OWN
AND, LIKE, A PLACE
WHERE SHE CAN COME
AND WRITE HER STORY,
IT'S HUGE.
I LOVE IT.
I THINK IT'S GONNA BE AWESOME.
WE'VE GOT OUR BLANK CANVAS.
ALL WEEK, SOMEONE'S BEEN
SNEAKING AROUND, HELPING ME OUT
WITH OLIVIA'S ROOM.
IT'S SO CUTE!
I TURN MY BACK, AND ALL OF A
SUDDEN, THINGS MAGICALLY APPEAR.
HMM.
WHO COULD HAVE DONE THIS?
Ed:
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
NICE FLAT GROUND,
PINK CAR'S COMING IN.
Jillian: HERE WE GO.
ED, YOU LOOK LOVELY IN PINK.
Paige:
YEAH, YOU LOOK GREAT.
YOU'RE GOOD. JUST ABOUT
RIGHT HERE WILL BE FINE.
WATCH YOUR BRAKE.
WHOA. WHOA. WHOA. WHOA.
NO, THAT'S GOOD.
CAN YOU TURN A BIT?
YOU WANT TO GO
A LITTLE BIT OVER.
KEEP IT GOING
STRAIGHT BACK NOW.
YEAH.
THIS LOOKS GOOD, EH?
YEAH, LOOKS GOOD.
COME ON.
HOP INTO THE BACK.
LET'S SEE HOW MANY
WE CAN GET IN. OKAY.
SO, WE GOT 1, 2, 3,
IN THE FRONT
AND WE GOT 1, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12!
SOMEONE GET THE POPCORN,
START THE MOVIE, WILL YA?
♪ DECK THE HALLS
WITH BOUGHS O' HOLLY ♪
♪ FA LA LA LA LA LA LA LA LA
Michael: OKAY, SO LET'S
GET ALL THIS ORGANIZED.
BREAK IT DOWN BY CATEGORY.
WE'LL GET IT ALL ON THE SHELVES
OVER HERE
AND THEN WE CAN GET ALL THE
BABY STUFF OVER HERE, YOU GUYS.
ONCE OF OUR GOALS THIS WEEK
IS TO NOT ONLY
BUILD THIS FAMILY A HOME
BUT TO HELP OUT
WITH THE HOUSE OF HOPE.
THIS IS AN ORGANIZATION THEY
WERE RUNNING OUT OF THEIR HOME.
THEY'RE ACTUALLY
HELPING OTHER FAMILIES
WHO ARE ADOPTING AND
FOSTERING -- THEY HELP PARENTS
WHO NEED DIAPERS OR STROLLERS
OR PLAYPENS.
WE'VE GOT A LOT OF DONATIONS,
BUT THE SHELVES ARE NOT FULL.
SO, WE CALLED OUR FRIENDS
AT SEARS,
AND THEY SAID
THEY'D LOVE TO HELP.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪ FOLLOW ME IN MERRY MEASURE
♪ FA LA LA LA LA LA LA LA LA
♪ WHILE I TELL YOU
YULE TIDE TREASURE ♪
♪ FA LA LA LA LA LA LA LA LA
HI! HEY, EVERYBODY!
ALL THE PRODUCTS ARE HERE.
LET'S GIVE THESE GUYS A HAND!
LET'S LOAD THESE SHELVES
FOR THE FRIDAY FAMILY!
ALL RIGHT!
♪ SING WE JOYOUS, ALL TOGETHER
OH, MY GOSH!
THIS IS AMAZING!
ALL RIGHT!
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
THIS IS AWESOME!
♪ FA LA LA LA LA LA LA LA LA
COMING UP...
Chris: IT'S JUST AMAZING JUST TO
BE ON THE COURT WITH EVERYBODY.
[ ENGINE REVS ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Share "Not even close."
Share "You owe me..."
Share "Just right."
The Share Everything Plan.
Shareable data across 10 devices
with unlimited
talk and text.
Hurry in for a Droid Razr M
by Motorola for $49.99.
BUT KISSING
IS AT AN ALL-TIME HIGH!
I WANT ANSWERS!
♪
OH. RIGHT.
KAY.
[ Female announcer ] IT'S TRUE,
EVERY KISS DOES BEGIN WITH KAY.
WHERE YOU CAN SAVE 25%
ON ANY BULOVA WATCH.
BULOVA. DESIGNED TO BE NOTICED.
AT KAY, THE NUMBER-ONE
JEWELRY STORE IN AMERICA.
♪
OHHHH. RIGHT.
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
BODY WASHES WITH PAPER
THAT REACTS LIKE SKIN.
IF OTHERS CAN STRIP THIS PAPER,
IMAGINE HOW HARSH
THEY CAN BE TO YOUR SKIN.
OH MY GOSH.
[ Female Announcer ]
Dove IS DIFFERENT.
ITS NEW BREAKTHROUGH FORMULA
CHANGES EVERYTHING.
NEW Dove.
THIS IS CARE.
Whatever it takes, get toRMULA
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
Don't judge me!
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
♪ IT'S A WONDERFUL
WINTER MELODY ♪
Michael: WADE.
Wade: OH, HEY, MICHAEL.
MORE ORNAMENTS!
AWESOME!
SO, IT'S LOOKING PRETTY AWESOME,
ISN'T IT?
IT'S LOOKING GREAT.
SO, YOU KNOW,
THIS IS THE FIRST TIME
THIS FAMILY'S GONNA BE
ALL TOGETHER AT CHRISTMAS.
IT'S GONNA BE SPECIAL.
YES. I WANT IT TO BE
REALLY SPECIAL.
SO, THE BUS IS GONNA MOVE
AT NIGHT.
ALL OF THIS, EVERYTHING
YOU SEE WILL BE LIT.
IT'S GONNA BE AMAZING.
SO, LET'S GET THESE ON.
YES, LET'S GO!
WE'VE GOT MORE OF THESE,
MORE OF THESE, MORE OF THESE.
♪ NOW, THIS IS
MY FAVORITE TIME OF YEAR ♪
♪ IT'S FULL OF GLADNESS,
FULL OF CHEER ♪
Ed: OKAY, BIG MAN.
YOU GET THE TOP OF THAT.
I'LL GET THE BOTTOM.
WE'LL JUST PLAY AROUND
WITH IT A LITTLE BIT.
OKAY, YOU HAPPY?
YEP.
IT'S THE DEFINING MOMENT,
RIGHT?
'CAUSE NOW WE GET TO
PUT THEM INTO PLACE.
AND I THINK THIS IS GONNA BE
REALLY COOL.
Ty: SO, ONE OF THE PROJECTS
I'M WORKING ON THIS WEEK
IS DEVONDA AND JAMES'
MASTER BEDROOM,
AND I REALLY WANT TO GIVE THEM
SOMETHING IN THEIR ROOM
THAT REFLECTS
THE AMOUNT OF LOVE THEY HAVE
AND HOW MANY KIDS
THEY'VE FOSTERED.
THESE BRICKS WE ACTUALLY SAVED
FROM THE OLD HOUSE,
YOU KNOW, CLEANED 'EM UP.
WE PAINTED THEM
AND THEN WE ENGRAVED THE NAMES
OF ALL THE KIDS
THAT HAVE BEEN FOSTERED.
I THINK THE BRICKS FROM THEIR
OLD HOUSE IS A GOOD METAPHOR
FOR THE STRENGTH THAT THEY'VE
GIVEN ALL THESE KIDS.
SO, I WANT THEM TO BE ABLE
TO WALK INTO THEIR ROOM
AND SEE THAT.
OKAY, THE COOL THING IS
WE'VE LEFT SPACE NOW
SO THAT IF DEVONDA AND JAMES
WANT TO FOSTER EVEN MORE KIDS,
THEY'VE GOT ROOM TO ACTUALLY
FILL IN MORE BLANKS.
AND I GET THE FEELING THEY'RE
REALLY PROBABLY GONNA DO THAT.
Paige:
THE DOLL HOUSE LOOKS GREAT.
I THINK LONDON IS ABSOLUTELY
GOING TO LOVE THIS.
SO, WE GOT LUKE, JDIAH, CHRIS,
DEVONDA, LONDON, OLIVIA, JAMES.
YOU CAN'T HAVE A ROCK WALL
AND NOT CLIMB IT.
SO, THIS WEEK, WHAT'S REALLY
IMPORTANT IS THAT WE REALIZE
JUST HOW SPECIAL
AND HOW INCREDIBLE
DEVONDA AND JAMES ARE.
THESE ARE REALLY GOOD PARENTS,
AND THEY'RE THE ROLE MODELS
FOR OTHER FOSTER PARENTS.
Ed:
THE SCOREBOARD'S GOING UP.
AND SHOOTING -- GAME ON!
Ty: THAT'S WHY
IT'S IMPORTANT THIS WEEK
THAT WE GIVE THIS FAMILY
AS MUCH AS WE CAN,
BECAUSE WE'RE NOT ONLY HELPING
THIS FAMILY.
WE'RE ALLOWING THIS FAMILY TO BE
ABLE TO HELP SO MANY OTHERS.
LUKE AND LONDON WHEN LONDON
GOT HER FIRST TOOTH.
SO, BEFORE WE SHOW THE FRIDAY
FAMILY THEIR BRAND-NEW HOUSE,
WE'RE BRINGING THEM HOME EARLY.
THERE ARE A FEW MORE THINGS
WE WANTED THEM TO SEE
THAT I KNOW
THEY WERE GONNA LOVE.
I MEAN, EVERYTHING IS HERE.
I JUST FEEL LIKE WE NEED
JUST A LITTLE SOMETHING MORE.
UM --
[ GASPS ]
OH, MY GOODNESS! THE BOOK!
AND IT'S THE GRINCH!
I KNEW I HAD HELP THIS WEEK!
I JUST KNEW IT.
GIVE ME SOME LOVE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH!
THE ROOM IS PERFECT!
WOW!
AWESOME!
HI!
HI, HOW ARE YOU?
WE'RE SO GLAD YOU GUYS ARE HERE.
Y'ALL EXCITED FOR TONIGHT?
YEAH!                    YEAH!
AWESOME.
WELL, THE GUYS GET TO BE
HONORARY BALL BOYS FOR THE TEAM,
AND THE GIRLS,
HONORARY LADY CATS WITH US.
[ ALL CHEERING ]
YOUR WHOLE FAMILY GETS TO SIT
IN MICHAEL JORDAN'S SUITE
TO WATCH THE GAME.
WOW.
[ ALL CHEERING ]
Devonda: OH!
WHOA!
OH, MY GOD!
James: WENT UP
TO MICHAEL JORDAN'S SUITE.
MICHAEL JORDAN, THE BOBCATS,
THEY PROVIDED A BUFFET FOR US.
THEY LOADED US UP WITH
A BUNCH OF JORDAN GEAR,
AND TO SEE A PERSONAL LETTER
FROM MICHAEL JORDAN HIMSELF,
AND IT WAS SIGNED
AND EVERYTHING...
"ENJOY THE GAME.
"CONGRATULATIONS, AND
BEST WISHES TO YOUR NEW HOME.
MICHAEL JORDAN!
IT MEANT A LOT.
WE'RE DEFINITELY
GONNA HAVE TO FIND A PLACE
FOR THAT FRAMED LETTER
IN OUR HOME.
Woman: WHOO!
[ MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Chris:
IT WAS JUST UNBELIEVABLE.
WE GOT TO SEE ALL THE PLAYERS,
LeBRON JAMES AND D.J.
IT WAS JUST AMAZING JUST TO BE
ON THE COURT WITH EVERYBODY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
IT'S OLIVIA!
IT WAS FUN
TO BE BE THE LADY CAT.
I LIKE HOW THEY CHEER.
MY GIRLS, THEY GET TO CHEER
FOR THE BOBCATS.
IT'S AWESOME!
IT WAS FUN.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Man: IT'S UP!
Y'ALL LIKE THE GAME?
All: YEAH!
DID Y'ALL LIKE THE GAME?
YEAH!
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
WAIT A MINUTE.
I'VE GOT A PHONE CALL.
DID YOU LIKE THE GAME?
HOLD ON.
OKAY.
HELLO?
HEY, JAMES?
HEY, IT'S TY.
HEY, TY. IT'S TY.
HEY, TY! HI!
ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
SO, HERE'S THE THING.
I KNOW YOU CAN'T WAIT
TO SEE YOUR NEW HOME,
BUT BEFORE THAT HAPPENS,
WE'VE GOT
one more really cool
surprise for you.
ALL RIGHT.            ALL RIGHT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Oh, yeah.
All right, guys.
So, have a great time,
and we'll see you when
you get home, okay?
ALL RIGHT. BYE, GUYS!
ALL RIGHT.
BYE, TY!     BYE, TY!
BYE, TY!                BYE, TY!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WELCOME BACK, FRIDAY FAMILY!
WELCOME BACK!
DEVONDA, I KNOW
HOW PASSIONATE YOU ARE
ABOUT GIVING NEW FOSTER FAMILIES
THE ESSENTIALS,
THE THINGS THAT THEY NEED
WHEN THEY TAKE ON THE CHILDREN.
YEAH.
WELL, THROUGH YOUR COMMUNITY AND
SOME REALLY AMAZING DONATIONS,
WE WERE ABLE TO PROVIDE YOU
WITH THE NEW
HOUSE OF HOPE
NEIGHBORHOOD RESOURCE CENTER!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
AND THROUGH MANY, MANY, MANY
DONATIONS,
THE RENT HAS ALREADY BEEN PAID
FOR OVER TWO YEARS.
OH, WOW.
[ CHUCKLES ]
THAT'S AMAZING.
MY WIFE AND I HAD AN
ORGANIZATION, THE HOUSE OF HOPE,
A NEIGHBORHOOD RESOURCE CENTER.
THE FOSTERING COMMUNITY
BENEFITED GREATLY FROM IT,
BUT WE COULD NOT
KEEP THE HOUSE OF HOPE OPEN.
OUR RENT WAS TOO HIGH.
AND WE'RE LOOKING FORWARD
TO OPENING THE DOORS AGAIN.
IT'S JUST AMAZING.
IT JUST KEEPS GETTING BETTER.
SO, I WANT YOU TO LOOK UP THERE.
"HOUSE OF HOPE." IT SAYS
"NEIGHBORHOOD RESOURCE CENTER."
WELL, TO MAKE SURE THE
NEIGHBORHOOD HAS THE
RESOURCES THEY WANT,
OUR FRIENDS AT SEARS
HAVE MADE SURE
THAT THE SHELVES IN THERE
ARE STOCKED.
THEY ARE FULL, AND THERE'S
PLENTY FOR EVERYBODY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
NOW, YOU CAN'T HAVE
A GRAND OPENING
WITHOUT A RIBBON CUTTING,
RIGHT?
SO, LET'S CUT THE RIBBON
AND OPEN THE NEW HOUSE OF HOPE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Devonda: HOUSE OF HOPE
NEIGHBORHOOD RESOURCE CENTER
IS AN ORGANIZATION
THAT GIVES BACK TO THE FOSTERING
AND ADOPTING COMMUNITY
BY HELPING
WITH CAR SEATS, CLOTHING,
AND ALL HOUSEHOLD PRODUCTS.
I'M SO USED TO GIVING AND
NOT BEING ON THE RECEIVING END.
AND I JUST CANNOT BELIEVE
THIS HAS REALLY, REALLY
HAPPENED TO ME.
OVER HERE, JUST SOME BASIC
THINGS FOR THE HOME,
THINGS THAT'LL MAKE LIFE
A LITTLE EASIER,
I THINK,
FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE.
OH, IT WILL.
WELL, I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
IT DOES KEEP GETTING BETTER.
WOULDN'T BE CHRISTMAS UNLESS YOU
HAD A PRESENT TO OPEN, RIGHT?
OH, MY GOD.
RIGHT.
SO, WHY DON'T YOU GO AHEAD
AND OPEN THAT UP.
Boy: OH, MY GOODNESS.
WOW.
FOR SEARS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
THOSE SEARS GIFT CARDS
WILL MAKE SURE
THAT THE SHELVES HERE ARE
STOCKED FOR THE NEXT TWO YEARS.
OH, MY GOD!
James: WOW!
JUST LIKE THIS.
IT'S JUST GONNA AMAZING TO BE
ABLE TO HELP SO MANY PEOPLE.
AND SO MANY PEOPLE OUT THERE
NEED HELP.
YEAH.
WE CAN LIFT
THOSE BURDENS.
WELL, GOOD THINGS HAPPEN
TO GOOD PEOPLE.
OH...MY GOSH.
WE ARE GONNA BE ABLE TO HELP SO
MANY PEOPLE IN THIS COMMUNITY.
I CAN'T BELIEVE THIS.
WE'RE GONNA BE ABLE TO DO
SO MUCH WITH THIS.
IT'S SO BEAUTIFUL.
SO, YOU GUYS READY
TO GO SEE THE HOUSE?
YEAH!     YEAH!
YEAH!                   YEAH!
[ APPLAUSE ]
LET'S GO CHECK OUT
YOUR HOUSE!
[ ALL CHEERING ]
COME ON!
TO FIND OUT MORE
ABOUT THE PRODUCTS USED
ON TONIGHT'S SHOW,
GO TO abc.com.
Bye!
Santa, we made a video for
your trip!
Yeah, you can watch it on your
sleigh!
OK!
Here you go.
Aw, thanks elves.
I also made you a video.
You are so sweet.
But you probably shouldn't watch
it on the sleigh.
Say goodbye to Santa boys!
Bye!
Good bye Santa!
Share videos instantly with
S Beam
on the Galaxy S3 and Note 2.
For a limited time, get two
flipcovers for the price of one,
Exclusively at Verizon.
I DIDN'T WANT TO CHANGE
TOOTHPASTES...
I ALREADY HAD A PRODUCT
THAT MADE MY MOUTH FEEL CLEAN...
THE FIRST THING HE RECOMMENDED
WAS SENSODYNE.
IT HELPS
WITH THE SENSITIVITY ISSUES
AND IT SATISFIES THE NEEDS
THAT I WOULD LOOK FOR
IN A TOOTHPASTE.
♪
DOING IT WITH A COLD,
JUST NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
VICKS DAYQUIL --
POWERFUL NON-DROWSY
6-SYMPTOM COLD & FLU RELIEF.
♪
NO MATTER WHAT CITY
YOU'RE PLAYING TOMORROW.
[ coughs ]
[ Male Announcer ] YOU CAN'T
LET A COLD KEEP YOU UP TONIGHT.
♪
VICKS NYQUIL --
POWERFUL NIGHTTIME
6-SYMPTOM COLD & FLU RELIEF.
♪
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
HEY, PEOPLE!
WE FINISHED THE HOUSE!
LET'S BRING 'EM HOME!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WELCOME HOME, FRIDAY FAMILY!
James:
TO SEE THE SEA OF PEOPLE
THAT WAS THERE FOR US
AND SUPPORTING US,
IT REALLY LET ME KNOW THAT
WE LIVE IN A GREAT COMMUNITY.
IT REALLY MEANT A LOT.
WHEN YOU GUYS
TOOK IN THE FAB FIVE,
YOU GUYS REALLY HAVE CHANGED
THESE KIDS' LIVES FOREVER.
AND NOW, YOU GUYS
ARE GONNA BE CELEBRATING
THE FIRST CHRISTMAS TOGETHER
AS A FAMILY, RIGHT?
MM-HMM.
YES.
I THINK FOR TONIGHT,
THERE'S ONLY ONE GUY WHO
SHOULD REALLY MOVE THIS BUS,
AND THAT GUY IS A GUY
BY THE NAME OF NICK.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
IT'D BE SO AWESOME IF YOU WOULD
ACTUALLY MOVE OUR BUS FOR US.
WOULD YOU DO THAT?
I WOULD LOVE TO, TY.
SANTA'S GONNA MOVE THE BUS!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THIS GUY CAN DRIVE, TOO.
I'VE SEEN HIM ON THE INTERSTATE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
HO, HO, HO.
MOVE THAT BUS!
MOVE THAT BUS! MOVE THAT BUS!
YOU GUYS KNOW WHAT TO SAY,
RIGHT?
SO, SAY IT WITH ME!
HERE WE GO!
BUS DRIVER, MOVE THAT BUS!
[ ENGINE REVS ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WHEN I SEEN THE HOUSE,
I JUST FELL TO MY KNEES.
I'VE NEVER LIVED
IN A HOUSE LIKE THAT BEFORE.
I THINK IT'S JUST A MIRACLE THAT
ALL MY FAMILY WILL BE TOGETHER.
THIS IS THE BEST CHRISTMAS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WHEN THAT BUS MOVED, I COULD NOT
BELIEVE THAT THAT WAS OUR HOUSE.
MY OLD HOUSE, EVEN THOUGH WE
ADDED ON, WE DIDN'T HAVE SPACE,
AND THE FOUNDATION
WAS COMING APART.
TO BUILD SUCH A BEAUTIFUL HOUSE
LIKE THAT IS JUST UNBELIEVABLE.
[ Voice breaking ]
MY PRAYERS HAVE BEEN ANSWERED.
[ Sobbing ]
I'M JUST SO THANKFUL.
THAT'S MY HOUSE!
YES, IT IS.
OH, MY!
DO ME A FAVOR.
GIVE A HUG TO THE PEOPLE
WHO HAVE REALLY
MADE IT ALL HAPPEN THIS WEEK.
OF COURSE, I'M TALKING ABOUT
OUR BUILDERS THIS WEEK --
WADE MILLER AND FRANK HEREDA
FROM BELLAMY HOMES!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ LAUGHS ]
Frank: IT ALL STARTS WITH
THE KIDS, WITH THE CHILDREN.
AND THEY'VE GONE THROUGH
SOME PRETTY TOUGH TIMES.
THAT'S THE MAIN REASON, I THINK,
WE REALLY WANTED TO HELP
THIS FAMILY OUT.
I'M JUST GLAD NOW THAT THEY CAN
SHARE HOLIDAYS WITH THEIR FAMILY
AND THEY CAN BE TOGETHER.
WHAT WE WANTED TO DO WAS
SET THEM UP AS GOOD AS POSSIBLE
TO MAKE THEIR LIFE
WHATEVER THEY WANT IT TO BE.
YOU GUYS MAKE
SO MANY MIRACLES HAPPEN
FOR SO MANY CHILDREN
IN THIS COMMUNITY,
AND WE THE COMMUNITY LOVES
YOU GUYS AND SUPPORT YOU GUYS.
THROUGH THE COMMUNITY,
WE WERE ABLE TO RAISE
AN ADDITIONAL $20,000
FOR A FAMILY MAINTENANCE FUND
FOR YOU GUYS TO USE FOR
WHATEVER YOU FEEL IS NECESSARY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW, THE CHRISTMAS LIGHTS
ARE SO FESTIVE, AREN'T THEY?
YES.
James: YEAH, THEY ARE.
Ty: WELL, WE'VE GOT
ONE MORE SURPRISE FOR YOU.
WE DECIDED TO TAKE THE CHRISTMAS
LIGHTS TO A WHOLE NEW LEVEL.
GO AHEAD AND PLUG THAT IN.
[ ROCK 'N' ROLL
CHRISTMAS MUSIC PLAYS ]
BEHOLD!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THE LIGHTS WAS DANCING,
AND THEY WAS FUN TO LOOK AT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE CONTINUE ]
TO ME, IT FELT LIKE A NEW START.
ALL THE LIGHTS MEANT PEACE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE CONTINUE ]
Ty: YEAH!
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE SHOW THESE GUYS THE HOUSE?
YEAH!     YEAH!
YEAH!                   YEAH!
I'VE BEEN WAITING
TO SAY THIS ALL WEEK.
FRIDAY FAMILY, GO CHECK OUT
YOUR BRAND-NEW HOUSE.
OH, MY GOD!
[ LAUGHS ]
James: OH, MAN!
OH, MY GOODNESS!
WHEN WE WALKED IN,
IT WAS BEAUTIFUL.
A LOT OF SPACE FOR US AND OUR
CHILDREN TO SPREAD OUT AND GROW.
NOW WE HAVE THE SPACE AVAILABLE
TO FOSTER MORE CHILDREN.
Devonda:
WILL YOU LOOK AT THIS?
"CARLY CELEBRATES HER FIRST
CHRISTMAS WITH THE FRIDAYS."
OH, MY GOODNESS.
LOOK. LOOK.
I SEE THIS TIMELINE.
IT STARTS FROM THE TIME JAMES
AND I GOT TOGETHER TO TODAY.
OH, MY GOD.
James: THE TIMELINE
IN OUR HOME WAS GREAT
TO ACTUALLY SHOW THE CHILDREN
WHERE WE COME FROM,
WHERE WE'RE AT,
AND WHERE WE WANT TO GO.
WANT TO BUILD ON THAT TIMELINE.
YOU KNOW, WE WANT TO ADD TO IT.
FRIDAY FAMILY!
[ LAUGHS ]
THIS IS NICE.
REMEMBER THE TREE
WE PICKED OUT?
[ CHEERING ]
OH, MY GOD.
AND SO, MICHAEL WANTED TO
MAKE SURE, YOU KNOW,
HE TOOK CARE OF YOU GUYS
IN THE BIG LIVING AREA.
DID YOU GUYS SEE
YOUR FAMILY TIMELINE?
All: YES.
OH, MY GOD.
MY FAVORITE IS
"LONDON LOSES HER FIRST TOOTH."
[ LAUGHTER ]
IN HERE,
THE FRIDAY FAMILY TABLE.
EVERYBODY HAS A SEAT.
WE ALL HAVE A SEAT.
YEAH.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
AWESOME.
DOES IT FEEL LIKE HOME?
Chris: YES.
IT'S FOREVER.
AND SO,
IN HERE IN YOUR KITCHEN,
YOU GUYS HAVE GOT
ALL NEW APPLIANCES.
OUR FRIENDS AT SEARS
WANTED TO MAKE SURE
THAT THEY PROVIDED
EVERYTHING YOU GUYS NEEDED
TO MAKE YOUR HOUSE
REALLY A HOME.
SO, YOU GUYS HAVE GOT
STAINLESS-STEEL FRIDGE,
DISHWASHER, OVEN.
AND IT FEELS LIKE A REAL HOME,
DOESN'T IT?
OH, YEAH.
YES.
SO, BEFORE, YOU GUYS
WERE IN A GROUP HOME
WHERE YOU GUYS HAD TO SHARE
SO MUCH, RIGHT?
YES.
WELL, WHEN WE WERE
BUILDING THE HOUSE,
WE WANTED TO MAKE SURE
TO GIVE YOU GUYS
SOMETHING YOU GUYS
REALLY HAD NEVER HAD,
AND THAT'S ROOMS OF YOUR OWN.
[ ALL GASP ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
OH, WOW.
YOU HEAR THAT?
KAMAYA?
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF THAT?
[ SOBS ] OH, GOD.
THAT'S SOMETHING
YOU NEVER HAD BEFORE, HUH?
NO.
I'VE ALWAYS HAD TO SHARE
WITH EVERYBODY
AND NEVER GOT
ANYTHING OF MY OWN,
AND NOW I DO,
AND THAT'S AWESOME.
[ SNIFFLES ]
IN FACT, WE CREATED
AN ENTIRE SECOND FLOOR
JUST TO MAKE SURE
YOU GUYS ALL HAD BEDROOMS.
WELL, HERE'S THE THING.
THERE'S A LOT MORE TO SEE.
WE'VE GIVEN YOU A PLACE
THAT'S SO AWESOME,
YOU'RE GONNA WANT TO STUDY
EVERY HOUR OF THE DAY.
[ LAUGHS ]
SO, GUYS, GO CHECK OUT
YOUR NEW STUDY AREA!
[ CHEERING ]
[ ALL GASPING ]
Kamaya:
WHEN WE COME HOME FROM SCHOOL,
WE CAN GO IN THERE AND STUDY.
WE HAVE OUR OWN COMPUTER,
A LOT OF SUPPLIES UP THERE.
IT WAS JUST AMAZING.
LOOK!
OH, MY GOODNESS.
Y'ALL, COME ON.
OH, MY GOD!
OH, MY GOSH!
WHEN WE WERE DOWNSTAIRS, TY ALL
OF A SUDDEN PULLS UP THIS WALL.
Ty:
THERE'S YOUR KIDS.
[ ALL SCREAMING HAPPILY ]
THEY GOT THEIR OWN
ROCK-CLIMBING WALL.
Ty: YOU KNOW, NOT ONLY DO
THE KIDS NOW HAVE A STUDY AREA,
BUT THEY'VE ALSO GOT A PLACE
WHERE THEY CAN LET OUT
FUN ENERGY.
THEY CAN DO THE THINGS
THEY LOVE DOING.
AND LUCKILY, WE'VE PUT IN
A SOUNDPROOF GARAGE DOOR
SO THE FAMILY DOESN'T
HAVE TO HEAR TOO MUCH OF IT.
OH, GOODNESS.
Devonda:
HOW AWESOME IS THAT?
THEY ARE ABSOLUTELY LOVING
THIS AREA.
SO, YOU GUYS LIKE
WHAT YOU SEEING UP HERE?
YES!    YES!
YES!                        YES!
WELL, DO ME A FAVOR!
GO CHECK OUT YOUR ROOMS!
[ GASPS ] OH, MY GOSH!
AWESOME!
Hey buddy, I bet Mom
would love this, huh?
Jack?
Jaaack?
Jaaack?!
Jack?!
Looks good
ladies!
Jack!
Come on,
stop the car.
JACK!
No, no, no, no, no!
The only thing more surprising
than finding the
perfect gifts..
Niice.
...is where you find them.
How did you know?
I had a little help.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
THAT'S WHY NEW
Dove Style + Care
Frizz Free Cream Serum
NOURISHES AND CONDITIONS,
KEEPING HAIR SMOOTH SHINY
AND FREE FROM FLYAWAYS.
NEW Dove Style + Care
Frizz Free Cream Serum.
BETTER STYLE
THROUGH BETTER CARE.
NEW Dove Style + Care
Frizz Free Cream Serum.
AND IT FEELS LIKE YOUR LIFEATE
REVOLVES AROUND YOUR SYMPTOMS,
ASK YOUR GASTROENTEROLOGIST
ABOUT HUMIRA ADALIMUMAB.
HUMIRA HAS BEEN PROVEN
TO WORK FOR ADULTS
WHO HAVE TRIED OTHER MEDICATIONS
BUT STILL EXPERIENCE
THE SYMPTOMS OF MODERATE
TO SEVERE CROHN'S DISEASE.
IN CLINICAL STUDIES, THE
MAJORITY OF PATIENTS ON HUMIRA
SAW SIGNIFICANT SYMPTOM RELIEF,
AND MANY ACHIEVED REMISSION.
HUMIRA CAN LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS,
INCLUDING TUBERCULOSIS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL EVENTS,
SUCH AS INFECTIONS, LYMPHOMA,
OR OTHER TYPES OF CANCER,
HAVE HAPPENED.
BLOOD, LIVER AND
NERVOUS SYSTEM PROBLEMS,
SERIOUS ALLERGIC REACTIONS,
AND NEW OR WORSENING HEART
FAILURE HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING HUMIRA, YOUR
DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU FOR TB.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU LIVE IN
OR HAVE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL
INFECTIONS ARE COMMON.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
HAD TB, HEPATITIS B,
ARE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
OR HAVE SYMPTOMS SUCH AS
FEVER, FATIGUE, COUGH, OR SORES.
YOU SHOULD NOT START HUMIRA IF
YOU HAVE ANY KIND OF INFECTION.
GET HEADED IN A NEW DIRECTION.
WITH HUMIRA,
REMISSION IS POSSIBLE.
[ GASPS ] OH, MY GOSH!
THIS IS AWESOME!
LOOK AT ALL THESE CLOTHES!
[ LAUGHS ]
I LOVE IT.
A FASHION ROOM
WITH CLOTHES, SHOES, FACES
THAT YOU CAN DRESS UP WITH.
IT'S AMAZING.
AWESOME!
I GOT A CARTOON ROOM.
PICTURES!
THEY LOOK LIKE MY DRAWINGS.
A BED! [ LAUGHS ]
[ GASPS ]
OH, MY GOSH!
OH, WOW.
THIS IS COOL.
I'VE NEVER HAD MY OWN ROOM,
AND IT FEELS AWESOME
THAT I CAN HAVE MY OWN ROOM.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT IS AMAZING.
ISN'T IT?
OH, MY GOSH. YES.
I WANT YOU TO GO STAND
OVER THERE.
[ GASPS ]
[ LAUGHS ]
OH, MY GOSH!
THAT IS SO COOL!
THIS IS YOUR OWN LITTLE
SECRET HIDEAWAY.
I'M GOING TO READ.
I'M GOING TO WRITE.
I'M GOING TO TALK ON THE PHONE
AND GO TO SLEEP.
YOU DESERVE IT, BABE.
PROMISE YOU'LL SEND ME
THE FIRST COPY?
YES.
OR SECOND?
OKAY.
OH, MY GOSH.
THIS IS SO COOL.
DUDE, THIS IS AWESOME.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
I COULD NEVER DREAM OF HAVING
AN AWESOME, EXCITING,
ENTERTAINING ROOM LIKE THAT
IN MY WHOLE ENTIRE LIFE.
IT'S JUST SOMETHING
THAT YOU WOULD NEVER THINK OF,
THE WAY ED PUT IT TOGETHER.
HOW YOU DOING, BUDDY?
THIS IS AWESOME.
YOU LIKE COMPUTER GAMES,
RIGHT?
RIGHT.
YOU LIKE VIDEO GAMES?
YOU CAN HAVE SPLIT-SCREEN GAMES
WITH THREE FRIENDS.
SPLIT THE FOUR CONTROLLERS,
AND YOU CAN GO AT IT ONLINE.
THIS IS -- THANK YOU.
THIS IS AWESOME.
London: COOL!
COOL! OH, MY GOODNESS!
I'M FEELING THAT I LIVE
IN A DOLLHOUSE.
OH! COOL!
COOL.
THAT'S THE BIGGEST TREE
THAT I'VE EVER SEEN.
WOW! OH, MY GOSH!
OH!
I NEVER HAD THIS BEFORE.
OH, MY GOSH.
THIS IS MY FRIEND.
HELLO.
I LIKE MY ROOM.
DID YOU SEE YOUR NAME
ON THE WALL?
I HAD A VERY SPECIAL HELPER
ALL WEEK.
JILLIAN? TY?
NOT JILLIAN. NOT TY.
DO YOU WANT TO MEET HIM?
YEAH?
[ LAUGHS ]
IT'S THE GRINCH!
HE HELPED ME ALL WEEK.
MY FAVORITE WAS THE GRINCH,
AND HE GAVE ME A HUG.
OH, MY GOSH!
OH! [ LAUGHS ]
LOOK AT MY ROOM!
[ GASPS ]
OH, MY GOD!
MY OWN LAPTOP IN MY ROOM!
MY ROOM WAS AMAZING BECAUSE
IT WAS ABOUT WHAT I LIKE TO DO.
BASKETBALL ROOM --
THIS IS PRETTY COOL.
NOW, LISTEN,
LET ME TALK YOU THROUGH IT.
NOW, YOU GOT 70-INCH TV
WITH THE CABLE NETWORK SUPPLIER
THAT WE'VE GIVEN YOU.
YOU'RE ABLE TO WATCH ONE GAME,
TWO GAMES, THREE, FOUR.
FOUR SEPARATE GAMES
AT ANY ONE TIME.
[ LAUGHS ]
ED, HE DID A WONDERFUL JOB
ON MY ROOM.
HAVE MY OWN ROOM TO MYSELF NOW.
OH, MY GOSH!
DUDE, LOOK! LOOK, LOOK, LOOK!
[ LAUGHS ]
ALL THE BASKETBALL SHOES
ARE GOOD FOR OUTSIDE COURTS,
AND HE'S GONNA NEED THESE
BECAUSE IF WE WIND UP
THIS WINDOW HERE...
LOOK AT THAT!
[ ALL SHOUTING ]
THAT IS ACTUALLY
COLLEGE-SIZE REGULATION NET.
SO WE'RE GETTING YOU READY
FOR COLLEGE, BUDDY, AS WELL.
SWISH.
James: FOR CHRIS
AND HIS BROTHERS AND SISTERS
TO GET SPACE THEY NEVER HAD,
IT MEANS EVERYTHING.
Jdiah: I THINK WE'RE GONNA BE
ON THAT BASKETBALL COURT
ALMOST EVERY DAY PRACTICING.
COME ON, GANG.
GLAD YOU LIKE IT, BUDDY.
THERE'S SOMETHING ELSE
IN THE BACKYARD
THAT I KNOW TY WANTS TO SHOW,
SO THE FUN DON'T STOP HERE.
TO LEARN MORE ABOUT
ADOPTING AND FOSTERING...
AND TO LEARN HOW TO GIVE
A CHRISTMAS
TO A CHILD
THAT TRULY NEEDS IT...
GO TO...                GO TO...
abettercommunity.com!
[ CHEERING ]
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
DISCOVER THE TEMPTING LAYERS
OF FERRERO ROCHER.
A WHOLE HAZELNUT,
SMOOTH CHOCOLATY CREAM
INSIDE A WAFER SHELL,
COVERED IN MILK CHOCOLATE
AND HAZELNUT PIECES.
♪
FERRERO ROCHER.
MAKE YOUR MOMENTS GOLDEN.
♪
[ squawk ]
[ shouts ]
[ lightsaber hums ]
[ growls ]
♪
[ characters cheering ]
YES, I'M A JEWELRY STORE.
AND YES, I'M TALKING TO YOU.
MIKE HERE NEEDS A NECKLACE.
BUT NOT JUST ANY NECKLACE.
HE NEEDS A "HONEY,
I LOVE YOU EVEN MORE
THAN THE DAY WE GOT MARRIED"
NECKLACE.
WELL, I DON'T WANT TO BRAG,
BUT MY SELECTION IS LARGER
THAN ORDINARY JEWELRY STORES,
WITH TRULY UNIQUE PIECES
YOU WON'T FIND JUST ANYWHERE,
MAKING IT EASY FOR MIKE TO FIND
THE NECKLACE THAT TELLS
HIS WIFE EXACTLY HOW HE FEELS.
THERE.
THAT'S WHY HE WENT TO JARED.
[ laughter ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR TIM AND RICHARD SMUCKER,
GIVING A GIFT
OF THEIR FAMILY'S DELICIOUS JAM
ALWAYS MADE THE HOLIDAYS
JUST A LITTLE BIT SWEETER.
WE FORGOT TO PUT OUR NAMES
ON THEM!
RICHARD, I THINK THEY'LL KNOW
WHO IT'S FROM.
♪
THANK YOU BOYS.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
[ Male Announcer ]
HAPPY HOLIDAYS
FROM OUR FAMILY TO YOURS.
I LOVE CHRISTMAS!
I GOT YOUR
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
MOM?
WHO'S MOM?
I'M THE GIANTS MASCOT.
THE GIANTS DON'T HAVE
A MASCOT!
OHHH! EAT UP!
NEW JAMMIN JERK CHICKEN SOUP
HAS TASTY PIECES OF CHICKEN
WITH RICE AND BEANS.
HMMM.
FOR GIANT HUNGER!
THANKS MOM!
SEE YA!
WHOAA...OOPS!
MOM?
I'M OK.
GRANDMA?
HI SWEETIE!
SHE OPERATES THE HEAD.
[ Male Announcer ]
CAMPBELL'S CHUNKY SOUP.
IT FILLS YOU UP RIGHT.
Whatever it takes, get to
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
Don't judge me!
SHE OPERATES THE HEAD.
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
BECAUSE I KNOW I WANTED YOU
TO HAVE A SPACE OF YOUR OWN
THAT COULD BE A PLACE TO RELAX
AND GET AWAY FROM CHAOS.
BUT I ALSO
WANTED TO REFLECT
AND SEE THE LOVE THAT
YOU'VE GIVEN SO MANY KIDS.
DO ME A FAVOR. GO CHECK OUT
YOUR NEW MASTER BEDROOM.
WOW.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
OH. FIREPLACE.
A FIREPLACE.
OH, MY.
[ GASPS ]
OH, VONDA, LOOKIE HERE.
OH, MY GOD.
IT'S GOT
EVERYBODY'S NAME.
[ LAUGHS ]
IN THE QUILTS.
[ GASPS ]
OH, MY GOD.
LOOK AT THE BATHROOM.
OH, MY GRACIOUS.
[ LAUGHS ]
OH, MY GOD!
OH, MAN.
LOOK HOW BIG THIS THING IS.
LOOK.
James:
DEVONDA WAS REAL EXCITED.
I WAS MORE HAPPY FOR HER
THAN I WAS FOR MYSELF.
SHE TRIES TO DO SO MUCH
FOR SO MANY PEOPLE.
SHE FORGETS ABOUT HERSELF A LOT.
THAT'S JUST HER NATURE.
SO, I WANTED THIS A LOT
FOR HER.
HOW'D WE DO?
OH, MAN.
GOD,
THIS IS SO BEAUTIFUL.
THIS IS PERFECT.
DID YOU SEE THE QUILT?
OH, MY GOODNESS, TY.
NAMES IN IT.
THAT'S SPECIAL.
AND I THOUGHT WHAT WAS REALLY
COOL ABOUT THE IDEA OF THE QUILT
IS THAT
ALL THE DIFFERENT FABRIC
COMES FROM
DIFFERENT BACKGROUNDS.
IT ALL HAS
A DIFFERENT STORY
UNTIL IT ALL ARRIVES IN ONE
PLACE TO BE STITCHED TOGETHER.
WOW.
AND SO, THAT'S
WHAT YOUR FAMILY IS.
IT'S BEEN STITCHED TOGETHER
FROM ALL OVER.
NOW, THOSE BRICKS
ARE FROM YOUR OLD HOUSE.
WOW.
OH, MY GOSH.
IT'S NOT EVERY DAY THAT YOU CAN
SAY YOU FOSTERED THAT MANY KIDS.
I KNOW.
THAT'S SOMETHING
TO BE PROUD OF.
IF YOU WANT TO EVER
BRING IN MORE BRICKS,
YOU CAN JUST
HAVE THEM ENGRAVED,
AND THEN YOU GOT SPACE
TO JUST PUT EVEN MORE IN.
Devonda:
OH, MY GOD.
THAT'S AMAZING.
TY HAD PUT REMOVABLE BRICKS
FOR MORE FOR ME TO FOSTER.
THAT'S SO SPECIAL,
AND I'M GONNA DO THAT.
I'M GONNA CONTINUE.
THERE'S ONE MORE THING
I WANT YOU GUYS TO SEE,
AND I THINK EVERYBODY
IN THE FAMILY NEEDS TO SEE THIS.
THINK YOU GUYS CAN HANDLE
ONE MORE THING?
[ LAUGHS ] NO.
COME ON. COME ON.
OH, WOW.
Ty:
EVERYBODY BUNDLED UP?
YEAH!     YEAH!
YEAH!                   YEAH!
WELL, WE'RE GONNA NEED
OUR JACKETS,
BECAUSE WE'RE GOING TO A PLACE
WHERE I KNOW
YOU GUYS LOVE HAVING FUN,
WHICH IS OUTSIDE, RIGHT?
YES.
OKAY.
SO, HERE'S THE THING.
IT'S CHRISTMASTIME,
AND I THINK YOU'RE GONNA REALLY
HAVE A FUN CHRISTMAS
WHEN YOU SEE WHAT'S
ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THIS DOOR.
YOU GUYS WANT TO CHECK OUT
YOUR BACKYARD?
YES!    YES!
YES!                        YES!
WELL, GO CHECK IT OUT!
[ JAMES LAUGHS ]
[ CHEERING ]
Devonda: OH, MY GOD!
James: WOW!
[ LAUGHS ]
LOOK AT THIS.
SO, GUYS, CHECK IT OUT.
IT'S THE FRIDAY DOUBLE-FEATURE
DRIVE-IN MOVIE THEATER!
YOU GUYS HAVE GOT SPEAKERS
RIGHT HERE.
CHECK OUT THE MOVIE!
Girl: OH, MY GOD!
ISN'T THIS AWESOME?
MAN, WHAT A GREAT SHOW.
Jdiah:
I'VE NEVER HEARD OF ANYONE
HAVING AN ACTUAL DRIVE-IN
MOVIE THEATER IN THEIR BACKYARD,
BUT WE ACTUALLY HAVE ONE
IN OUR BACKYARD.
I'M JUST REALLY EXCITED
THAT YOU GUYS CAN HAVE
THE FIRST CHRISTMAS TOGETHER
AS A FAMILY IN THIS HOUSE NOW
THAT YOU'RE PROBABLY
GONNA OPEN UP
AND LET EVEN MORE FOSTER KIDS
COME THROUGH THE DOORS.
ABSOLUTELY. ABSOLUTELY.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THANK YOU FOR TAKING OUT
THE TIME
TO COME SEE ABOUT US...
...AND TO HOPE THAT SOMEBODY
WILL LOOK WHAT WE DONE
AND OPEN THEIR DOORS
TO A TOWN
OR TO MORE CHILDREN
AND JUST PAY IT FORWARD.
AND I THINK MORE KIDS
WILL FIND FAMILIES.
ABSOLUTELY.
I JUST WANT PEOPLE TO REALIZE
HOW IMPORTANT IT IS TO FOSTER.
HAVE GOT SOME WONDERFUL CHILDREN
AND HAVE MET
SOME WONDERFUL PEOPLE,
AND I JUST WANT PEOPLE TO LOOK
DEEP DOWN IN THEIR HEARTS
AND GET INVOLVED.
I GUARANTEE YOU,
YOU WON'T REGRET IT.
WELL, I GUESS THERE'S JUST
ONE THING LEFT TO SAY.
WELCOME HOME, FRIDAY FAMILY!
WELCOME HOME!
[ ALL CHEERING ]
AND MERRY CHRISTMAS!
WHO WANTS SOME PRESENTS?
COME ON!
[ LAUGHS ]
THERE YOU GO.
TO FIND OUT MORE
ABOUT THE PRODUCTS
USED ON TONIGHT'S SHOW,
GO TO abc.com.
♪ FRIDAY HOUSE,
OH, FRIDAY HOUSE ♪
♪ SO MUCH MORE TO GIVE
♪ WELL, TAKE IT DOWN
WITH CARE AND PRIDE ♪
♪ TOP TO BOTTOM, SIDE TO SIDE
♪ FRIDAY HOUSE,
OH, FRIDAY HOUSE ♪
♪ WILL CONTINUE TO GIVE
OKAY, ONE LAST BOX,
AND I'M READY FOR COLLEGE.
SWEETHEART,
THIS IS A LOT OF STUFF.
YOU DO REALIZE, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO TAKE ALL OF THIS STUFF
WITH YOU TO YOUR DORM ROOM?
LIKE THIS. WHAT IS THIS?
REMEMBER? I WANTED TO RIDE
MY BIKE WITHOUT TRAINING WHEELS,
LIKE THE BIG KIDS,
AND I DID.
SO YOU GOT ME
MY VERY OWN GOLD MEDAL.
OH, WELL, HONEY, THAT IS--
THAT'S A VERY SWEET MEMORY,