AEOLOGIST
JOAN CONNELLY.
JOAN, I KNOW YOU GET
A LITTLE EMBARRASSED
WHEN PEOPLE REFER TO YOU
AS INDIANA JOAN,
BUT IF I WERE TO CAST
A HOLLYWOOD MOVIE
WITH A FEMALE ARCHAEOLOGIST,
YOU WOULD BE IT.
AS WE EXPLORE THE ISLAND
OF THE GODS,
WE LEARN ABOUT CLEOPATRA'S
GREATEST CONQUEST.
ROMAN EMPEROR
THE HEART OF ROMAN EMPERORND
JULIUS CAESAR.
- SHE KNEW EXACTLY WHAT
SHE WAS DOING
WHEN SHE INVITED HIM
ON A CRUISE UP THE NILE.
BY THE END OF THE CRUISE,
HE HAD GIVEN HER
THE ISLAND OF CYPRUS.
WHAT BETTER LOVE TOKEN
TO GIVE YOUR NEW GIRLFRIEND
THAN THE ISLAND ON WHICH
APHRODITE WAS BORN?
- AND ON OUR JOURNEY,
WE DISCOVER HOW THE PAST
AND PRESENT HAVE MERGED.
SO I'M IN THIS LITTLE TOWN
CALLED KYPEROUNTA,
AND I SEE A WEDDING
AND I THINK,
OH, MAYBE KIND OF INTERESTING
TO CHECK IT OUT.
SO SUDDENLY THEY INVITE ME
TO THE WEDDING.
ARTY.
OF THE WEDDING PARTY.
SO SUDDENLY THEY INVITE ME
TO THE WEDDING.
WELCOME TO CYPRUS.
[intense percussive music]
♪
I'M RICHARD WIESE.
I'VE BEEN AN EXPLORER
MY ENTIRE LIFE,
AND I'M STILL PASSIONATE
ABOUT ADVENTURE,
NEW PEOPLE, PLACES,
AND NATURAL WONDERS.
I WAS BORN TO EXPLORE.
OUR EXPEDITION BEGINS HERE,
IN THE IDYLLIC ISLAND OF CYPRUS.
CYPRUS IS A MEDITERRANEAN ISLAND
BORDERED BY THREE CONTINENTS.
EUROPE TO THE NORTH,
AFRICA TO THE SOUTH,
AND ASIA TO THE EAST.
IT IS ALSO THE BIRTHPLACE OF
MANY ANCIENT GODS AND LEGENDS.
WITH ITS PRISTINE BEACHES,
STUNNING MOUNTAIN RANGES,
AND CAPTIVATING RUINS,
CYPRUS IS A REMARKABLE PLACE
TO EXPLORE.
ITS VIBRANT HISTORY,
RICH IN GREEK INFLUENCES,
TRACES BACK MORE
THAN 9,000 YEARS.
THE PROUD PEOPLE
OF THIS ISLAND COUNTRY
HOLD DEAR THOSE
ANCIENT TRADITIONS.
[jaunty fiddle music]
EVERYWHERE YOU GO,
THERE IS MUSIC AND DANCE
CELEBRATING LOVE AND ROMANCE.
STORIES ABOUT ANCIENT GODS,
FROM APOLLO TO APHRODITE,
THE GODDESS OF LOVE,
ARE STILL PASSED DOWN
FROM GENERATION TO GENERATION.
- APHRODITE IS THE SYMBOL
OF LOVE AND BEAUTY.
SO WHENEVER ANY LADY
IS VERY BEAUTIFUL,
WE LOOK AT HER AND SAY,
"MY GOD,
SHE IS LIKE AN APHRODITE."
- IT'S EASY TO GET MESMERIZED
BY THE TALES
OF THESE ANCIENT GODS.
IN CYPRUS, THERE'S A LEGEND
THAT IF YOU SWIM AROUND
THE ROCK OF APHRODITE,
THAT IT WILL BRING YOU GOOD LUCK
AND ETERNAL YOUTH.
I'M NOT SURE ABOUT
THE GOOD LUCK,
BUT LET'S FACE IT,
I'M NOT GETTING ANY YOUNGER.
[waves crashing]
MYTH HAS IT THAT APHRODITE
WAS BORN AT THIS VERY SPOT,
RISING FROM THE FOAMY SEAS.
SHE SYMBOLIZES ALL
THE JOYS AND PLEASURES OF LIFE,
AND IS STILL REVERED
THROUGHOUT CYPRUS TODAY.
WHOO!
I'M NOT SURE I FEEL ANY YOUNGER,
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M READY FOR AN ADVENTURE.
I'M JOINING RENOWNED
ARCHAEOLOGIST JOAN CONNELLY
TO HELP PROVE THAT THE RUINS
ON THE NEARBY ISLAND
OF YERONISOS
ARE THOSE OF A TEMPLE BUILT
BY CLEOPATRA
TO HONOR THE GREEK GOD APOLLO.
- IT WAS A MAGICAL PLACE
TO COME.
THE SUN COMES OVER
THE TROODOS MOUNTAINS
AND LIGHTS UP YERONISOS
LIKE A GOLDEN ISLAND.
AND YOU CAN UNDERSTAND
WHY PEOPLE
WOULD HAVE INVESTED SUCH
A VISION
WITH A SENSE OF THE SACRED.
IN THIS CASE,
THE WORLD OF APOLLO.
- JOAN BELIEVES THAT CLEOPATRA
BUILT THIS SANCTUARY
IN GRATITUDE
FOR HER SON CESAREAN,
THE CHILD FROM HER AFFAIR
WITH JULIUS CAESAR.
- WELCOME TO YERONISOS,
RICHARD.
- WOW.
WHAT A VIEW.
I LOVE YOUR OFFICE.
- YEAH.
- WHAT WAS THIS?
WHAT WAS YERONISOS?
- WELL, YOU'RE WALKING
IN THE FOOTSTEPS
OF ANCIENT PILGRIMS
FROM THE FIRST CENTURY B.C.
WHO WOULD HAVE COME HERE
TO WORSHIP THE GOD APOLLO.
WE HAVE MANY ISLAND SANCTUARIES
OF APOLLO
THROUGHOUT THE MEDITERRANEAN,
BUT NONE MORE SPECIAL,
IN MY OPINION,
THAN THE ONE HERE
JUST UP THE COAST
OF WESTERN CYPRUS.
- EVERY MORNING,
JOAN BRIEFS HER TEAM
OF NEW YORK UNIVERSITY
ARCHAEOLOGY STUDENTS.
- OKAY, TEAM, THIS MORNING
WE ARE GOING BACK
TO THE CENTRAL SOUTH SECTOR,
OUR RICHEST AREA ON YERONISOS.
THE SERIES OF SMALL ROOMS
FOR SLEEPING AND DINING
WHERE WE HAVE FOUND
GREAT QUANTITIES
OF DRINKING BOWLS,
CASSEROLES,
JUGLETS.
AND THEN I'M GOING
TO GIVE A LITTLE JOB TO RICHARD.
- WHOA.
OKAY, JOAN.
- YEAH, SO WE HAVE GOT
AN ANCIENT HELLENISTIC OVEN.
- OKAY.
- IT'S A LITTLE TRICKY DIGGING.
I HOPE YOU'RE UP
TO THE TASK.
- WHEN WE COME BACK,
JOAN GIVES ME A LESSON
ON THE TOOLS OF THE TRADE.
- YOU'RE LIKE A SCIENTIST
IN A LABORATORY.
- AND I'LL UNEARTH
AN ANCIENT ARTIFACT
THAT WAS LAST TOUCHED
OVER A THOUSAND YEARS AGO.
TO ENCOUNTER FANTASTICAL
SEA CREATURES AND STUFF,
THE OCEAN SHAMU OF THE SEA RISEW
WHEN OUR SONAR DETECTED
A TURTLE WORLD.
SO I TOOK CONTROL
AND STEERED US THROUGH IT.
THEN A CURIOUS SEA CREATURE
APPROACHED, AND AS OUR EYES MET
WE WERE TRANSPORTED
TO A SUPER-SECRET
UNDERWATER CAVERN...
SeaWorld?
I THINK THEY LIKED IT.
[ Female Announcer ]
START YOUR ADVENTURES TODAY
AT Seaworld.com
AND FIND SPECIAL OFFERS.
♪
This holiday when Kmart
Shop Your Way members
check out, they
can win...
... a trip to
Universal Orlando Resort,
during our 30 Days of
Surprise Sweepstakes.
You could have a despicably
good time.
Fly with Harry.
Or win lots of other
great prizes.
For more chances to win visit
Shop Your Way .com
Only at Kmart.
FROM SILVER SCREENS...
TWIZZLERIZE YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT EVERYDAY
WITH TWIZZLERS,
THE TWIST YOU CAN'T RESIST.
[ Female Announcer ]
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
RICH DARK CHOCOLATE,
TOASTED OATS.
PERFECT COMBINATIONS OF
NATURE'S DELICIOUS INGREDIENTS,
FROM NATURE VALLEY.
♪
NATURE VALLEY GRANOLA BARS,
NATURE AT ITS MOST DELICIOUS.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
she doesn't
Even though our really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...Madden Gi?
No way,     she doesn't
EvMadden Girls??really get us.
Nike!
Who's your mommy now?
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
- WE'RE HERE EXPLORING CYPRUS,
AN ISLAND RICH IN HISTORY
AND GREEK MYTHOLOGY.
I'M ON A DIG ON THE NEARBY
ISLAND OF YERONISOS
WITH ARCHAEOLOGIST
JOAN CONNELLY
AND HER TEAM OF NYU STUDENTS.
FOR OVER 20 YEARS,
JOAN HAS BEEN EXCAVATING
THIS SITE
TO CONFIRM THAT THE RUINS
WERE THOSE OF A TEMPLE BUILT
BY CLEOPATRA
IN THE FIRST CENTURY B.C.
I'M EAGER TO ROLE UP MY SLEEVES
AND START DIGGING,
BUT, FIRST, JOAN GIVES ME
A PRIMER
ON THE TOOLS OF THE TRADE.
- SO I'D LIKE
TO KIND GET YOU USED
TO HANDLING TWO DIFFERENT TOOLS.
LET'S START WITH THE HAND PICK.
- OKAY.
- NOW, EVERYONE HAS THEIR
OWN PERSONAL DIGGING STYLE.
- OKAY.
- BUT I MYSELF,
I LIKE TO TURN IT
AT A SLIGHT DIAGONAL
LET THE WEIGHT
OF THE HEAD ITSELF
DO THE DIGGING FOR YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO REALLY PUT ANY
EFFORT INTO IT.
BUT WHAT WE WANT TO DO IS--
LET'S START DOWN HERE.
WE WANT TO WORK ON A PATH.
- OKAY.
- AND WE'RE GOING
TO JUST CAREFULLY--
- IT'S LIKE PEELING OFF
LAYERS OF AN ONION.
YOU WANT TO BE WORKING
SAME PACE AND SAME AIR.
YOU'RE A LITTLE SHALLOWER
THAN I AM AND THAT'S OKAY.
- THAT'S IN A LOT OF WAYS.
- [laughs]
WHEN YOU SCRAPE BACK,
KEEPING YOUR WORK STATION CLEAN,
YOU COULD WORK YOUR WAY
THROUGH THIS SOIL
WITH THE TROWEL.
SWEEP UP YOUR EARTH AFTER
YOU HAVE FINISHED.
IF YOU FIND ANYTHING
YOU'RE UNCERTAIN OF,
YOU KNOW WHO TO ASK.
- I DO, AND I WILL
NOT TOUCH ANYTHING
OR MOVE ANYTHING THAT IS OF
POTENTIAL HISTORIC SIGNIFICANCE.
OKAY, YOU'VE--
- GOOD BOY.
- ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU, JOAN.
ARCHAEOLOGICAL EXCAVATION
IS BASICALLY DETECTIVE WORK--
SLOW, PAINSTAKING,
AND METHODICAL.
IT'S FAR FROM THE IMAGE
OF A SWASHBUCKLING INDIANA JONES
GRABBING ARTIFACTS
FROM EXOTIC TOMBS.
- OKAY, JOAN, I'M SEEING
LOTS OF STUFF HERE.
I'M EXTREMELY NERVOUS
BECAUSE I DON'T WANT
TO SCREW UP ANYTHING HERE.
- WELL, THIS IS QUITE
A REMARKABLE CONSTRUCTION
OF AN OVEN, AN ANCIENT
HELLENISTIC
FIRST CENTURY B.C. OVEN.
- OH, COOL.
- YOU SEE THE BURNING
DOWN BELOW.
THIS IS LIVE CHARCOAL.
IT WAS A SHAPE OF A BEEHIVE.
IT'S COLLAPSED.
AND THE SIDES ARE MADE
WITH REUSED AMPHORA SHERDS.
AND THIS BROKE.
THEY DECIDED TO REUSE IT.
THEY SET IT IN THIS LOVELY MUD--
WHAT WE CALL P.I.S.E.
IT'S A MUD PLASTER.
AND WE HAVE HINTS
OF SOME FINE DINING.
LOOK AT THE DIFFERENCE
OF THIS POTTERY.
IT IS NARROW-WALLED,
HARD-FIRED.
THIS IS A NICE SIGILLATA WARE.
DO YOU SEE...
- YEAH.
- DO YOU SEE HOW NICE
THE GLOSS IS COMING UP
WITH RED GLAZE?
BEAUTIFUL STUFF.
- IT'S EASY TO SEE
WHY JOAN'S STUDENTS
ARE SO THRILLED TO BE WORKING
BY HER SIDE.
HER ENTHUSIASM ABOUT
THE PAST CIVILIZATIONS OF CYPRUS
IS POSITIVELY INFECTIOUS.
I'VE ALWAYS ADMIRED
THE LEVEL THAT YOU HAVE GONE TO
WITH THE LOCAL PEOPLE.
IT TAKES ON A LIFE ALMOST
BEYOND THE DIG.
- WELL, I'M VERY, VERY COMMITTED
TO THE VIEW
THAT I DON'T COME IN HERE
AS AN OUTSIDER,
TAKE MY SCIENTIFIC DATA,
AND LEAVE.
THIS IS THEIR CULTURAL HERITAGE.
AND THIS IS SOMETHING
THAT WE SHARE.
AND FOR
OUR UNDERGRADUATE STUDENTS
TO MEET A COMMUNITY
OF PEOPLE,
THEY LEARN SO MUCH MORE
THAN JUST ARCHAEOLOGY.
THEY LEARN A VERY BEAUTIFUL
NATIVE CYPRIOT TRADITION,
WAY OF LIFE, OF THE VILLAGE.
- NEXT I TRAVEL
TO A LOCAL VILLAGE...
[horn honks]
TO EXPERIENCE ONE OF THE MOST
CHERISHED TRADITIONS
HERE IN CYPRUS:
A WEDDING.
[cheers and applause]
It just wouldn't go away.
My doctor diagnosed it
as fibromyalgia,
thought to be the
result of overactive nerves
that cause chronic
widespread pain.
Lyrica is believed
to calm these nerves.
I learned Lyrica can provide
significant relief
from fibromyalgia pain.
And for some people,
it can work in as early as
the first week of treatment.
So now I can plan my days
and accomplish more.
Lyrica is not for everyone.
Lyrica may cause serious
allergic reactions
or suicidal thoughts or actions.
Tell your doctor right away
if you have these,
new or worsening depression,
or unusual changes in mood
or behavior,
or any swelling or
affected breathing or skin,
or changes in eyesight,
including blurry vision
or muscle pain with fever
or tired feeling.
Common side effects
are dizziness, sleepiness,
weight gain, and swelling of
hands, legs and feet.
Don't drink alcohol
while taking Lyrica.
Don't drive or use machinery
until you know
how Lyrica affects you.
With less pain,
I'm feeling better
now that I've found Lyrica.
Ask your doctor
if Lyrica is right
for your fibromyalgia pain.
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
AIMS. sigh of relief ]
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
with hand-layered pasta,
tomatoes,
and real mozzarella cheese.
But what makes us even
prouder...
is what our real
dinners can do for your family.
Stouffer's.
Let's fix dinner.
♪uncer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
- I'M ON THE ISLAND
OF CYPRUS
CHAEOLOGIST JOAN CON SEA WITH
ARCHAEOLOGIST JOAN CONNELLY,
AS SHE TRIES TO SOLVE ONE OF
CLEOPATRA'S ANCIENT SECRETS.
LOVE AND ROMANCE IS AS MUCH
IN THE AIR IN CYPRUS TODAY
AS IT WAS CENTURIES AGO.
I'M SORT OF A ROMANTIC MYSELF,
SO WHEN I GET AN INVITATION
TO A WEDDING
IN THE TINY MOUNTAIN VILLAGE
OF KYPEROUNTA,
I HAVE TO ADMIT
I'M REALLY EXCITED.
[jaunty guitar
and fiddle music]
ON THIS ISLAND,
THE BIRTHPLACE OF APHRODITE,
A WEDDING IS A BIG DEAL.
I'M STRUCK BY HOW EVEN HERE
ON THIS EXOTIC ISLAND,
I STILL SEE THE
SAME FAMILIAR SCENES
AS IN WEDDINGS BACK HOME.
THE BEAUTIFUL BRIDE,
KONSTANTINAS KOUPI,
A MATH TEACHER,
GREW UP IN THIS TOWN.
SHE'S NERVOUSLY PREPARING
FOR THE CEREMONY
ON HER PARENTS' BALCONY,
SURROUNDED BY FAMILY
AND FRIENDS.
EACH BRIDESMAID NOW SIGNS
THE SOLE OF THE BRIDE'S SHOE.
LEGEND HAS IT
THAT THE BRIDESMAID
WHOSE NAME IS LAST TO WEAR OFF
WILL BE THE NEXT YOUNG LADY
TO BE MARRIED.
NORMALLY, IN A WEDDING,
IT'S A LITTLE MORE PRIVATE,
SO IT SEEMS LIKE THE WHOLE TOWN
IS HERE FOR THE BRIDE.
- YES, YOU SEE, ALL THIS BEAUTY
HAS TO BE SHARED
BY EYES OF EVERYBODY.
- CYPRIOT WEDDING RITUALS
HAVE CHANGED LITTLE
OVER THE CENTURIES.
IN A FINAL PREWEDDING BLESSING,
THE BRIDE'S PARENTS
WRAP A RED SASH
THREE TIMES AROUND HER WAIST
TO WISH THE NEWLYWEDS
A LONG, HAPPY,
AND FERTILE LIFE TOGETHER.
NOW KONSTANTINAS
IS ESCORTED
FROM HER PARENTS' HOME
TO THE CHURCH THROUGH
THE STREETS OF KYPEROUNTA.
EVERYONE IN THE TOWN
HAS SHOWN UP,
AND I MEAN EVERYONE.
- PEOPLE HERE ARE VERY FRIENDLY
AND THEY'RE CLOSE TOGETHER.
THEY KEEP THE TRADITIONS,
THE GREEK CYPRIOT TRADITIONS,
AND THIS--I'M VERY PROUD
OF ALL THIS.
I MEAN, MORE THAN 2,000 PEOPLE
IN THE PARTY
BECAUSE WE KNOW EACH OTHER.
- WELL, YOU KNOW,
IN THE UNITED STATES,
ALWAYS THE BIG ARGUMENT
BETWEEN THE BRIDE AND THE GROOM
IS THE GUEST LIST,
WHO'S INVITED.
BUT HERE IT SEEMS LIKE
EVERYBODY'S INVITED.
I WAS INVITED.
[laughter]
THE GROOM,
GEORGIOS KONSTANTIDAS,
IS AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TEACHER
IN THE NEARBY TOWN OF LIMASSOL.
WHEN HIS BRIDE ARRIVES,
GEORGIOS PRESENTS HER
WITH HER WEDDING BOUQUET.
AS WAS THE CUSTOM
WITH THE ANCIENT GREEKS,
THIS WEDDING IS HELD
ON A SUNDAY WITH A FULL MOON.
[people chanting
indistinctly]
THE LUCKY COUPLE HAS BLESSINGS
BESTOWED UPON THEM
BY SEVEN PRIESTS.
[priests chanting indistinctly]
THE CHURCH IS PACKED
WITH FAMILY AND FRIENDS
FROM THE VILLAGE
AND ALSO FROM NEIGHBORING TOWNS.
[priest singing]
A GREEK ORTHODOX WEDDING
IS STEEPED
IN ANCIENT TRADITIONS.
RITUALS ARE PERFORMED
IN THREES
TO REPRESENT THE HOLY TRINITY.
CROWNS TIED TOGETHER
WITH A RIBBON
SYMBOLIZING THE UNION
ARE PLACED
ON THE COUPLE'S HEADS,
THEN EXCHANGED THREE TIMES.
FOR COMMUNION,
THE COUPLE TAKES THREE BITES
OF BREAD
AND THREE SIPS OF WINE.
THE PRIEST LEADS THEM
AROUND THE ALTAR THREE TIMES
AS THE COUPLE TAKES
THEIR FIRST STEPS
AS HUSBAND AND WIFE.
[lively fiddle music]
I DIDN'T EXPECT
TO BE GOING TO A WEDDING TODAY,
BUT MAYBE THIS
WAS VERY SYMBOLIC
OF A SMALL CYPRIOT VILLAGE.
PEOPLE HERE ARE FRIENDLY,
SO THIS WAS A GREAT TRADITION
AND IT WAS REALLY NICE
TO BE PART OF IT.
WHEN BORN TO EXPLORE CONTINUES,
WE DISCOVER ANOTHER CLUE
THAT BRINGS US
ONE STEP CLOSER TO SOLVING
THE MYSTERY
OF CLEOPATRA'S LONG LOST TEMPLE.
- SOMEONE THREW A LOT
OF MONEY AT YERONISOS
AROUND ABOUT 47 B.C.
AND THE ONLY KIND OF PERSON
WITH THAT KIND OF MONEY
IS CLEOPATRA.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Fem♪ ] Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
LOSING YOUR CHEX MIX TOO EASILY?
TIME TO DEPLOY
THE BORING-POTATO CHIP
DECOY BAG.
THEN NO ONE WILL WANT TO STEAL
THE DELICIOUSNESS.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
ONLY CHEX MIX
IS A BAG OF INTERESTING.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH A
VARIETY OF TASTES AND TEXTURES,
OH, IT'S GREAT!
NOW I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
WELL, INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT'S POWERFUL ENOUGH
TO CARRY MORE COFFEE
AND FRESH WATER TO MAKE COFFEE
THAT'S STRONGER
AND BIGGER...
AND EVEN HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW THE COFFEE YOU LOVE --
STRONGER, BIGGER, OR HOTTER --
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
TO FLAT SCREENS...NS...
TWIZZLERIZE YOUR
ENTERTAINMENT EVERYDAY
THE TW
THE TWIST YOU CAN'T RESIST.
- OUR TIME HERE IN CYPRUS
HAS BEEN RICH IN HISTORY
AND CULTURE.
WE'VE EXPERIENCED
THE WONDERS
OF FIELD ARCHAEOLOGY
FIRSTHAND
WITH "INDIANA" JOAN CONNELLY.
JOAN CONNELLY
IS REALLY INDIANA JOAN.
I MEAN, SHE'S SMART.
SHE'S PRETTY.
SHE, UH, RUNS
A GREAT DIG.
SHE'S PASSIONATE ABOUT
THE LOCAL PEOPLE.
SO IT'S A VERY CONTAGIOUS
FEELING THERE.
YOU JUST CAN'T HELP BUT FEEL
REALLY GOOD
ABOUT AN EXPEDITION LIKE THIS.
EVEN THOUGH JOAN
HAS BEEN DIGGING UP
THE MOST EXTRAORDINARY
ARTIFACTS HERE
FOR OVER 20 YEARS,
SHE STILL GETS GOOSEBUMPS
EVERY TIME ONE OF HER STUDENTS
UNEARTHS A NEW DISCOVERY.
- ALL RIGHT, YOU LOOK EXCITED.
WHAT HAPPENED?
- WE FOUND THIS.
IT CAME OUT OF THE PILE
OF ROCKS
AT THE SITE OF OUR TRENCH.
- NICE PIECE
OF ARCHITECTURAL MOLDING
FROM OUR HELLENISTIC LEVEL.
WELL DONE.
NOW YOU WANT TO GET
THE COORDINATES.
WE COLLECT THEM ALL,
WE DRAW THEM ALL,
AND WE CAN PIECE SOME
OF THEM TOGETHER
BACK IN OUR STOREROOM.
AND WE ARE, WITH RICHARD
ANDERSON, OUR ARCHITECT,
RECONSTRUCTING THE PROFILES
OF OUR MAJOR BUILDINGS.
- LOOK AT YOU.
YOU'RE BOTH SMILING.
THERE'S A SECRET.
THIS IS CLEOPATRA'S SECRET
BEING REVEALED RIGHT HERE.
- IT'S VERY EXCITING.
IT'S THE FIRST
SUBSTANTIAL THING,
I THINK, THAT I'VE FOUND
SINCE I'VE BEEN HERE.
- OH, CONGRATULATIONS.
- THANK YOU.
- IS IT ONE OF THOSE THINGS
THAT YOU'RE LOOKING VERY COOL
FOR CAMERA,
THEN YOU GO BACK
AND YOU GO, "DEAR DIARY,
?"
THAT YOU'RE LOOKING VERY COOL
FOR CAMERA,
- [laughing] YES.
IN MY WORLD,
THIS IS UP THERE,
AND DEFINITELY WORTH WRITING
ABOUT.
- SOMEONE PUT AN ENORMOUS
AMOUNT OF EFFORT
INTO BRINGING ALL
THESE MATERIALS UP
TO THIS VERY UNLIKELY,
IMPROBABLE PLACE.
SOMEONE THREW A LOT
OF MONEY AT YERONISOS,
AND THE ONLY KIND OF PERSON
WITH THAT KIND OF MONEY
WAS CLEOPATRA
AND HER ADMINISTRATION.
- A KEY RESPONSIBILITY
FOR ARCHAEOLOGISTS
IS TO PRESERVE THE ARTIFACTS
THEY'VE DISCOVERED.
ANDS OF YEARS,
ARTIFACTS BEGIN TO DECAY WHEN
EXPOSED TO AIR AND SUNLIGHT.
I'M HELPING ONE
OF JOAN'S COLLEAGUES,
ESTEEMED ARCHAEOLOGIST
PAUL CROFT,
TO RECONSTRUCT
AN EXPOSED WALL
THAT WAS ONCE PART
OF A CEREMONIAL DANCE FLOOR.
- WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO HERE
IS TO MIX UP SOME
OF THIS CONSTRUCTIONAL MUD.
AND IT'S VERY SIMPLE
AND QUITE FUN, ACTUALLY,
TO BE ON A HOT DAY.
- A LITTLE WATER.
- ONCE WE MADE IT
INTO A FAIRLY WET MUD...
- OKAY.
- YOU'RE GONNA WALK IN IT.
- YOU KNOW, THE MARKETING PERSON
IN ME SAYS
I WOULD SELL THIS AS, LIKE,
CLEOPATRA'S MUD--
YEAH, SOME THERAPY THING
FOR PEOPLE
AND SAY, "OKAY, THIS IS A BEAUTY
SECRET OF CLEOPATRA."
AND WHAT'S GONNA HOLD
THIS MUD TOGETHER?
- WE'RE GONNA TREAD IN
WITH OUR BARE FEET TOGETHER
THIS WHEAT CHAFF.
- I'M GONNA PUT THIS IN A JAR
AND SELL IT
IN SOME BEAUTY STORE.
- SO I'M GONNA START PUTTING
THE CHAFF WHEAT NOW.
- I KNEW I WAS GONNA GET
MY HANDS DIRTY,
BUT I DIDN'T EXPECT THIS.
IT ACTUALLY FEELS KIND OF NICE
BETWEEN THE TOES.
- YEAH, IT'S NICE, ISN'T IT?
- YEAH, IT IS.
[squelching]
ALL RIGHT, I AM READY
TO RECONSTRUCT HISTORY.
- OKAY, WE'LL JUST HAVE
TO WET IT DOWN A BIT FIRST
SINCE IT'S PRET
WET IT A LITTLE.
- SOMETHING TELLS ME
THE TECHNIQUE
IS NOT AS INVOLVED
IN SOME OF THE OTHER THINGS.
- THE REASON THAT WE'RE SECURING
THIS STRIP OF EARTH
BENEATH THE WALL IS THAT
IT'S FAIRLY LOOSE AND FRAGILE,
AND WITH THE PASSAGE OF TIME,
IT WILL BECOME ERODED AWAY
AND THE WALL WILL COLLAPSE.
WITH GOOD LUCK,
IT SHOULD LAST SEVERAL YEARS
BEFORE WE HAVE TO RENEW IT.
- YOU KNOW, I MAY HAVE FOUND
MY CALLING.
[both chuckle]
JOAN CERTAINLY PUT ME TO WORK
DURING MY BRIEF VISIT
TO YERONISOS,
AND I LOVED IT.
WHAT AN INCREDIBLE THRILL
TO UNEARTH AN ARTIFACT
LAST TOUCHED BY SOMEONE WHO
LIVED THOUSANDS OF YEARS AGO.
JOAN'S STILL SEARCHING
FOR THE DEFINITIVE EVIDENCE
THAT PROVES CLEOPATRA
BUILT THIS TEMPLE,
AND I HAVE NO DOUBT
SHE'LL SOON FIND IT.
- THIS IS THE KIND OF PLACE
WHERE YOU CAN TEASE OUT
THE HISTORY
THAT FALLS BETWEEN THE CRACKS.
JOB.
WHERE YOU CAN TEASE OUT
SO THIS IS OUR JOB.
THIS IS THRILLING.
AND WE CONTRIBUTE
IN OUR OWN SMALL WAY
TO TELLING THE STORY
OF THE LONG MARCH OF HISTORY.
- UP NEXT, WE PARTY
WITH JOAN'S TEAM
AND CELEBRATE HER BIRTHDAY.
[rhythmic clapping]
stuffed with a gooey center
toasted up all golden brown
then given a delicious design?
A toaster strudel.
Pillsbury Toaster Strudel.
So Delicious...So Fun.
And when I get a cold I take
Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
[rhythmic clapping
and fiddling]
- OUR TIME ON CYPRUS HAS BEEN
A REMARKABLE COMBINATION
OF HISTORY AND HOSPITALITY.
IT FEELS LIKE EVERYONE
HAS SHOWN UP
TO CELEBRATE
THE YERONISOS DIG TEAM
AND JOAN'S BIRTHDAY.
- WELCOME, EVERYONE.
THIS IS OUR 22ND ANNUAL
YERONISOS ISLAND DIG PARTY.
THEY SEEM TO BE GETTING BETTER
AND BETTER.
- WITH JOAN AS OUR
UNOFFICIAL AMBASSADOR,
WE COULDN'T HAVE HOPED
FOR A MORE WELCOMING
AND EXHILARATING EXPERIENCE
WITH THE PEOPLE OF CYPRUS.
AS WE SING AND DANCE
INTO THE NIGHT,
IT FEELS LIKE THIS GATHERING
IS A HEARTFELT WAY
FOR ALL OF US
TO SAY HONORING OUR TRADITIONS
IS A WONDERFUL THING.
SHARING THEM WITH FRIENDS
IS EVEN BETTER.
[cheers and applause]
SAM: TODAY ON SEA
RESCUE, A DOLPHIN
BEACHES ON SHORE WITH
GRUESOME INJURIES ALL
OVER ITS BODY.
JON: IT'S PHENOMENAL
THAT THE ANIMAL WAS
STILL ALIVE.
SAM: NOW IT'S UP TO
RESCUERS TO SAVE HIM.
I'M SAM CHAMPION, AND
WE'RE ON A SEA RESCUE.
♪ MUSIC