HAPPENS.
WE'RE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
SHOOTING TONIGHT.
HERE'S DETAILS.
REPORTER: SUNDAY MOURNERS
FLEDDED INTO THE CHURCH, STILL
REELING.
REPORTER: FLOWERS, TEDDY BEARS
AND CANDLES ARE PILING UP AT A
CONTINUOUS PACE AS ALL
AVENUETOWN TURNS INTO ONE LARGE
GROWING MEMORIAL.
>> THE FEELING OF EMPTINESS AND
PEOPLE JUST REACHING OUT FOR
EACH OTHER AND AT A LOSS FOR
WORDS.
REPORTER: THAT SOMBER TONE
TURNED BRIEFLY TO ALARM.
POLICE AND S.W.A.T. TEAMS BROKE
UP PRAYERS WITH GUNS DRAWN TO
EVACUATE A THOUGHT PEOPLE FROM
MASS.
>> SOMEONE THREATENED TO DISRUPT
THE SERVICE, SO WE ACTED
SWIFTLY.
>> SECURITY IS ON EDGE WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA IN NEWTOWN FOR
AN EVENING BROTHER VIGIL.
HE'LL MEET WITH THE FAMILY0S OF
THE SHOOTING VICTIMS.
INVESTIGATORS ARE STILL TRYING
TO FIND OUT WHAT PROMPTED
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA TO SHOOT
HIS MOTHER MULTIPLE TIMES IN THE
FACE BEFORE CONTINUING HIS
KILLING SPREE AT SANDY HOOKLETLY
THAT ONLY END WHEN HE SHOT
HIMSELF IN THE HEAD.
NOW THE TOWN IS WORKING TO HAVE
THE YOUNGEST SURVIVORS NOT HAVE
THEIR LIVES IMPACTED.
>> THE POLICEMAN TOLD US TO
CLOSE OUR EYES.
AND JUST GO OUT.
>> TOLD TO US CLOSE OUR EYES
BECAUSE THE MAN WAS PROBABLY
DEAD RIGHT THERE.
REPORTER: A NEARBY UP TO IS
HELPING BY OFFERING UP A SCHOOL
THAT IS SILTING EMPTY TO THE
CHILDREN OF SANDY HOOK.
THE IDEA WHEN THEY GO BACK TO
SCHOOL, THEY DON'T HAVE TO DO IT
IN A BUILDING STRUCK BY TRAGEDY.
>> Ama: THE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN
SHAKEN BY THIS TRAGEDY, AND IT'S
NOT JUST THOSE DIRECTLY AFFECTED
IN THE SHOOTING.
LAURA AN HAPPY TO IS LIVE FROM
SANDY HOOK WITH REACTION FROM
FOLKS IN TOWN.
LAURA?
REPORTER: THIS IS A VERY
TIGHT-KNIT SMALL COMMUNITY, A
VILLAGE.
TODAY IT WAS FILLED WITH PEOPLE
AND CARS FROM ALL OVER THE AREA.
BUT WE HEARD VERY LITTLE NOISE.
VERY LITTLE CONVERSATION.
IT WAS COLD.
IT DRIZZLED ALL DAY.
THE SKY WAS GRAY.
BUT IT VERY MUCH FIT THE MOOD.
>> THE FEELINGS ARE IN THE FACES
OF THE THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE WHO
HAVE DESCENDED ON TINY SANDY
HOOK, CONNECTICUT.
AND IDEAL VILLAGE, THE TOWN IS
IN SHOCK, NOWMED THE REALITY
THAT A DISTURBED YOUNG MAN TOOK
SO MUCH.
27 PEOPLE FROM ONE SMALL PLACE.
>> I WALK UP AND DOWN AND IT'S
JUST -- YOUR SPINE JUST -- GET
THAT SHIVER.
>> SADNESS.
AND DISBELIEF.
REPORTER: AT THE ENTRANCE TO THE
SCHOOL, AROUND A SIGN THAT SAYS
VISITORS WELCOME, THERE STANDS
27 CHRISTMAS TREES FOR EACH
VICTIM, DEM CRATED FOR THE --
DECORATE FOR THE HOLIDAY.
INCLUDING STUFFED ANIMALS FOR
THOSE LOST HERE.
>> SHE LEFT THEM BEHIND.
>> WHY DID YOU WANT TO DO THAT?
>> BECAUSE I HOPED --
>> THERE WERE MANY CHILDREN
AMONG THOSE COMING TO PAY THEIR
RESPECTS, LIKE THEIR PARENTS,
STILL STRUGGLING TO GRASP WHAT
HAPPENED HERE.
>> THOSE PEOPLE WHAT HAPPENED.
>> DOWN THE ROAD, LOCAL HIGH
SCHOOL STUDENTS AND RECENT
GRADUATES SET UP A TABLE
COLLECTING DONATIONS FOR THE
FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS.
FAMILIES THAT MANY OF THEM KNOW.
>> PEOPLE HAND US DONATIONS IT'S
THE HEAD NOD, AND YOU DON'T
SPEAK ABOUT IT.
YOU JUST KIND OF NOD BACK AND
YOU UNDERSTAND WITH THAT NOD.
YOU RECOGNIZE THAT YOU'RE GOING
THROUGH THE SAME THING, AND THE
SAME PAIN.
>> HOW DOES THIS COMMUNITY MOVE
ON, DO YOU THINK, OR CAN THEY?
>> I'M NOT SURE THEY CAN.
I THINK THIS WILL FOREVER -- I
DON'T HAVE THE WORDS TO EXPLAIN
IT.
REPORTER: AND TONIGHT, AS WE
SPEAK, THERE IS A PUBLIC
MEMORIAL, A VIGIL, AN INTERFAITH
VIGIL, PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL
SPEAK SHORTLY.
TOMORROW BEGINS THE VERY PRIVATE
BUSINESS OF BURYING THOSE WHO
WERE KILLED HERE.
THOSE SERVICES BEGIN WITH THE
FUNERALS OF TWO YOUNG BOYS, TWO
FIRST-GRADERS.
TONIGHT ON ABC-7 NEWS AT 6:00.
WE'LL HEAR FROM A LOCAL SALON
OWNER WHO COUNTED MANY OF THESE
YOUNG VICTIMS AMONG HER CLIENTS.
IN SANDY HOOK, CONNECTICUT,
ABC-7 NEWS.
>> Ama: THANK YOU FOR THAT.
A FRIEND OF THE FAMILY SAYS THAT
ADAM LANZA LEARNED HOW TO SHOOT
GUNS FROM HIS MOM.
HE SAYS THEY WERE HER HOLIDAY.
AUTHORITIES FOUND THREE GUNS
USED IN THE SHOOTING THAT
BELONGED TO HIS MOTHER.
THEY INCLUDE A GLOCK TEN
MILLIMETER, A SIGNATURE SAUER
NINE MILLIMETER HAND GUN AND A
BUSH MASTER ASSAULT RIFLE.
THE SAME TYPE OF RIFLE USED IN
THE 2002DC SNIPER ATTACKS.
SENATOR DINE FEINSTEIN WILL CALL
FOR A VOTE ON AN ASSAULT WEAPONS
BAN.
THE NATION'S GUN STATISTIC MAY
SURPRISE YOU.
THERE ARE MORE REGISTERED GUN
SELLERS THAN McDONALD'S
RESTAURANTNESS THE U.S.
THERE ARE AN ESTIMATED 270 TO
300 MILLION GUNS AND 313 MILLION
PEOPLE.
SENATOR FEINSTEIN SAYS IT'S TOO
MANY, ESPECIALLY EASY TO LOAD
AUTOMATIC WEAPONS.
THIS MORNING SHE OFFERED DETAILS
OF THE BAN.
>> IT WILL BAN THE SALE,
TRANSFER, IMPORT ADDITION, AND
THE POSSESSION -- NOT
RETROACTIVELY BUT PROSPECTIVELY,
AND WILL BAN THE SAME FOR BIG
CLIPS, DRUMS, OR STRIPS.
OF AMERICAN TEN BULLETS.
WE EXEMPT OVER 900 SPECIFIC
WEAPONS THAT WILL NOT BE -- FALL
UNDER THE BILL.
BUT THE PURPOSE OF THIS BILL IS
TO GET WEAPONS OF WAR OFF THE
STREETS OF OUR CITY.
>> Ama: THIS MORNING, SENATOR
JOE LIEBERMAN CALLED FOR A
COMMISSION TO LOOK AT OUR
NATION'S GUN LAWS AND MENTAL
HEALTH SYSTEM.
>> ON THIS FIRST SUNDAY AFTER
THE NEWTOWN SHOOTING, PEOPLE
HERE IN THE BAY AREA LOOKED FOR
SOLACE AT THEIR PLACES OF
WORSHIP.
WE'RE LIVE AT ST. MARY'S
CATHEDRAL IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> TODAY SEEMED TO BE THE KIND
OF DAY WHEN PARENTS WANTED TO BE
VERY CLOSE TO THEIR CHILDREN,
ESPECIALLY AT PLACES OF WORSHIP
LIKE HERE.
HERE THEY PLAYED FOR THE VICTIMS
OF NEWTOWN BUT ALSO FOR THE
SAFETY OF THEIR OPEN -- OWN
CHILDREN.
REPORTER: NEW AT THE CATHEDRAL,
MONSIGNOR OFFERED PRAYERS FOR
THE VICTIMS OF NEW TIEWN AND WAS
JOINED BY MANY PARISHIONERS.
>> TODAY IS A DAY TO PRAY,
ESPECIALLY FOR ALL THOSE PEOPLE.
THAT WERE MASSACRED AND FOR
THEIR FAMILIES.
REPORTER: EVEN A SPECIAL PRAYER
WRITTEN FOR THE VICTIMS.
HE IS THE PASTOR OF ST. MARY'S
AND SAYS PEOPLE HAVE COME TO
MASS NOT JUST TO PRAY BUT TO TRY
TO MAKE SOME SENSE OF THE EVIL
THAT OCCURRED.
>> AND SEEKING TO FIND CONSTANCE
NATION THE PROMISE AND HOPE OF A
GOD WHO FEELS WITH US AND LONGS
TO HELP US.
REPORTER: AT GLIDE MEMORIAL
CHURCH, THE CHURCH DID WHAT IT
DOES BEST, HELPED THE
CONGREGATION CELEBRATE LIFE
WHILE RECOVERING FROM THE SORROW
OF THE TRAGEDY.
FOR REV REPS CECIL WOMEN'S THE
CHURCH WAS FILLED TO STANDING
ROOM ONLY AND SAYS THE RESPONSE
IS INCREDIBLE.
>> NEVER SEEN SOMETHING LIKE
THIS IN MY 50 YEARS, NEVER SEEN
IT TOUCH COMMUNITIES AND
INDIVIDUALS LIKE THIS HAS DONE.
REPORTER: HE SAYS THE KILLING OF
INNOCENTS AFFECTED PEOPLE
EVERYWHERE.
>> IT HAPPENS ALL OVER THE
WORLD.
BECAUSE THEY WENT FOR THE
CHILDREN.
HE WENT TO DESTROY THE CHILDREN.
FOR SOME REASON.
REPORTER: MANY OF THE PEOPLE WHO
CAME TO GLIDE, CAME WITH THEIR
CHILDREN HELD TIGHT.
THIS IS MARION'S FIRST VISIT TO
GLIDE CHURCH.
SHE BROUGHT HER DAUGHTER ALONG
FOR A SPIRITUAL HEALING.
>> OUR FIRST TIME HERE, AND THIS
IS TO SHARE THE LOVE AND THE
HEARTACHE THAT EVERYBODY IS
FEELING.
REPORTER: BOTH GLIDE AND
ST. MARY'S HAVE SET UP SPECIAL
AREAS FOR CONTEMPLATION AND ALSO
FOR PRAYERS.
WE'RE LIVE IN SAN FRANCISCO,
ABC-7 NEWS.
>> Ama: INVESTIGATORS ARE STILL
FIGURING OUT WHAT LED TO THE
SHOOTING.
ABC-7 NEWS WILL CONTINUE TO
COVER THE STORE.
YOU CAN ALSO FIND NEW
INFORMATION ON OUR FACEBOOK PAGE
AND TWITTER FEEDS.
>>> STILL AHEAD.
REPUBLICANS GIVE AN INCH IN THE
FISCAL CLIFF DEBATE.
WHAT THEY'RE WILLING TO GIVE UP
TO KEEP TAX CUTS FOR THE MIDDLE
CLASS FROM EXPIRING.
>> SO MUCH VIOLENCE, PEOPLE IN
THE BAY AREA ARE FIGHTING BACK.
THESE RANDOM ACTS OF KINDNESS
COMING UP.
>> Leigh: I'M LEIGH GLASER.
AccuWeather SEVEN-DAY
FORECAST SHOWING A PRETTY STORMY
OUTLOOK FOR THIS U
>> Ama: DOWELING NEWS.
A DRIVER FLIPPED HER CAR NEAR
THE CALDECOTT TUNNEL.
ITS BURT BURST INTO FLAMES.
THE DRIVE LOST CONTROL, HER CAR
NIPPED AND HIT A TREE.
BOTH WOMEN INSIDE WERE ABLE TO
ESCAPE WITHOUT INJURY.
>>> WE CAN ALL PROBABLY USE A
BIG HUG AND THAT'S WHAT
VOLUNTEERS FROM THE HUNTING
HAPPINESS PROJECT WERE
DELIVERING AT THE OAKLAND
FARMERS MARKET TODAY.
AS A VISITOR WHO BROWSED IN JACK
LONDON SQUARE, THEY WERE HIT
WITH RANDOM ACTS OF KINDNESS.
HUGS AND HIGH FIVES OR
ENCOURAGING WORDS, SMALL
GESTURES THAT MAKE A BIG
DIFFERENCE.
>> HUGS CAN HELP YOU GET THROUGH
THE DAY.
I THINK THAT'S SOMETHING THAT IS
MEANINGFUL.
>> IT'S NICE TO REACH OUT AND
JUST BE NICE.
SOMETHING WE NEED TO DO MORE OF,
I THINK.
>> Ama: THE VOLUNTEERS AT THE
BOOTH ALSO WROTE NOTES OF
INSPIRATION, ENCOURAGING OTHERS
TO STEP UP AND SPREAD THE GOOD
WILL.
>>> COMING UP, A LOOK AT WHO
WILL LIKELY BE THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF DEFENSE.
PLUS, REPUBLICANS AGREE TO GIVE
UP A LITTLE MORE IN THE FISCAL
CLIFF DEBATE.
WE WE'LL LOOK AT THEIR NEW
[ Female Announcer ]
MARTINELLI'S GOLD MEDAL
SPARKLING CIDER
IS THE PERFECT CHOICE
FOR HOLIDAY GATHERINGS.
MARTINELLI'S IS NON-ALCOHOLIC,
FESTIVE LIKE CHAMPAGNE,
AND TASTES GREAT!
MARTINELLI'S: SINCE 1868.
FESTIVE LIKE CHAMPAGNE,
AND TASTES GREAT!
OH MY GOD, HIM DANCE?
HE SHOULHAVE YOU SEEN HIS SHOES?
THEY LOOK LIKE,
THEY LOOK LIKE FLIPPERS.
[ aunts laughing ]
[ Male Announcer ]
FIND SOME PEACE THIS HOLIDAY.
GET AN 8 PIECE MEAL
NOW WITH A DOZEN
DELICIOUS COOKIES
BAKED IN-STORE.
THE KFC FESTIVE FEAST.
ALL FOR JUST $19.99.
YES YOU DID.
NO I DIDN'T.
DID NOT.
[ Male Announcer ]
TODAY TASTES SO GOOD.
>> Ama: WITH AMERICANS
ACCELERATING TOWARDS THE FISCAL
CLIFF CLIFF, HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER REPORTEDLY OFF EVERRED
PRESIDENT OBAMA THAT WOULD RAISE
TAX BREAKS FOR THOSE MAKING MORE
THAN A MILLION DOLLARS A YEAR.
THE PRESIDENT'S PLAN CALLS FOR A
HIGHER RATE FOR THOSE EARNING
MORE THAN $250,000 A YEAR.
NEITHER SIDE HAS OFFERED ON --
COMMENTED ON THE OFFER.
>>> NOW PRESIDENT OBAMA BACKS AS
HIS NEXT SECRETARY OF DEFENSE IS
A MODERATE REPUBLICAN WHO WORKS
WITH THE PRESIDENT.
CHUCK HAGEL LEFT POLITICS POLITF
APPROVED BY THE SENATE, HE WILL
TAKE OVER FROM LEEON PANETTA.
>> FOR A LOOK AT THE WEATHER,
HERE'S LEIGH GLASER.
>> Leigh: LOOKS STORMY HEADING
INTO THURSDAY, FRIDAY, AND NEXT
WEEKEND.
RIGHT NOW WE'RE SEEING THE
CLOUDS THICKEN UP.
OUR HIGH DEFINITION EAST BAY CAM
SHOWING THE CLOUDS STARTING TO
THICKEN OVER THE BAY.
NOW LET'S GET TO LIVE DOPPLER
7HD.
YOU CAN SEE FOR YOURSELF, MUCH
OF THE DAY IT HAS BEEN THAT
LOW-LEVEL MOISTURE, THE HEAVY
MIST AND DRIZZLE, FROM SAN
FRANCISCO, POINTS NORTHWARD,
CLOVERDALE, SANTA ROSA, VALLEJO,
SACRAMENTO, AND OUT TOWARDS
NAPA, AS WELL AS DOWN TOWARDS
ST. HELENA, ALL THOSE LOCATIONS
PICKING UP LOW-LEVEL MOISTURE
BUT SOUTH OF SAN FRANCISCO YOU
SAW A LITTLE BIT MORE IN THE WAY
OF SUNSHINE.
RIGHT IN THIS AREA, A LITTLE SUN
FOR SAN JOSE.
YOU POPPED UP INTO THE 50s
TODAY.
IN THE NORTH BAY THAT'S WHERE
THE CLOUDS HUNG AROUND, AND
TEMPERATURES THERE TODAY 'ONLY
MANAGED MID-UP TOKER 40s IN
MOST CASES.
RIGHT NOW A LITTLE WARMER.
NAPA, 50, 49 IN SAN RAFAEL, 49,
LIGHT MIST AND DRIZZLE.
54 IN SAN FRANCISCO, 5 -- 57 IN
HANDJOSE.
RAIN ON THE INCREASE OVERNIGHT
TONIGHT.
GET READY FOR A VERY WET MORNING
COMMUTE TOMORROW, AND THEN LOOKS
STORMY HEADING TOWARDS THE
LATTER PART OF THE WORK WEEK.
THIS IS THE COLD FRONT THAT WILL
MOVE THROUGH TONIGHT.
THIS WARM SECTOR PROVIDED THE
LIFT AND ALL THE MOISTURE FOR
THE NORTH BAY TODAY.
AS WE PROGRESS OVERNIGHT, THE
COLD FRONT WILL SPREAD THE RAIN
SOUTH.
SO WE'LL BEGIN OUR FORECAST AT
8:00 TONIGHT.
AND YOU'LL NOTICE SANTA ROSA, UP
NORTH, START TO SEE THE
BEGINNINGS OF THE COLD FRONT.
BY 10:00 SHOULD START TO DRAPE
ACROSS MUCH OF THE NORTH BAY,
AND THEN OVERNIGHT, THIS WILL
SLIDE SOUTH.
THE MAJORITY OF THE BAY AREA
WILL HAVE TO DEAL WITH WET
PAINFUL TOMORROW MORNING, AND
THEN THIS SYSTEM BY 8:00 STARTS
TO FOCUS TOWARDS THE SOUTH BAY,
AND THEN BY LUNCHTIME, 1:00,
2:00, 3:00, SCATTERED SHOWERS
AND THE EVENING COMMUTE SHOULD
BE RELATIVELY DRY.
MOST OF THE RAIN WILL HAVE MOVED
OUT AND WE'LL ALONG FOR
CLEARING.
WE'RE LOOKING TO CLOSE TO AN
INCH OF RAIN MAINLY IN THE NORTH
BAY MOUNTAINS.
THIS IS NOT A HUGE RAIN-MAKER,
MAYBE A QUARTER TO HALF AN INCH
ELSEWHERE.
IT WILL MOVE IN TONIGHT.
AND IT WILL MOVE OUT BY TOMORROW
AFTERNOON.
LOWS TONIGHT, OBVIOUSLY WITH THE
CLOUDS MOVING IN, WILL BE MUCH
WARMER, UPPER 40s TO LOW 50s
AND HIGHS FOR MONDAY, THE RAIN
IN THE MORNING FOLLOWED BY
AFTERNOON SCATTERED SHOWERS AND
PARTIAL CLEARING.
52, SAN RAFAEL, AND SAN
FRANCISCO, LIVERMORE, 54.
50s FOR WATSONVILLE AND
GILROY.
HERE'S THE SEVEN-DAY FORECAST.
A SLIGHT BREAK TUESDAY.
WEDNESDAY MORNING, GET READY FOR
MORNING FROST.
IT WILL BE COLD BUT A DRY DAY ON
WEDNESDAY.
THEN HEAVY RAIN AND WIND
EXPECTED ON THURSDAY.
PERIODS OF RAIN COULD BE HEAVY
AT TIMES ON FRIDAY.
AND IT LOOKS LIKE ANOTHER STORM
PROBABLY SATURDAY NIGHT AND
EARLY SUNDAY MORNING.
SO, DEFINITELY STAY TUNED WITH
US AND WE'LL KEEP YOU UPDATED.
>> SHU IS HERE WITH SPORTS.
RAIDERS BIG TIME.
>> Mike: THE PLAYOFF PICTURE
COMING INTO FOCUS.
THE RAIDERS PLAYING A TEAM THEY
BEAT SEVEN
>> Mike: THE RAIDERS HOSTING
KANSAS CITY.
THE LAST TIME THEY BEAT THE
KANSAS CITY CHIEFS, SEVEN WEEK
AGO.
THE HIGHLIGHTS ARE NOT UP TO NFL
STANDARDS.
CHIEFS, 17 YARDS OFFENSE IN THE
FIRST HALF.
BRADY QUINN, PICKED OFF BY
HANSEN.
THAT LED TO A JANIKOWSKI 50-YARD
FIELD GOAL.
6-0 RAIDERS.
THIRD QUARTER, McFADDEN, WITH
A 19-YARDER.
THAT LED TO JAP COW SKI'S FOURTH
FIELD GOAL OF THE GAME.
12-0 RAIDERS.
MIKE GOODSON, SPENDS AWAY FROM
ONE TACKLE.
SHAKE AND BAKES AROUND ANOTHER.
43 OF HIS 89 ON THE GROUND AND
THAT LED TO, YOU GUESSED IT,
ANOTHER FIELD GOAL.
15-0 RAIDERS.
BUT THE RAIDER DEFENSE DID SHUT
OUT THE CHIEFS.
SNAPPING A SIX-GAME SKID BEHIND
JANIKOWSKI'S FIVE FIELD GOALS,
15-0 THE FINAL.
>> ANDREW LUCK AND HIS COLDS
FIGHTING FOR A WILD CARD SPOT
AGAINST THE TEXANS.
THE SCOOP AND SCORE, 23 TEXANS.
THIS 61-YARDER TO HILL WASN'T
ENOUGH.
TOX WITH THE 29-17 VICTORY.
>> DENVER SEALED THE AFC WEST
DIVISION WEEKS AGO BUT HAS A
CHANCE FOR TOP SPOT.
FLACCO IS PICKED OFF.
GOES 98 YARDS, BUT MADE IT INTO
THE END ZONE.
PEYTON MANNING, THREW ONLY ONE
TOUCHDOWN PASS TO DECKER.
BRONCOS WITH THE NINE-GAME WIN
STREAK, TRAIL THE TEXANS BY ONE
GAME.
34-17 THE FINAL.
>>> THE PATRIOTS BEAT THE
49ers TONIGHT THEY'RE THE
SECOND SEED IN THE AFC BECAUSE
THEY OWN THE TIEBREAKER OVER
DENVER.
49ERS ARE THE SECOND SEED.
A LOSS TONIGHT THEY FALL BEHIND
GREEN BAY.
>> SEAHAWKS KEEPING THE PRESSURE
ON THE 49ers.
THEY BEAT THE BILLS.
RUSSELL WILSON RAP FOR THREE
T.D.s IN THE GAME AND THE
DEFENSE CAME UP BIG.
RYAN FITZPATRICK IS PICKED OFF.
GOES 57 YARDS.
NINERS TAKE A SEAHAWKS TEAM THAT
SCORED 10 POINTS, NEXT SUNDAY IN
SEATTLE.
THAT COULD DECIDE THE DECISION
AS THE SEAHAWKS WIN.
>> PACKERS ARE THE TEAM TO BEAT,
SHOWED WHY AGAINST THE GIANTS.
14-0 ATLANTA AFTER ONE QUARTER.
RYAN COULDN'T DO ANYTHING WRONG.
270 YARDS.
THREE T.D.s, TWO TO JONES.
THEY HANG ON TO THE TOP SPOT IN
NFC WITH THEIR SHUTOUT.
>> PACKERS AND BEARS, WHAT A
GAME FOR JAMES JONES.
THREE T.D. CATCHES ON FIVE
RECEPTIONS.
GREEN BAY CLINCHES THE NFC NORTH
FOR THE SECOND STRAIGHT SEASON.
IF THE 49ers LOSE, PACKERS
WILL PASS THEM FOR THE SECOND
SEED IN THE NFC.
21-13 THE FINAL.
>> PLAYOFF PICTURE STARTING TO
CLEAR UP.
WILD CARDS UP FOR GRAPH.
MORE AT
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>> Ama: COMING UP IN A HALF HOUR
AT 6:00, THE TOUCHING MEMORIAL
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, AND THE
SEARCH FOR ANSWERS.
LAURA ANTHONY IS THERE LIVE.
>> NEW DETAILS ABOUT THE DEADLY
ACCIDENT INVOLVING A BAY AREA
CHP OF.
JOIN US AT 6:00.
>>> A WORLD SERIES CHAMPIONSHIP
IS THE GIFT THAT KEEPS ON
GIVING.
THE FANS AND HOLIDAY SHOPPERS
TURNED OUT AT THE GIANTS TEAM
STORE FOR A MEMORABILIA TODAY.
IT INCLUDED EQUIPMENT, AND
UNIFORMS, AS WELL AS BANNERS.
THE PROCEEDS WILL BENEFIT THE
GIANTS COMMUNITY FUND.
THAT DOES IT FOR US AT 5:00.
Captioned by Closed Captioning
Services Inc.
>> THE ABC-7 NEWS EXCLUSIVE
ALARM CLOCK APPING AVAILABLE FOR
YOUR ANDROID AND YOUR iPHONE.
SEE YOU BACK AT 6:00.
>>> I'M DAVID MUIR.
THIS IIA
THIS IS A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"WORLD NEWS."
TONIGHT THE TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THIS EVENING THE PRESIDENT
TRAVELS TO NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
AS THE NATION MOURNS THE VICTIMS
AFTER THE DEADLIEST SHOOTING AT
AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN AMERICA.
THE 20 CHILDREN, THE LITTLE GIRL
AT THE PIANO WITH HER BROTHER,
SHE DID NOT SURVIVE.
♪ COME NOW ALMIGHTY KING
>> THE NEW DETAILS ABOUT THE
CHILDREN WHO DID ESCAPE.
THE CHILDREN FOUND HIDING WHEN
POLICE ARRIVED.
THE EXTRAORDINARY INSTINCTS OF
ONE LITTLE GIRL, THE ONLY ONE TO
SURVIVE IN HER CLASS.
>> AND THE FIRST WORDS SHE SAID