>> THIS MORNING WE REMEMBER
THOSE LOST.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM, BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS.
>> AND ASK WHY.
>> THIS WAS NOT GOD'S PLAN.
THIS WAS A MAN WHO HAS SERIOUS
ISSUES IN HIS LIFE.
>> AND NOW AS AMERICA GRIEVES,
HOW SHOULD OUR LEADERS RESPOND?
WHAT CAN ALL OF US DO TO STOP
THIS SENSELESS VIOLENCE?
>> WE WILL FIND A WAY TO HEAL.
>> WE'LL GET TO THE HEART OF
THOSE QUESTIONS RIGHT NOW.
>> Announcer: FROM ABC NEWS,
THIS IS A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"THIS WEEK" WITH GEORGE
STEPHANOPOULOS.
"TRAGEDY AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL."
REPORTING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, GEORGE
STEPHANOPOULOS.
>>> AND GOOD MORNING FROM THE
LIBRARY AT NEWTOWN MIDDLE
SCHOOL.
THIS IS WHERE THE 20 CHILDREN
KILLED AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
WOULD HAVE CONTINUED TO LEARN
AND GROW.
JUST DOWN THE ROAD FROM NEWTOWN
HIGH SCHOOL WHERE PRESIDENT
OBAMA WILL COME TONIGHT TO
COMFORT THE FAMILIES, THANK THE
FIRST RESPONDERS AND CONSOLE THE
COMMUNITY STILL IN SHOCK.
THE HEARTBREAK HERE IS MAGNIFIED
BY THE AGE OF ALMOST ALL THE
VICTIMS, LITTLE CHILDREN, 6 AND
7 YEARS OLD, ALL IN JUST THE
FIRST GRADE.
OVERNIGHT THE SHOOTER'S FATHER,
PETER LANZA, RELEASED HIS FIRST
PUBLIC STATEMENT.
"WE ARE IN A STATE OF DISBELIEF
AND TRYING TO FIND WHATEVER
ANSWERS WE CAN.
WE TOO ARE ASKING WHY."
AND THIS MORNING AMERICA IS
HONORING THE VICTIMS.
TODAY EVERY NFL TEAM WILL
OBSERVE A MOMENT OF SILENCE
BEFORE THE GAMES.
THE GIANTS AND PATRIOTS WILL
WEAR SPECIAL DECALS ON THEIR
HELMETS.
OUR GUESTS AND EXPERTS ARE
STANDING BY FOR A CONVERSATION
ON WHAT HAPPENED AND WHY TO CUSS
WHAT IT MEANS TO
TAKE MEANINGFUL ACTION,
THAT'S PRESIDENT OBAMA'S PHRASE
AND A SHATTERING MOMENT OF
MINDLESSNESS.
>>> THE LATEST ON THE
INVESTIGATION, BRIAN ROSS OUR
CHIEF INVESTIGATIVE
CORRESPONDENT AND, BRIAN,
INVESTIGATORS ARE BEGINNING TO
PIECE TOGETHER WHAT HAPPENED IN
THAT TERRIFYING TEN MINUTES IN
THE SCHOOL.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, GEORGE, THEY
SAY THEY ARE MAKING GOOD
PROGRESS IN KNOWING MUCH OF THE
HOW, ALTHOUGH LESS OF THE WHY OF
THE STUNNING CRIME.
IN PARTICULAR, THEY ARE FOCUSING
ON THE WEAPONS USED, THERE WERE
THREE WEAPONS RECOVERED, TWO
HANDGUNS AND A SEMIAUTOMATIC
ASSAULT-STYLE RIFLE THAT
AUTHORITIES BELIEVE WAS OWNED
ACTUALLY BY
ADAM LANZA'S MOTHER, NANCY.
HER FRIENDS SAY SHE WAS A GUN
ENTHUSIAST WHO BOUGHT THE
WEAPONS FOR SELF-DEFENSE WHEN
SHE WAS DIVORCED AND LIVED IN A
LARGE HOME BY HERSELF AND OFTEN
TOOK HER SONS, HER FRIENDS SAY,
TO A NEARBY FIRING RANGE FOR
TARGET PRACTICE.
>> SO THEY CONFIRM THAT THE
WEAPONS BELONGED TO HER, BUT
THERE HAD ALSO BEEN SOME
REPORTS, AT LEAST ONE IN THE
"L.A. TIMES" THAT THE SHOOTER
MAY HAVE TRIED TO BUY A WEAPON
RECENTLY.
>> OUR REPORTING DOESN'T CONFIRM
THAT, AND THE FACT IS IN
CONNECTICUT, THERE IS A WAITING
PERIOD TO BUY ANY WEAPON.
YOU NEED A PERMIT TO BUY A
HANDGUN, NOT A LONG RIFLE, BUT
EVEN SO THERE IS A WAITING
PERIOD, AND IF THERE WAS AN
ATTEMPT TO BUY ONE IN A SHORT
PERIOD OF TIME, THAT WOULDN'T
WORK.
>> THERE HAD ALSO BEEN SOME
INFORMATION EARLIER THAT THE
SHOOTER'S MOM MAY HAVE HAD SOME
CONNECTION TO SANDY HOOK, MAY
HAVE BEEN A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER
OR A VOLUNTEER THERE, BUT THE
SUPERINTENDENT HAS SAID THAT IS
NOT THE CASE.
DO WE HAVE ANY BETTER IDEA OF
WHY ADAM LANZA CHOSE THIS
SCHOOL?
>> WELL, THE SUPERINTENDENT HAS
SAID THAT THE MOTHER, NANCY
LANZA, DID NOT WORK THERE, SHE
WAS NOT A TEACHER, BUT HER
RELATIVES SAY SHE DID VOLUNTEER
AS A TEACHER'S AIDE AT SANDY
HOOK APPARENTLY AROUND THE SAME
TIME THAT ADAM WAS A STUDENT
THERE.
HE WAS A TROUBLED YOUNG MAN,
ACCORDING TO FRIENDS, AND
ACCORDING TO RELATIVES, NANCY
HAD MANY ISSUES WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT ABOUT HOW THEY WERE
TREATING HIM AND HANDLING HIS
PARTICULAR SPECIAL NEEDS, SO IT
MAY HAVE BEEN A SOURCE OF
CONFLICT, AND AT ONE POINT
ACCORDING TO THE AUNT OF ADAM,
THE MOTHER PULLED ADAM OUT OF
THE PUBLIC SCHOOL SYSTEM AND
HOME-SCHOOLED HIM BECAUSE OF HER
UNHAPPINESS WITH THE WAY HE
WAS BEING TREATED AT SCHOOL.
>> AND THE POLICE ALSO SPENT AN
AWFUL LOT OF TIME AT THE HOME
WHICH IS ALSO A CRIME SCENE FOR
WHERE THE MOTHER WAS MURDERED.
WHAT ELSE HAVE THEY BEEN ABLE TO
FIND INSIDE THAT HOME?
>> WELL, THEY SAY THEY HAVE MADE
GOOD PROGRESS FROM EVIDENCE
FOUND IN THE HOME UNSPECIFIED AS
TO THE WHY AND THE MOTIVE.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THAT MEANS
WE DON'T KNOW IF THERE WAS A
NOTE OR SOME SORT OF
A VIDEO, BUT THEY SAY THEY ARE
MAKING PROGRESS IN DETERMINING A
MOTIVE HERE THAT WAS INVOLVED IN
WHICH, YOU KNOW, HE STARTED THE
DAY BY SHOOTING HIS MOTHER AND
THEN DROVE ABOUT TEN MINUTES TO
THE SCHOOL.
SO HE HAD A VERY DETERMINED
MISSION IN HIS HEAD WHEN HE
STARTED THAT DAY FRIDAY.
>> I SAW ONE REPORT THAT THE
HARD DRIVE, THE HARD DRIVE OF
HIS COMPUTER AT HIS HOME HAD
BEEN BROKEN.
IS THAT TRUE?
>> WE HAVEN'T BEEN ABLE TO
CONFIRM THAT.
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF REPORTS.
THE POLICE SAY THEY'RE PURPOSELY
KEEPING A LOT OF THINGS CLOSE TO
THE VEST AS THEY PUT TOGETHER A
FULL PICTURE.
THE BEST INFORMATION REALLY
ABOUT ADAM AND HIS BACKGROUND
COMES FROM FORMER CLASSMATES WHO
ATTENDED SCHOOL WITH HIM AND SAY
HE WAS AWKWARD AND SOCIALLY VERY
ILL AT EASE
AROUND PEOPLE, DIDN'T LIKE TO BE
TALKED TO.
HE WAS A MEMBER OF
THE TECH CLUB AT HIS HIGH
SCHOOL.
FRIENDS SAY HE WAS
VERY BRIGHT, VERY SMART, BUT
WITHDRAWN.
>> BUT THE MYSTERY STILL WHY HE
DID THIS.
>> THAT REMAINS A SERIOUS
QUESTION.
THERE SEEMS TO BE SOME
CONNECTION, AT LEAST IN HIS
TWISTED WAY OF THINKING, THAT
PUT HIM ON THAT PATH, BUT IT'S
NOT CERTAIN YET JUST WHAT THAT
WAS, GEORGE.
>> OKAY, BRIAN ROSS, THANKS VERY
MUCH.
>>> AND AS WE SAID EARLIER, SO
MANY AMERICANS JOINING IN TO
HONOR AND REMEMBER THOSE LOST ON
FRIDAY AND THIS WHOLE COMMUNITY.
ON "SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE" LAST
NIGHT A CHILDREN'S CHOIR SANG
"SILENT NIGHT."
♪ SILENT NIGHT HOLY NIGHT
♪ ALL IS CALM ALL IS BRIGHT
>> AND HERE IN NEWTOWN A
CONTINUOUS VIGIL AS A COMMUNITY
CONTINUES TO COME TOGETHER IN
PRAYERS AND TEARS AND JUJU CHANG
IS AT ST. ROSE OF LIMA CHURCH
THIS MORNING.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING,
GEORGE.
THE SECOND MASS IS ALREADY UNDER
WAY AT ST. ROSE AND THE
OUTPOURING IS SO STAGGERING,
STATE TROOPERS HAVE TO CONTROL
THE FLOW.
PEOPLE ARE COMING TOGETHER TO
EXPRESS CONDOLENCES, COME
TOGETHER AS A COMMUNITY AND TO
PONDER THOSE QUESTIONS TO WHICH
THERE ARE NEVER EASY ANSWERS
LIKE HOW DOES A GUNMAN SLAUGHTER
SUCH INNOCENTS, ALL THIS WHILE
MORE PHOTOS, IMAGES ARE EMERGING
OF LIVES CUT SHORT, SNAPSHOTS,
IF YOU WILL.
20 CHILDREN WHO DIED IN THAT
THOSE 2 CLASSROOMS, ALL 6 OR 7,
AND OF THEM 9 LEFT BEHIND
SIBLINGS.
ROBBY PARKER SPOKE POIGNANTLY AT
ST. ROSE CHURCH ABOUT HIS
DAUGHTER EMILIE WHO LEFT BEHIND
TWO GRIEVING PARENTS AND TWO
LITTLE SISTERS.
>> SHE WAS AN EXCEPTIONAL ARTIST
AND ALWAYS CARRIED AROUND HER
MARKERS AND PENCILS SO SHE
NEVER MISSED AN OPPORTUNITY TO
DRAW A PICTURE OR MAKE A CARD
AND WAS A MENTOR TO HER TWO
LITTLE SISTERS AND DELIGHTED
IN TEACHING THEM TO READ, DANCE
AND THE SIMPLE PLEASURES IN
LIFE.
>> Reporter: OF THE SIX ADULTS
WHO DIED AT THAT SCHOOL, WE'RE
HEARING ABOUT ACTS OF HEROISM.
THE PRINCIPAL DIED AFTER
CONFRONTING THE GUNMAN AND
WE HEARD OF ONE TEACHER,
VICKI SOTO, WHO SHIELDED SOME OF
HER CHILDREN BY HIDING THEM IN A
CLOSET AND BY PROTECTING THE
OTHER CHILDREN LITERALLY WITH
HER BODY.
SHE LOST HER LIFE THAT DAY.
MONSIGNOR ROBERT WEISS IS
THE PRIEST HERE AND HAS BEEN
PLANNING MASSES FOR THE
CONGREGANTS.
WE LEARNED FROM CHURCH OFFICIALS
THERE WILL BE EIGHT FUNERALS
HERE FOR EIGHT CHILDREN, EIGHT
FAMILIES DEVASTATED BUT IT'S NOT
JUST THIS CHURCH, THERE ARE
HOUSES OF WORSHIP AROUND THIS
COMMUNITY THAT ARE COMFORTING
THOSE WHO HAVE LOST THEIR
INNOCENCE IN A WAY HERE.
THERE ARE MAKESHIFT MEMORIALS
POPPING UP NOT JUST WITH CANDLES
AND FLOWERS BUT CHILDLIKE
OBJECTS, A SOCCER BALL SIGNED BY
THE NEWTOWN SOCCER CLUB OR
LITTLE TEDDY BEARS THAT A 6 OR
7-YEAR-OLD WOULD TAKE TO BED OR
SIGNS THAT SAY HUG A TEACHER
TODAY OR SLEEP IN EVANLY PEACE.
THERE ARE FOUR MASSES PLANNED AT
THIS CHURCH AND ONE FINAL SAD
FOOTNOTE ON EACH AND EVERY
ONE OF THOSE AISLE THERE IS A
BOX OF KLEENEX WAITING FOR THE
OUTPOURING OF TEARS.
>> OKAY, JUJU, THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> MORE NOW FROM THE ELECTED
OFFICIALS I'M JOINED BY
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT, DAN
MALLOY.
I KNOW YOU HAVE BEEN GOING
AROUND THE CLOCK FROM THE VERY
BEGINNING OF THIS.
DOWN FROM HERE MEETING WITH
THOSE FAMILIES SHATTERED RIGHT
NOW DOWN TO THE FIREHOUSE.
>> YEAH, YOU KNOW, IT'S -- THOSE
OF US IN CONNECTICUT HAVE SEEN
THIS PLAY OUT IN OTHER STATES
AND OTHER NATIONS, AND WE ALWAYS
THANK GOD IT WASN'T IN OUR
COMMUNITY OR IN OUR STATE, AND
OBVIOUSLY WHEN SOMETHING LIKE
THIS HAPPENS, IT'S A GIGANTIC
SHOCK FOR EVERYONE.
WE HAVE SPOUSES HAVING BEEN
LOST, DAUGHTERS, SONS, THE
DAMAGE DONE TO THE COMMUNITY, AS
WELL AS OBVIOUSLY TO THOSE
FAMILIES IS PRETTY STAGGERING.
>> I KNOW YOU HAD TO TELL SOME
OF THE PARENTS THE
WORST POSSIBLE NEWS THAT THEIR
CHILD HAD DIED.
>> FRIDAY IT WAS CLEAR TO ME
THAT THERE WAS A RELUCTANCE TO
SPEAK TO THE FAMILIES, BUT IT
WAS ALSO CLEAR TO ME WE KNEW
EVERYTHING WE NEEDED TO KNOW AT
THAT POINT, SO IT FELL UPON MY
SHOULDERS TO INFORM THE FAMILY
OF WHAT HAD TRANSPIRED AND THAT
THEIR LOVED ONE WOULDN'T BE
JOINING THEM AGAIN, AND IT WAS A
TOUGH, TOUGH TIME.
>> WE ALSO -- AS JUJU JUST
REMINDED US -- ARE HEARING
STORIES OF REAL BRAVERY, THE
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOCHSPRUNG AND
THE PSYCHOLOGIST MARY SHERLACH
BOTH CHARGING.
>> IT'S AN EXTRAORDINARY SET OF
STORIES, WHAT HAPPENED.
OF THIS CRIME AND YET PEOPLE
DOING EVERYTHING IN THEIR POWER
TO PROTECT CHILDREN.
I SPENT A LOT OF TIME WITH THE
TEACHER SOTO'S DAD WHO ACTUALLY
WORKS --
>> VICKI SOTO.
>> YEAH, WORKS FOR THE STATE OF
CONNECTICUT, AND THERE WAS AS
THOSE DETAILS WERE BREAKING,
THERE WAS A SENSE OF PRIDE, BUT
OBVIOUSLY PROFOUND LOSS THAT SHE
TRIED TO SHIELD CHILDREN FROM
THE EFFECTS OF THOSE GUN ROUNDS.
>> WHAT MORE CAN THE STATE DO
FOR THIS COMMUNITY RIGHT NOW?
>> WE'RE DOING EVERYTHING WE
CAN, AND I'VE MADE IT PERFECTLY
CLEAR FROM THE MOMENT THAT WE
WERE NOTIFIED THAT WHATEVER
RESOURCES ARE NECESSARY, TO HELP
THE COMMUNITY RESTORE ITSELF AS
QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE INCLUDING
HELPING WITH THE SCHOOL
BUILDING, WORKING WITH OTHER
COMMUNITIES TO MAKE SURE THAT
THERE'S ENOUGH CLASSROOMS, THERE
WILL BE A GREAT NUMBER OF
FUNERALS.
WE HAVE ASSETS READY, STATE
TROOPERS, OTHER POLICE
DEPARTMENTS, ANYTHING THEY NEED,
QUITE FRANKLY.
I THINK THE FIRST HAS DONE A
TREMENDOUS JOB, THE POLICE CHIEF
IS PERFORMING AT HIGH STANDARDS,
A SMALL DEPARTMENT IN A SMALL
COMMUNITY.
THEY NEED HELP, AND WE'LL GIVE
IT.
>> YOU'RE HELPING, AS YOU JUST
SAID, THE POLICE CHIEF.
WHAT CAN YOU SHARE?
IT SEEMS LIKE THIS MAN HAD A
PRETTY COMMITTED PLAN.
>> HE SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL WAS LOCKED.
HE USED A WEAPON TO OPEN UP THE
GLASS AND THEN --
>> HE BLASTED RIGHT THROUGH IT.
>> WITH SEVERAL ROUNDS -- A
NUMBER OF ROUNDS.
HE DISCHARGED TO MAKE AN OPENING
AND THEN WENT THROUGH IT, WENT
TO THE FIRST CLASSROOM, AS YOU
KNOW, WENT TO THE SECOND
CLASSROOM.
WE SURMISE THAT IT WAS DURING
THE SECOND CLASSROOM EPISODE
THAT HE HEARD RESPONDERS COMING
AND APPARENTLY AT THAT DECIDED
TO TAKE HIS OWN LIFE.
>> AND THE RESPONSE WAS PRETTY
QUICK, WITHIN TEN MINUTES.
>> IT WAS TO THE BEST OF MY
KNOWLEDGE PRETTY QUICK FROM THE
TIME THAT THE CALL WAS MADE AND
THE CALL OF THE FIRST CALL WE
BELIEVE WAS MADE BY ONE OF THE
PEOPLE IN THE OFFICE THAT WAS
INJURED, BUT WILL RECOVER,
AND THEN OBVIOUSLY ADDITIONAL
CALLS WERE MADE AFTER THAT.
BUT, YOU KNOW, THIS SICK FELLOW,
YOU KNOW, CLEARLY MENTALLY ILL,
KILLED HIS MOTHER, PROCEEDED TO
GO ON AND KILL A GREAT NUMBER OF
PEOPLE.
>> YOU KNOW, I KNOW YOU'VE HAD
TO DEAL WITH EMOTIONAL ISSUES IN
YOUR OWN FAMILY, AND THERE'S
SOME STATISTICS I'VE SEEN,
CONNECTICUT'S MENTAL HEALTH
SYSTEM PROVIDES COVERAGE FOR
LESS THAN ONE IN FIVE
CONNECTICUT RESIDENTS.
IS THERE ANYTHING MORE THAT CAN
OR SHOULD BE DONE TO ADDRESS
THESE YOUNG MEN DRIVEN BY
DEMONS?
>> WELL, ACTUALLY, I'M NOT SURE
WHICH STATISTICS YOU'RE USING,
BUT WE HAVE ACTUALLY STARTED A
PROGRAM WELL AHEAD OF CHANGES TO
THE NATIONAL MEDICAID POLICY SO
WE ACTUALLY HAVE 83,000 PEOPLE
COVERED IN OUR STATE WHO
WOULDN'T BE COVERED IN ANY OTHER
STATE RIGHT NOW.
IT'S AN EXPENSIVE PROPOSITION,
AS YOU MIGHT IMAGINE.
WE ALSO DO PUT A GREAT DEAL OF
CREDENCE AND IMPORTANCE, I
SHOULD SAY, ON MENTAL HEALTH.
I THINK OUR COUNTRY NEEDS TO
STEP IT UP QUITE A BIT IN THAT
REGARD.
WE NEED TO REACH OUT TO FAMILIES
THAT ARE IN CRISIS, AND IT
APPEARS THAT THERE WAS A CRISIS
IN THIS FAMILY.
THEY NEED TO KNOW THERE WERE
RESOURCES.
HAVING SAID THAT ALL,
THE FAMILY HAD THE RESOURCES
PERSONALLY TO HANDLE THE
SITUATION BY ALL APPEARANCES.
BUT, YOU KNOW, THESE ARE
DIFFICULT ISSUES.
I THINK OUR NATION NEEDS TO TAKE
A VERY DIFFERENT APPROACH TO
MENTAL HEALTH, AND WE NEED TO
SPEAK ABOUT IT MORE HONESTLY
JUST AS WE NEED TO DO OTHER
THINGS.
>> AND, FINALLY, PRESIDENT OBAMA
COMING TO NEWTOWN TONIGHT.
WHAT DOES THE COMMUNITY HERE
WANT TO HEAR FROM HIM?
>> WELL, I THINK AN
EXPRESSION BY THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES THAT HE
UNDERSTANDS THE DIFFICULTY THAT
THIS COMMUNITY IS GOING THROUGH
IS, I THINK, GREATLY APPRECIATED
BY THE COMMUNITY.
I THINK WHAT MOTIVATES THE
PRESIDENT IS HIS DESIRE TO TOUCH
THE FAMILY MEMBERS WHO WANT TO
HAVE THAT CONVERSATION, WHO WANT
TO BE ASSURED THAT THE PRESIDENT
OF THE UNITED STATES UNDERSTANDS
THAT THE PAIN THAT THEY'RE
SUFFERING FROM, AND I SUPPOSE
THAT THERE WILL BE QUESTIONS IN
THAT SESSION WITH THOSE PARENTS
OR THOSE SIBLINGS, BUT A LEVEL
OF REASSURANCE THAT THEY'LL GET
FROM THE VERY HIGHEST OFFICE IN
OUR NATION.
>> GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY, THANK
YOU VERY MUCH.
>> THANK YOU.
>>> LET ME TURN NOW TO SENATOR
RICHARD BLUMENTHAL AND ALSO --
SENATOR-ELECT AND
CONGRESSMAN CHRIS MURPHY HERE
WITH US.
SENATOR BLUMENTHAL, YOU SPENT
LAST OF THE 48 HOURS HERE.
>> I SPENT A GOOD PART OF THE
LAST TWO DAYS IN THIS COMMUNITY
AND I MUST, FIRST OF ALL, GIVE
ME THANKS TO THE GOVERNOR FOR
HIS STRENGTH AND
DETERMINATION BUT ALSO TO THE
COMMUNITY WHICH HAS REALLY COME
TOGETHER AND DEMONSTRATED A KIND
OF FIBER AND FAITH THAT IS
REMARKABLE.
I SPENT TIME IN THIS COMMUNITY
BEFORE AND ALWAYS BEEN IMPRESSED
BY THE REAL LINKS AND BONDS, THE
PEOPLE YOU KNOW AND THE
AMBULANCE AND
FIRE DEPARTMENT ARE LARGELY
VOLUNTEER, SO THAT MANY OF THE
HEROIC STORIES HERE ARE ABOUT
VOLUNTEERS COMING FORWARD AND
TRYING TO DEAL WITH THIS
SEARING, ALMOST UNBEARABLE PAIN
THAT SO MANY FEEL KNOWING THE
FAMILIES, KNOWING THE VICTIMS
AND, OF COURSE, AS A PARENT
MYSELF, FOUR CHILDREN, I CAN
REALLY HAVE SOME SENSE OF WHAT
THEY ARE GOING THROUGH.
>> AND, CONGRESSMAN, THIS IS IN
YOUR DISTRICT.
YOU'VE BEEN REPRESENTING IT FOR
MANY YEARS AND I'VE SEEN THIS IN
THE LAST COUPLE OF DAYS.
THIS IS A COMMUNITY THAT IS
TIGHTLY TIED TOGETHER TALKING TO
MONSIGNOR WEISS.
HE HAD BAPTIZED MANY OF T
CHILDREN IN THAT TOWN.
>> YOU WANT TO TALK ABOUT
NEWTOWN.
LABOR DAY PARADE THAT'S THE
PRIDE OF THIS COMMUNITY THAT
RUNS THROUGH MAIN STREET EVERY
YEAR, AND EVERY SINGLE SCHOOL
AND COMMUNITY GROUP PLANS THE
ENTIRE YEAR TO BE PART OF THAT
CELEBRATION OF AMERICA.
IT'S A SMALL TOWN, A VERY
TIGHTLY-KNIT TOWN, A TOWN THAT
GRIEVES PROBABLY A LITTLE DEEPER
BECAUSE OF THIS INCIDENT,
BECAUSE OF EVERYONE THAT WAS
TAKEN WAS WITHIN A FEW SQUARE
MILES OF EACH OTHER.
IT WILL BE MORE DIFFICULT BUT A
TOWN THAT CAN BE REBUILD BECAUSE
ITS FAITH IS SO STRONG AND
BECAUSE ITS TIES TO EACH OTHER
ARE SO STRONG.
THERE HAVE BEEN MIRACLES THAT
HAPPENED EVERY DAY SINCE THE
TRAGEDY HIT AND POINTS THE WAY
TOWARDS THE WAY BECAUSE OF
NEWTOWN BECAUSE OF ITS
CLOSE-KNIT STRUCTURE CAN HEAL.
>> THE SCHOOLS HERE WILL BE
CLOSED TOMORROW.
WHAT IS THE STEP-BY-STEP PROCESS
GOING FORWARD AFTER THAT?
>> WELL, I THINK THAT'S GOING TO
BE A CONSULTATION WITH THE FIRST
SELECT WOMAN AND THE BOARD OF
EDUCATION.
I THINK IT'S IMPORTANT FOR
STUDENTS AND FOR FACULTY TO BE
ABLE TO PROCESS THIS TOGETHER,
AND SO I THINK THERE IS A NEED
FOR THIS COMMUNITY TO GET BACK
TO SOME SEMBLANCE OF A SCHEDULE.
BUT EACH INDIVIDUAL FACULTY
MEMBER AND EACH INDIVIDUAL
STUDENT, FAMILIES WILL TAKE
THEIR OWN TIME SO I THINK WE ARE
STILL 48 HOURS OUT
FROM THIS INCIDENT
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT HOW TO
THINK ABOUT IT, NEVER MIND THE
STEP-BY-STEP PROCESS OF GRIEVING
AND RECONSTRUCTING THE
COMMUNITY.
IT WILL TAKE A WHILE.
>> SENATOR, I KNOW THAT YOU AS
WE MOVE ON WANT TO BEGIN A
CONVERSATION IN THE SENATE ABOUT
HOW THE COUNTRY CAN COME
TOGETHER TO ADDRESS THIS
VIOLENCE.
>> YOU KNOW, I COME TO THIS
ISSUE WITH A BACKGROUND OF
ALMOST 30 YEARS IN LAW
ENFORCEMENT, BOTH CRIMINAL --
>> ATTORNEY GENERAL.
>> -- AND CIVIL,
AS A UNITED STATES ATTORNEY AND
CHIEF FEDERAL PROSECUTOR AND 20
YEARS AS ATTORNEY GENERAL,
AND I'M HEARING FROM THE
COMMUNITY, AS WELL AS MY
COLLEAGUES IN LAW ENFORCEMENT,
WE NEED TO DO SOMETHING, AND I'M
HEARING FROM MY COLLEAGUES IN
THE SENATE AROUND THE COUNTRY,
SOME IN STATES LIKE WISCONSIN
AND COLORADO WHERE THERE HAVE
BEEN SIMILAR HORRIFIC, HORRIBLE
TRAGEDIES, MAYBE NOT INVOLVING
CHILDREN WITH THIS KIND
OF INCOMPREHENSIBLE
KIND OF CIRCUMSTANCE, BUT WE
NEED TO DO SOMETHING
AT THE VERY LEAST PERHAPS ABOUT
THE HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES THAT
WERE USED IN THIS CRIME BUT, OF
COURSE, THE INVESTIGATION HERE
IS CONTINUING, AND WE'LL LEARN
MORE, AND OUT OF RESPECT TO THE
FAMILIES AND THEIR GRIEF, AT
THIS POINT I'M NOT GOING TO BE
MORE SPECIFIC ABOUT THAT
CONVERSATION, BUT CERTAINLY THIS
HORRIBLE EPISODE AND INCIDENT
AND CRIME BY THIS DERANGED
PERSON POSSESSED BY DEMONS, AS
YOU HAVE PUT IT, WILL SPUR AND I
THINK TRANSFORM THE NATIONAL
CONVERSATION AND I INTEND TO
TALK ABOUT IT ON THE FLOOR OF
THE UNITED STATES SENATE PERHAPS
AS EARLY AS THIS WEEK.
>> CONGRESSMAN, DO YOU THINK
THIS CAN BE A TIPPING POINT?
>> WELL, I THINK THE TIPPING
POINT SHOULD HAVE HAPPENED A
LONG TIME AGO, FRANKLY, AND AS I
THINK EAGER AS PEOPLE ARE GOING
TO BE TO FIND SOME SIMPLE
SOLUTION FROM A POLICY
STANDPOINT, WE HAVE TO
ACKNOWLEDGE THERE IS NO SIMPLE
SOLUTION AND, YES, THERE HAS TO
BE A CONVERSATION ABOUT GUN
CONTROL BUT THE WAY WE TREAT
MENTAL ILLNESS AND
THE CULTURE OF
VIOLENCE IN THIS COUNTRY
THAT MAY HAVE CONTRIBUTED TO THE
WAY IN WHICH THIS
DISTURBED MAN THOUGHT.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A VERY
COMPLICATED PROCESS OF ASKING
WHY.
WE ALSO HAVE TO ADMIT IT'S GOING
TO BE A VERY COMPLICATED PROCESS
OF HEARING WHAT TO DO FROM HERE.
WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT IT.
THE TIME FOR SAYING WE CAN'T
TALK ABOUT THE IMPLICATIONS OF
THIS TRAGEDY IS NOT OVER.
WELL, WE'LL GRIEVE AND MAKE SURE
THE FAMILIES HAVE EVERYTHING
THEY NEED, WE'RE GOING TO BE ON
THE FLOOR OF THE SENATE TO TALK
ABOUT WHAT'S TO GO ON FROM HERE.
>> WE'RE ALL GRIEVING WITH YOU
TODAY.
THANK YOU.
WHEN WE COME BACK,
MORE COVERAGE OF THE TRAGEDY AT
SANDY HOOK.
HOW CAN WE MAKE OUR SCHOOLS MORE
SECURE, KEEP OUR KIDS SAFE?
BACK WITH MORE OF THIS SPECIAL
EDITION OF "THIS WEEK."
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
NAVIGATING YOUR FUTURE
CAN BE DAUNTING
WITHOUT A FINANCIAL PLAN.
YOUR PLAN SHOULD BE BUILT
TO YOUR SPECIFIC NEEDS
SO THAT IT LASTS THROUGH
EVERY STAGE OF YOUR LIFE.
♪
AT PACIFIC LIFE,
WE CAN GIVE YOU THE TOOLS
TO HELP YOU ACHIEVE
FINANCIAL INDEPENDENCE.
♪
TOOLS THAT HELP YOU
PROTECT YOUR FAMILY,
SUPPLEMENT YOUR RETIREMENT,
BUILD YOUR BUSINESS,
AND PLAN YOUR LEGACY.
♪
FOR MORE THAN 140 YEARS,
PACIFIC LIFE HAS ASSISTED
FAMILIES AND BUSINESSES
IN MEETING THEIR GOALS,
EVEN IN UNCERTAIN
ECONOMIC TIMES.
♪
LET US HELP PROTECT THE THINGS
THAT YOU WORK SO HARD FOR.
TO FIND OUT HOW,
VISIT PACIFICLIFE.COM.
♪
PACIFIC LIFE.
THE POWER TO HELP YOU SUCCEED.
>>> AND WE ARE BACK AT NEWTOWN
MIDDLE SCHOOL FOR THE SPECIAL
EDITION OF "THIS WEEK" AND
JOINED BY OUR CHIEF JUSTICE
CORRESPONDENT PIERRE
THOMAS AND MAYOR SEGARRA.
WE WANT TO TALK MORE ABOUT THE
LAW ENFORCEMENT ASPECTS OF THIS,
AND, PIERRE, FOUR MONTHS AGO,
AUGUST, COMING OUT OF AURORA,
YOU SAID WE WOULD BE HERE AGAIN.
ALL TOO SOON.
>> DIDN'T MEAN TO BE PROPHETIC
BUT THESE ARE THE FACTS.
IN THIS COUNTRY WE HAVE A LOVE
AFFAIR WITH GUNS.
THEY ARE SOLD COMMERCIALLY.
IN FACT, THE FBI DID BACKGROUND
CHECKS ON BLACK FRIDAY TO
SUNDAY, THE FRIDAY AFTER
THANKSGIVING, AND THERE WERE
154,000 GUN CHECKS ON THAT DAY
ALONE.
AND, IN FACT, IN NOVEMBER FOR
THE MONTH OF NOVEMBER, AMERICANS
ATTEMPTED TO BUY 2 MILLION GUNS,
SO WHAT THAT MEANS IS THAT
PEOPLE WHO ARE HEADING TO THE
DARK SIDE, IF YOU WILL, HAVE
EASY ACCESS TO WEAPONS
EASY ACCESS TO WEAPONS AND
THIS IA A COMPLICATED SITUATION.
>> THE GUNS ARE EVERYWHERE.
WHAT PEOPLE WILL POINT OUT IS IN
THIS CASE THE SHOOTER DIDN'T
HAVE TO GO BUY A GUN.
THEY WERE RIGHT THERE IN THE
HOME.
>> WE HAVE INFORMATION THAT THE
MOM OR THE FAMILY HAD AT LEAST
FIVE WEAPONS READILY AVAILABLE
AND ASSAULT-STYLE RIFLES ARE
BOUGHT AND SOLD IN THIS COUNTRY
LIKE HANDGUNS, AND THE
PARTICULAR WEAPON WE BELIEVE WAS
USED IN THIS CRIME HAS THE
CAPACITY, THE ASSAULT-STYLE
RIFLE OF THIS WEAPON, TYPICALLY
CAN FIRE AND ALSO CAN HOLD UP TO
100 OR MORE ROUNDS AND CAN FIRE
THOSE BULLETS WITHIN SECONDS.
>> YOU'VE MADE THE POINT, THE
VOLUME OF THE GUN SALES MEANS
THE -- WE'RE BEYOND THE POINT OF
NO RETURN.
THERE ARE SO MANY GUNS OUT THERE
RIGHT NOW IN THE UNITED STATES.
>> TO USE THE CLICHE, THE GENIE
IS OUT OF THE BOTTLE.
200 MILLION GUNS PLUS IN
CIRCULATION.
IF YOU STOP SELLING THEM TODAY
THEY ARE NOT BIODEGRADABLE.
THEY'RE NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
YOU WOULD HAVE TO FIGURE OUT HOW
TO REMOVE THEM FROM THE STREETS.
THAT WOULD BE VERY DIFFICULT.
>> YOU HAVE WORKED ON THAT IN
THE CITY OF HARTFORD.
MAYOR, YOU'VE HAD SOME SUCCESS
BUYING THOSE GUNS BACK.
>> WE DID.
WE HAD A GUN BUYBACK PROGRAM A
COUPLE OF WEEKS AGO.
WE'RE A SMALL CITY OF 125,000.
IN LESS THAN THREE HOURS, ALMOST
ONE WEAPON PER MINUTE WAS TURNED
IN, SO THERE IS A DESIRE
ON BEHALF OF THE COMMUNITY TO
TURN THESE WEAPONS BACK IN,
ALTHOUGH I DON'T KNOW HOW MUCH
OF THOSE EFFORTS COULD LEAD TO
PREVENTING SOMETHING SIMILAR
FROM HAPPENING TO WHAT HAPPENED
IN NEWTOWN, BUT THERE IS A NEED
TO HAVE SOME FOCUS ON USING A
SYSTEMS APPROACH BECAUSE THERE
ARE DIFFERENT SYSTEMS THAT COME
IN PLAY HERE IN TERMS OF MENTAL
HEALTH SYSTEMS, BUT WE HAVE BEEN
EFFECTIVE AND JUST ALSO BY
WORKING THROUGH OUR SHOOTING
TASK FORCE AND OTHER PROGRAMS
WE'VE HAD TO TRY TO LIMIT THE
NUMBER OF SHOOTINGS, BUT THIS IS
CALL, A WAKE-UP CALL IN ADDITION
TO THE THINGS HAPPENING AND IF
THIS CRISIS, THIS HORE FINK
INCIDENT DOES NOT SEND A MESSAGE
THAT SOME STRONGER AND IMMEDIATE
ACTION NEEDS TO HAPPEN IN OUR
COUNTRY, I DON'T KNOW WHAT WILL.
>> YOU JOINED A COALITION OF
MAYORS WHO HAVE CALLED FOR MORE
ACTION.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID IT'S TIME
ON FRIDAY FOR MEANINGFUL ACTION.
WHAT SPECIFICALLY WOULD YOU LIKE
TO SEE?
>> FIRST OF ALL, I THINK THAT AS
SOON AS WE GET THROUGH THIS
PROCESS OF TRYING TO GET OUR
OR HELP OUR COMMUNITY, HAVE HAVE
MAYOR BLOOMBERG AND OUR
CONFERENCE CHAIR FROM
PHILADELPHIA, MAYOR NUTTER, COME
TOGETHER.
I MEAN WE ARE -- WE'RE THE
CLOSEST.
THE TOWNS AND CITIES ARE THE
CLOSEST TO HAVING DEAL WITH THE
EFFECTS OF THIS VIOLENCE, SO IT
SHOULD BE INCUMBENT UPON US TO
SOLIDIFY OURSELVES, TO BE A PORE
POWERFUL VOICE, TO BE MORE POWER
THAN WE'VE EVER BEEN TO COME
TOGETHER WITH A BAN ON
ASSAULT WEAPONS TO MAKE SURE WE
PUT THE PRESSURE ON AND REALLY
MEET THE CHALLENGE OF HOW DO YOU
BALANCE -- WHAT WE'RE ASKING FOR
IS SOME BALANCE.
WE DO RECOGNIZE OUR
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHT TO BEAR
ARMS, BUT I THINK THAT THIS HAS
GONE TO A POINT NOW TO AFFORD
SOME PEOPLE WITH THE ABILITY OF
CONDUCTING THESE MASS
EXTERMINATIONS IS JUST NOT
WHAT --
>> THIS HAS STRUCK HOME FOR YOU
PERSONALLY.
YOUR FATHER AND TWO FRIENDS, THE
VICTIMS OF GUN VIOLENCE.
>> MY FATHER WAS KILLED WHEN I
WAS A YEAR OLD.
I NEVER GOT TO MEET HIM.
I NEVER GOT TO KNOW WHAT IT IS
TO HAVE A FATHER, SO THIS HITS
VERY CLOSE, AND I ENDED UP IN
CONNECTICUT WHERE I LIVED IN THE
SOUTH BRONX WHERE MY TWO CLOSEST
FRIENDS WERE KILLED AS CHILDREN
THROUGH GUNS.
I FEEL STRONGLY ABOUT IT AND
EMOTIONALLY VESTED, BUT I
RECOGNIZE IT'LL HAVE TO TAKE A
GROUP OF VERY DEDICATED PEOPLE
TO WORKING TOGETHER BECAUSE WE
DO NEED TO TAP DIFFERENT SOCIAL
SYSTEMS.
I WORKED AS A PSYCHOTHERAPIST.
WHEN YOU GET PEOPLE THAT ARE
DISTRAUGHT INTO A CLINICAL
STUDY, IT DOESN'T TAKE VERY LONG
TO FIND OUT THAT THERE IS A
PROBLEM.
THE ISSUE BECOMES HOW DO WE
REACH OUT IN A WAY THAT
ELIMINATES THE POTENTIAL FOR
THESE FOLKS TO TO DO THIS DAMAGE
BY HAVING A WIDER NET.
>> MAYOR SEGARRA AND PIERRE
THOMAS, THANKS VERY MUCH.
>>> MUCH MORE OF OUR SPECIAL
EDITION OF "THIS WEEK" AHEAD.
OUR ROUNDTABLE JOINS US NEXT.
>>> THESE NEIGHBORHOODS ARE OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS, AND THESE
CHILDREN ARE OUR CHILDREN.
AND WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE
MEANINGFUL ANGST TO PREVENT
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS REGARDLESS
OF THE POLITICS.
>> IT'S NOT RIGHT TO TALK ABOUT
THIS YESTERDAY.
IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN A YEAR AGO.
IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN TWO YEARS
AGO.
IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN THREE YEARS
I'M GOING TO TAKE HIM AT HIS
WORD THAT WE WILL TRY TO DO
SOMETHING TO REDUCE GUN VIOLENCE
IN THIS COUNTRY, AND I'M WILLING
TO WORK WITH HIM ON WHAT THAT
WILL BE.
>> I THINK WE HAVE TO BE CAREFUL
ABOUT NEW -- SUGGESTING IT'S NEW
GUN LAWS.
I MEAN THERE'S -- YOU KNOW, WE
NEED TO LOOK AT WHAT DRIVES A
CRAZY PERSON TO DO THESE KINDS
OF ACTIONS AND MAKE SURE THAT
WE'RE ENFORCING THE LAWS THAT
ARE CURRENTLY ON THE BOOKS.
>> AND WE ARE BACK IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, FOR OUR SPECIAL
EDITION OF "THIS WEEK."
I AM JOINED ON OUR ROUNDTABLE BY
GEORGE WILL, DONNA BRAZILE, JOE
KLEIN OF "TIME" MAGAZINE AND
CONGRESSMAN JASON CHAFFETZ AND
CONGRESSWOMAN DONNA EDWARDS.
INTO FRIDAY AND SATURDAY, THERE
IS A DEPRESSING SAMENESS TO THE
CONVERSATION COMING OUT OF EACH
TRAGEDY.
>> YES, AND OUR RESPONSE IS
ALWAYS TO THINK IS THERE SOME
DEFECT IN THE SOCIAL SYSTEM OR
SOME PROMPTING IN THE SOCIAL
ATMOSPHERE THAT CAUSES THIS AND,
THEREFORE, WE ASSUME WE CAN
TAILOR A LAW TO CORRECT THE
DEFECT.
THE PROBLEM IS, THE LAW CAN DO
THREE THINGS.
IT CAN DETER WITH SEVERE
PUNISHMENTS.
OF COURSE, WE ALREADY HAVE
LOTS OF DETERRENTS AGAINST
MURDER AND IMPEDE THE ACCESSES
TO PUBLIC SPACES OR TO WEAPONS
OR, THIRD, THE LAW CAN MONITOR
AND IN SOME CASES CONFINE PEOPLE
WHO MEET THE PROFILE OF THESE
PEOPLE.
THE PROBLEM WITH THIS IS THESE
PEOPLE ARE DETERMINED, PSYCHOTIC
AND OFTEN SUICIDAL.
IT'S VERY DIFFICULT TO DETER
SOMEONE LIKE THAT OR IMPEDE, AND
THEN WHEN YOU COME TO THE
QUESTION OF MONITORING
CONFINING, YOU LOOK AT THE
PROFILE.
THESE ARE OFTEN MEN, YOUNG MEN,
YOUNG UNMARRIED MEN, YOUNG MEN
WHO ARE SOCIALLY AWKWARD AND
SOMETIMES YOUNG UNMARRIED
SOCIALLY AWKWARD MEN HAVE BEEN
DIAGNOSED OR EVEN PRESCRIBED
SOME KIND OF PSYCHOTROPIC
MEDICINE.
THE CIVIL LIBERTIES AND PRIVACY
ISSUES INVOLVED IN TRYING TO
MONITOR PEOPLE AND THIS NOT
INSIGNIFICANT COHORT WHO FIT
THAT PROFILE ARE INSEPARABLE.
>> YOU LAID SO MUCH ON THE
TABLE.
YOU ARE NODDING YOUR HEAD TO
PARTS OF IT.
>> ANGRY, ALIENATED,
DISCONNECTED FROM SOCIETY AT A
TIME WHEN WE'RE TALKING ABOUT
BUDGET CUTS.
TWO-THIRDS OF STATES HAVE CUT
SERVICES TO MENTAL HEALTH
AGENCIES.
$1,300 IS THE POLICY OF TREATING
ONE WITH MENTAL HEALTH
DISORDERS.
17,000 IS WHAT WE END UP PAYING
WHEN WE HAVE NO BEDS, AND
MEDICARE CANNOT FILL THE GAP.
GUN SAFETY LAWS IN THIS COUNTRY
ARE BROKEN, AND I WOULD HOPE
MEMBERS OF CONGRESS WOULD LIKE
AT COMMONSENSE STEPS THAT WE CAN
TAKE TO AT LEAST FIX THE
BACKGROUND OR AT LEAST KNOW WHEN
PEOPLE ARE BUYING GUNS, WHO THEY
ARE AND IF THEY HAVE A RECORD.
>> I WANT TO GO TO THE MEMBERS
IN JUST A MOMENT,
BUT, JOE, LET ME BRING IT TO
YOU.
ONE OF THE FIRST THINGS YOU'LL
HEAR IN THIS CASE IS THAT THE
BACKGROUND CHECK WASN'T EVEN
TRIPPED BECAUSE ALL THE GUNS
WERE IN THE HOME.
>> RIGHT, I MEAN I THINK THERE
ARE THINGS YOU -- THERE ARE
THINGS YOU COULD DO THAT WILL
LIMIT THESE INCIDENTS, NOTHING
THAT YOU CAN DO THAT WILL
TOTALLY ELIMINATE THEM.
THE STRIKING PIECE OF NEWS TO ME
TODAY WAS THAT THE MOTHER WAS
VERY ANGRY AT THE SCHOOL SYSTEM
FOR NOT GIVING HER THE SUPPORT
SHE NEEDED TO DEAL WITH HER SON.
RIGHT NOW ALL OVER THIS COUNTRY
THERE ARE PARENTS OF YOUNG MEN
WITH SEVERE PSYCHOLOGICAL
PROBLEMS WHO ARE SCARED TO DEATH
THAT THEIR KIDS ARE GOING TO GO
AND DO SOMETHING LIKE THIS TOO,
AND IN MANY CASES AFTER THEY
PASS THE AGE OF 18, THESE
PARENTS MAY WANT THE CHILDREN TO
BE IN, YOU KNOW, IN SOME KIND OF
A RESIDENTIAL SETTING, BUT THEY
DON'T HAVE THE POWER, THE LEGAL
POWER TO HAVE ANYTHING TO DO
WITH IT.
WE GOT RID OF MENTAL HOSPITALS
IN THIS COUNTRY 50 YEARS AGO,
AND THAT WAS A GOOD THING.
THEY WERE SUPPOSED TO BE
REPLACED BY MEDICATION AND BY
RESIDENTIAL SETTINGS LIKE
HALFWAY HOUSES, BUT NOBODY
WANTED TO HAVE HALFWAY HOUSES IN
THEIR NEIGHBORHOOD.
SO WE HAVE ABDICATED OUR
RESPONSIBILITY TO THE MENTALLY
ILL IN THIS COUNTRY AND TO THE
PARENTS OF THE MENTALLY ILL WHO
ARE SUFFERING RIGHT NOW.
>> GOVERNOR, WHAT IS THE
GOVERNMENT'S RESPONSIBILITY?
>> I WISH THERE WAS ONE THING WE
COULD DO TO MAKE SURE IT NEVER
EVER HAPPENS AGAIN AND GOD BLESS
THOSE FAMILIES DEALING WITH A
SITUATION.
I CAN'T EVEN IMAGINE BUT WE HAVE
TO DEAL WITH THE MENTAL HEALTH
ASPECT AND I THINK IT'S FAIR
GAME, AND WE SHOULD TALK ABOUT
THE INTERSECTION OF A LETHAL
WEAPON AS IT RELATES TO MENTAL
HEALTH.
ABSOLUTELY WE HAVE TO HAVE THAT
DISCUSSION IN THIS COUNTRY AND
ALSO HAVE TO DEAL WITH THE NEW
SOCIAL RAMIFICATIONS OF THE
BOMBARDMENT AND THE IMMEDIACY OF
SOCIAL INTERACTION BETWEEN
VIOLENCE, THE REALISM YOU FIND
IN GAMES AND MOVIES.
SOME PEOPLE, THE YOUNG PEOPLE AS
THEY'RE MAKING THIS TRANSITION
FROM THEIR TEEN YEARS INTO
ADULTHOOD AREN'T ABLE TO
MENTALLY MAKE THAT TRANSITION
AND THERE DOES NEED TO BE HELP
BUT WE'LL ALSO NEED TO LOOK TO
FAMILIES AND COMMUNITIES AND
CHURCHES.
IT'S NOT JUST A GOVERNMENT
SOLUTION.
>> BASED ON WHAT YOU SAID, THERE
HAVE BEEN SOME REPORTS,
CONGRESSWOMAN EDWARDS, THIS
YOUNG MAN, WAS HE PLAYING A LOT
OF THOSE VIOLENT VERY REALISTIC
GAMES?
>> YOU KNOW, I THINK THERE ARE
MULTIPLE THINGS WE HAVE TO DO
HERE AND USE THIS CIRCUMSTANCE,
THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN TO CREATE
BOTH POLICY SOLUTIONS BUT ALSO
CULTURAL SOLUTIONS.
I THINK THAT IT -- WELL, IT IS
TRUE.
WE HAVE TO REBUILD OR BUILD A
FABRIC FOR MENTAL HEALTH
SERVICES, ESPECIALLY FOR YOUNG
PEOPLE TO GIVE PARENTS THE
RESOURCES THAT THEY NEED AND
WRAP OUR HANDS AROUND IT THAT
THIS COMMUNITY WILL NEED
AND SURVIVING FAMILIES AND
CHILDREN.
BUT WE ALSO -- WE'VE GOT TO GET
THE GUNS.
I MEAN, WE JUST DO.
THERE WERE ASSAULT WEAPONS USED
HERE, WEAPONS THAT ARE USED BY
MILITARY AND LAW ENFORCEMENT,
AND IT SEEMS TO ME THAT THERE
CAN BE A BRIGHT LINE FOR
REMOVING THOSE KINDS OF WEAPONS.
THERE CAN BE A BRIGHT LINE FOR
BACKGROUND CHECKS THAT DON'T
JUST COVER 60% OF THE GUNS THAT
COME THROUGH GUN SHOWS AND
INDIVIDUAL SALES.
WE REGULATE CARS IN THAT RESPECT
KNOWING WHO TRANSFERS A CAR MORE
THAN WE KNOW WHO TRANSFERS A
WEAPON.
THERE ARE REAL THINGS THAT WE
CAN DO, AND WE HAVE AN
OBLIGATION, AND IF THIS DOESN'T
CALL US TO ACTION I DON'T KNOW
WHAT WILL.
>> THAT'S ONE OF THE QUESTIONS
WE WILL FIND AN ANSWER TOO
SOON, I SUPPOSE.
BUT, GEORGE, ON THAT, IT'S KIND
OF STRIKING,
YOU READ 24 HOURS AFTER THIS
THAT A VERY SIMILAR INCIDENT
HAPPENED IN CHINA.
A MAN IN AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WITH A KNIFE, NOT AN ASSAULT
WEAPON, ALMOST TWO DOZEN KIDS
INJURED BUT NOT KILLED.
>> IN 1996 A MAN WENT INTO A GYM
CLASS IN SCOTLAND, KILLED 16
5-YEAR-OLDS AND 6-YEAR-OLDS AND
THE TEACHER.
A FEW YEARS AGO IN NORWAY, A
YOUNG, DERANGED, YOUNG MAN
KILLED, WHAT, 69 PEOPLE ON AN
ISLAND, MOSTLY TEENAGERS.
CONNECTICUT HAS AMONG THE
TOUGHEST GUN LAWS IN THIS
COUNTRY.
DIDN'T HELP.
SCOTLAND AND NORWAY HAVE VERY
TOUGH GUN LAWS, DIDN'T HELP.
>> DIDN'T STOP BUT IT DOES
LESSEN THE OCCASION OF VIOLENCE,
DOESN'T IT?
>> SINCE COLUMBINE THERE HAVE
BEEN 181 OF THESE SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS.
>> REMEMBER, WE DID HAVE A BAN
ON ASSAULT WEAPONS.
WHEN WE PUT THE BAN IN PLACE
THESE INCIDENTS DIDN'T DECLINE
IN A MEASURABLE WAY.
AND WHEN WE TOOK THEM OFF
THEY DIDN'T INCREASE IN A
MEASURABLE WAY.
>> THERE WERE FIVE GUNS IN THE
HOUSE.
THE SHOOTER CHOSE TWO
SEMIAUTOMATIC PISTOLS AND ONE
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
HE DID NOT CHOOSE THE TWO DEER
HUNTING RIFLES.
IT SEEMS TO ME THAT THE
CONGRESSWOMAN IS ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT, THERE IS A BRIGHT LINE
HERE THAT WE SHOULD BE ABLE TO,
YOU KNOW, HUNT.
YOU KNOW, HUNTERS SHOULD BE ABLE
TO GO ABOUT THEIR SPORT, BUT
THERE'S NO NEED TO HUNT WITH A
SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLE.
THERE'S NONE.
>> CONGRESSMAN?
>> WELL, LOOK I'M A CONCEALED
CARRY PERMIT GUN HOLDER.
I HAVE A GLOCK .23.
I'M NOT THE PERSON YOU NEED TO
WORRY ABOUT AND THERE ARE
MILLIONS WHO DEAL WITH THIS
PROPERLY.
IT'S THEIR SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHT TO DO SO.
BUT WE HAVE TO LOOK AT THE
MENTAL HEALTH ACCESS.
>> IS THERE SUCH -- ANY KIND OF
WEAPON, ANY CAPACITY --
>> THERE ARE PROHIBITIONS -- GUN
RULES ARE VERY STRINGENT.
THERE IS A LOT OF CONJECTURE OUT
THERE THAT I DON'T THINK
NECESSARILY WOULD SOLVE THIS
PARTICULAR PROBLEM, AND I WANT
TO LOOK AT ANYTHING THAT WE
THINK WILL SOLVE ALL THE
PROBLEMS, BUT WE HAVE TO, I
THINK, LOOK AT THE MENTAL HEALTH
ASPECT.
>> WE DO HAVE TO LOOK AT THE
MENTAL HEALTH ASPECT, BUT THE
COMPLEX PROBLEMS REQUIRE COMPLEX
SOLUTIONS, AND IT ISN'T ONE
THING.
IT'S ALL OF THESE THINGS, AND
SOME PEOPLE WOULD LIKE TO
DEFLECT THE CONVERSATION ONLY TO
THE MENTAL HEALTH PROBLEMS THAT
ARE SEVERE
AND THAT WE NEED TO DEAL WITH
WITHOUT DEALING WITH THE REALITY
WE HAVE, A LOT OF WEAPONS OUT
THERE, AND PEOPLE HAVE ACCESS TO
THEM, AND WE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT
A WAY THAT WE CAN PROTECT OUR
CHILDREN IN THEIR KINDERGARTEN
AND FIRST GRADE CLASSROOMS.
>> I WANT TO BRING THIS TO DONNA
BRAZILE.
AND AS I DO THIS, DONNA, THE
POLITICS OF ALL THIS, GENERALLY
SHOW -- I WANT TO SHOW THIS PEW
SUPPORT, SUPPORT FOR GUN
CONTROL, GENERALLY DOESN'T GO UP
AFTER MAJOR SHOOTINGS, AFTER
AURORA AND GABBY GIFFORDS, IT
WENT DOWN, AND VIRGINIA TECH
WENT UP A LITTLE BACK IN 2007
AND THE PRESIDENT HAS BEEN
RELUCTANT TO TAKE THIS ON AND
YOU SAW HIM SAY IT'S TIME FOR
MEANINGFUL ACTION.
WHAT DO YOU EXPECT AND DO YOU
THINK NOW THAT THE PRESIDENT
WON'T FACE ELECTION AGAIN, HE
WILL ADDRESS THEM IN A DIFFERENT
WAY?
>> I HOPE SO BECAUSE THERE'S
EXPECTATIONS I THINK NOT JUST
FROM THE FAMILIES BUT OTHERS WHO
WOULD LIKE TO SEE THE PRESIDENT
TAKE SOME STEPS.
HE'S TALKED ABOUT IT BEFORE
AFTER AURORA WHERE HE SAID WE
NEED TIGHTER RESTRICTIONS ON
PEOPLE WHO HAVE MENTAL
DISABILITIES FOR HAVING GUNS AND
SPOKE AT THE NATIONAL URBAN
LEAGUE ABOUT THIS, BUT THERE'S A
TIME FOR THIS, AND HOPEFULLY
IT'S SOONER RATHER THAN LATER.
YOU KNOW, I'M A -- AS A
SOUTHERNER, I'M A BIG ADVOCATE
OF THE SECOND AMENDMENT AND GREW
UP WITH GUNS AND GREW UP WITH
PEOPLE WHO UNDERSTOOD HOW TO USE
THEM RESPONSIBLY.
I DID NOT GROW UP WITH PEOPLE
WITH ASSAULT RIFLES OR
SEMIAUTOMATIC GUNS.
I DO BELIEVE THAT WE HAD NEED A
CONVERSATION, A REAL
DEEP CONVERSATION AND THIS
SIMPLY CANNOT BE STOPPED SIMPLY
BECAUSE PEOPLE ARE AFRAID OF THE
POLITICS.
>> YOU ALSO GREW UP TO BE THE
CAMPAIGN MANAGER OF AL GORE WHO
LOST THE HOME STATE OF
TENNESSEE, THE MYTH IS AT LEAST
IN PART BECAUSE HE SUPPORTED GUN
CONTROL.
THIS IS A POLITICAL, NOT A
JURISPRUDENTIAL PROBLEM.
THE SECOND PART, THE HILLER CASE
CONCERNING AN ABSURDLY
RESTRICTIVE D.C. LAW IS REALLY
MUCH MORE PERMISSIVE THAN PEOPLE
REALIZE, AND I'M NOT SURE THERE
WOULD BE A SECOND AMENDMENT
IMPEDIMENT TO BANNING A CATEGORY
OF WEAPONS.
THERE WOULD BE A POLITICAL ONE.
>> 60,000 MURDERS SINCE
COLUMBINE.
>> AND THE LARGE CAPACITY OF
THESE WERE USED IN THESE WEAPONS
THAT ALLOWED THIS PERPETRATOR TO
GO INTO A SCHOOL AND EACH OF THE
VICTIMS SUFFERING MULTIPLE
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
THIS IS JUST NOT ACCEPTABLE.
>> THERE'S A -- YOU KNOW, I
THINK THAT WE CAN'T THINK ABOUT
THIS IN TERMS OF IRRADICATION.
THESE INCIDENTS ARE ALWAYS GOING
TO HAPPEN.
>> REDUCTION.
>> WE CAN THINK THE MENTAL
HEALTH PIECE IS OBVIOUSLY
IMPORTANT.
I THINK THERE IS A BRIGHT LINE
ON GUN CONTROL, AS WELL BUT
THERE'S A THIRD PIECE AND THAT
IS THE CELEBRATION OF VIOLENCE.
WE NOT ONLY HAVE A SECOND
AMENDMENT IN THE COUNTRY,
WE ALSO HAVE A
FIRST AMENDMENT THAT PROTECTS,
YOU KNOW, SYLVESTER STALLONE'S
RIGHT TO FIRE THOUSANDS OF
BULLETS IN ANY GIVEN MOVIE, BUT
I THINK THAT, YOU KNOW, THAT
WHAT WE NEED TO DO IN THIS
SOCIETY IS TREAT PEOPLE WHO
CREATE VIOLENT MOVIES AND
VIOLENT VIDEO GAMES WITH THE
SAME DEGREE OF RESPECT THAT WE
ACCORD PORNOGRAPHERS.
THEY NEED TO BE SHUNNED.
>> I NEED TO ADD TO THAT.
WE'RE GETTING A LOT OF RESPONSE
ON FACEBOOK ABOUT HOW ALL OF US
COVERED THIS AND IN THE MEDIA
AND THE WAY OF THESE SHOOTINGS.
SCOTT LARARCHE "MEDIA
SENSATIONALISM CONTRIBUTES MORE
TO THIS THAN GUNS.
IT'S ALWAYS THE PERSON WHO PULLS
THE TRIGGER, NOT THE GUN THAT
KILLS.
WE NEED TO STOP MAKING THESE
KILLERS FAMOUS.
>> BILL COTTON "STOP THE
WALL-TO-WALL COVERAGE.
WE TRIED TO TALK LESS ABOUT THE
KILLER BUT, CONGRESSMAN, THIS IS
SOMETHING, JOE BRINGS UP AND
THOSE VIEWERS BRING UP, AS WELL,
HOW DO WE TALK ABOUT THIS IN A
WAY THAT DOESN'T ENCOURAGE THE
CONTAGION?
>> I DON'T KNOW THAT THE NEWS
COVERAGE THAT I'VE SEEN IS
GLAMORIZING THE KILLER AS MUCH
AS ALLOWING THE REST OF THE
COUNTRY TO GRIEVE.
AS A PARENT WE ALL SHED A TEAR.
I DO AGREE WITH JOE THAT YOU PUT
VIOLENCE AND DEATH AND GORE IN A
MOVIE, YOU'RE NOT GOING TO GET
AN "R" RATING.
YOU DO SOMETHING ELSE, OKAY.
I GOT TO TELL YOU, I THINK THE
MOVIE RATINGS ARE TERRIBLY
MISLEADING WHEN IT COMES TO
VIOLENCE, DEATH, GORE AND
GLAMORIZING IT.
>> ALL OF THOSE THINGS ARE TRUE
BECAUSE WE DO HAVE A CULTURE
THAT CELEBRATES VIOLENCE, BUT IT
DOESN'T TAKE AWAY OUR
RESPONSIBILITY, AND I WANT TO
URGE AND CHALLENGE MY COLLEAGUES
TO WORK WITH ME TO WORK WITH
US ON THIS SO NO PARENT HAS TO
EXPERIENCE WHAT THESE PARENTS
AND FAMILIES DO IN NEWTOWN.
THE BRIGHT LIFE BETWEEN THOSE
WHO ARE HUNTERS AND SHOOTERS AND
OUTDOORS PEOPLE, BUT THEY DON'T
NEED AN ASSAULT RIFLE.
THEY DON'T NEED HIGH-CAPACITY
MAGAZINES THAT CREATE HAVOC AND
VICIOUSNESS AND DEATH AND WE CAN
DO THAT.
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
WE CAN DO THAT.
WE CAN CLOSE THAT UP, AND THEN
WE ALLOW OURSELVES TO HAVE -- TO
ENJOY THE SECOND AMENDMENT
RIGHTS THAT ARE SO IMPORTANT BUT
ALSO WE RESPECT HUMAN LIFE.
>> GEORGE, WHEN MY LITTLE
NEPHEWS LEFT NEW ORLEANS AFTER
KATRINA, I'LL NEVER FORGET WHAT
THEY SAID.
"AUNTIE, I DON'T HEAR GUNSHOTS
AT NIGHT."
TOO MANY OF OUR KIDS ARE
LIVING WITH GUNS.
THEY ARE LIVING WITH THE FEAR OF
VIOLENCE.
THEY ARE DYING SOMETIMES IN
THEIR HOMES, SOMETIMES WALKING
HOME FROM SCHOOLS AND WHILE THIS
TRAGEDY IS INCOMPREHENSIBLE, YOU
GOT TO UNDERSTAND THAT THERE ARE
TOO MANY OF OUR BABIES BEING
MURDERED EVERY DAY SENSELESS AND
THAT'S WHY WE NEED TO HAVE THIS
CONVERSATION.
>> WE'RE HAVING IT.
>> THE QUESTION IS WHAT TO DO
AND WHAT IS POSSIBLE TO DO.
>> WELL, WE OUGHT TO BRING IN
MAYOR RAHM EMANUEL OF CHICAGO.
CHICAGO IS IN AN EPIDEMIC OF
VIOLENCE WITH YOUNG, LARGELY
UNPARENTED, THAT IS, NO FATHER
IN THE HOME, ADOLESCENT MALES.
NOW, THAT'S A PROBLEM QUITE
SEPARATE FROM THIS.
ANOTHER THING THAT WE'RE GOING
TO DO AND MAKES ONE'S HEART
SINK, GEORGE, IS THIS,
WE'RE GOINT TO RATCHET UP THE
PUBLIC PLACES.
THEY'RE ALREADY BLIGHTED BY
THIS.
FOR GENERATIONS PEOPLE HAVE BEEN
USING THE WATER ON THE MALL TO
RUN LITTLE SAILING BOATS.
NOW THE GOVERNMENT IN ITS WISDOM
HAS BANNED REMOTE CONTROL LITTLE
BOATS ON THE MALL WATER IN
WASHINGTON BECAUSE IT SOMEHOW
REPRESENTS A SECURITY THREAT TO
THE COUNTRY.
WE HAVE TO BE A LITTLE BIT
REASONABLE, AND UNLESS WE
SURROUND OUR CITIZENRY WITH THE
QUITE FALSE IDEA THAT THIS IS AN
EXTREMELY DANGEROUS --
>> AND ON THAT POINT, JOE KLEIN,
PEOPLE SHOULD BE REMINDED.
PARENTS SHOULD BE REMINDED THAT
THE OVERWHELMING MAJORITY OF
SCHOOLS IN THIS COUNTRY ARE
SAFE.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
ALTHOUGH, YOU KNOW, I HAD THIS
CREEPY FEELING WALKING INTO THIS
SCHOOL THIS MORNING THAT I
WASN'T IN A PLACE OF SAFETY IN
THIS TOWN.
>> EVEN THOUGHT THERE WAS NO
RATIONAL --
>> IT WAS A COMPLETELY
IRRATIONAL THOUGHT, AND WHEN I
SAY THAT I THINK ABOUT ALL THE
CHILDREN WHO ARE GOING TO BE
WALKING INTO SCHOOLS TOMORROW.
>> AND THAT GIVES US A PLACE WE
HAVE TO STOP BECAUSE WE WANT TO
TALK ABOUT THAT WITH DR. RICHARD
BESSER WHEN WE COME BACK.
>> THIS WAS NOT GOD'S PLAN.
THIS WAS A MAN WITH SERIOUS
ISSUES IN HIS LIFE.
WHY HE'D WANT TO DESTROY
INNOCENT CHILDREN, NO ONE CAN
FIGURE OUT.
>> WE'RE GRIEVING WITH YOU.
>> I APPRECIATE IT.
I'M SO TIRED.
IT'S JUST BRUTAL.
SAME SO TIRED.
(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
>> THIS WAS NOT GOD'S PLAN.
IT'S JUST BRUTAL.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
>>> AND NOW AS THE NATION MOURNS
THOSE LOST HERE IN NEWTOWN, WE
ALSO HONOR OUR FELLOW AMERICANS
WHO SERVE AND SACRIFICE.
THIS WEEK THE PENTAGON RELEASED
THE NAMES OF FIVE SERVICE
MEMBERS KILLED IN AFGHANISTAN.
>> AND WE'LL CONTINUE WITH OUR
SPECIAL EDITION OF "THIS WEEK"
FROM NEWTOWN.
>> THE SHE GAVE US AN EXAMPLE
THAT SHE SHOWED US IS
REMARKABLE.
SHE IS AN INCREDIBLE PERSON, AND
I'M SO BLESSED TO BE HER DAD.
But when I was in an accident...
I was worried the
health care system
spoke a language all its own
With UnitedHealthcare,
I got help that fit my life.
Information on my phone.
Connection to doctors who
get where I'm from.
And tools to estimate what
my care may cost.
So I never missed a beat.
We're more than 78,000
people looking out for
more than 70
million Americans.
That's health in numbers.
UnitedHealthcare.
♪
>>> MAY THEY ALL REST IN PEACE.
SO HARD TO SEE THE AGE OF THOSE
VICTIMS.
WE'RE GOING TO TALK NOW MORE
ABOUT HOW
THIS COMMUNITY HERE CAN COPE
BACK WITH CONGRESSWOMAN-ELECT
ESTY, DR. RICHARD BESSER AND
FATHER WILLIAM HAMILTON
FOR THE FIRST RESPONDERS.
LET'S START WITH DR. BESSER.
THIS SCHOOL TOMORROW WILL BE
CLOSED, BUT EVERYBODY COMING
BACK ON TUESDAY.
HOW DO THE PARENTS AND THE
TEACHERS TALK TO THE KIDS HERE
AND THEN MORE GENERALLY, PARENTS
AT HOME?
>> RIGHT, YOU KNOW, TALKING TO
KID, IT DEPENDS SO MUCH ON THEIR
AGE, THEIR LEVEL OF DEVELOPMENT
AND KNOWING YOUR OWN CHILD.
VERY YOUNG CHILDREN WHO WEREN'T
IN THIS COMMUNITY, YOU WANT TO
SHIELD THEM FROM THIS, BUT IN
THIS COMMUNITY, WHEN YOU TALK
ABOUT REBUILDING AND MOVING
FORWARD, SCHOOLS PLAY AN
ABSOLUTELY CRITICAL ROLE.
IT ALLOWS CHILDREN TO NORMALIZE
THEIR LIFE.
THEY'RE GETTING BACK INTO THEIR
ROUTINE.
IT ALSO PROVIDES A VERY SAFE
PLACE FOR CHILDREN TO TALK ABOUT
WHAT THEY'RE EXPERIENCING, WHAT
THEY'RE FEELING, AND TEACHERS
AND ADMINISTRATORS WHO ARE WELL
TRAINED, AND THEY'RE GETTING
TRAINING HERE WILL BE ABLE TO
IDENTIFY KIDS RIGHT NOW, BUT
ALSO GOING FORWARD, WHO ARE NOT
COPING WELL, SO THEY CAN GET
THIS SPECIALIZED SERVICE THAT
WILL HELP PREVENT LONG-TERM
PROBLEMS.
>> AND, CONGRESSWOMAN, WHAT MORE
ARE YOU HEARING FROM THE PEOPLE
IN THE COMMUNITY, THIS IS YOUR
COMMUNITY, ABOUT WHAT THEY NEED,
WHAT THEY WANT RIGHT NOW?
>> WELL, THEY WANT TIME TO HEAL
AND TIME TO GRIEVE.
I WAS -- I'M A MOTHER OF THREE
CHILDREN, AND I WAS A ROOM
PARENT IN A FIRST GRADE
CLASSROOM, AND I JUST CAN'T
IMAGINE THE GRIEF THEY'RE GOING
THROUGH RIGHT NOW, BUT IN
MEETINGS YESTERDAY WITH THE
WONDERFUL FIRST SELECT WOMAN,
ALSO A MOTHER HERSELF, PAT
LLODRA, THERE IS A LOT OF FOCUS
ON WHAT THE DOCTOR WAS REFERRING
TO, SUPPORTING AND KEEPING THESE
CHILDREN TOGETHER, KEEPING THEM
WITH THEIR TEACHERS, ALLOWING
THIS COMMUNITY TO GRIEVE
TOGETHER.
THE DEPTH OF THEIR GRIEF IS A
REFLECTION OF THE DEPTH OF THE
LOVE THIS COMMUNITY HAS.
IT'S A VERY SPECIAL PLACE, AND I
THINK IT'S IMPORTANT FOR PEOPLE
TO REALIZE THAT ABOUT NEWTOWN.
>> AND BUT YOU MADE THIS POINT
YESTERDAY, RICH, YOU HAVE TO
ALSO BE CAREFUL WITH THESE KIDS
THAT THEY DON'T SOMEHOW DEFINE
THEMSELVES BY THIS TRAGEDY.
>> THAT'S SO VERY IMPORTANT.
THERE ARE PHASES, AND WE'RE SO
EARLY IN THIS, BUT YOU DON'T
WANT THESE CHILDREN TO BECOME
TRAGEDY CELEBRITIES.
YOU DON'T WANT IT TO BE AS THEY
GREW UP WHAT THEY'RE KNOWN FOR.
THEY NEED TO BE KNOWN FOR HOW
THEY PLAY SOCCER OR HOW THEY
STUDY IN CLASS OR WHAT THEY DID
FOR SOMEONE IN THEIR COMMUNITY.
BUT IF YOU'RE NOT CAREFUL, THIS
CAN BE THE DEFINING THING IN
THEIR LIFE.
>> AND, FATHER, SO OFTEN
FORGOTTEN, THE TOLL THIS TAKES
ON THOSE WHO COME TO SAVE, THOSE
WHO COME TO HELP,
THE FIRST RESPONDERS,
AND THAT IS YOUR JOB TO COUNSEL
THEM.
>> EXACTLY, THE FIRST
RESPONDERS ARE MEMBERS OF PUBLIC
SAFETY.
THEY DO TREMENDOUS WORK FOR US
AND YET THEY'RE A PARENT AS
WELL, THEY HAVE CHILDREN.
THEY'RE SEEING THIS AND MOST OF
THE TIME THEY'RE RESPONDING TO
CRIMINAL ACTIVITY OF PEOPLE WHO
MAY BE LIFELONG CRIMINALS.
NOW WE'RE DEALING WITH THE
INNOCENCE OF A COMMUNITY OF ITS
CHILDREN, OF ITS FUTURE.
AND SO AS A RESULT, THEY'RE
RESPONDING TO PEOPLE THAT THEY
KNOW, PEOPLE THAT THEY LIVE IN
THE COMMUNITY WITH, THAT THEY
SHARE WITH.
>> I WOULD IMAGINE ALSO
THAT'S -- THEY RESPOND TO THE
INNOCENCE BUT THEY HAVE TO
CONFRONT THOSE WHO PERPETRATE
THESE CRIMES.
>> EXACTLY.
>> THEY MUST BE DEALING WITH SO
MUCH ANGER.
>> IT CAN BE, AND THAT'S A REAL
EMOTION, AND THAT'S WHY WE WANT
TO BE AROUND SO THEY CAN HAVE A
SAFE ENVIRONMENT WHERE WHEN THAT
ANGER BUILDS UP, THEY CAN
EXPRESS IT SO IT DOESN'T TAKE
OVER THEM.
THE ANGER CANNOT BE AN IMPETUS
FOR HOW THEY ACT BUT RATHER A
RESULT OF WHAT THEY'VE SEEN AND
WHAT THEY'VE HAD TO DO.
>> CONGRESSWOMAN, WHAT MORE WILL
YOU BE LOOKING TO DO IN THIS
COMMUNITY OVER THE NEXT SEVERAL
DAYS AND WEEKS?
>> WELL, TO BE SUPPORT -- TO
HAVE ALL THE RESOURCES WE CAN
BRING TO BEAR WORKING WITH THE
GOVERNOR, THE LOCAL COMMUNITY.
THERE'S BEEN AN OUTPOURING OF
SUPPORT FROM AROUND THE COUNTRY
FOR TRAINED PROFESSIONALS TO
HELP.
IT NEEDS TO BE ON FOCUSED ON
NEWTOWN, AND THE FATHER IS
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
THE FIRST RESPONDERS TOO ARE
TRAUMATIZED.
YOU KNOW, THEY ARE PARENTS.
THESE ARE THEIR LOVED ONES,
THEIR CHERISHED ONES, SO I WANT
TO MAKE SURE WE'RE KEEPING THEM
AS PART OF THIS PROCESS, AND
WHEN I TAKE OFFICE NEXT MONTH,
TRULY THERE'S GOING TO BE MUCH
MORE WORK TO BE DONE TO MAKE
SURE THEIR JOBS AREN'T DONE IN
VAIN AND DO SOMETHING AS A
COUNTRY, RESPOND IN A WAY THAT
ACKNOWLEDGES THIS IS
UNACCEPTABLE, BUT RIGHT NOW IT
IS THE FOCUS ON CHERISHING THE
FAMILY.
>> WE HAVE ONLY 30 SECONDS LEFT,
RICH, ON THIS POINT OF MENTAL
HEALTH AND IDENTIFYING THOSE WHO
MIGHT BE SUSCEPTIBLE TO A
PROBLEM, WHAT IS THE SINGLE MOST
IMPORTANT THING WE CAN DO?
>> WELL, I THINK ACCESS TO CARE.
THERE'S SO MANY PEOPLE WHO
EITHER DON'T HAVE HEALTH
INSURANCE OR THEIR PLANS DON'T
COVER MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES OR
ONLY COVER IT WHILE THEY'RE A
CHILD.
YOU NEED TO BRIDGE THAT SO THAT
IF YOU IDENTIFY SOMEONE, THERE'S
SOMEWHERE YOU CAN SEND THEM SO
THAT THEY'RE GETTING CARE.
>> RICHARD BESSER, CONGRESSMAN
ESTY, FATHER HAMILTON, THANK YOU
ALL.
THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR SUNDAY
WITH US.
DAVID MUIR WITH
HAVE THE VERY LATEST ON NEWTOWN
TONIGHT ON
"WORLD NEWS" TONIGHT AND I'LL
SEE YOU TOMORROW ON "GOOD
MORNING AMERICA."
STEE YOU
TOMORROW ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA."
EE YOU
TOMORROW ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA."
>>> IN THE NEWS THIS SUNDAY
MORNING, DECEMBER 6 --
16th, FEDERAL AGENTS TURN
THEIR FOCUS TO GUN STORES IN
THE CONNECTICUT AREA.
AND POLICE SHUTDOWN A SAN
FRANCISCO STORE AS THEY SEARCH
FOR A SUSPECTED IT GUNMAN.
>> GOOD MORNING FROM THE EAST
BAY.
YOU ARE WAKING UP TO MILDER
TEMPERATURES, AND A LITTLE
PATCHY FOG AND OUR NEXT WET
WEATHER MAKER IS ON THE WAY.
I'LL TIME IT ALL OUT FOR YOU
COMING UP NEXT ON