THOSE THINGS
AS WE GET INTO
OUR FIRST "TOSS UP."
THE CATEGORY FOR THIS ONE
IS "PHRASE."
IT'S WORTH $1,000.
AND HERE WE GO.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
WE JUST MADE IT.
JOE?
SOUNDS LIKE A PLAN.
YEAH, IT DOES.
GHT.
[ APPLAUSE ]
YOU WERE ONE LETTER AWAY,
THERE.
THAT'LL WORK.
YOU GOT IN THERE.
JOE SHEPHERD.
YES.
LOUISVILLE, KENTUCKY.
ALL RIRRIED MAN?
YES.
MY WONDERFUL WIFE, PATRICIA.
AND I HAVE A DAUGHTER, TARA,
AND A SON, JOEY.
AND WHAT DO YOU DO
BACK THERE?
I AM A TRANSPORTATION
COORDINATOR
FOR THE JEFFERSON COUNTY
PUBLIC SCHOOLS.
UH-HUH. SO,
YOU'RE INVOLVED WITH MAKING SURE
THAT PEOPLE NEED TO GET
WHERE THEY'RE GOING
AND ALL THAT STUFF?
WE GET THE STUDENTS
TO AND FROM ON TIME.
THAT SOUNDS LIKE IMPORTANT WORK.
AND YOU DO SOME WINE-MAKING?
I DO.
AMATEUR WINE-MAKER. YES.
GOOD FOR YOU. WELL, HOPE YOU WIN
SOME MONEY TONIGHT.
YOU'RE OFF TO A GOOD START.
ALL RIGHT. THANKS.
ONNETA BRUTON.
DID I GET THAT RIGHT?
THAT'S
ABSOLUTELY COR
WELL, GOOD.
FROM SHAW AIR FORCE BASE,
SOUTH CAROLINA.
WHICH SEEMS, TO ME,
TO INDICATE, PERHAPS,
THERE'S SOME MILITARY
CONNECTION TO THAT.
YES. MY HUSBAND IS
IN THE UNITED STATES ARMY.
UH-HUH.
AND I'M A HOMEMAKER.
I'M A STAY-AT-HOME MOM.
WE HAVE
TWO CHILDREN TOGETHER --
ALEXANDRI, WHO'S 3 YEARS OLD,
AND ERIN, WHO'S AT 19-MONTHS.
NOW, YOU STILL WORK
AT A HOTEL, RIGHT?
BEFORE I BECAME
A STAY-AT-HOME MOTHER,
I WORKED IN THE HOTEL INDUSTRY,
AND I GOT AN OPPORTUNITY TO HOST
ONE OF OUR FORMER PRESIDENTS --
PRESIDENT GEORGE BUSH
AND HIS FAMILY -- AT OUR HOTEL.
WELL, THAT MUST HAVE BEEN
EXCITING FOR YOU.
IT WAS VERY EXCITING.
WELL, HAVE SOME EXCITEMENT
TONIGHT, TOO, OKAY?
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
GOOD TO HAVE YOU HERE.
HI, TINA.
HI.
TINA NOBLE.
ROUND ROCK, TEXAS.
YES.
A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
WHAT LEVEL?
JUST BECAME ONE.
ELEMENTARY.
OH, OKAY.
K THROUGH 5th.
IT'S GONNA BE OKAY.
I HOPE. [ LAUGHS ]
YOU'RE MARRIED?
I AM MARRIED TO AN AMAZING MAN.
HIS NAME IS JUSTIN.
WE HAVE THREE DAUGHTERS --
KAYLEE, RYAN, AND GRACIE.
AND THEY'RE AT HOME.
AND YOU'RE A BINGO PERSON.
LOVE BINGO.
DO YOU HAVE LOTS OF BINGO THINGS
IN FRONT OF YOU WHEN YOU PLAY?
LIKE HOW MANY...?
I-I...YES.
LIKE 10.
WOW.
'CAUSE I GOT TO SWITCH THEM OUT,
PAT.
OF COURSE. IT'S IMPORTANT.
THERE'S A LOT OF STRAT--
BINGO'S NOT
JUST CALLING NUMBERS.
THERE'S STRATEGY INVOLVED.
THERE'S A LOT OF STRAT--
YES.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT THE STRATEGY IS.
[ LAUGHS ]
LET'S DO ANOTHER "TOSS UP."
THIS ONE IS WORTH $2,000.
AND THE CATEGORY
IS "FOOD & DRINK."
HERE WE GO.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
TA.
TOMATO JUICE.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
[ APPLAUSE ]
YOU GOT $2,000.
AND WE HAVE JIM THORNTON.
I THINK WE CAME OUT ON TOP.
I HOPE SO, PAT.
TONIGHT'S JACKPOT ROUND
IS BROUGHT TO YOU
BY SIMPLE GREEN
ALL-PURPOSE CLEANER.
MY NAME BRUCE FaBRIZIO.
IN 1975, I INVENTED SIMPLE GREEN
BASEHREE PRINCIPLES --
IT HAD TO BE SAFER TO USE,
IT HAD TO WORK,
AND IT HAD TO BE
COMPLETELY MADE IN AMERICA.
AND HERE'S
TONIGHT'S FEATD ON TRIZE.
EXPLORE AMERICA'S HERITAGE
ON A TOUR
FEATURING THE CAPITAL CITY
OF THE UNITED STATES,
WASHINGTON, D.C.,
COURED P OF COLLETTE VACATIONS.
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE
TO THE LINCOLN MEMORIAL,
EXPLORE WASHINGTON'S
ICONIC LANDMARKS,
AND DIVE INTO AMERICAN HISTORY
COMPLIMENTS OF
COLLETTE VACATIONS --
YOUR GUIDE TO EXTRAORDINARY
TRAVEL EXPERIENCES
ON ALL SEVEN CONTINENTS.
SEE THE WORLD
WITH COLLETTE VACATIONS.
collettevacations.com.
[ APPLAUSE ]
OKAY.
"LANDMARK" IS THE CATEGORY.
AND, ONNETA,
YOU'RE GONNA START.
OKAY.
S.
TWO S's.
AND A GOOD START IT IS.
GET OUT OF THERE.
AHH.
WELL, GET THEM
OUT OF THE WAY EARLY.
TINA, GO AHEAD.
Joe: ALL RIGHT, TINA.
T.
MM-HMM. ONE T.
I'D LIKE TO BUY AN I.
ONE I.
OHH. THAT WAS CLOSE.
JOE.
Joe: ALL RIGHT.
WELL, NOW THAT
EVERYBODY'S BEEN BURIED HERE,
LET'S SEE IF WE COULD...
ONNETA.
Onneta: L.
ONE L.
I'D LIKE TO BUY A VOWEL.
SURE.
E.
MM-HMM. THREE E's.
N.
ONE N.
H.
YEAH. ONE H.
THAT'S STARTING TO ADD UP, NOW.
$2,450.
I'D LIKE TO
BUY ANOTHER VOWEL. A.
TWO A's.
AHH. THAT ONE HURT.
I'M SORRY. TINA.
Tina: I WILL SPIN.
F.
YEAH. TWO F's.
M.
YEP. THREE M's.
$2,400.
I WOULD LIKE TO SOLVE,
I'LL BET. GO AHEAD.
THOMAS JEFFERSON MEMORIAL.
SURE.
NICE GOING.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU!
FUN TO GET ONE, ISN'T IT?
YES!
SO, NOW I SEE
MONEY UNDER YOUR NAME.
I SEE MONEY
UNDER EVERYBODY'S NAME.
YOUR TOTAL IS $2,400
TO THIS
AND WE HAVE A MESSAGE OR TWO.
VERY IMPORTANT STUFF.
PAY ATTENTION.
WE'LL BE BACK.
NOW YOU CAN RELAX
AND HAVE A GOOD TIME.
HEY, PAT AND VANNA,
CONGRATULATIONS FROM ALL OF US
HERE AT "THE JEFF  SHOW"
ON 30 SEASONS!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WHOO!
HERE AT TONIGHT'S  SHOW"
"AMERICAN HERITAGE" SHOW
IS BROUGHT TO YOU
BY THE FOLLOWING...
Woman: CH-CH-CH-CHIA!
Announcer: CHIA PETS,
THE POTTERY THAT GROWS!
AND NOW...
Children:
SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS!
Announcer: CHIA SPONGEBOB.
AND EVERYONE'S FAVORITE GAL --
CHIA HELLO KITTY.
SPREAD THE SEEDS, WATER,
AND WATCH IT GROW.
Woman: CH-CH-CH-CHIA!
Announcer: THERE'S EVEN
CHIA ALEX AND CHIA MARTY.
SO MANY CHIA PETS,
YOU CAN COLLECT THEM ALL!
AND TONIGHT'S MYSTERY ROUND
WANTS YOU TO MAKE HISTORY
WITH CASH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
HEY, SOMEONE CAN MAKE A LOT
OF MONEY IN THIS NEXT ROUND
BECAUSE IT'S
A FAIRLY LENGTHY PUZZLE
BECAUSE IT'S "TITLE/AUTHOR."
THERE IT IS.
AND, TINA,
YOU'LL START THIS ONE.
OKAY.
N.
AND THERE ARE TWO N's.
T.
THERE ARE FOUR T's.
CAN I BUY AN E, PLEASE?
THERE ARE FOUR E's.
Onneta:
LET'S GO, TINA.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
H.
ONE H. PICK IT UP.
[ CHEERS AND APP
ALL RIGHT.
THERE YOU GO, THERE.
ALL RIGHT, PUT IT DOWN THERE.
TRY TO FORGOT ABOUT THAT
FOR A WHILE.
DON'T LET IT THROW YOU, HERE.
NOW WHAT DO YOU WANT TO DO NEXT?
I WOULD LIKE TO BUY AN I.
YES. ONE I.
R.
WELL,
THERE ARE THREE R's.
SO, THE RISK IS $6,400
AND, BY THE WAY,
THE $1 MILLION WEDGE.
BUT THERE'S
A 50/50 CHANCE THA
SHE'S NOT GONNA DO IT.
NO. [ CHUCKLES ]
Man: GO FOR IT!
OKAY, SHE'S NOT.
[ AUDIENCE SHOUTING ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
I WOULD LIKET --
ALL RIGHT.
THERE'S ONE U. UH-HUH.
B.
YES. ONE B.
I WOULD LIKE TO BUY AN A.
THERE ARE FOUR A's.
I WOULD LIKE TO SOLVE.
OKAY.
"THE ADVENTURES OF TOM SAWYER"
BY MARK TWAIN.
THAT'S IT. YEAH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
OH, MY GOD.
WELL...
SO...YOU'VE TAKEN
THE FIRST STEP.
YOU HAVE THIS.
WE HAVE A LONG WAY TO GO,
AND, AGAIN, DON'T LET IT
DISTRACT YOU TOO MUCH.
BUT YOU'RE DOING GREAT.
$6,600 ADDED ON.
SHE'S UP TO $9,000,
BUT YOUAND WE'RE UPEAT.
FOR COMMERCIAL TIME.
AND SHE'LL HOLD THIS FOR ME.
AND WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
OH, MY GOSH.
Vanna: CAN YOU SOLVE
THIS PUZZLE FROM 1997?
IT'S A "THING."
WE'LL GIVE YOU THE ANSWER WHEN
WE COME BACK RIGHT AFTER THIS.
GET REWARDED FOR YOUR LOVE
OF MOVIES, MUSIC, GAMES,
JOIN SONY REWARDS.
REWARDING YOU FOR
WHAT YOU ALREADY LOVE TO DO.
LEARN MORE AT sonyrewards.com.
HERE'S THE CORRECT
PUZZLE SOLUTION.
WATCH TOMORROW NIGHT
FOR ANOTHER CLASSIC PUZZLE.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
AND IT'S A PRIZE PUZZLE, WHICH
IS "FUN AND GAMES" IN ITSELF.
ALL RIGHT, J
SPIN IT!
ALL RIGHT.
GO, GO, GO!
OE!     ALL RIGHT.
AN N.
THREE N's.
ALL RIGHT.
GOOD START.
A T.
ONE T.
I'D LIKE TO BUY A VOWEL.
AN A.
TWO A's, YEAH.
AN R.
ONE R.
CAN I BUY AN E?
ONE E, YEAH.
DOING JUST FINE HERE, JOE.
IT UP!
300!
AN S.
ONE S.
AND CAN I BUY AN I?
MM-HMM. TWO I's.
AND I WOULD LIKE
TO BUY THE O.
THERE ARE FOUR O's,
ACTUALLY.
A G.
ONE G.
AND I WOULD LIKE
TO BUY THE U.
MM-HMM.
THAT'S THE LAST OF THE VOWELS.
THAT'S IT.
KEEP GOING! KEEP GOING!
GET YOOF THERE FIRST.
AN M.
AHA. ONE M.
I WOULD LIKE
TO SOLVE THE PUZZLE.
DO IT!
ZOOMING AROUND ON A JET SKI.
YEAH!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
NICE GOING!
CONGRATULATIONS!
ALL RIGHT!
$4,300
AND YOU'RE GOIMAUI!
OH, MY GOODNESS!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
OH, WOW!
ALOHA, JOE.
NG TO  CHEETHIS TRIP ISUSE ]
AS SWEET AS HAWAIIAN SUGARCANE.
OH, WOW!
AN ISLAND GETAWAY AWAITS YOU
AT THE WESTIN KA'ANAPALI
OCEAN RESORT VILLAS,
I BEACH.
ENJOY ACTIVITIES LIKE
STAND-UP PADDLE, HULA LESSONS,
SPA SERVICES, GOLF,
AND MUCH MORE!
ANAPAL VISIT US AT
westinkaanapali.com.
TRAVEL PROVIDED
BY hotwire.com --
TAKE MORE OF THE TRIPS YOU LOVE
WITH RIDICULOUSLY LOW PRICES,
LIKE FOUR-STAR HOTELS
AT TWO-STAR PRICES
AND AMAZING DEALS
ON CAR RENTALS AND AIRFARE.
VISIT hotwire.com TODAY
AND START SAVING.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WOW!
LOOK WHO SUDDENLY HAS $11,334
AND THE LEAD.
MORE WHEEL
COMING UP AFTER THIS.
GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU.
Vanna: CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED BY...
Announcer: INTRODUCING
LIMITED-TIME HOLIDAY FLAVORS,
LIKE PUMPKIN PANCA
MMM.
ONLY AT DENNY'S.
[ BELL RINGS ]
YOUR SPIN I.D.
COULD BE WORTH $5,000.
WELCOME BACK.
WE'LL DO ANOTHER "TOSS UP" HERE.
IT'S OUR THIRD.
IT'S WORTH $3,000,
AND IT'S A "THING."
EVERYBODY'S READY,
AND HERE GOES VANNA.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
ONNETA?
NEWSPAPER HEADLINE.
THERE YOU GO! YOU'RE UP TO
$5,000. GOOD FOR YOU!
[ APPLAUSE ]
[ LAUGHING ]
THIS TIME THE CATEGORY
IS "AROUND THE HOUSE," OKAY?
[ BELL DINGS ]
HANG ON, ONNETA.
OH, YOU STOPPED --
HOLD BACK THERE.
I'M GONN THE WHEEL
A FINAL SPIN, ACTUALLY.
ASK YOU TO GIVE ME A LETTER.
IF IT'S IN THE PUZZLE, YOU HAVE
THREE SECONDS TO SOLVE IT.
EVERY CONSONANT
WORTH $1,400.
CATEGORY IS "AROUND THE HOUSE,"
AND, ONNETA, WE START WITH YOU.
A LETTER, PLEASE.
L.
NO L. TINA?
T.
HMM.
[ BUZZER ]
JOE?
R.
ONE R.
AND YOUR TIME WILL START
ABOUT NOW.
[ BUZZER ]
ONNETA?
N.
ONE N.
[ BUZZER ]
TINA?
S.
E S.
WE'RE GETTING THEM
ONE AT A TIME HERE.
[ BUZZER ]
JOE?
F.
NO. ONNETA?
M.
THREE M's.
[ BUZZER ]
TINA?
C.
TWO C's.
[ BUZZER ]
JOE?
I WOULD LIKE TO SOLVE.
YOU WANT TO CALL A LETTER?
IT'S UP TO YOU.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO
IF YOU DON'T WANT TO.
COMMEMORATIVE COINS.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
[ LAUGHS ]
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT LIKE
TO GET SOME MORE MONEY,
BUT IF YOU'RE HAPPY
WITH WHAT YOU GOT,
TO DO ANYTHING
YOU DON'T WANT TO DO.
YOU WON $1,400 THAT ROUND
AND YOU'RE OUR BIG WINNER!
$12,734!
CONGRATULATIONS!
THANKS. THU
[ APPLAUSE ]
THANK YOU.
WELL, THAT'S SORT OF
A MIXED BAG HERE, ISN'T IT?
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN NICE
TO GO TO THE BONUS ROUND
CARRYING THIS ALONG WITH HER.
BUT IT WAS FUN
TO HOLD ON TO FOR A WHILE.
AND YOU REALLY HAD A GOOD NIGHT.
YOU END UP WITH $9,000.
THANKS, TINA, VERY MUCH.
YES. THANK YOU SO MUCH!
GUARD THAT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
DID YOU HAVE A GOOD TIME?
YES, I DID.
WELL, I'M GLAD YOU DID.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR BEING HERE.
THANK YOU.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT,
SO WE'LL PACK YOU UP,
SEND YOU
OVER TO THE BONUS ROUND,
AND THEN
YOU'LL WIN SOME MORE.
THAT'LL WORK. SOUNDS GOOD.
SIMPLE AS THAT.
WE'LL BE BACK
TO SEE HOW THAT WORKS OUT.
OKAY. THANKS.
STAY TUNED.
COULD RIDE HOE
IN A NEW FORD ESCAPE.
THE BONUS ROUND IS NEXT.
JOE  LOOK, IF YOU HAVE COPD LI,
IN A NEW FORD ESCAPE.
YOU KNOW IT CAN BE HARD TO
BREATHE, AND HOW THAT FEELS.
COPD INCLUDES CHRONIC
BRONCHITIS AND EMPHYSEMA.
SPIRIVA HELPS CONTROL
TOMS MY COP
BY KEEPING MY AIRWAYS
OPEN FOR 24 HOURS.
PLUS, IT REDUCES COPD FLARE-UPS.
DSPIRIVA IS THE ONLY ONCE-DAILY
INHALED COPD MAINTENANCE
TREATMENT THAT DOES BOTH.
SPIRIVA HANDIHALER TIOTROPIUM
BROMIDE INHALATION POWDER
DOES NOT REPLACE FAST-ACTING
INHALERS FOR SUDDEN SYMPTOMS.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU HAVE
KIDNEY PROBLEMS, GLAUCOMA,
TROUBLE URINATING, OR
AN ENLARGED PROSTATE.
THESE MAY WORSEN WITH SPIRIVA.
DISCUSS ALL MEDICINES
YOU TAKE, EVEN EYE DROPS.
STOP TAKING SPIRIVA AND SEEK
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
IF YOUR BREAORSENS,
YOURT OR TONGUE
SWELLS, YOU GET HIVES,
VISION CHANGES OR EYE PAIN,
OR PROBLEMS PASSING URINE.
OTHER SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
DRY MOUTH AND CONSTIPATION.
NOTHING CAN REVERSE COPD.
SPIRIVA HELPS ME BREATHE BETTER.
(BLOWING SOUND)
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT SPIRIVA.
VE BEEN A SUPERINTENDENT
FOR 30 SOME YEARS AT MANY
DIFFERENT PARK SERVICE UNITS
ACROSS THE UNITED STATES.
THE ONLY TIME I'VE EVER
HAD A BREAK IS WHEN
I WAS ON MATERNITY LEAVE.HAVE O
I HAVE R I' FROM DOING
THIS ONE THING THAT I LOVED.
NOW, I'M GOING TO BE
ABLE TO HAVE THE TIME
TO EXPLORE SOMETHING DIFFERENT.D
IT'S LIKE ANOTHER CHAPTER.
YOU HAVE OVER $12,000
CASH AND PRIZES.
SO, WHO'S OUT IN THE AUDIENCE
WITH YOU?
MY WIFE, PATRICIA,
AND MY DAUGHTER, TARA.
I'M SURE THEY'RE PRETTY THRILLED
ABOUT THINGS, TOO.
AND NOW I'LL ASKO GIVE
THAT WHEEL A GOOD SPIN, JOE.
OKAY.
[ APPLAUSE ]
AND THERE WE GO.
AS SOON AS IT STOPS.
YES.
RIGHT THERE.
THANK YOU, SIR.
FOLLOW ME.
SURE.
AND YOU PULL UP
RIGHT OVER THERE.
AND HERE WE GO.
IT'S A "QUOTATION" TONIGHT.
R, S, T, L, N, E.
VANNA, PLEASE.
IS YOUR WORK FINISHED?
[ JOE LAUGHS ]
IS THAT IT? YOU WANT TO
SIT DOWN? YOU WANT TO REST?
ALL RIGHT, THREE MORE
CONSONANTS, ONE MORE V
A C.
ONE.
AN M.
AND AN H.
AND YOUR VOWEL WOULD BE?
AN A.
OKAY. VANNA WILL GO
BACK TO WORK.
WE HOPE. YES.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WHOOP!
HMM.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
LOOKS CHALLENGING TO ME,
BUT MAYBE NOT.
WE'LL SEE,
BUT IT'S A "QUOTATION."
SO, YOU HAVE 10 SECONDS
TOUS WHAT IT IS.
GOOD LUCK.
UM, B...
[ BUZZER ]
NO.
WELL, LET'S SEE.
LET'S LEARN TOGETHER.
JACK BE QUICK.
WOW.
YEAH, WELL.
[ LAUGHS ]
JACK BE WRONG,
IN THIS CASE.
AND WHAT DO WE HAVE HERE?
OH, WE COULD USE THAT.
OHH!
I'M SORRY.
HEY, WE'LL HIDE THAT.
LET'S ACCENTUATE THE POSITIVE,
WHICH IS HE'S WON $12,734!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
NICE JOB, JOE.
ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANK YOU.
VANNA AND I'LL BE BACK
IN ONE SECOND!
OR TWO, OR FOUR.
ACCOMMODATIONS PROVIDED
BY GAYLORD NATIONAL RESORT,
JUST MINUTES
FROM WASHINGTON, D.C.
GAYLORD NATIONAL
CHRISTMAS CELEBRATION
FEATURES A 60-FOOT-TALL
GLASS CHRISTMAS TREE,
AND ICE! --
A LIFE-SIZE WINTER ATTRACTION
WITH TWO-STORY HIGH SLIDES
MADE FROM ICE.
VISIT
christmasonthepotomac.com.
Vanna: IT PAYS TO BE
A WHEEL WATCHER'S CLUB MEMBER.
WE'RE GIVING AWAY 5K EVERY DAY.
IF THIS IS
YOUR SPIN I.D. NUMBER --
LC7079476 --
CONGRATULATIONS!
YOU'VE WON $5,000
JUST FOR WATCHING "WHEEL"!
YOU HAVE 24 HOURS TO LOG ON
TO wheeloffortune.com
AND CLAIM YOUR $5,000.
CELEBRATING OUR
AMERICAN HERITAGE THIS WEEK.
YES, WE ARE.
SOME GREAT MEN BEHIND US.
I WISH MEN STILL WORE
POWDERED WIGS.
[ LAUGHTER ]
REALLY?
I THINK I'D LOOK GOOD IN ONE.
DON'T YOU?
NO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
OH.
I MEAN, I'LL WEAR THEM
FOR SPECIAL OCCASIONS,
BUT, YOU KNOW, IF I'M GOING TO
A SPECIAL PARTY OR SOMETHING,
BUT THAT'S ABOUT IT.
BUT I LIKE IT.
I LIKE THE STYLE.
DO YOUANYTHING
TO ADD TO THIS?
[ LAUGHS ] NO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
WOULD YOU LIKE TO SEE ME
IN A POWDERED WIG?
NO.
WOULD YOU LIKE
A POWDERED DONUT?
[ Chuckling ] YES.
WELL, WE'RE GONNA TAKE HAVE DER,
AND WE'LL SEE YOU NEXT TIME.
SO LONG.
GOODBYE!
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
Announcer:
GRAB A BOX O A POWK-UMMS.
ADD EGGS FOR BREAKFAST,
OR A WRAP FOR LUNCH.
TRY A CHEESE STEAK ON A ROLL.
YOUR TASTE. YOUR STEAK-UMM!
THE ALL-AMERICAN BURGER BUSTER.
STEAK-UMM SLICED STEAKS.
♪ CLAP ON
[ CLAPPING ]
♪ CLAP OFF
Announcer:
PRESENTING THE CLAPPER.
JUST PLUG IT IN.
TURNS THINGS ON...
[ CLAPPING, MUSIC PLAYS ]
NG.
F,  TURNS THINGS ON...
JUST BY CLAPPING.
[ CLAPPING, MUSIC PLAYS ]
THE CLAPPER COMES
WITH AN EXTRA FEATURE
TO MAKE YOUR HOME MORE SECURE.
TURN TO THE "AWAY" FUNCTION
AVAILABLE AT WALGREENS AND CVS.
-- Captions by VITAC --
www.vitac.com
[ APPLAUSE ]
EVE, PUT THE TURKEY DOWN.
PLEASE, MOM,
LET ME TOSS THIS.
WE'VE BEEN PICKING
THESE BONES FOR A WEEK.
LET THE POOR BASTARD
REST IN PEACE.
HEY, I SPENT DAYS PREPARING
A THANKSGIVING FEAST
FOR 26 PEOPLE. I'VE EARNED
THE RIGHT TO PHONE IT IN.
YOU AREN'T KIDDING.
TONIGHT'S DINNER
WAS 1-800-CRAP.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH THE PRESENTS?