FIND SOME OF THE BEST
COOKING IN THE SOUTH.
AND FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO LIVE
HERE GREAT SOUTHERN COOKING
STARTS WITH GETTING THE FRESHES
INGREDIENTS AND ONE OF THE BEST
PLACES TO DO THAT IN RALEIGH IS
AT THIS FARMERS MARKET.
FRED THOMPSON IS
AN EXPERT ON FOOD.
A GREAT COOK AND AN
AUTHOR WHO UNDERSTANDS
THE IMPORTANCE OF FAMILY
RECIPES AND THE TRADITIONS
OF SOUTHERN COOKING.
NOW I CAUGHT UP WITH FRED
AND HIS SON IN LAW KYLE
AT THE FARMERS MARKET TO
LEARN WHY THEIR RECIPE
FOR COLLARD GREENS ROCKS.
SO FRED I'VE BEEN HEARING
ABOUT YOU MAKE OBVIOUSLY
THIS KIND OF DISH WITH
COLLARD GREENS AND YOU
CALL THEM COLLARDS.
COLLARDS.
GET A LITTLE OF THAT
SOUTHERN IN YOU.
COLLARDS.
GET SOME OF THEM COLLARDS.
AND I LIVE IN FLORIDA.
BUT THE COLLARDS, NOT MANY
PEOPLE KNOW EXACTLY WHAT THEY AE
AND HOW IS IT TO COOK THEM.
IS IT A LONG PROCESS?
AND ALL THAT
KIND OF STUFF.
WHERE DID YOU COME
UP WITH THIS KIND OF
RECIPE FIRST OF ALL?
WELL LET'S GIVE YOU
A LITTLE HISTORY.
ALRIGHT YOU WERE IN
THE COLLARD BELT.
YOU WERE IN THE MIDDLE OF
THE COLLARD BELT, MORE
COLLARD GREENS IN NORTH
CAROLINA, SOUTH CAROLINA
THAN ANYWHERE ELSE
IN THE UNITED STATES.
WHAT ARE COLLARD GREENS?
WHY ARE THEY IMPORTANT?
WELL THEY GROW IN EASTERN
NORTH CAROLINA, EAST OR SOUTH
CAROLINA LIKE RABBITS MULTIPLY.
AND IT'S A STABLE FOOD.
IT WAS ALSO INEXPENSIVE.
DURING THE DEPRESSION
YEARS, ESPECIALLY IN
EASTERN NORTH CAROLINA
COLLARDS AND SWEET
POTATOES KEPT A LOT OF
PEOPLE ALIVE, BECAUSE YOU
COULD BE A LITTLE BIT OF
MEAT AND COLLARD GREENS
AND YOU CAN BASICALLY FEED
THE WHOLE FAMILY;
BISQUITS, CORN BREAD,
COLLARD GREENS, SWEET POTATOES.
WAS PRETTY STABLE FAIR
FOR A LOT OF FOLKS.
MY PARENTS INCLUDED.
THE RECIPE FRED IS COOKING
UP FOR US TODAY CALLS FOR
FROST BITTEN CABBAGE GREENS.
ONE OF THE CRITICAL
SECRETS FRED'S MOTHER
SLOWLY GAVE UP OVER 20 YEARS.
FRED'S JOURNEY TO LEARN EVERY
ASPECT OF HOW TO COOK
HIS MOTHERS COLLARDS TOOK
A LOT OF TIME.
AND PICKING UP THE RIGHT
COLLARDS IS ANOTHER CRUCIAL STEP
IN MAKING THIS FAMILY RECIPE.
NOW OK WE'RE HERE,
OK WHAT KIND OF
COLLARDS ARE THESE?
THESE ARE CABBAGE
COLLARDS.
CABBAGE I FEEL LIKE I'M
LIKE AT THE CABBAGE PATCH
LAND WAITING FOR IT TO
OPEN UP AND A BABY'S HEAD
I WAS GOING TO PICK THE
CABBAGE PATCH DOLL UP.
THIS IS LIKE ONE...
YEAH PICK IT UP, PICK IT UP.
THIS IS WHAT WE'RE
GOING TO COOK.
AND TO ME THIS IS THE
BEST WAY, THIS THE WAY MY
MOTHER TAUGHT ME TO DO IT
WAS TO FIND THE WHOLE
HEAD AND WORK DOWN
FROM THE WHOLE HEAD.
NOW THE OTHER THING IS
IMPORTANT IS THEY GOT
TO BE FROST BITTEN.
FROST BITTEN?
KYLE, HOW DOES THAT WORK WITH
THE FROST BITTEN?
KYLES GRANDDADDY
BEEN GROWING
COLLARDS FOREVER SO.
I GREW UP IN AADDY
FAMILY AND MY GRANDDADDY
WE ALL CALLED HIM PAPA
PAUL HAS GROWN CABBAGE
AND COLLARDS AS LONG
AS I'VE BEEN ALIVE.
AND HE WOULD NEVER, EVER PICK
COLLARDS OUT OF HIS PATCH TILL
AFTER WE HAD OUR FIRST FROST.
IT FEELS LIKE RIGHT NOW ITS LIKE
WE HAD OUR FIRST FROST RIGHT NO,
YEAH WE'VE HAD A FROST
THINGS ARE GOING
TO BE FINE.
OKAY.
NOW COLLARD GREENS
CAN BE VERY INTIMIDATING
WHEN YOU FIRST SEE THEM.
THE IDEA OF COOKING A
PLANT THE SIZE OF A
VOLKSWAGON JETTA CAN SEEM
A LITTLE DAUNTING BUT
FRED AND KYLE ASSURE
ME IT'S A SNAP.
NOW AFTER WE FINISH UP OUTSIDE
THE BOYS TOOK US INSIDE TO GRAB
ANOTHER IMPORTANT INGREDIENT.
ALRIGHT FIRST I'M
GOING TO ASK YOU, WHAT
EXACTLY IS HOCKS PORK?
I KNOW IT'S FROM
A PIG BUT WHERE?
WHAT ITEM DO YOU USE?
YOU NEED TO THINK
ABOUT THIS SMOKED
PORK OSSO BUCO.
GOT YOU.
OKAY.
ITS THAT PART OF THE PIG.
ITS REALLY KIND OF
A CRITICAL THING.
THESE WERE THE TYPE OF THINGS
THAT WHEN MY MOM WAS COMING UP
THEY COULDN'T SELL THIS.
THEY RAISED HOGS.
THEY COULDN'T SELL THEM.
BUT THEY COULD SELL THE
TENDERLOINS AND THE RIBS
AND ALL THAT RIGHT?
PEOPLE IN RURAL NORTH CAROLINA
THIS IS WHAT THEY ATE AND THIS S
WHAT THEY USE TO SEASON.
WITH OUR GREENS IN THE CAR
AND FRESH IN HOCK IN HAND
IT WAS TIME TO HEAD HOME
WITH FRED AND KYLE TO
START COOKING THE FAMILY
RECIPE FOR COLLARD GREENS.
FRED LIVES JUST NORTH OF
RALEIGH IN A GREAT
NEIGHBORHOOD SURROUNDED BY
CAROLINA PINE FORREST.
NOW HE'S MADE FOOD HIS
PASSION AND CAREER OVER 20
YEARS AND HAS WRITTEN TOP
SELLING COOK BOOKS ON
SOUTHERN FOODS AND DRINKS.
MORE THAN ANYTHING COLLARD
GREENS HAVE BECOME A
CONNECTION TO MY MOTHER,
TO MY FATHER, TO THEIR
PAST, TO THEIR HISTORY AND
THE HISTORY OF THE SOUTH.
COLLARD GREENS ARE
THE KIND OF THE CENTER
OF THE PLATE THING.
THEY BRING PEOPLE
TO THE TABLE.
THROUGH THE TABLE I THINK
YOU SOLVE PROBLEMS.
I'VE OFTEN SAID THAT IF WE
COULD SIT DOWN AND HAVE A
GOOD MEAL WITH SOME OF OUR
ENEMIES WE'D BE OKAY.
BECAUSE NOBODY'S REALLY
PISSED OFF WHEN THEY'RE
EATING GOOD FOOD.
AS WE FOUND OUT FRED'S
KITCHEN WAS KIND OF SMALL
BUT IT WAS WELL EQUIPED
FOR GOURMET COOKING.
AND THE FIRST STEP IN
GETTING HIS MOTHER'S
RECIPE FOR COLLARDS GREENS
GOING IN THE RIGHT
DIRECTION STARTS WITH
AN INGREDIENT THAT'S
IMPORTANT IN A LOT
OF SOUTHERN MEALS.
BACON.
ALRIGHT SO WE HAVE
THE COLLARD GREENS
BUT THESE ARE HUGE.
HOW DO WE BREAK
THESE DOWN?
WHAT DO WE DO?
WE JUST THROW THIS
IN A POT LIKE THIS?
I MEAN IS IT THIS HUGE?
YOU DON'T HAVE A POT
BIG ENOUGH DO YOU?
NO.
MAYBE MY RELATIVES DID.
WE NEED TO FIND HIM A POT.
OBVIOUSLY IT'S ABOUT THE
ONLY PEOPLE THAT WOULD
HAVE A POT THIS BIG.
ITALIANS THEY'RE
MAKING GRAVY.
ITALIANS WOULD.
BUT NO WE'RE GOING
TO BREAK THIS DOWN AND
WE'RE GOING TO MAKE IT
SOMETHING,
INTO SOMETHING THAT'S
REALLY, REALLY TENDER.
OKAY.
AND WE KIND OF START
WITH THE POT LIQUOR.
REMEMBER US TALKING
ABOUT THE POT LIQUOR?
YEAH.
SO WHAT I'VE DONE HERE IS I'VE
GOT SOME BACON RENDERING BECAUSE
I WANT THAT BACON FAT.
WE JUST ABOUT DONE SO I'M
GOING TO TAKE A SPOON AND
GET RID OF THE BACON.
THAT'S WHAT WE REALLY
WANT IS THE FAT.
NOW WE'RE GOING
TO USE THIS.
WE'LL USE THIS.
OKAY SO YOU ARE GOING TO
USE IT BUT WHAT WE MOSTLY
WANT IS WHAT'S IN.
RIGHT AT THIS POINT WE
WANT THAT BACON FAT.
OKAY.
WE DO NOT THROW
BACON AWAY.
WE DO NOT.
IN ANY SHAPE, FORM AT ALL.
EVERYTHING GOES GOOD
WITH BACON I THINK.
OH YES ABSOLUTELY.
BACON MAKES THE
WORLD GO ROUND.
EXACTLY.
COMING UP NEXT WE UNLOCK
THE SECRET OF THE COLLARD
GREENS POT LIQUOR.
A CRITICAL PART OF MAKING
THIS RECIPE ROCK AND
SOMETHING FRED CLAIMS TO
HAVE MAGICAL
HEALING PROPERTIES.
I'M DRINKING ALL OF THAT.
THEN WITH KNIFE IN HAND
I SET OUT TO BREAK THESE
MAMMOTH GREENS DOWN A SIZE.
WHEN MY FAMILY RECIPE
ROCKS RETURNS.
WE'RE IN RALEIGH, NORTH
CAROLINA IN AT THE HOME OF FRED
THOMPSON AND HIS SON
IN LAW CHEF KYLE.
FRED IS COOKING UP A
CLASSIC SOUTHERN DISH OF
COLLARD GREENS FROM AN OLD
FAMILY RECIPE HIS
MOTHER KEPT SECRET
FOR MANY YEARS.
THE POT LIQUOR
IS A BIG PART OF HOW TO
MAKE THESE GREENS SINK.
NOW AFTER RENDERING DOWN
SOME BACON FAT FRED ADDED
THE NEXT INGREDIENT TO THE MIX.
THE NEXT THING WE'RE GOING
TO DO IS WE'RE GOING TO
PUT SOME CHOPPED ONIONS IN HERE.
SO THIS IS KIND OF LIKE IF
I WERE TO MAKE FOR ME LIKE
I SAID I'M ITALIAN TALKING
ABOUT THE POT, BUT IF I
WERE TO MAKE SOMETHING I'D
USUALLY PUT EXTRA VIRGIN
OLIVE OIL, BUT FOR YOU
IT'S THE BACON FAT.
IT'S THE BACON.
THAT'S KIND OF
LIKE THE OIL.
NOW HERE'S SOMETHING
YOU GET HOME AND YOU
WANT TO TRY THIS.
TAKE SOME PANCETTA.
YOU CAN PUT PANCETTA IN HERE
WITH A LITTLE OLIVE OIL AND
IT'S REALLY, REALLY GOOD.
AND I DO THAT ON OCCASIONS
JUST TO SORT OF CHANGE IT
UP A LITTLE BIT.
AND LIKE EVERY GOOD
ITALIAN KNOWS WE'RE GOING
TO PUT GARLIC IN BECAUSE
WE DON'T WANT TO
BURN THE GARLIC.
TIPE THIS IS
OF MOMS RECIPE THIS IS
KYLE AND MY DOING HERE.
RIGHT.
OKAY WE HAD TO HAVE
A LITTLE, JUST GOT TO
HAVE A LITTLE GARLIC.
FRED'S SON IN LAW KYLE IS
AN AWSOME CHEF AND GREW
UP EATING COLLARD GREENS.
NOW HIS LOVE FOR FOOD CAME
AT AN EARLY AGE AND HIS
APPRECIATION FOR SOUTHERN
COOKING COMES
FROM THE HEART.
TALKING ABOUT BRINGING
PEOPLE TOGETHER GROWING
UP SOUTHERN BAPTIST HOMECOMING.
THE BIG CHURCH LUNCHEONS AND
EVERYTHING LIKE THAT AND FAMILY
AND EVERYTHING LIKE THAT.
EVERYBODY'S SITTING AT
BIG TABLES SHARING FOOD
AND SHARING GOOD TIMES.
IT'S WHAT REALLY BRINGS IT ALL
TOGETHER AND THAT WAS ORIGINALLY
WHY I GOT SO INTERESTED IN
COOKING WAS JUST YOU NEVER SEEN
ANYOBDY UPSET WITH A PLATE OF
FOOD IN FRONT OF HIM.
SO YOU CAN'T GO
WRONG WITH FOODS.
BACK IN FREDS
KITCHEN WE KEEP THE
POT LIQUOR ROLLING.
COOKING DOWN ALL THIS
BACON ADDING THE ONIONS,
GARLIC AND HAM HOCKS IS
ALL PART OF CREATING A
TASTY POT FOR THE GREENS
TO ACTUALLY COOK IT BUT
BEFORE THIS GIANT PLANT
CAN EVEN FIT IN THE POT
WE'VE GOT SOME WORK TO DO.
SO YOU GOT YOUR SON
IN LAW HERE TO HELP US
WITH THE DEFLOWERING.
YEAH DEFLOWER THAT'S A
PROPER WAY TO DO IT.
KYLE YOU SORT OF MET HIM
AT THE FARMERS MARKET.
KYLE HOW YOU DOING?
KYLE IS MY SON IN LAW I TOLD
MY DAUGHTER THAT I'M KEEPING HIM
EVEN IF HE GETS RID OF HER.
HES A FABULOUS CHEF, HES A SOUS
CHEF OVER AT A GREAT RESTAURANT
KIND OF ON A LOT OF COOKSI HAVED
ON A LOT OF COOKS
BOOKS TOGETHER.
WE JUST LIKE TO
COOK TOGETHER.
OKAY SO YOU HAVE
TO WASH THE GREENS.
NATURALLY THEY GROW ON
THE GROUND SO VERY DIRTY
ON THE INSIDE SO THE LAST
THING ANY SOUTHERN
WANTS IS SOME GRITTY
COLLARD GREENS.
RIGHT.
SO THE OUTSIDE LEAVES
WHICH ARE VERY GREEN ARE
YOUR BITTER BUT AS YOU CAN
TELL IN THE INSIDE
THESE ARE YOUR OUTSIDE
SEE HOW GREEN THEY ARE?
AS YOU GET TOWARDS THE
INSIDE SEE HOW THEY GET
THE WHITE LIME GREEN COLOR
THESE ARE GOING TO
BE YOUR SWEET, THAT
BITTER SWEET BALANCE.
SO TAKE THIS OFF
JUST LIKE THAT.
COME ON SUCKER.
WHAT DO YOU THINK KYLE?
DOES HE HAVE
POTENTIAL OVER THERE?
HE DOES, HE DOES.
LITTLE QUICK AT LEARNING.
EVEN THE SMALL ONES
AS YOU GO DOWN TOO.
EXACTLY.
BECAUSE THESE ARE THE
SWEETER ONES AREN'T THEY.
EXACTLY.
WHEN YOU SHUT THE KNOTS ON THEM
IT'S KIND OF LIKE ROLLING A JOIT
AND THEN CUTTING THEM UP.
GOT YOU.
IF YOU GROW UP IN THE 70'S
ANY TIME PAST THE 70'S IT'S
EASY TO DO CHEF OBLIVIA.
GOT YOU.
IS THAT, AM I
DOIN YOU ARE, YOU'
YOU ARE, YOU'RE
DOING PERFECT.
IT'S ALMOST LIKE WHAT
YOU DOING WITH THE BAY
LEAVES OR WHATEVER.
OR LIKE THE BASIL LEAVES.
YOU ROLL THEM UP.
EXACTLY.
I'M NOT FAMILIAR
WITH THE JOINT BUT.
AFTER GETTING INTO IT I CAN SEE
WORKING WITH COLLARD GREENS
WASN'T ALL THAT BAD.
I MEAN ONCE WE GOT THEM CLEANED
UP, REMOVE THE STEMS AND CUT THM
DOWN INTO SMALLER PIECES
THEY'RE READY TO ADD TO
THE POT LIQUOR FOR A SLOW AND
LOW RISE ON THE STOVE.
ALRIGHT JOEY THE NEXT THING
WE'RE GOING TO DO IS WE'RE GOING
TO COOK THESE SUCKERS.
AND ONE OF THE THINGS I
DID WHILE YOU WERE OVER
THERE CLEANING WORKING
WITH KYLE IS I THREW
IN OUR HAM HOCK.
OKAY.
SO THAT'S GOT TO GO IN
THERE RIGHT BEFORE IT
STARTS TO GET TO A BOIL?
RIGHT BEFORE IT
COMES TO A BOIL, THEN
LET IT SIMMER A BIT.
THAT'S THE HUGE SEASONING
INGREDIENT HERE AS WELL.
ALRIGHT LET ME TELL
YOU ABOUT POT LIQUOR.
ALRIGHT.
POT LIQUOR IS YES IT'S
A MEDIAN TO COOK THESE
GREENS IN BUT FOR A
SOUTHERNER ESPECIALLY
AN OLD SOUTHERNER
THIS IS A CURE ALL.
IT CURES CANCER, HEART
DISEASE, GINGIVITES,
DANDRUFF, IMPOTENCE,
KIDNEY PROBLEMS IT
IS THE HEALTHIEST
THING IN THE WORLD.
I'M DRINKING ALL OF THAT.
YEAH, I MEAN THIS IS
THE PERFECT HEALTH.
..SO IT'S A
CURE ALL IN ALL.
WE'RE GOING TO TEACH YOU
LATER ON HOW TO EAT IT
WITH CORN BREAD WHICH IS
REALLY THE PROPER
WAY TO DO IT.
OKAY.
BELIEVE IT OR NOT
WE'RE GOING TO GET ALL
THOSE GREENS IN THERE.
ALL OF THESE IN THERE?
ALL OF THEM.
ALL OF THEM?
HOW IS THAT EVEN POSSIBLE?
WE'RE PROBABLY GOING TO
DROP SOME ON THE FLOOR
SO DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
HOW DO WE GET ACTUALLY
ALL OF THIS IN THERE?
BECAUSE THEY WILL WILT
DOWN AS THEY START
HITTING THIS LIQUID.
COMING UP NEXT ON MY FAMILY
RECIPE ROCKS; FRED AND KYLE THRW
ME A LITTLE COLLARD
GREENS CURVE BALL BY ADDING
ANOTHER INGREDIENT THAT I
DIDN'T EVEN SEE COMING.
WE CAP OFF THIS SOUTHERN MEAL
WITH A SIP OF SOME POTENT PUNCH
NORTH CAROLINA IS KNOWN FOR.
OH THAT'S GOOD.
I WAS WAITING FOR A KICK.
BE SURE TO CHECK OUT THE
MY FAMILY RECIPE ROCKS
FACEBOOK FAN PAGE.
COME ALONG WITH US ON THE
ROAD FOR UPDATES BEHIND
THE SCENE PICS AND MORE.
GO TO LIVEWELLNETWORK.COM
CLICK ON THE SHOW AND
HIT THE FACEBOOK BUTTON
TO GET THE PARTY STARTED.
(x
WE'RE COOKING UP COLLARD GREENS
IN NORTH CAROLINA WITH FOOD
AUTHOR AND CHEF FRED THOMPSON.
FRED'S MOTHER WAS SLOW
TO GIVE UP HER RECIPE FOR
THE FAMILY DISH TO FRED.
MAKING HIM WORK FOR
OVER 20 YEARS TO GET
EVERY SECRET STEP.
NOW AFTER GETTING THE
GREENS CHOPPED UP AND PUT
INTO THE POT LIQUOR WE'RE
ALMOST READY FOR THE LOW
AND SLOW COOKING TO BEGIN.
SO WE'VE GOT
EVERYTHING IN THE POT.
WE'RE DONE.
YEP.
YOU'RE CONVINCED
NOW THAT WE CAN GET
THEM ALL IN THERE.
YOU DID.
LET'S PUT A LITTLE BLACK
PEPPER IN THERE, IT'S
FRESHLY GROUND BLACK PEPPER.
SPRINKLE THOSE...THE LITTLE
FINALE BEFORE WE ACTUALLY GET TO
RELEASE IT THERE.
ALRIGHT.
WE'RE GOING TO
COVER THEM UP.
LET'S GO GET A BEER BECAUSE
ABOUT TWO HOURS THEY'LL BE DONE
BUT WE GOT TIME TO HAVE A BEER.
THAT'S SOUNDS
GOOD LET'S DO IT.
NOW FOR MANY PEOPLE IN
THE SOUTH COLLARD GREENS
WERE AN IMPORTANT PART OF
SURVIVING THE
GREAT DEPRESSION.
I MEAN THEY GREW LIKE
CRAZY HERE IN NORTH
CAROLINA AND COULD EASILY
FEED FAMILIES HIT
BY A TOUGH TIMES.
FRED'S MOTHER HELD THE
SECRET TO THIS DELICIOUS
RECIPE FOR OVER 20 YEARS.
SLOWLY REVEALING THE
IMPORTANT PARTS OF
IT TO FRED OVERTIME.
FOR MY MOTHER THIS HAS BEEN SORT
OF AN INTERESTING JOURNEY AND
INTERESTING TRIP WITH HER.
TAKING LITERALLY
20 YEARS TO GET THE
RECIPE OUT OF HER.
GIVING ME SO MANY EXCUSES
TO BE AROUND HER, BE WITH
HER AND TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
LIFE WAS LIKE
GROWING UP FOR HER.
COOKING COLLARD GREENS
RIGHT TAKES TIME.
I MEAN IT TAKES A COUPLE OF
HOURS FOR THE LEAVES TO BREAK
DOWN IN THE POT LIQUOR WITH THIS
RECIPE AS THEY SLOWLY SUCK UP
ALLTHE SMOKEY FLAVORS OF THE HAM
HOCK, BACON, ONIONS AND GARLIC.
COOKING TRADITIONAL
MEALS LIKE THIS IS
ALWAYS SPECIAL FOR FRED.
AND USING SOME OF THE TOOLS THAT
HIS MOTHER USED
TO ACTUALLY PREPARE THE DISH
REALLY BRINGS IT HOME.
ALRIGHT SO THIS
SMELLS ABSOLUTELY
GREAT RIGHT NOW.
SO ARE WE READY TO EAT?
YOU REMEMBER
THE MONSTROSITY
THAT WE STARTED.
RIGHT?
AND THEN YOU WEREN'T
CERTAIN THAT I WOULD GET
THEM SMALL IN THE POT.
RIGHT AND YOU DID.
ALRIGHT NOW THIS IS MAYBE
A LITTLE SURPRISE THAT'S
WHAT THEY'VE COOKED DOWN TO.
OKAY.
THAT'S WHY I ALWAYS
DO A COUPLE OF
BATCHES AT ONE TIME.
RIGHT.
AND NOW YOU JUST
WANT TO EAT THEM.
ONE OF THE LAST TRICKS
THAT MY MOTHER TOLD ME
ABOUT ALL THESE THINGS WAS
SHE CHOPPED HOW TO KNOW
HOW THIS COLLARD CHOPPER
IS BECAUSE THIS WAS THE
BIGGEST FIGHT WHEN SHE
DECIDED TO BREAK UP
HOUSEKEEPING AND CLEAR THE
RETIREMENT CENTER.
WE GOT THE CHOPPER.
AT THAT TIME I COOKED
MORE THAN MY SISTER DID.
SO YOU GOT IT?
I GOT THE CHOPPER.
I COULD SELL THIS TO MY SISTER
FOR A GREAT DEAL OF MONEY BUT
IT'S NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
RIGHT.
AND THIS IS MY MOMS BOWL.
OH REALLY?
OH COOL.
IT ACTUALLY WAS
HER MOTHERS BOWL.
HER MOTHER USED IT TO
MAKE BISQUITS OUT OF IT.
SO HOW OLD WOULD YOU
SAY THAT BOWL IS THEN?
WE'RE LOOKING AT CLOSE
TO 100 YEARS OLD.
WOW.
FRED AND KYLE HAVE
PEFECTED A GREAT WAY TO
ENJOY THESE GREENS, THAT A
LOT OF PEOPLE WOULD LOVE.
AS THE GREENS COOK DOWN
KYLE GOT THE GRILL READY
AND SEASONED SOME FAT NEW
YORK STEAKS TO SERVE
OVER THE GREENS.
AFTER THE COLLARDS HAVE
COME OUT AND ARE STRAINED
FOR THE SHINING PART OF
THE RECIPE FRED BREAKS
DOWN THE MEATY HAM HOCK
TO ADD BACK INTO THE POT.
ALRIGHT JOEY I'M
GOING TO GIVE THEM
A LITTLE QUICK TEST.
BUT SINCE YOU'RE NOT
AROUND HERE I'M GOING TO
LET YOU TASTE A LITTLE
QUICK TEST AND WE'RE
GOING TO DECIDE HOW
MUCH SALT WE NEED.
GET A LITTLE
SWEET AND SOUR?
I DON'T THINK I
WOULD CHANGE IT.
YEAH.
WELL I THINK THEY
GET TOO MUCH SALT.
WHEN YOU'RE PUTTING
YEAH OBVIOUSLY WHEN THAT
SEASON HAS SALT IN IT.
I THINK IT'S PERFECT.
SO I'LL SHOW YOU THE OLD
FASHIONED WAY OF EATING
COLLARD GREENS AND THEN
WE'LL DO SOME UP A
LITTLE BIT WITH A STEAK.
ALRIGHT.
COMING UP NETE UP FRED'S AMAZINE
TO PLATE UP FRED'S AMAZING
COLLARD GREENS OVER STEAK.
AND WE GET A TASTE OF SOME HOME
BREW THAT WILL DEFINITELY PUT A
LITTLE SKIP IN YOUR STEP.
WHEN MY FAMILY RECIPE
ROCKS RETURNS.
WE HAD SUCH A GREAT TIME
MEETING FRED AND KYLE
IN NORTH CAROLINA.
AND LEARING THE TRADITIONS
OF SOUTHERN COOKING.
THE LAST STEP IN THIS
RECIPE IS AN UNUSUAL ONE
BUT IT WAS TOP SECRET TILL
FRED'S MOM FINALLY
GAVE IT UP.
ALRIGHT REMEMBER WE TALKED
ABOUT THE SHINE WHICH WAS
ONE OF THE VERY CRITICAL
THINGS THAT MY MOM
JUST REALLY LEFT OUT.
WELL WHAT THE SHINE IS,
IS THIS STUFF THAT COMES
TO THE TOP OF YOUR POT LIQUOR.
AND HOW DOES THAT
GET LIKE THAT?
HOW DOES IT FORM?
WELL IT JUST AFTER IT SITS
FOR ABOUT 20 MINUTES THE
STUFF COMES UP TO THE TOP
OR YOU CAN STICK INTO THE
REFRIGERATOR REAL QUICK
AND THIS IS THE MAGIC STUFF.
AND YOU JUST KIND OF WORK
THIS IN AND BELIEVE IT OR
NOT IT DOESN'T LOOK LIKE A
WHOLE LOT BUT IT PUTS IN
A WHOLE LOT OF FLAVOR.
AND KYLE YOU
GROWED THIS RIGHT?
KYLE IS THE KING OF MEAT.
WHAT DID YOU DO
WITH THE SEASONING?
WHAT DID YOU PUT ON THERE?
IT'S JUST SALT AND PEPPER.
SALT AND PEPPER?
DON'T GO CRAZY WITH
THE STEAKS LET THE
MEAT SHINE THROUGH.
I LIKE THAT.
WHAT DID YOU THINK OF THAT
COMBONATION TOGETHER?
LET ME TAKE A LITTLE PIECE
OF EVERYTHING RIGHT THERE.
GET A LITTLE MORE OF
THAT TRUFFLE BUTTER.
RIGHT THERE.
PUT A LITTLE TRUFFLE
BUTTER OVER THE TOP.
I LIKE THAT.
STEAK IS LIKE RIDICULOUS.
I HATE WHEN YOU TALK WITH
YOUR MOUTH FULL BECAUSE
YOU SOUND LIKE AN IDIOT.
WE WANT YOU TO SOUND LIKE AN
IDIOT WE WANT YOU TO BE
BLUBBERING BECAUSE THE
FOOD IS SO GOOD.
WELL LOOK WHAT I'M
DOING RIGHT NOW.
WELL KEEP EATING.
BECAUSE WHEN PEOPLE SEE THEY'RE
LIKE OH THAT WAS REALLY GOOD, OH
NO I'M FULL, THANK YOU.
I DON'T WANT ANYMORE.
THAT MEANS THEY
DON'T LIKE IT.
SO WITH THIS WHOLE
COLLARD GREENS AND KIND
OF TRADITIONAL SOUTHERN
HOSPITALITY WE HAVE
SOMETHING TO DRINK.
SOME STUFF HERE.
THAT'S A LITTLE POTENT
AND I MEAN YOU'RE
IN NORTH CAROLINA.
WE HAVE A REPUTATION FOR
FINE DISTILLED SPIRITS.
WELL IT'S
DISTILLED ALRIGHT.
WELL BEFORE I DRINK
THIS, LIKE I SAID THANK
YOU SO MUCH AGAIN.
I HAD A GREAT TIME KYLE
ABSOLUTELY AMAZING FRIENDS
HERE SO ABSOLUTELY AMAZING.
IF YOU WANT TO GO ON THE
WEBSITE AND CHECK OUT
FRED'S RECIPE ALL YOU GOT
TO DO IS GO ON
LIVEWELLNETWORK.COM CLICK ON MY
FAMILY RECIPE ROCKS AND IT WILL
BE THERE ALONG WITH MANY OTHER
SLEW OF OTHER RECIPES THAT YOU
CAN TRY AT HOME.
SO THANK YOU AGAIN.
APPRECIATE IT.
CHEERS.
I GOT YOU.
JUST IN CASE.
OH THAT'S GOOD.
I WAS WAITING FOR A KICK.
IT'S WARM IT'S FUZZY.
BUT IT'S GOOD.
WE KIND OF SMOOTHED IT
DOWN A LITTLE BIT NOT
EVERYTHING IS PURE.
ALL OF THIS
DEFINITELY ROCKS.
SEE YOU NEXT TIME.
THAT'S ALRIGHT.
GET READY TO SEE THIS
CLASSIC SOUTHERN RECIPE
COME TO LIFE RIGHT HERE IN
RALEIGH NORTH CAROLINA.
YOU GOT IT.
YOU GET READY TO SEE
THIS CLASSIC SOUTHERN
DISH COME TO LIFE.
CORN LIQUOR?
THEY GOT CORN LIQUOR?
WHO MAKES CORN LIQUOR?
CORN LIQUOR.
EVERY WEEK WE GO THROUGH
HUNDREDS OF BOXES OF FRESH
FRUITS AND VEGETABLES.
IT IS NICE TO GO DOWN TO THE
PRODUCE MARKET AND SEE WHAT IS
FRESH AND TASTE IT.
♪
>>> YOU CAN SEE THAT WE ARE
PRETTY BUSY.
WE A LOT GOING NONE MY KITCHEN
RIGHT NOW.
GETTING THE TRUCK READY AND THE
CATERING READY AND PASTRY
ORDERS GOING ON AND THE ORDERS
COMING IN.
THE LIST THIS MORNING FROM THE
STRAWBERRIES AND WAY SILL AND
ALL OF THE GREAT FOOD THAT IS
IN.