THANKS FOR JOIN UG US.
JOINING US.
I'M CAROLYN TYLER.
WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
VICTIM FROM THE DEADLY
SHOOTING RAMPAGE ON FRIDAY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA IS HEADED
THERE TO HELP COMFORT THE
SURVIVORS.
ABC NEWS REPORTER TOMAN
BRADLEY HAS MORE.
>> THE ANGUISH IS VISIBLE
EVERYWHERE.
IN THE MORNING, A TEARFUL VING
GIT.
AND EVEN "SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE"
PAID TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS.
>> ALL IS CALM ♪
>> A FATHER OF ONE OF THE
VICTIMS, ROBBIE, PARKER
DESCRIBES THE LAST TIME HE SAW
HIS DAUGHTER.
>> SHE SAID SHE LOVED ME AND
GAVE ME A KISS AND WENT OUT
THE DOOR.
>> SHE IS ONE OF THE VICTIMS
THE GUNMAN TARGETED.
ALL OF THE CHILDREN FIRST
GRADERS, SIX OR SEVEN YEARS
OLD.
SIX ADULTS WERE KILLED AND
AMONG THEM A PRINCIPAL AND
PSYCHOLOGIST, ALL CHILDREN.
>> THE PRINCIPAL OF THE SCHOOL
WAS RUNNING TOWARD THE SHOOTER
TO PROTECT THE STUDENTS.
AS WAS THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
>> THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S GRIM
DETAILS DEALT THE GRIEVING
COMMUNITY ANOTHER BLOW.
HE SAYS SOME CHILDREN WERE
SHOT AS MANY AS 11 TIMES.
>> THIS IS THE WORST I HAVE
SEEN.
>> WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT
THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER WHO
HEAVILY ARMED AND COATED IN
CEVLAR BROKE INTO THE SCHOOL
BY BREAKING THE GLASS AT THE
ENTRANCE.
HIS MOTHER IS A FORMER STUDENT
AND HIS MOTHER WORKED AS A
TEACHER'S AID.
>> SHE ENDED UP HOME SCHOOLING
HIM BECAUSE SHE BATS TELLED
WITH THE SCHOOL DISTRICT.
IN WHAT CAPACITY I AM NOT
CERTAIN.
>> THE GUNMAN'S FATHER ISSUED
A STATEMENT SAYING NO WORDS
CAN EXPRESS HOW HEART BROKEN
WE ARE.
WE ARE IN A STATE OF DISBELIEF
AND TRYING TO FIND WHAT
ANSWERS WE CAN.
FOR THE SURVIVORS, THERE IS
ONLY HEARTBREAK AND HAUNTING
IMAGES FROM A DAY OF TERROR.
>> MY TEACHER SAVED A LIFE AND
SHE CALLED MR. GUNN HER
HUSBAND AND HE CALLED THE
POLICE.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL BE
HERE TO MEET WITH THE GRIEVING
FAMILIES AND ATTEND A PRAYER
VIGIL.
SANDY HOOK, CONNECTICUT.
>>> AND THIS BREAKING NEWS,
POLICE JUST FINISHED A NEWS
CONFERENCE AND AMONG THE
THINGS THEY TALKED ABOUT WAS
RECOVERING EVIDENCE.
THEY SAID THE WEAPONS ARE
BEING STUDIED BACK TO WHEN
THEY WERE BEING ASSEMBLED.
THE WEAPONS THAT SHOOTER ADAM
LANZA HAD.
THEY ARE STILL COMBING THROUGH
THE SCHOOL AND THE VEHICLES
AND THE CARS AROUND THE SCHOOL
ARE BEING SEARCHED.
WHEN THEY FINISH THE SEARCH
THEY GIVE THEM BACK TO THEIR
OWNERS.
THEY ARE QUITE CONCERNED ABOUT
MISINFORMATION.
MISINFORMATION IS GETTING OUT
THERE ON SOCIAL MEDIA FROM
PEOPLE POSING AS THE SHOOTER
OR OTHER BOGUS PLAYERS IN THIS
TRAGEDY.
WE WILL HAVE MORE FROM WHAT
THEY HAD TO SAY AT THAT NEWS
CONFERENCE ON ABC7 NEWS.
>>> THAT GRIEVING COMMUNITY IN
NEWTOWN CAME TOGETHER FOR A
VIGIL.
THEY SHARED THEIR STORIES AND
THE SENSE OF LOSS.
A DOCTOR WHO HELPED TREAT
VICTIMS IS DEEPLY SHAKEN BY
WHAT HE EXPERIENCED.
>> THIS IS THE DARKEST THING I
EVER WALKED INTO BY FAR.
I HAVE BEEN THROUGH MEDICAL
TRAINING WHICH IS -- WHICH HAS
TAUGHT ME A LOT ABOUT DEALING
WITH STRESSFUL SITUATIONS AND
THIS IS THE DARKEST THING THAT
I HAVE EVER EXPERIENCED IN MY
LIFE.
VERY TRAUMATIC.
JUST HORRIFIC.
>> AND THERE WAS A CHURCH
SERVICE THERE TO GIVE THE
PEOPLE A CHANCE FOR SPIRITUAL
HEALING.
THERE WAS A GROWING MEMORIAL,
FLOWERS AND MESSAGES AS PEOPLE
REACHED OUT TO TRY TO SUPPORT
ONE ANOTHER.
THE BAY AREA IS GRIEVING AND
OFFERING CONDOLENCES TO THE
INNOCENT VICTIMS WHO DIED AT
THE SCHOOL.
AT THIS MORNING'S MASS AT
SAINT MARY'S CATHEDRAL, THERE
WAS A MOMENT OF SILENCE AND
REFLECTION.
ABC7 NEWS REPORTER KYRA
CLABBER IS LIVE TO -- CLAPPER
IS LIVE TO GIVE US THE
DETAILS.
>> I AM PRETTY SURE IT IS SAFE
TO SAY IT IS GOING ON ACROSS
THE COUNTRY AS PEOPLE GO TO
THEIR PLACES OF WORSHIP.
AS YOU MENTIONED MONSIGNOR
STARTED THIS MORNING'S MASSES
BY SAYING A SPECIAL PRAYER FOR
THE VICTIMS AND THOSE AFFECTED
IN CONNECTICUT.
AND THEN HE PROCEEDED WITH THE
MOMENT OF SILENCE.
HE SAID "OUR HEARTS ARE
WRENCHED AND WE ASK FOR GOD'S
MERCY" IN THE CHURCH A SMALL
MEMORIAL IS SET UP.
A WREATH WITH 26 RIBBONS, ONE
FOR EACH OF THE INNOCENT
VICTIMS AT SANDY HOOKS
SCHOOL.
PEOPLE LEFT FLOWERS AND LIT
CANDLES.
THE WORDS READ "THEY HAVE LOST
SO MUCH, CHILDREN, FAMILY
MEMBERS AND FRIENDS, THEIR
SENSE OF SECURITY AND
MEANING.
LET THEM KNOW YOU ARE WITH
THEM EVEN WITH THEIR SHOCK AND
GRIEF."
AT THIS MORNING'S 7:30 A.M.
MASS CONGRESS GRAW GHENTS
DIDN'T WANT TO BE ON CAMERA,
BUT THEY WOULD BE SAYING
ADDITIONAL PRAYERS FOR THOSE
NO CONNECTICUT.
ONE MAN SHOWED HIS WEEKLY
PRAYER LIST AND HE IS ADDING
THE NAMES OF THE VICTIMS TO
HIS LIST.
>> THESE ARE PEOPLE WHO PASSED
AWAY ON THE LEFT HAND SIDE.
THE PEOPLE THAT ARE SICK.
OF COURSE MY WIFE HAD AN
ACCIDENT RECENTLY, JUST
EVERYBODY.
I THINK ABOUT THEM EVERY
SUNDAY.
>> WE WILL BE ADDING THE LIST
OF THE CONNECTICUT VICTIMS.
>> CERTAINLY.
>> TODAY IS A DAY TO PRAY
ESPECIALLY FOR ALL OF THOSE
PEOPLE MASACRED AND FOR THEIR
FAMILIES OR FRIENDS.
TO ALL OF THOSE PEOPLE WHO ARE
IN PAIN AND SORROW.
>> THERE ARE TWO MORE MASSES
WHICH THE MONSIGNOR WILL LEAD
A PRAYER FOR THOSE WHO WERE
KILLED, THOSE WHO LOST AND ALL
AFFECTED BY THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
ALSO HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO AT
GRACE CATHEDRAL, ALL REMAINING
HOLIDAY CONCERTS WILL BE
DEDICATED TO THOSE VICTIMS.
REPORTING LIVE IN SAN
FRANCISCO, SKIER -- KYRA
CLAPPER, ABC NEWS.
>> I'M SURE YOU ARE RIGHT.
IT IS GOING EVERYWHERE.
>>> THOSE WHO KNEW ADAM LANZA
SAID HE WAS A SHY AND SOCIALLY
AWKWARD MEMBER.
HE WAS AN HONOR STUDENT AND
MEMBER OF THE TECH CLUB.
>> I KNOW SHE HAD ISSUES WITH
SCHOOL.
SHE EVENTUALLY WOUND UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
IN WHAT CAPACITY I AM NOT
CERTAIN.
WHETHER IT WAS BEHAVIOR OR
LEARNING DISABILITY.
>> ADAM LANZA'S FATHER, PETER
ISSUED A STATEMENT.
IT SAYS "OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO
THE FAMILY AND FRIENDS WHO
LOST LOVED ONES.
WE TOO ARE ASKING WHY."
AND THIS MORNING WE ARE
LEARNING NEW DETAILS ABOUT THE
YOUNG VICTIMS OF FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING RAMPAGE.
IT IS ONLY AMPLIFYING THE
HEARTBREAK OF THE NATIONAL
TRAGEDY.
WE HAVE WILLED TO YOU BEFORE
HOW TONIGHT PRESIDENT OBAMA IS
GOING TO VISIT THESE GRIEVING
FAMILIES IN PERSON.  LAURA
ANTHONY IS IN NEW TOWN,
CONNECTICUT -- NEWTON,
CONNECTICUT AND SHE WILL BRING
US THE DETAILS AS THE STORY
UNFOLDS.
LAURA, IF YOU ARE THERE, LET'S
HEAR FROM YOU NOW.
>> HI, CAROLYN.
I CAN HEAR YOU.
YES, WE JUST ARRIVED THIS
MORNING FROM THE HOTEL A FEW
MILES AWAY.
I CAN TELL YOU COMING THROUGH
TOWN THIS MORNING THERE WAS AN
INTENSE FEELING OF GRIEF AND
SORROW.
FOLKS LINED UP TRYING TO COME
INTO TOWN TO PAY THEIR
RESPECTS.
IN THE MEANTIME, THE
INVESTIGATION HERE ALSO
CONTINUES.
FEDERAL AGENTS AS WE SAID ARE
FANNING OUT TO GUN SHOPS AND
DRIVE RANGES HERE, GUN RANGES
IN THE AREA TRYING TO LEARN
ANYTHING THEY CAN ABOUT THIS
TWENTY-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER, ADAM
LANZA.
HE WAS HEAVILY ARMED AND
WEARING BODY ARMOR WHEN HE
LITERALLY SHOT HIS WAY INTO
SANDY HOOKS SCHOOL BREAKING
WINDOWS AT THE FRONT
ENTRANCE.
HE SHOT AND KILLED THE
PRINCIPAL AND PSYCHOLOGIST
RUNNING TOWARD HIM TRYING TO
PROTECT THE CHILDREN.
THIS MORNING WE ARE HEARING
FROM SURVIVING CHILDREN.
TWO TWIN BOYS DESCRIBE HOW
THEIR TEACHERS AND -- TEACHER
SAVED THE LIAR.
>> WE HID IN MY TEACHER'S
OFFICE.
EVERYONE WAS QUIET.
MY TEACHER SAVED THE LIFE.
SHE ALSO CALLED HER HUSBAND,
AND HE CALLED THE POLICE.
WHEN THE POLICEMEN CAME IN TO
GET US, HE TOLD US TO CLOSE
OUR EYES.
LIKE ON THE PICTURE ON THE
NEWS DO THIS.
>> AND RUN.
>> AND JUST GO OUT.
>> MANY, MANY STORIES LIKE
THAT COMING OUT OF THIS TOWN
THIS MORNING.
AS I SAID THIS MORNING WE HAD
A CHANCE TO DRIVE THROUGH THIS
TINY COMMUNITY.
THE DOWNTOWN AREA, IF YOU
WILL, THERE WERE LINES OF CARS
PROBABLY A MILE LONG.
PEOPLE GETTING INTO TOWN.
OTHERS WERE PARKING OUTSIDE OF
TOWN AND THEY WERE WALKING IN
WITH FLOWERS.
WE SAW PEOPLE WITH TOYS.
THERE ARE MEMORIALS THROUGHOUT
THE TOWN AND THERE ARE SIGNS
SAYING EVERYTHING FROM GOD
BLESS NEWTON TO HUG A
TEACHER.
VERY SOMBER IN CONNECTICUT.
CAROLYN?
>> YES, I WAS GOING TO ASK YOU
ABOUT THAT, BEING SO SOMBER
THERE.
KIND OF SET THE SCENE FOR US
FOR WHAT YOU HAVE SEEN AND
FELT.
IS IT AN EERIE FEELING THERE?
>> VERY MUCH SO, CAROLYN.
IT IS VERY SOMBER.
AS WE WERE IN TOWN THIS
MORNING THERE ARE LOTS OF
PEOPLE WHO VIRTUALLY NO ONE IS
TALKING.
THOSE WHO ARE TALKING ARE
WHISPERING AMONG THEMSELVES.
VIRTUALLY EVERY BUSINESS IN
TOWN HAS A SIGN UP ASKING FOR
PRAYERS .
WE SAW FOLKS GOING INTO A
CHURCH BRINGING FLOWERS AND
GOING IN TO PAY THEIR
RESPECTS.
THIS IS A SLEEPY COMMUNITY.
IT IS A VERY SAFE COMMUNITY.
THESE FOLKS ARE CLEARLY ROCKED
BY WHAT HAPPENED TWO DAYS
AGO.
AS YOU CAN SEE THE WEATHER
FITS THE OCCASION.
IT IS DARK.
IT IS COLD.
IT IS VERY SO MANY -- VERY
SOMBER.
>> WE KNOW YOU JUST GOT
THERE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE WILL BE LOOKING FOR YOUR
REPORTS TONIGHT ON ABC7 NEWS.
>>> WELL, THE UNITED WAY OF
WESTERN CONNECTICUT HAS
STARTED A DONATION DRIVE FOR
THE VICTIMS OF THE SHOOTING.
THERE IS A LINK TO THE WEB
PAGE AT ABC7NEWS.COM.
JUST CLICK ON SEE IT ON TV.
YOU CAN POST THIS BADGE TO
YOUR FACEBOOK WALL.
IT IS A SILENT SHOW OF SUPPORT
FOR EVERYONE IN THAT TOWN,
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>>> LET'S TURN NOW TO OUR
WEATHER.
HERE IS LISA ARGEN WITH A
QUICK FIRST LOOK AT THE
ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST.
>> HI, CAROLYN, YOU CAN SEE
THE CLOUDS BEHIND YOU.
WE HAVE HAD DRIZZLE AND LIGHT
RAIN NOT ONLY IN THE NORTH
BAY, BUT HERE IS WHERE WE
START, AND MUCH OF THE
MOISTURE IS FALLING UNDER THE
RADAR BEAM.
WE ARE LOOKING AT SOME HIGHER
RAIN FROM MOUNTAIN VIEW TO SAN
JOSE.
TEMPERATURES IN MID40s TO
NEAR 50.
WE HAVE THE RAIDERS GAY I'M
AND OCCASION -- WE HAVE THE
RAIDERS GAME.
THAT WILL BE ARRIVING LATER ON
TONIGHT.
>>> NOW BACK TO OTHER NEWS.
SAN FRANCISCO POLICE DETAINED
A MAN AFTER A DOMESTIC DISPUTE
LEAD TO A LENGTHY STANDOFF ON
KNOB HILL.
IT STARTED WITH AN ARGUMENT
AROUND 6:30.
WHEN POLICE ARRIVED THEY
BACKED OFF THINKING THE MAN
MIGHT HAVE A WEAPON.
NEARBY RESIDENTS WERE
EVACUATED AND TOLD TO SHELTER
IN PLACE UNTIL THE
SURRENDERED.
THEY WERE SEARCHING FOR A
WEAPON PAST MIDNIGHT.
>>> TWO ADULTS AND A JUVENILE
HAVE BEEN ARRESTED IN
CONNECTION WITH THE SHOOTING
DEATH OF TWO TEENAGERS IN
OAKLAND LAST MONTH.
A 15-YEAR-OLD AND HER BEST
FRIEND WERE GUNNED DOWN ON A
QUIET STRAIT CORNERS.
THE GIRLS WERE STANDING ON THE
2600 BLOCK OF MENNA AVENUE
WHEN A CAR DROVE BY AND FIRED
AT LEAST 36 SHOTS.
>>> A 16-YEAR-OLD BOY IS
ACCUSED OF SPRAY PAINTING BOMB
THREATS THAT SHUTDOWN TWO
SCHOOLS IN THE SOUTH BAY.
MORE ON THAT LATER.
BUT COMING UP NEXT, THE CHANGE
OF THE GUARD IN JAPAN.
THE NATION CELEBRATING NEW
LEADERSHIP AFTER TODAY'S
PARLIMENTARY ELECTIONS.
AND A TOP REPUBLICAN OFFERS TO
RAISE TAXES ON THE WEALTHY,
THE VERY WEALTHY.
WE'LL TELL YOU WHAT H
>>> NEW THIS MORNING JAPAN'S
LIBERAL DEMOCRATIC PARTY HAS
WON THE ELECTION AND A FORMER
PRIAL MINISTER -- AND A FORMER
PRIME MINISTER.
HE RESIGNED FOR HEALTH REASONS
IN 2007 AFTER ONLY ONE YEAR IN
OFFICE.
NOW A SECOND CHANCE TO LEAD
JAPAN OUT OF THE ECONOMIC
SLUMP.
EGYPT'S ISLAMISTS ARE CLAIMING
A MAJORITY VOTE ON THAT
COUNTRY'S PROPOSED CHARTER.
THEY HAVE A NARROW MAJORITY IN
THE FIRST ROUND OF A
REFERENDUM ON THE
CONSTITUTION.
THIS MORNING THE BROTHERHOOD'S
OWN COUNT SHOWS 57% OF THE
INITIAL 26 MILLION VOTERS
APPROVED THE CHARTER.
MORE VOTING FOR THE COUNTRY'S
REMAINING 25 MILLION VOTERS.
THEY HAILED FROM THE MUSLIM
BROTHERHOOD WHICH HAS
ACCURATELY PREDICTED PAST
ELECTION RESULTS.
>>> AS U.S. LAWMAKERS AND
PRESIDENT OBAMA GRAPPLE WITH
WAYS TO AVOID THE IMPENDING
FISCAL CLIFF, A TOP REPUBLICAN
WILL RAISE INCOME TAXES ON
AMERICANS MAKING MORE THAN $1
MILLION A YEAR.
THE MOVE BY HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BANER IS A CONCESSION IN
NEGOTIATIONS WITH PRESIDENT
OBAMA TO AVOID THE FAST
APPROACHING END OF TEMPORARY
TAX CUTS.
IT FALLS FAR SHORT OF THE
PRESIDENT'S DEMANDS FOR AN
INCREASE ON HOUSEHOLDS EARNING
$ 250,000.
WHILE IT SUGGESTS A POSSIBLE
BREAKTHROUGH IN THE STANDOFF,
A SPOKESMAN FOR SPEAKER BANER
SAYS A DEAL IS DEFINITELY NOT
IMMINENT.
ANOTHERRING SOGGY DAY IN THE
BAY AREA.
LISA ARGEN IS HERE TRACKING
ALL OF THIS WET WEATHER.
>> MOST OF THE HEAVY RAIN,
WELL I SHOULD SAY ALL OF THE
HEAVY RAIN WILL ARRIVE
TONIGHT.
JUST SCATTERED LIGHT SHOWERS.
MAINLY NORTH AND IN THE CITY
RIGHT NOW.
YOU CAN SEE THE CLOUDS OUT
THERE, BUT WE HAVE SUNSHINE IN
PARTS OF THE SOUTH BAY AND THE
EAST BAY.
WHAT TO EXPECT THE REST OF
YOUR SUNDAY.
I'LL LET YOU KNOW ABOUT THAT
AND THE PRETTY WET WEEK
AHEAD.
THAT'S COMING UP.
>> ALSO AHEAD, HUNDRED OF --
HUNDREDS OF NURSES ARE USING
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON TO SEND A
MESSAGE TO THEIR EMPLOYERS.
WHAT THEY HAVE PLANNED THIS
>>> THOUSANDS OF BAY AREA
UNION NURSES WILL HOLD A
ONE-DAY STRIKE ON CHRISTMAS
EVE.
THE CALIFORNIA NURSE'S
ASSOCIATION SAYS THE STRIKE
AFFECTS SEVEN BAY AREA
HOSPITALS OPERATED BY SUTTER
HEALTH AND TWO MORE SAN JOSE
HOSPITALS UH AFFILIATED WITH
THE HOSPITAL CORPORATION OF
AMERICA.
THIS WILL BE THE EIGHTH STRIKE
SINCE SEPTEMBER OF LAST YEAR.
IT COMES AS UNION LEADER REIS
MAIN ADD -- AT ODDS OVER
STAFFING LEVELS AND OTHER
CONTRACT ISSUES.
AND THOSE NURSES COULD BE OUT
THERE ARE MA OFING IN THE
RAIN, RIGHT?
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE WILL HAVE ON AND OFF RAIN
SHOWERS TODAY.
THEY ARE CERTAINLY OFF IN THE
SOUT BAY WHERE THERE IS
SUNSHINE.
IT HAS BEEN GRAY IN THE CITY
WITH SOME LIGHT RAIN.
HERE IS A LOOK AT THE GOLDEN
GATE BRIDGE.
AND LOOKING AT IT, A FEW DROPS
HERE AND THERE.
BUT RIGHT NOW IT LOOKS DRY.
LIVERMORE REPORTING SOME FOG.
QUARTER MILE VISIBILITY AS
WELL AS SANTA ROSA AND CONCORD
THIS MORNING.
CAREFUL IN THE EAST BAY.
STARTING OUT WITH LIVE DOPPLER
7HD, AND THE SWEEP IS ON TOP
OF MOUNT SAINT HUH LENA --
MOUNT SAINT HELENA.
IT IS NOT PICKING UP A LOT OF
IT.
YOU CAN SEE THE RETURNS UP TO
THE NORTH IN UKIAH AND SO MUCH
OF THE NORTH BAY HAS BEEN
LOOKING AT THE CLOUD COVER
WHILE THE EAST BAY HAS SOME
FOG AND THE SOUTH BAY HAS SEEN
SOME CLEAR SPOTS WITH SOME
SUNSHINE.
THIS IS A VISIBLE PICTURE.
WE WILL SEE FROM TIME TO TIME
SOME MIXED SKIES WITH SOME
SUN, CLOUD COVER AND A LITTLE
PRE SIP OUT THERE.
THE NUMBERS ARE MUCH MILDER
FROM 50 AT THE COAST.
YESTERDAY THE HIGH WAS 49 IN
SAN FRANCISCO.
IF YOU THOUGHT IT WAS COLD,
YOU WERE RIGHT.
WE HAVE BEEN RIGHT AT 49 ALL
MORNING LONG.
STARTING OUT MILDER AND
SUNSHINE HERE AS WELL WITH 51
IN MONTEREY.
24 HOURS AGO WE WERE MUCH WILL
COULDER.
WE ARE 10 DEGREES WARM NEITHER
SANTA ROSA AS WELL AS EAST BAY
VALLEYS.
5 TO 6 DEGREES MILDER WITH RED
ROOD CITY AT 8 -- WITH REDWOOD
CITY AT 8 DEGREES.
CLOUDS AND SUN AND A
POSSIBILITY OF A FEW SHOWERS.
THE NEXT SYSTEM COMES ON
THROUGH OVERNIGHT.
HERE IS A LOOK AT SOME RAIN TO
THE NORTH.
MOUNT SHASTA PICKED UP A
COUPLE OF INCHES.
1:00 IN THE AFTERNOON, YOU
WILL NOTICE A BIT OF A BREAK.
THEN THE NEXT SYSTEM.
WIDESPREAD RAIN TONIGHT AND
HEAVIER RAIN THROUGH THE
OVERNIGHT HOURS.
IT IS OUT OF HERE BY EARLY
TOMORROW MORNING.
RAINFALL AMOUNTS ARE NOT
MUCH.
JUST A TRACE IN THE SOUTH BAY
WITH ABOUT A HALF INCH IN THE
EAST BAY AND THEN IN THE NORTH
WE COULD SEE MORE THAN THAT.
LOW 50S AND A SLIGHT CHANCE OF
A SHOWER LATER TODAY.
MORE CLOUDS AROUND THAN SUN,
BUT IF YOU SEE SOME SUN,
CONSIDER YOURSELF LUCKY.
TEMPERATURES ENDING AROUND THE
50 DEGREE MARK.
MORE HEAVY RAIN AT THE END OF
THE WEEK.
>> AND WINTER BEGINS ON FRIDAY
THE 21st.
THANK YOU, LISA.
>>> IN SPORTS THERE WILL BE A
MOMENT OF SILENCE AROUND THE
NFL IN REMEMBRANCE OF THE
CONNECTICUT VICTIMS.
WHEN THE NEW ENGLAND PATRIOTS
MEET THE SAN FRANCISCO 49ERS
THEY WILL HAVE SPECIAL DECALS
ON THEIR HELMETS.
>>> ELSEWHERE IN SPORTS, THE
WARRIORS ARE HAVING A
TREMENDOUS START TO THEIR
SEASON.
HERE IS SHU WITH THIS
MORNING'S SPORTS.
>> GOOD MORNING.
WELL, THE WARRIORS' LONGEST
ROAD TRIP OF THE YEAR, SEVEN
GAMES IN 11 DAYS ENDED
YESTERDAY IN ATLANTA.
THEY WON THE FIRST FIVE WHICH
INCLUDED A WIN OVER THE
DEFENDING WORLD CHANNEL M --
CHAMPION MIAMI HEAT.
IT ENDED WITH A WIN COMING
HOME 6-1.
THE BEST START SINCE THE
1991-1992 SEASON.
BARNES IMPROVING EVERY GAME.
HE HAD 19 IN THE GAME.
CHECK OUT THIS FOLLOW-UP, ONE
HAND SLAM.
HE HAD 19 AS WELL.
62-49 WARRIORS AT THE HALF.
THIS TEAM IS MOST EFFECTIVE
WHEN EVERYONE IS INVOLVED.
THREE OF HIS 13.
DISAIF -- DAVID LEIGH AVERAGES
A DOUBLE-DOUBLE.
SETH CURRY PLAYING LIKE AN
ALLSTAR.
TWO REBOUND STOPS AND A TRIPLE
DOUBLE.
A STEEL AND SLAM AND HE HAD 18
POINTS.
6 AND 1 ON A ROAD TRIP FOR THE
FIRST TIME IN FRANCHISE
HISTORY.
115-93 THE FINAL.
LET'S MOVE OVER TO COLLEGE
HOOPS.
STANFORD MEN FACING UC DAVIS.
NONCONFERENCE MATCH UP AFTER A
COUPLE WEEKS OF EXAMS.
THE ONLY AGGIE PLAYER TO SHOW
UP.
23 OF HIS TEAM'S 52 SHOWING
DESPITE THE LAYOFF, HE NEVER
SLEEPS.
HE HAD 14 POINTS AND CARDINALS
LEAD AT THE HALF.
POWELL LEAD ALL CARDINAL
PLAYERS AS STANFORD IMPROVES
TO 7-3 WITH A 75-52 VICTORY.
CAL HOSTING 16th RANKED
CRAYTON.
6th IN THE NATION IN
SCORING, BUT ONLY TWO POINTS
IN THE FIRST HALF.
HE HAD 18.
BUT THEY WERE NO MATCH FOR
DOUG MCDERMOTT.
34 POINTS AND MONSTER GAME FOR
THE BLUEJAYS.
CAL FALLS TO 6 AND 3.
TO HIGH SCHOOL FOOTBALL STATE
CHAMPIONSHIP.
IT IS THE OPEN DIVISION CROWN
AND CENTENNIAL HAS THE STATE'S
LEADING OFFENSE AVERAGING 542
YARD WITH TWO 1,000-YARD
RUSHERS.
HE IS TALKING ABOUT RETIRING
AFTER 34 YEARS AT THE HELM.
THREE OF HIS FOUR RUSHING
TOUCHDOWNS IN THE FIRST HALF.
THIS ONE FOR 46 YARDS.
THEY WERE UP 21-0.
THE SECOND HALF AND CHRIS
WILLIAMS GUNS IT AND TO AUSTIN
LOAN STAR, GREAT NAME.
35-14 SPAR -- SPARTANS.
THEY HAVE A GREAT OFFENSE, BUT
COULDN'T GET ANY CLOSER.
DE LA SALLE OPEN DIVISION
STATE CHAMP YINS FOR --
CHAMPIONS FOR THE FOURTH
YEAR.
DIVISION 3 TITLE GAME.
HE IS HEADED TO CAL AND THREW
FOUR TD'S AND IS THIS ONE TO
HANLEY.
MADISON ANSWERS ON THE ENSUING
DRIVE.
HE RAN FOR 272 YARDS.
YOU CAN'T COACH SPEED, AND
THIS KID HAS SOME.
79 YARDS AND MADISON IS YOUR
DIVISION 3 CHAMPION WITH A
38-35 VICTORY.
THE RAIDERS HOSTING KANSAS
CITY TO TAKE ON THE PATRIOTS
TONIGHT.
WE'LL HAVE ALL OF THAT FOR YOU
LATER ON.
I'M MIKE SHU -- MIKE SHUMANN,
HAVE A GREAT DAY.
>>> AND PANIC IN AN UPSCALE
MALL.
FORTUNATELY IT DOES NOT HAVE A
TRAGIC ENDING.
>> SOME PEOPLE HERE IN THE BAY
AREA ARE HONORING THE VICTIMS
OF THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
SHOOTING BY GETTING RID OF
>>> POLICE JUST GAVE AN UPDATE
INTO THE FRIDAY SCHOOL
SHOOTINGS.
THE PRIMARY CRIME SCENE IN THE
SCHOOL IS STILL AN ACTIVE
INVESTIGATION.
POLICE ARE ALSO QUITE
CONCERNED ABOUT BOGUS POSTINGS
ON SOCIAL MEDIA FROM PEOPLE
CLAIMING TO BE THE SHOOTER OR
MAKING THREATENING REMARKS.
>> IT IS IMPORTANT TO KNOW
THAT WE HAVE DISCUSSED WITH
FEDERAL AUTHORITIES THAT THESE
ISSUES ARE CRIMES.
THEY WILL BE INVESTIGATED
STATEWIDE AND FEDERALLY AND
PROSECUTION WILL TAKE PLACE
WHEN PEOPLE PERPETRATING THIS
INFORMATION ARE IDENTIFIED.
>> LIEUTENANT VANCE SAYS THE
INVESTIGATION INTO THE TWO
HAPPENED GUNS AND ASSAULT
RIFLE USED IS ON GOING.
EVERY DETAIL ABOUT THE GUNS IS
BEING STUDIED RIGHT DOWN TO
WHEN AND WHERE THEY WERE
ASSEMBLED.
>>> WE ARE GETTING A MORE
COMPLETE PICTURE OF THE GUNMAN
AS POLICE TRIED TO LEARN WHY
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA WENT ON
THE DEADLY RAMPAGE.
INVESTIGATORS TELL ABC NEWS
THOSE WEAPONS THAT WE TALKED
ABOUT LANZA USING WERE LIKELY
REGISTERED TO HIS MOTHER WHO
HAS BEEN DESCRIBED AS A GUN
ENTHUSIAST.
ABC'S CHIEF INVESTIGATIVE
CORRESPONDENT BRIAN ROSS HAS
THE LATEST.
>> POLICE SAY THEY ALREADY
FOUND IMPORTANT CLUES IN THE
LANZA'S FOUR-BEDROOM, $600,000
HOME WHERE THE KILLER'S MOTHER
, 52-YEAR-OLD NANCY LANZA, WAS
THE FIRST VICTIM.
>> AND HOPEFULLY PAINTING THE
COMPLETE PICTURE OF HOW AND
MORE IMPORTANTLY WHY THIS
OCCURRED.
>> AUTHORITIES SAY NANCY LANZA
OWNED THE SAME STALE GUNS HER
SON USED TO KILL HER AND THE
26 VICTIMS AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
MOST WERE KILLED WITH MULTIPLE
SHOTS FROM THE HIGH POWERED
SEMIAUTOMATIC WEAPON.
>> THIS IS PROBABLY THE WORST
I HAVE SEEN.
>> THE CONNECTION BETWEEN ADAM
LANZA AND THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WAS WHEN HE
WENT TO SCHOOL THERE AND HIS
MOTHER WAS A TEACHER'S AID.
ACCORDING TO HIS MOTHER'S
SISTER.
>> SHE HAD PROBLEMS WITH
SCHOOL AND SHE ENDED UP HOME
SCHOOLING HIM.
SHE BATTLED WITH THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT.
IN WHAT CAPACITY I AM NOT
CERTAIN IF IT WAS BEHAVIOR OR
LEARNING DISABILITIES.
>> AS A FULLER PICTURE BEGAN
TO EMERGE, INCLUDING HIS
MEMBERSHIP IN THE HIGH SCHOOL
TECH CLUB, FORMER CLASSMATES
TOLD ABC NEWS HE WAS A SMART,
BUT SOCIALLY AWKWARD STUDENT.
>> HE ALWAYS CARRIED A
BRIEFCASE.
THAT'S WHAT STICKS OUT IN MY
MIND.
>> ADAM'S PARENTS, WENT
THROUGH AN UNCONTESTED DIVORCE
THREE YEARS AGO.
NANCY PURCHASED SO MANY
WEAPONS BECAUSE SHE WAS
CONCERNED FOR HER SAFETY
LIVING ALONE.
>> I THINK THE REASON SHE MAY
HAVE HAD THEM.
FOR THE SAKE OF MANY MORE IN
THIS COUNTRY IT WAS FOR
SELF-DEFENSE AND NO OTHER
REASON.
>> BRIAN ROSS REPORTING.
A PREVIOUSLY SCHEDULED GUN BUY
GABBING -- BUY BACK PROGRAM
HAS GOTTEN A BOOST.
HUNDREDS OF GUNS WERE TURNED
OVER YESTERDAY AND BOUGHT BY
OAKLAND AND SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE.
ABC7 NEWS REPORTER THOMAS
ROMAN HAS THE STORY.
>> I DECIDED TO GIVE UP ON
GUNS.
I DON'T NEED IT.
>> MICHELLE WHO DIDN'T WANT TO
GIVE HER LAST NAME WAS ONE OF
MORE THAN 200 PEOPLE WILLING
TO SELL THEIR GUNS TO SAN
FRANCISCO POLICE.
MANY WHO STOOD AND WAITED IN
THIS LONG LINE AT THE SAN
FRANCISCO OMEGA BOYS CLUB WERE
BROUGHT HERE BY THE SAME
TRAGEDY.
IT WAS THE MASS MURDER OF 20
CHILDREN IN CONNECTICUT.
>> IT HIT ME PRETTY STRONG.
>> IS THAT WHY YOU BROUGHT THE
GUN?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
I NEVER THOUGHT ABOUT GETTING
RID OF THEM BEFORE.
>> HE IS A VIETNAM VET AND HE
AND HIS WIFE SOBBED WHILE
WATCHING THE NEWS.
JAN WAS TURNING IN HER GUN SO
IT COULD NEVER BE USED TO TAKE
A LIFE.
>> I FEEL IF THIS IS SOMETHING
THAT MIGHT HURT SOMEBODY SOME
DAY, THEN I WOULD FEEL
TERRIBLE.
>> THE GUN BUY BACK WAS FUNDED
BY A GROUP IN OAKLAND.
THEY CONTACTED THE OMEGA BOYS
CLUB IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THE DIRECTOR DOCTOR JOSEPH
MICHAEL SAYS THE TURNOUT SHOWS
BOTH COMMUNITIES CARE ABOUT
GUN VIOLENCE.
>> WHEN THE COMMUNITY SAYS
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH YOU HAVE A
GOOD CHANCE AT SOMETHING LIKE
THIS.
>> IN OAKLAND PEOPLE LINED UP
AT 6:00 A.M. TO TURN IN GUNS
AT SAINT BENEDICT'S CHURCH.
th IS WHERE THE DIRECTOR
OF YOUTH UPRISING AND OAKLAND
POLICE WERE BUYING THE GUNS.
>> WE HAVE EVERY ANTICIPATION
THAT WE WILL BE EXCEEDING OUR
WILDEST EXPECTATIONS.
>> THE INITIAL TARGET WAS
TAKING 500 GUNS OFF THE
STREET.
A FINANCIAL INCENTIVE HELPED
BRING THESE PEOPLE OUT.
>> THE MONEY, MONEY, MONEY.
>> $200 WAS PAID FOR EACH
HANDGUN OR RIFLE.
A LIMIT OF THREE WEAPONS FOR
EACH RESIDENT, AND PEOPLE HAD
TO PROVE THEY RESIDED IN THE
CITY BUYING THE GUNS.
OAKLAND AND SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE DEPARTMENTS ARE GOING
TO BE ASKING THE GOVERNOR TO
SEE IF HE CAN MAKE THIS GUN
BUY BACK A STATE PROGRAM.
IN SAN FRANCISCO, I'M THOMAS
ROMAN, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> POLICE IN ORANGE COUNTY
ARRESTED A MAN WHO FIRED ABOUT
50 SHOTS IN THE PARKING LOT OF
AN UPSCALE NEWPORT BEACH
SHOPPING MALL.
SOMEONE CAPTURED THE SOUND OF
THE GUNFIRE ON HOME VIDEO.
NO ONE WAS INJURED
FORTUNATELY.
POLICE ARRESTED A 42-YEAR-OLD
MAN WHILE THE OUTDOOR MALL
WENT INTO LOCK DOWN.
A BOMB SQUAD ROBOT
INVESTIGATED THE CAR WHERE THE
SUSPECT WAS ARRESTED TO MAKE
SURE NOTHING DANGEROUS WAS
INSIDE.
IT IS NOT CLEAR WHY THE MAN
WAS SHOOTING HIS GUN IN THE
AIR, BUT POLICE AND MERCHANTS
REACTED QUICKLY IN THE WAKE OF
THE CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
TRAGEDY.
>>> GOVERNOR JERRY BROWN
RECENTLY REJECTED A NEW CAL
TRANS PR CONTRACT THAT WOULD
HAVE COST TAXPAYERS NEARLY $10
MILLION OVER THREE YEARS.
BUT IT TURNS OUT THE PLAN
WOULD HAVE BEEN A RENEWAL OF
THE PRICEY DEAL.
TODAY SAN FRANCISCO CHRONICLE
REPORTS OVER THE LAST FOUR
YEARS CAL TRANS HAS SPENT $8
MILLION ON PUBLIC RELATIONS.
MUCH OF IT GOING TO THE SAME
CONSULTANTS WHO WERE PUSHING
FOR THIS NEW DEAL.
THE FIVE-MEMBER COMMUNICATIONS
TEAM WAS BILLING THE STATE AT
RATES TOPPING OUT AT $160 AN
HOUR FOR EACH MEMBER.
THEY PUT TOGETHER TWO WEBSITES
AND CONDUCTED MEDIA TOURS OF
THE NEW BAY BRIDGE PROJECT.
>>> A SECTION OF HIGHWAY 1
THROUGH SONOMA COUNTY WILL
REMAIN CLOSED INDEFINITELY.
THE HIGHWAY WAS CLOSED BETWEEN
FORT ROSS AND MEYERS GRADE
ROAD.
A SMALL SECTION OF THE ROAD
COLLAPSED EARLIER THIS MONTH
WHEN THAT SERIES OF STORMS HIT
OUR AREA.
OFFICIALS INITIALLY HOPE TO
REOPEN THE HIGHWAY THIS WEEK,
BUTTON GIN NEARS HAVE
DETERMINED THE WORK WILL TAKE
LONGER THAN EXPECTED.
>>> TAXI DRIVERS IN SAN
FRANCISCO ARE FIGHTING BACK.
THEY ARE UPSET ABOUT APPS THAT
HAVE PRIVATE CARS TAKING AWAY
THEIR BUSINESS.
SO THEY HAVE LAUNCHED AN
AGGRESSIVE NEW CAMPAIGN OF
THEIR OWN WITH AN APP THAT
LETS YOU CALL THEM TO COME
PICK YOU UP.
AS ABC7 NEWS REPORTER JONATHON
BLOOM EXPLAINS, WHILE THE
OTHER APPS ARE BUTTING HEADS
WITH GOVERNMENT REGULATORS,
THIS ONE IS WORKING WITH
THEM.
>> AS HE DRIVES HIS TAXI
THROUGH THE BUMPY STREETS OF
SAN FRANCISCO, A LITTLE SMART
PHONE MOUNTED RIGHT BELOW THE
METER STARTS TO RING.
THE PHONE IS RUNNING A
BRAND-NEW APP CALLED FLY
WHEEL.
IF YOU ARE A CUSTOMER, THE APP
LOOKS LIKE THIS, A MAP OF ALL
OF THE PARTICIPATING CABS IN
THE CITY.
>> YOU PUSH ONE BUTTON, THE
ONE NEAREST TO YOU IS ASSIGNED
AND DISPATCHED TO YOU.
>> THE TECHNOLOGY HAS BEEN
AROUND FOR TWO YEARS.
SOME CAB COMPANIES WERE USING
IT BEFORE THEY CALLED THE
BLACK TOWN CARS.
NOW WITH THE CEREMONIAL
DRIVEOFF IT IS BEING REBORN AS
FLY WHEEL.
IT IS COMPLETE WITH BOLD NEW
ADVERTISING AND A PROMISE TO
HELP CABBIES COMPETE WITH THE
BLACK CARS AND THE LIFT
DRIVERS WITH THEIR PINK
MUSTACHES.
>> THEY GET 20 TO 30% MORE BY
HAVING THE MOBILE APPS HAVING
TO ACCESS THE REALTIME.
>> IT IS ALREADY IN A THIRD OF
SAN FRANCISCO TAXIS NEXT TO
THE OTHER COMMUNICATION
DEVICE.
>> WHICH IS A UHS RADIO.
THERE WASN'T ANY ADVANCEMENT
IN 50 YEARS.
NOW WE HAVE THE POWER OF A
CELL PHONE.
>> FOR CAB COMPANIES, FLY
WHEELS CAN REPLACE OLDER
DISPATCH SYSTEMS OR WORK
ALONGSIDE THE TWO-WAY RADIO TO
GIVE A BIRD'S EYE VIEW OF
WHERE THE DRIVERS ARE.
>> I NEED FOUR CAPS IN ABOUT
10 OR 12 MINUTES.
>> BY WORKING WITH
DISPATCHERS IN ASSISTED OF
GOING AROUND THEM -- INSTEAD
OF GOING AROUND THEM THEY HAVE
BROAD SUPPORT OF THE CAB
COMPANIES.
>> THREE HAVE BEEN ASSIGNED.
>> AND WHILE LIFT, UBER AND
SIDE CAR BATTLE FINES, FLY
WHEEL EARNED A GLOWING
ENDORSEMENT FROM THE CITY.
>> THIS COMPANY WORKED WITH
US, AND IT IS SOMETHING WE
WOULD RECOMMEND.
>> THE MTA SAYS SOON IT PLANS
TO GET ALL CAB COMPANIES USING
THE LOCATION TRACKING SO FLY
WHEEL AND OTHER APPS CAN HAIL
ANY CAB IN THE CITY.
JONATHON BLOOM, ABC7 NEWS.
>> AND THE TIME RIGHT NOW IS
9:39.
LET'S TAKE A LIVE LOOK FROM
OUR EMERYVILLE CAM.
IT IS GOING TO HAVE AN
ISOLATED SHOWER OR TWO TODAY,
AND THE TEMPERATURE WILL NOT
CLIMB MUCH HIGHER THAN 53
DEGREES.
I HAVE THAT FROM OUR
METEOROLOGIST LISA ARGEN WHO
WILL BE ALONG WITH A FULL
>>> AND NOW MORE ABOUT THE
SENSELESS SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
THAT STATE'S GOVERNOR TELLS
ABC NEWS THE SCHOOL GUNMAN
COMMITTED SUICIDE WHEN HE
HEARD FIRST RESPONDERS
COMING.
ON ABC'S THIS WEEK, GOVERNOR
DANIEL MALLOY RAISED THE
POSSIBILITY THAT LANZA PLANNED
A LARGER MASACRE THAN THE ONE
HE CARRIED OUT ON FRIDAY WHEN
HE USED A HIGH POWERED RIFLE
TO KILL 20 CHILDREN AND SIX
ADULTS.
>> HE SHOT HIS WAY INTO THE
SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL WAS LOCKED.
HE USED A WEAPON TO OPEN UP
THE GLASS AND THEN --
>> HE BLASTED RIGHT THROUGH
IT, RIGHT?
>> WITH A NUMBER OF ROUNDS.
HE DISCHARGED TO MAKE AN
OPENING AND THEN WENT THROUGH
IT.
WENT TO THE FIRST CLASSROOM AS
YOU KNOW, WENT TO THE SECOND
CLASS M RUE.
WE SUM MYSELF -- SUMMIZE IT
WAS DURING THE SECOND
CLASSROOM EPISODE THAT HE
HEARD RESPONDERS COMING, AND
APPARENTLY HAD DECIDED TO TAKE
HIS OWN LIFE.
>> THE GOVERNOR SAYS POLICE
GOT THERE QUICKLY ARRIVING
WITHIN 10 MINUTES FROM THE
TIME THE FIRST CALL WAS MADE
BY SOMEONE IN THE SCHOOL
OFFICE WHO WAS INJURED, BUT IS
EXPECTED TO FULLY RECOVER AND
MAY BE ABLE TO PROVIDE MORE
INSIGHT.
>>> THIS AFTERNOON VOLUNTEERS
WITH GLIDE CHURCH WILL SORT
THROUGH DONATIONS FOR NEXT
SATURDAY'S BIG TOY
DISTRIBUTION.
YOU CAN SEE FROM THIS VIDEO
FROM PAST YEARS IT BRINGS
MAGIC TO THE EYES OF LOCAL
CHILDREN WHO MIGHT NOT
OTHERWISE HAVE A HAPPY
HOLIDAY.
VOLUNTEERS WILL MEET AT 2:00
THIS AFTERNOON AT SAINT MARY'S
CATHEDRAL IN SAN FRANCISCO.
THE ACT OF GIVING BACK AND
SHARING, THE WEALTH IS VERY
MUCH ALIVE THIS HOLIDAY.
AT GLIDE YESTERDAY, THE
BUILDING WAS PACKED WITH
PEOPLE.
EACH RECEIVED A BLANKET
DONATED BY THE SIKH
COMMUNITY.
THIS IS THE 16th YEAR THEY
HAVE COLLECTED BLANKETS AND
PASSED THEM OUT TO THOSE IN
NEED.
>>> A WET WEEKEND ALL OVER THE
BAY AREA.
COLD AS WELL.
METEOROLOGIST LISA ARGEN IS
HERE NOW TO LET US KNOW WHEN
CAN WE PUT THE UMBRELLAS
AWAY.
>> WELL, WE ARE LOOKING AT OUR
NEXT ORGANIZED RAIN NOT UNTIL
TONIGHT.
TODAY IS AN OPPORTUNITY TO SEE
A LITTLE BIT OF SUN.
THERE STILL SHOULD BE A FEW
SHOWERS AROUND, BUT WE ARE
LOOK AT MILDER NUMBERS NEAR
50.
THIS IS OUR ROOF CAMERA.
YOU CAN SEE THE CLOUDS SO
DON'T PUT AWAY THE UMBRELLA.
WE'LL LET YOU KNOW WHEN WE
WILL SEE THE MORE MEASURE
RABBLE RAIN RAIN -- MEASURABLE
RAIN.
>> HERE IS SOMETHING FOLKS
WANT TO KNOW ABOUT GETTING A
PIECE OF THE WORLD SERIES
CHAMPIONS, THE SAN FRANCISCO
GIANTS.
IF YOU ARING LOOING FOR A
HOLE -- IF YOU ARE LOOKING FOR
A HOLIDAY GIFT FOR A BASEBALL
FAN,
>>> HERE IS YOUR CHANCE TO GET
YOUR HANDS ON SOME MEMORABILIA
FROM THE WORLD CHAMPION SAN
FRANCISCO GIANTS.
AT NOON ITEMS USED OR WORN BY
TEAM PLAYERS THIS PAST SEASON
WILL GO ON SALE AT AT&T PARK.
A PORTION OF THE PROCEEDS WILL
GO TO BENEFIT THE GIANTS
COMMUNITY FUND.
THIS MAY BE YOUR CHANCE TO BUY
A FUTURE COLLECTIBLE.
LISA, WOULD YOU MIND GOING
OVER TO AT&T PARK AROUND NOON
TODAY AND LOOKING FOR
SOMETHING FROM ANGEL PAGAN I
THINK?
>> AREN'T WE ALL?
IT WON'T BE A BAD DAY OUT
THERE.
IF YOU ARE HEADED OUT TO DO
SOME SHOPPING WE ARE IN
BETWEEN WEATHER SYSTEMS AS WE
SAY.
MAYBE YOU CAN RUN OUT AND DO
THAT.
A LIVE LOOK OUTSIDE RIGHT
NOW.
HERE IS LAKE TAHOE WHERE THE
TEMPERATURES ARE IN THE
30s.
SO JUST ABOVE FREEZING WITH
SOME SUNSHINE.
WE DO HAVE SOME NEW SNOW IN
THE FORECAST.
WE HAVE A WINTER STORM WARNING
AND IT WILL BE AWFULLY WINDY
HERE TODAY WITH THE LAKE WIND
ADVISORY.
AND WE ARE LOOKING AT A LITTLE
RAIN HERE AND THERE TODAY.
BUT OVERALL, THE MORE
ORGANIZED RAIN HOLDS OFF
TONIGHT -- UNTIL TONIGHT WITH
THE NEXT SYSTEM THAT ARRIVES
THROUGH THE OVERNIGHT HOURS
AND THEN IS OUT OF HERE BY
MIDDAY TOMORROW.
HERE IS A LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER
7HD.
FORT ROSS OFFSHORE FROM BODEGA
BAY.
WE ARE LOOKING AT A FEW LIGHT
AREAS OF RAIN.
THE CLOUD COVER, THE MIST AND
THE DRIZZLE HAS BEEN TO THE
NORTH OF THE GOLDEN GATE.
SAN FRANCISCO JUST SAW A
SHOWER, AND WE ARE LOOKING AT
FOG FROM CONCORD TO LIVERMORE
AND AROUND SANTA ROSA, .001
THIS MORNING, BUT SUNSHINE AND
BREAKS AROUND THE SOUTH BAY
THIS MORNING.
SO WHERE THE SUN HAS BEEN
SHINING THE TEMPERATURES ARE
JUST ABOUT 50 DEGREES.
OTHERWISE MID40s WITH THE
FOG.
THOSE SOUTHLY WINDS AHEAD OF
THE NEXT ANEMIC SYSTEM THAT
ISN'T GOING TO BRING -- WELL,
ACTUALLY YESTERDAY WAS THE
ANEMIC SYSTEM.
THE ONE TONIGHT IS GOING TO
BRING -- OH IT COULD BRING A
HALF AN INCH TO AN INCH IN THE
NORTH BAY.
10 DEGREES WARMER THIS MORNING
IN THE NORTH BAY WITH 5 TO 8
DEGREES WARMER IN THE SOUTH
BAY.
SO A FEW SHOWERS THIS
AFTERNOON.
THE RAIDERS GAME, YOU MIGHT
SEE A STRAY SHOWER.
CLOUDY AND A FEW SUNNY
BREAKS.
THE NEXT SYSTEM COMES ON
THROUGH WITH A BIG BREAK AFTER
THAT ONE.
THAT IS PRETTY GOOD BECAUSE WE
ARE LOOKING AT A WET TIME OF
IT AS WE HEAD TOWARD THE END
OF THE UPCOMING WORKWEEK.
THREE AND A HALF INCHES AROUND
MOUNT SHASTA EARLIER.
HERE IS THE TIMING AND WHAT TO
EXPECT TODAY.
THE SCATTERED SHOWERS AROUND
THE BAY FROM THE NORTH BAY TO
THE COAST, 1:00, AND THEN
NOTICE 5:00, 6:00 A SHOWER.
HERE IS THE NEXT SYSTEM.
BY 8:00 TONIGHT IT IS PUSHING
INTO THE NORTH BAY, BUT IT IS
THROUGH HERE BY ABOUT 10:00
TOMORROW.
WE ARE NOT LOOKING AT MUCH IN
THE WAY OF RAIN.
THEN A DRYER AIR MASS MOVES IN
ON TUESDAY AND WEDNESDAY AND
THEN MAYBE SOME SHOWERS
PARALLELING THE COAST ON
TUESDAY.
WE WILL GET COLD AFTER THAT
SYSTEM WITH PERHAPS SOME
FROST.
BUT RAINFALL AMOUNTS HEAVIEST
IN THE NORTH BAY MOUNTAINS
WITH JUST UP TO A 10th AND
TRACE AMOUNTS IN THE SOUTH
BAY.
A QUARTER AN INCH TO HALF INCH
AROUND THE CENTRAL BAY.
AND THE NUMBERS TODAY UNDER
THE CLOUDS AND A FEW BREAKS
AND MAYBE A FEW LIGHT SHOWERS,
UPPER 40s FROM CLEAR LAKE TO
THE LOW 50s IN THE EAST
BAY.
AND HERE COMES THE NEXT
WEATHER MAKER.
INTO THE WEEKEND LOOKS ON AND
OFF INTO THE HEAVY RAIN, AND
THAT SHOULD TAKE US THROUGH
CHRISTMAS EVE AND CHRISTMAS
DAY.
WE WILL HAVE TO FINE-TUNE THAT.
>> OF COURSE KEEP YOUR EYE ON
THE DOPPLER HD.
>> THANK YOU, LISA.
>>> IF YOU WANT TO GO TO THE
MOVIES THIS WEEKEND NEW IN
THEATERS "THE HOBBIT."
IT HAS ALL OF THE "LORD OF THE
RIPTION" PEOPLE INVOLVED.
IT WAS CLAIMED IN A NEW 3-D
TECHNOLOGY THAT SOME SAY MADE
THEM SICK.
REPORTER DON SANCHEZ LOOKS
HEALTHY AFTER SEEING IT, JUST
NOT SO HAPPY.
>> I AM LOOKING FOR SOMEONE TO
SHARE IN AN ADVENTURE.
>> I CAN'T JUST GO RUNNING OFF
INTO THE BLUE.
>> Reporter: BUT HE DOES.
JOINING A BAND OF DWARFS ALL
CREATED BY MAKE UP PEOPLE IN A
HUH LOUSE NATION.
AND THESE CHARACTERS ARE ON A
MISSION.
>> THEY ARE ON A MISSION TO
RECLAIM A MOUNTAIN.
>> Reporter: IT IS GUARDED BY
A DRAGON.
>> THE DARK HOW BETTER HAS
FOUND A WAY BACK -- A DARK
POWER HAS FOUND A WAY BACK
INTO THE WORLD.
>> BUT IT CAN'T FIGURE OUT IF
IT IS ACTION ADVENTURE DRAMA
OR COMEDY.
>> I AM SURROUNDING --
SURROUNDED BY DWARFS.
>> IT HAS BIG SCALE ACTION
WITH SCARY MONSTERS.
PETER JACKSON LIKES TO USE A
HELICOPTER A LOT.
IT IS IN 3-D, ONE REGULAR AND
ONE AT 48 FRAMES PER SECOND.
THAT'S REALLY BREATHTAKING.
"THE HOBBIT" IS THE PREQUEL
TO" LORD OF THE RINGS."
IT IS A SMALLER BOOK, BUT IT
IS A TRILOGY AND THAT'S WHY
SCENES GO ON SO LONG.
EVENTUALLY THERE IS QUITE A
RIDE AHEAD.
>> THE WORLD IS AHEAD.
>> LET'S GET BACK TO THE
TECHNOLOGY.
48 FRAMES PER SECOND.
THE PICTURE IS LIKE A HIGH DEF
SCREEN, UNLIKE ANYTHING YOU
HAVE SEEN BEFORE.
I AM SO FOCUSED ON THE QUALITY
OF THE PICTURE I WASN'T PAYING
ATTENTION TO THE STORY.
AT TIMES I WAS LOOKING AT MY
WATCH TO SEE HOW LONG IT WOULD
LAST, AND IT IS A THREE-HOUR
FILM.
YES THERE ARE VISUALLY
SPECTACULAR SCENES, ABOUT YOU
THE FILM SEEMS TO HAVE NO
HEART.
I GIVE IT A LITTLE MORE THAN
HALF A BUCKET.
DON SANCHEZ, ABC NEWS, AND
WE'LL SEE YOU ON THE AISLE.
>>> A WOMAN IS PUTTING UP A
FIGHT TO BET HER PET BACK.
NO MONKEY BUSINESS HERE.
THAT LITTLE WANDERING MONKEY
MADE INTERNATIONAL NEWS.
NOW THE FIGHT TO GET HIM BACK
IS TAKING A NEW
>>> CHECK OUT THE WINNING
NUMBERS FROM LAST NIGHT'S $20
MILLION SUPERLOTTO PLUS,.
NO ONE GOT ALL SIX NUMBERS
RIGHT.
WEDNESDAY'S JACKPOT ROSES
ROAST TO $21 MILLION.
>>> A BAY AREA SCIENTIST
THINKS HE MAY KNOW WHY
THOUSANDS OF JUMBO SQUID HAVE
BEEN WASHING UP ON THE
CALIFORNIA SHORES.
THEY HAVE BEEN BEACHING
THEMSELVES FOR DECADES.
AND NOW A STANFORD BIOLOGIST
MAY HAVE FOUND OUT WHY.
THEY TELL LIVE SCIENCE.COM
THEY HAPPENED DURING RED
TIDES.
THEY ARE LARGE ALGAE BLOOMS.
THEY RELEASED THE TOXIN IN
LARGE DOSES AND IT COULD KILL
THE SQUID IN SMALL DOSES AND
MAYBE INTOXICATE THEM.
THEY THEN SWIM INTO WATERS
THEY ARE NOT FAMILIAR WITH AND
WASH UP ON SHORE.
>>> AN OWNER OF A WANDERING
MONKEY IN TORONTO IS GOING TO
COURT TO GET HIM BACK.
HE WAS FOUND WANDERING IN A
TORONTO EYE IKEA PARKING LOT
LAST WEEKEND.
CHECK HIM OUT WITH THE BIG,
WARM COAT.
THE WOMAN SAYS THE MONKEY
NAMED DARWIN SNUCK OUT OF
THEIR CAR.
IN A COURT AFFIDAVIT SHE
ARGUES THE TINY MONKEY WAS
ILLEGALLY TAKEN FROM HER AND
MOVED TO A PRIMATE SANCTUARY.
THE WOMAN SAYS DARWIN
CONSIDERS HIS HIS MOM.
>> HAVE I A COAT LIKE THAT.
I HAVE A COAT LIKE THAT.
>> LISA ARGEN IS HERE TALKING
ABOUT THE NEED FOR WARM COATS
THESE DAYS.
>> WE WON'T GET TOO WARM, BUT
WITH THE SUNSHINE AND ALL OF
THE CLOUDS WE HAVE MILDER
TEMPERATURES THIS, MONTH.
IF YOU ARE HEADED TO THE
RAIDERS GAME, LOW 50s WITH A
CHANCE OF A SHOWER.
ELSEWHERE ISOLATED SHOWERS
TODAY AND THE HEAVIER RAIN
TONIGHT INTO TOMORROW
MORNING'S CHUTE.
A BREAK MIDWEEK AND HEAVIER
RAIN ON THURSDAY, FRIDAY,
SATURDAY LOOKS LIKE BEYOND AS
WELL.
>> THAT IS GOING TO DO IT FOR
US.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US ON
THE ABC7 SUNDAY MORNING NEWS.
I'M CAROLYN TYLER ALONG WITH
LISA ARGEN, ABC7 NEWS
CONTINUES AT 5:00 THIS
AFTERNOON.
IF YOU ARE FORTUNATE ENOUGH TO
RECEIVE A NEW TABLET COMPUTER
OR SMART PHONE THIS HOLIDAY
SEASON, REMEMBER YOU CAN BE
CONNECTED WITH ABC7 NEWS ALL
THE TIME THROUGH OUR APP.
YOU CAN DOWNLOAD OUR POPULAR
ALARM CLOCK APP FOR YOUR
IPHONE, ANDROID OR
[ Boy 1 ] Hey!
That's the last Crescent.
Oh, did you want it?
Yea
We'll split it.
[ Female Announcer ]
Made fresh, so light,
buttery and flakey.
That's half
That's not half!
Guys, I have more!
Thanks Mom
[ Female Announcer ]
Pillsbury Crescents.
Let the Making Begin
[ Female Announcer ]
HOLIDAY COOKIES ARE A BIG JOB.
EVERYTHING HAS TO BE
JUST RIGHT.
PERFECTION IS IN THE DETAILS.
♪
GET TO HOLIDAY FUN FASTER
WITH PILLSBURY COOKIE DOUGH.
♪