DID YOU SEE YOUR WIFE
IN THAT ROOM?
PLUS AN EXCLUSIVE INTERVIEW
AND SNEAK PEEK
AT THE DRAMATIC NEXT SEASON
OF "THE BACHELOR"...
WHOO!
WITH SEAN LOWE.
AND THEN...
OH, MY GOODNESS!
AAH!
WHAT DID IT TAKE TO CREATE
THIS FANTASY WEDDING?
PREPARE YOURSELF.
THE LOOK...
(Ashley) I LOVE IT.
THE FLOWERS...
THIS IS SO BEAUTIFUL.
THE DRESS...
J.P. WILL LOVE IT.
AND MOST IMPORTANTLY,
WHAT WILL THEIR DOG BOO WEAR?
ARE YOU EXCITED FOR MOM AND DAD
TO GET MARRIED?
(growls and barks)
WE GOT OFF
ON INTERESTING TERMS.
BUT DOES EVERYONE TRULY SUPPORT
THEIR UPCOMING MARRIAGE?
(voice breaking)
I NEVER WANNA SEE HER HURT.
(Chris Harrison)
IS THERE ANYONE HERE TODAY
WHO OBJECTS TO THE MARRIAGE
OF THIS MAN AND THIS WOMAN?
IT ALL STARTS RIGHT NOW
ON THIS VERY SPECIAL EDITION
OF "THE BACHELORETTE"...
♪
(birds chirping)
HELLO, AND WELCOME
TO A VERY SPECIAL EDITION
OF "THE BACHELOR," CELEBRATING
ASHLEY AND J.P.'s WEDDING.
I'M CHRIS HARRISON.
THIS IS
OUR THIRD "BACHELOR" WEDDING.
FIRST, IT WAS TRISTA AND RYAN,
THEN JASON AND MOLLY,
AND TODAY HERE
AT THE LANGHAM HUNTINGTON HOTEL
IN PASADENA, CALIFORNIA,
ASHLEY AND J.P.
ARE GETTING MARRIED.
WE ARE VERY PROUD OF THAT.
I'M SURE YOU ALL KNOW
THAT THERE ARE NO GUARANTEES
WHEN IT COMES
TO MATTERS OF THE HEART.
SOMETIMES LOVE DOESN'T BLOSSOM,
BUT THIS SHOW IS
AND ALWAYS WILL BE
DEDICATED
TO HELPING PEOPLE FIND
MEANINGFUL,
LIFELONG RELATIONSHIPS,
AND I THINK "THE BACHELOR" HAS
BEEN VERY SUCCESSFUL AT THAT,
NOT ONLY WITH TRISTA AND RYAN,
JASON AND MOLLY,
AND ASHLEY AND J.P.,
BUT ALSO WITH
THE MANY OTHER MARRIED COUPLES
THAT HAVE FOUND LOVE
THROUGH OUR SHOW.
THERE'S HOLLY AND BLAKE,
DeANNA AND STEPHEN STAGLIANO,
JOHN PRESSER AND TARA DURR,
JESSE CSINCSAK AND ANN LUEDERS,
CHRIS LAMBTON AND PEYTON,
AND OF COURSE,
OUR NEW BACHELOR SEAN AND...
WELL, FOR THAT ONE, YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO WAIT AND SEE.
NOW SINCE THEIR FIRST MEETING
ON OUR SHOW,
ASHLEY AND J.P.'s RELATIONSHIP
REALLY HAS BEEN A FAIRY TALE,
AND THEY'VE ALREADY STARTED
BUILDING A LIFE TOGETHER.
SO BEFORE ALL
THE WEDDING EXCITEMENT BEGINS,
LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT THEIR JOURNEY TO FIND LOVE
AND HOW IT'S FOREVER
CHANGED THEIR LIVES.
♪
WHEN I DID "THE BACHELORETTE,"
I WAS SO NERVOUS
THAT FIRST NIGHT.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT.
♪
BUT THEN WHEN J.P. WALKED
OUT OF THE LIMO, I THOUGHT,
HOW DID I GET THIS LUCKY?
WOW. THAT DRESS IS STUNNING.
(laughs)
YOU'RE GORGEOUS. (kisses)
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
J.P.
J.P. NICE TO MEET YOU.
I'M ASHLEY.
HI, ASHLEY.
NICE TO MEET YOU, TOO.
J.P. WAS SO MUCH FUN.
HE REALLY PUT ME AT EASE.
THERE WAS SOMETHING BETWEEN US
THAT YOU COULD NOT DENY.
WE'RE GONNA FLIP A COIN
RIGHT NOW.
OKAY.
HEADS--I GET A KISS.
TAILS--I DON'T.
IT WAS JUST--
IT WAS LIKE LOVE AT FIRST SIGHT.
I KNEW THERE WAS
SOMETHING THERE.
(gasps)
DO YOU THINK YOU COULD SEE,
LIKE, US IN THE FUTURE?
LIKE A NORMAL
EVERYDAY LIFE?
YEAH. LIKE, I KINDA FEEL
THAT'S HOW IT IS NOW.
LIKE, THIS IS THE TIME
THAT I LOVE.
EVERY TIME I WAS WITH J.P.,
I JUST WANTED MORE,
AND I WANTED MORE.
WHEN WE KISSED,
THERE WERE SPARKS.
I'M NOT JOKING.
THERE WAS JUST SPARKS,
SPARKS, SPARKS.
WE TRAVELED ALL OVER THE WORLD
TOGETHER,
AND WE WENT
ON THESE AMAZING DATES,
AND EVERYTHING WAS PERFECT.
WHAT ARE YOU THINKING?
THAT THERE'S NO PLACE ON EARTH
I'D RATHER BE RIGHT NOW.
HANDS DOWN,
THERE WAS NO QUESTION IN MY MIND
SHE'S THE ONE.
SHE'S ALWAYS BEEN THE ONE.
(Ashley) SOMETIMES I LOOK BACK
AND I WONDER HOW
WE EVER GOT TO THIS POINT.
WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT
THAT THIS WOULD BE OUR LIFE,
THAT WE WOULD MEET
IN SUCH A ROMANTIC WAY,
AND REALLY, TRULY HAVE
THIS FAIRY TALE RELATIONSHIP?
(J.P.) I KNEW I LOVED HER,
AND I KNEW I WANTED HER
IN MY LIFE.
I KNEW I COULDN'T PICTURE
MY LIFE WITHOUT HER.
THERE'S NO ONE ELSE I EVER
WOULD WANNA BE WITH.
YOU ALWAYS SAY TO ME,
YOU'RE SMILING ALL THE TIME.
YOU'RE GONNA HAVE WRINKLES
WHEN YOU'RE OLDER.
WELL,
I SMILE BECAUSE OF YOU.
YOU BRING THAT OUT.
WHAT I DO KNOW
FOR ABSOLUTE CERTAIN
IS THAT I AM
MADLY IN LOVE WITH YOU.
ASHLEY...
WILL YOU MARRY ME?
YES.
(Ashley) ONE OF THE FEARS
THAT I HAD WAS
ARE THINGS GONNA CHANGE ONCE
WE GET BACK TO THE REAL WORLD?
WHO KNEW THAT WHEN WE GOT BACK
TO OUR EVERYDAY LIFE,
THINGS WOULD JUST KEEP GETTING
BETTER AND BETTER AND BETTER?
♪
BOTH J.P. AND I LOVE WHAT WE DO.
I LOVE
MY PEDIATRIC DENTAL RESIDENCY
IN PHILADELPHIA.
YOU READY TO GET
YOUR TEETH CLEANED?
YEAH?
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO.
CAN I GET TWO APPLES?
OKAY. THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THANK YOU.
(Ashley) J.P. LOVES WORKING
IN CONSTRUCTION MANAGEMENT
IN NEW YORK CITY.
WOW, SWEETIE,
EVERYTHING LOOKS REALLY GOOD.
BUT WE KNEW WE WANTED
TO BE TOGETHER,
SO WE COMPROMISED,
SPLIT THE DIFFERENCE,
AND WE LIVE
IN PRINCETON, NEW JERSEY.
♪
COME ON.
IT'S REALLY GOOD.
(laughs) THAT'S OH--
OUR LIFE IN PRINCETON
IS SO RELAXED.
I FEEL LIKE IT ALLOWS US
TO JUST KIND OF FOCUS
ON EACH OTHER,
FOCUS ON THE RELATIONSHIP.
I FEEL LIKE LIVING IN PRINCETON
MAKES YOU WANNA START
A FAMILY A LOT SOONER, TOO.
♪
(whines)
WHEN J.P. FIRST MET ME,
HE HAD NO IDEA.
I'M A PACKAGE DEAL.
DO YOU THINK
DAD LOVES US?
DO YOU THINK HE LOVES US?
YOU BETTER LOVE MY DOG,
'CAUSE SHE'S REAL CUTE.
AND YOU KNOW WHAT?
IF SHE DOESN'T LIKE YOU,
IT'S OVER.
TAKE THE RING BACK.
DOWN.
I DIDN'T SAY "ROLL" YET.
(barks)
I NEVER THOUGHT OF MYSELF
AS A "LITTLE DOG" PERSON
LET ALONE A DOG PERSON.
LET'S SAY DURING THE CEREMONY
SHE WEARS A TUTU.
(whimpers)
AND THEN DURING THE RECEPTION,
WE TAKE IT OFF
SO SHE CAN DANCE.
(laughs)
NO TUTU.
LIFE REVOLVES AROUND BOO.
(growls and whimpers)
(laughs)
GOOD THING SHE LIKED HIM.
YOU'RE VERY CUTE.
(giggles)
SOME PEOPLE SAY THAT HAPPINESS
IS FINDING SOMETHING TO DO,
SOMETHING TO LIVE FOR,
AND SOMEONE TO LOVE,
AND I FEEL SO HAPPY
BECAUSE I FOUND ALL THREE.
ALL RIGHT. I THINK
I WANT THIS ONE UP HERE.
(grunts)
(branch snaps)
GET A GOOD ONE?
(deep voice) UHH!
THERE'S A LADYBUG
ON THE INSIDE OF IT.
ASHLEY AND I HAVE A FAIRY TALE
TO TELL.
I MEAN, IT'S--IT'S--
IT'S THE ULTIMATE STORY.
LIKE, WHAT ARE THE ODDS?
LIKE, THIS IS--THIS IS FOR REAL
AND FOREVER.
AND ONE DAY WHEN WE HAVE KIDS
WHERE THEY'RE GONNA ASK,
"WELL,
HOW'D YOU AND MOMMY MEET?"
I'M GONNA BE LIKE,
"HAVE A SEAT."
(pats leg)
(Ashley) I CAN'T WAIT
FOR OUR WEDDING DAY.
I CAN'T WAIT TO MARRY J.P.
I CAN'T WAIT TO TELL HIM
HOW MUCH I LOVE HIM.
IF I HADN'T TAKEN THAT RISK
TO GO ON "THE BACHELORETTE"
AND LEAVE MY LIFE BEHIND ME,
I NEVER WOULD HAVE MET J.P.,
AND I NEVER WOULD BE HERE,
AND MY LIFE WOULD NOT BE NEARLY
AS RICH AS IT IS TODAY.
GOTTA GO.
I LOVE YOU, BABY.
COMING UP...
IT'S AN ALL-STAR
"BACHELOR" REUNION
WITH EMILY, JASON AND MOLLY,
JILLIAN,
AND ALI AND ROBERTO?
AND WHAT GOES INTO PLANNING
A FANTASY WEDDING?
DO YOU WANT THE WEDDING PARTY
TO STAND UP THERE?
HAVE YOU THOUGHT
ABOUT YOUR FIRST DANCE?
WHAT KIND OF FOOD
DO YOU WANT TO SERVE?
THIS MIGHT BE A LITTLE HARDER
THAN WE THOUGHT.
AND LATER, IT'S THE MOMENT
WE'VE ALL BEEN WAITING FOR,
WHEN J.P. AND ASHLEY EXCHANGE
THEIR EMOTIONAL WEDDING VOWS.
IT'S ALL COMING UP RIGHT NOW
ON THIS SPECIAL EDITION
OF "THE BACHELORETTE."
[ Male Announcer ]
EVERYONE LOVES TO DUNK.
♪
[ Game announcer ]
WILL HE DUNK IT?
YES, HE WILL.
[ Male Announcer ] McDonald's
TENDER, JUICY Chicken McNuggets
IN CREAMY RANCH
AND SPICY BUFFALO SAUCE.
JUST $4.99
FOR 20 OF YOUR FAVORITE
Chicken McNuggets.
♪
[ Game announcer ]
WILL HE DUNK IT?
YES, HE WILL.
[ Male Announcer ]
MORE WAYS TO LOVE McNuggets.
♪
TILL YOU FINISH YOUR VEGETABLES.
[ clock ticking ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THERE'S A BETTER WAY...
V8 V-FUSION.
VEGETABLE NUTRITION THEY NEED,
FRUIT TASTE THEY LOVE.
COULD'VE HAD A V8.
OR...TRY KIDS BOXES!
♪
WELCOME BACK
TO THIS VERY SPECIAL EDITION
OF "THE BACHELOR:
ASHLEY & J.P.'s WEDDING."
IT'S BEEN AN EXCITING JOURNEY
FOR ASHLEY AND J.P.
TO GET TO THIS MOMENT
HERE TODAY.
BUT FIRST, THEY HAD TO TELL
THEIR FAMILIES
THAT THE LONG WAIT
WAS FINALLY OVER
AND THAT THEY WERE ACTUALLY
GETTING MARRIED.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
♪
(Ashley) THERE'S SO MUCH THAT
GOES INTO PLANNING A WEDDING,
BUT THE FIRST THING
WE NEED TO DO
IS TELL OUR FAMILY
THAT WE FINALLY SET A DATE.
WE'RE MEETING BOTH OF
OUR FAMILIES HERE IN MANHATTAN,
AND I CAN'T WAIT FOR EVERYBODY
TO SHARE OUR GOOD NEWS.
(J.P.) HEY, EVERYBODY.
(all) HEY!
(J.P.) WE ARE CRAZY EXCITED
ABOUT IT BECAUSE
THEY'VE BEEN--I WOULDN'T SAY
THEY'VE BEEN NAGGING US,
BUT THEY'VE BEEN ANXIOUS
TO FIND OUT WHEN IT'S GONNA BE,
AND IT'S GONNA BE A GOOD DAY.
I LOVE J.P.'s FAMILY SO MUCH.
HIS MOTHER ILENE IS THE SWEETEST
WOMAN I'VE EVER MET.
PETER, HIS FATHER,
IS A BIG, LOVABLE TEDDY BEAR.
AND MY FAMILY'S HERE TODAY,
TOO--
MY MOTHER LAURIE
AND MY STEPFATHER MIKE.
SO WE DO HAVE SOME
REALLY, REALLY SPECIAL NEWS,
AND WE'RE SO EXCITED
TO SHARE IT WITH YOU GUYS.
FIRST, UM--
(man)
PREGNANT, PREGNANT, PREGNANT.
(Ashley) OH!
(laughter)
I'M PREGNANT.
J.P.'s PREGNANT! NO.
UM... SO WE HAVE...
SET A WEDDING DATE!
(cheering)
YAY. OH, MY GOD.
WE HAVE SET A WEDDING DATE
FOR DECEMBER 1st THIS YEAR...
(Ilene) OH.
IN BEAUTIFUL, SUNNY, CALIFORNIA.
OKAY.
WE'RE SO EXCITED, AND WE'RE
SO HAPPY TO SHARE IT WITH YOU.
WE LOVE YOU GUYS SO MUCH,
AND WE HOPE THAT YOU'LL BE
A VERY SPECIAL PART OF OUR DAY.
WE LOVE YOU8 SO MUCH.
(man) YEAH.
J.P.'s FAMILY,
THANK YOU GUYS SO MUCH
FOR TAKING ME IN
LIKE ONE OF YOUR OWN.
OF COURSE.
UM, I FELL IN LOVE WITH J.P.,
BUT I REALLY FELL IN LOVE
WITH EACH--EACH OF YOU.
MOM AND MIKE,
I LOVE YOU GUYS SO MUCH,
AND YOU GUYS HAVE ALWAYS
BEEN THERE FOR ME...
(voice breaking)
AND I'M SO THANKFUL.
I REALLY LOVE YOU.
YOU SHOULD TAKE OVER NOW.
(laughs)
(laughter)
I COULD NOT HAVE ASKED
FOR A BETTER SET OF IN-LAWS.
UH, YOU GUYS HAVE BEEN
SUPPORTIVE
SINCE THE DAY WE GOT BACK,
AND I REALLY, REALLY
APPRECIATE IT.
AND YOU GAVE THIS A CHANCE,
AND FROM THE BOTTOM
OF MY HEART, THANK YOU.
(Ashley) WE LOVE YOU GUYS!
(laughter)
(Ilene) YAY, YAY.
(J.P.) OUR FAMILIES COME
FROM DIFFERENT PLACES,
AND WE DON'T GET TO SPEND
THAT MUCH TIME TOGETHER
AS ONE BIG FAMILY,
BUT WHEN WE DO,
IT IS NOTHING BUT SMILES
AND FUN,
AND EVERYONE IS JUST--
IT'S--IT'S HOW FAMILY SHOULD BE.
(Peter) HERE'S TO CALIFORNIA.
(glasses clink)
CHEERS.
YEAH.
I'D LIKE TO SAY A TOAST
TO ASHLEY AND J.P.
(J.P.) WHEN I FIRST MET
ASHLEY'S SISTER,
IT DIDN'T... (laughs)
IT DIDN'T GO AS WELL
AS I HOPED IT WOULD GO.
I'M SKEPTICAL OF, I THINK,
YOUR RELATIONSHIP TOGETHER.
AT FIRST GLANCE
AND SEEING YOU TOGETHER,
I DON'T SEE IT.
I WAS TOTALLY NOT
EXPECTING THAT. (chuckles)
NEITHER WAS I.
♪
WE MAY HAVE GOT OFF
ON VERY... INTERESTING TERMS.
BUT I FULLY ADMIT THAT I WAS
WRONG AT MY FIRST IMPRESSION,
AND I AM SO GLAD
THAT I AM WRONG,
BECAUSE SEEING YOU TWO
IN THE LAST TWO YEARS
HAS JUST PROVEN ME WRONG
EACH AND EVERY DAY,
AND WE ARE VERY PROUD
AND EXCITED
TO ATTEND YOUR WEDDING
AND OFFICIALLY MAKE
ASHLEY ROSENBAUM.
(all) AW! CHEERS!
(clinks)
(Ilene) THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
(woman) YEAH.
(laughter)
YOU WERE RIGHT
ABOUT ONE THING.
WHAT'S THAT?
I CAN'T HANDLE HER.
(laughter)
THANK YOU.
WHEN MY SISTER FIRST MET J.P.,
SHE DIDN'T THINK THAT
HE WAS THE ONE FOR ME,
AND NOW SHE KNOWS
I WAS RIGHT.
SHE DOESN'T EVER SAY...
(laughter)
AND SHE BETTER MAKE
ONE DAMN GOOD SPEECH
ABOUT MY FIANCE
AND HOW SWEET HE IS.
THIS IS JUST GREAT.
YEAH, WE WERE EXCITED
TO TELL EVERYBODY.
IT'S REALLY--
IT'S VERY EXCITING.
THEY'RE GOOD TOGETHER.
WE LOVE ASHLEY.
WE LOVE J.P.,
AND WHAT EVERY PARENT WANTS
IS FOR THEM TO SEE THEIR--
THEIR CHILD HAPPY.
YOU DID GOOD.
(laughs)
(laughs) NOW I'M GONNA CRY.
DON'T CRY.
OKAY.
(laughs)
OKAY. I'M HAPPY FOR YOU.
WE JUST WANT TO GET NOW
THE PLANNING OUT OF THE WAY,
SO WE CAN...
I KNOW.
HAVE FUN AND PARTY.
IT'S GONNA BE A GOOD TIME.
IT'LL BE A WONDERFUL WEDDING.
YOU ARE SO HAPPY,
AND YOU ARE SO IN LOVE,
AND DAD AND I ARE THRILLED
TO DEATH FOR YOU.
A LOT OF GOOD THINGS GOING ON.
AND IT'S FUN.
THE WHOLE THING IS FUN.
COMING UP--ASHLEY AND J.P.
ARE IN FOR A SHOCK
WHEN THEY MEET
WITH THEIR WEDDING PLANNER
FOR THE FIRST TIME.
AND THEN SOME OF YOUR FAVORITE
BACHELORS AND BACHELORETTES
WILL BE HERE, AND WE'LL TALK
TO 'EM AS THEY ARRIVE.
IT'S ALL COMING UP WHEN
THIS SPECIAL WEDDING EDITION
OF "THE BACHELOR" RETURNS.
ARE YOU THE PERFECT MATCH
FOR THE NEXT BACHELOR
OR BACHELORETTE,
GO TO abc.com
AND CLICK "APPLY."
often comes with a set
of equally impressive
instructions ?
Shouldn't something
that's truly advanced,
not need much explanation
at all ?
With the Nokia Lumia 822
on Verizon,
there's not much to learn
because it's
powered by Windows...
to let you do more than you ever
imagined on your smartphone.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes
the most of your plan.
Only on Verizon.
THE Subway
WESTERN EGG & CHEESE
IS THE FEATURED $5 FOOTLONG
OF DECEMBER!
FRESH TOASTED
WITH BLACK FOREST HAM,
PEPPERS, ONIONS
AND AVAILABLE ALL DAY
STARTING AT 7AM.
HURRY, IT'S A $5 FOOTLONG
THIS DECEMBER ONLY.
Subway. EAT FRESH.
I made the clear choice.
Claritin-D.
Decongestant products on
the shelf can take hours
to start working.
Claritin-D starts to work in
just 30 minutes.
Power through
nasal congestion fast.
Get Claritin-D
at the pharmacy counter.
WELCOME BACK
TO THIS SPECIAL EDITION
OF "THE BACHELOR:
ASHLEY & J.P.'s WEDDING."
THERE'S A LOT
GOING ON HERE TODAY
AT THE LANGHAM HUNTINGTON HOTEL
IN PASADENA,
AS THE FINAL PREPARATIONS
FOR THE WEDDING
ARE STILL TAKING PLACE.
AND ASHLEY AND J.P. FOUND OUT
JUST HOW COMPLICATED
PLANNING THE PERFECT WEDDING
CAN BE
WHEN THEY MET
WITH THEIR WEDDING PLANNER
FOR THE FIRST TIME.
♪
ARE YOU EXCITED?
I'M A LITTLE NERVOUS
TO MEET MINDY.
REALLY? WHY?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT SEEMS LIKE A BIG DEAL.
SHE IS A BIG DEAL,
KINDA LIKE YOU.
YEAH, TRUE.
(laughs)
J.P. MIGHT LET ON LIKE
HE'S NOT INTO WEDDING PLANNING
AND DECOR AND DESIGN,
BUT I ACTUALLY THINK THAT HE'S
REALLY LOOKING FORWARD TO TODAY.
THIS IS OUR DAY,
BUT IT'S HER DAY,
AND I WANT HER TO GET EVERYTHING
THAT SHE WANTS.
LET'S GET THIS STARTED.
WE'RE SO EXCITED TO MEET YOU.
MINDY WEISS
IS OUR WEDDING PLANNER,
AND SHE'S DONE WEDDINGS
FOR ELLEN DeGENERES,
GWEN STEFANI,
AND SO MANY MORE CELEBRITIES.
I'M SO EXCITED TO TELL HER
ALL OF OUR IDEAS.
SO LET'S TALK ABOUT
THE CEREMONY A LITTLE...
OKAY.
JUST TO GET YOUR VISION.
I'VE DONE HUNDREDS OF WEDDINGS,
AND I ALWAYS LOVE TO SEE--
ARE THEY GONNA BE
ON THE SAME PAGE?
ARE THEY GONNA DISAGREE?
SO THIS IS KIND OF A TEST
TO SEE WHAT THEIR VISIONS ARE
AND HOW THEY'RE GONNA HANDLE
THEIR DIFFERENCES.
WHAT IS
YOUR PERSONAL STYLE?
YOU KNOW, I DON'T LIKE
TOO MANY PATTERNS,
OR I DON'T LIKE ANYTHING
THAT'S TOO BUSY.
I LIKE SIMPLE, CLEAN.
SO VERY...
FEMININE, NEUTRAL.
AND THEN HOW DO
WE MIX YOU IN THERE?
YEAH.
I'M LOW-MAINTENANCE.
UM, I'M EASY TO PLEASE.
AND WHEN HER FACE LIGHTS UP
EXPLAINING THIS STUFF,
IT GETS ME EXCITED ABOUT IT.
OH, THAT'S SO AWESOME. YEAH.
I THINK THAT'S PROBABLY
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING.
YEAH.
AND WHAT ABOUT COLORS?
IN MY HEAD, I HAD
A VISION OF A CHAMPAGNE
IN A VERY, VERY LIGHT--
NOT PINK...
BUT...
BUT LIKE A DUSTY ROSE.
WITH JUST A LITTLE COLOR
IN THERE.
LITTLE COLOR, YEAH.
OKAY.
YOU GOOD WITH THAT?
SOFT. SOFT.
I AM GOOD WITH THAT.
OKAY.
(Ashley) SO FAR, SO GOOD.
I CAN'T BELIEVE HOW WELL
THIS MEETING'S GOING.
NOW THAT I'M HERE WITH MINDY,
I FEEL LIKE THIS IS GONNA BE
A WHOLE LOT EASIER
THAN I THOUGHT.
AS FAR AS--ARE YOU GONNA
HAVE A CHUPPAH,
OR DO YOU WANT IT?
ARE YOU GONNA BRING IN SOME
OF THE JEWISH TRADITIONS?
YES, WE'RE GONNA HAVE A CHUPPAH.
RIGHT.
UH, WE'LL DO
THE BREAKING OF THE GLASS.
OH, GOOD.
DO YOU HAVE BRIDESMAIDS?
YES.
HOW MANY BRIDESMAIDS?
I THINK WE SETTLED ON NINE.
NINE ON EACH SIDE.
OKAY.
AND WE WOULD LOVE FOR OUR DOG
TO BE A PART OF IT.
SHE'S A LITTLE YORKIE,
ABOUT 4 POUNDS, REALLY SWEET.
WHAT'S HER NAME?
BOO.
OF COURSE IT IS.
(both laugh)
WE KNOW ALL THE PIECES,
BUT WE DON'T KNOW HOW
TO PUT 'EM TOGETHER.
THAT'S WHY MINDY'S HERE.
AND HOW OLD
ARE THE FLOWER GIRLS?
UM, 6 AND 8.
DO YOU WANT THE WEDDING PARTY
TO STAND UP THERE?
I THINK SO. WE HAVEN'T
REALLY THOUGHT ABOUT THAT.
AND HAVE YOU THOUGHT
ABOUT YOUR FIRST DANCE
AND WHAT YOU MIGHT WANNA...
I'M STARTING TO REALIZE THAT
THERE ARE WHOLE LOT OF THINGS
THAT WE HAVEN'T EVEN CONSIDERED.
THIS MIGHT BE A LITTLE HARDER
THAN WE THOUGHT.
HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT WOOD TABLES?
DO YOU LIKE THAT LOOK?
OH, I LIKE THAT.
YOU LOVE A DEEJAY
AS OPPOSED TO A BAND?
I DIDN'T EVEN THINK
OF THAT OPTION.
MAYBE YOU START OFF
WITH A BAND.
AND WERE YOU THINKING AT ALL
ABOUT A PARTY FAVOR?
IS THAT IMPORTANT TO YOU?
AH, THIS IS--
THIS IS YOUR CALL.
AS FAR AS THE CAKE,
I NEED PICTURES.
WHAT KIND OF FOOD
DO YOU WANNA SERVE?
HAVE YOU THOUGHT ABOUT,
LIKE, WHAT YOU MIGHT LIKE
TO GIVE
TO YOUR WEDDING PARTY?
(sighs) (bleep)
THIS IS GOOD.
I CAN ALREADY TELL.
YEAH.
THIS IS GOOD. YEAH.
♪
WOW. IT'S ALL BECOMING
SO REAL.
I KNOW. TODAY IT WAS
KIND OF A STEPPING-STONE,
LIKE... TO MEET MINDY
AND THE WEDDING INVITATIONS,
AND... IT'S--IT'S ALL
STARTING TO COME TOGETHER.
ARE YOU NERVOUS?
NO.
ARE YOU GETTING COLD FEET,
BABE?
NEVER.
(laughs)
THAT'S ONE THING ABOUT THIS--
ABOUT EVERYTHING
THAT WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH.
I HAVE NEVER BEEN NERVOUS
ABOUT US FOR A SECOND.
I'M HAPPIER THAN I'VE EVER BEEN
IN MY ENTIRE LIFE.
AW. THANKS, BABE.
I REALLY, HONESTLY
CANNOT WAIT TO MARRY YOU.
AND I CAN'T WAIT ALSO.
I LOVE YOU.
(clink)
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
WE LOVE EACH OTHER SO MUCH,
BUT WE'RE SO PLAYFUL,
THAT I CANNOT WAIT TO JUST BE
STANDING IN FRONT OF HIM
IN FRONT OF
ALL OF OUR FRIENDS AND FAMILY
AND DECLARING MY LOVE TO HIM
IN THE MOST SERIOUS
AND ROMANTIC AND SINCERE WAY.
DO YOU REMEMBER...
WHAT WE DID IN TAIWAN?
A LITTLE BIT
OF FORESHADOWING.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
(J.P.) ONE OF OUR GROUP DATES
ON "THE BACHELORETTE"
WAS IN TAIWAN, WHERE WE WENT
AND TOOK WEDDING PHOTOS,
AND I KNEW I LIKED HER.
I MEAN, I KNEW THERE WAS
SOMETHING SPECIAL.
DO YOU THINK
THAT THIS IS GONNA--
OH! (laughs)
THAT OUR WEDDING PICTURES
ARE GONNA COME OUT THE SAME?
OH, MY GOSH, BABY!
IS THIS OUR UNOFFICIAL
WEDDING PICTURE? (laughs)
IT KINDA IS.
DID YOU KNOW AT THAT POINT?
YOU COULD SAY "NO."
YES.
YEAH.
(laughs) WHY DO YOU THINK
YOU WERE WEARING THAT SUIT?
(both laugh)
THAT WAS
A YEAR AND A HALF AGO.
YEP.
WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT?
(J.P.) I WAS NEVER
A HUGE BELIEVER OF FATE,
BUT WHAT ARE THE ODDS
THAT I MEET
THE WOMAN OF MY DREAMS
THE WAY I MET HER?
I MEAN, THERE'S NOT A DAY
THAT GOES BY--
HONESTLY,
NOT A DAY THAT GOES BY
THAT I DON'T THINK ABOUT...
HOW LUCKY I AM.
I LOVE YOU, BOO.
I LOVE YOU, TOO, BABE.
COMING UP...
IT'S WHAT EVERY BRIDE
DREAMS ABOUT.
(Ashley) ARE YOU GUYS READY?
OH! (laughs)
(Ilene) OH, MY GOSH.
J.P. WILL LOVE IT.
BUT SHE'S NOT THE ONLY ONE
WALKING DOWN THE AISLE
IN HER DREAM DRESS.
OH. OHH! OH, BOO.
OH, COME ON!
AND LATER, WHAT TRISTA AND RYAN
AND JASON AND MOLLY
HAVE TO SAY ABOUT
OUR NEW BACHELOR, SEAN.
HIS ABS LOOK AMAZING.
(all laugh)
IT'S ALL COMING UP WHEN
"ASHLEY & J.P.'s WEDDING"
CONTINUES.
OTHER GIRLS WISH
TO SIMPLY GROW UP.
MAE AND BAILEY ARE FRIENDS
BATTLING KIDNEY CANCER
AT ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S
RESEARCH HOSPITAL.
WE DEVELOPED A TREATMENT FOR
THEIR CANCER THAT'S HELPING
KIDS LIKE THEM ACROSS AMERICA.
YOU KNOW WHAT I WISH FOR?
WHAT'S THAT HONEY?
MY HAIR BACK.
AND NO MORE CANCER.
WELL, GIRLS, ST. JUDE
IS WORKING ON THAT.
GO TO ST. JUDE DOT ORG
OR SHOP WHERE EVER YOU SEE
THE ST. JUDE LOGO.
♪
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
SHE'S NOT FAMOUS.
♪
SHE'S NEVER BEEN
ON A RED CARPET.
♪
BUT SHE'S THE STAR OF MY LIFE.
[ Female Announcer ]
KAY JEWELERS PRESENTS
A NEW COLLECTION
FROM HOLLYWOOD'S
PREMIER JEWELRY DESIGNER --
NEIL LANE DESIGNS.
MY DESIGNS ARE INSPIRED
BY HOLLYWOOD'S GLAMOROUS PAST.
[ Female Announcer ]
HAND-CRAFTED DIAMOND RINGS,
EARRINGS, AND NECKLACES
WITH A VINTAGE LOOK.
AT KAY, THE NUMBER-ONE
JEWELRY STORE IN AMERICA.
FOR THE STAR IN YOUR LIFE.
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
♪ SPREAD A LITTLE LOVE MY WAY
♪ SPREAD A LITTLE SOMETHING
TO REMEMBER ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
PHILADELPHIA CREAM CHEESE.
WITH FRESH MILK
AND REAL CREAM.
IT MAKES YOUR HOLIDAY RECIPES,
EVERYONE'S HOLIDAY FAVORITES.
♪
(birds chirping)
WELCOME BACK TO "THE BACHELOR:
ASHLEY & J.P.'s WEDDING."
THE LAST MINUTE TOUCHES
ARE BEING PUT IN PLACE--
THE FLOWERS, THE STAGE ITSELF.
THE GUESTS ARE GATHERING.
WE'RE GETTING CLOSER
TO THE MOMENT
WHEN ASHLEY AND J.P.
WILL EXCHANGE THEIR WEDDING VOWS
AND BECOME HUSBAND AND WIFE.
BUT FIRST, ASHLEY AND J.P.
GOT A SPECIAL SNEAK PEEK
AT WHAT THIS WEDDING
MIGHT LOOK LIKE.
♪
READY?
YEAH.
(Ashley) WHEN WE FIRST SAT DOWN
WITH MINDY,
WE EXPLAINED TO HER
WHAT WE HAD ENVISIONED
FOR OUR WEDDING DAY.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S PRETTY.
WE'RE SO EXCITED TO FINALLY SEE
HOW SHE PUT HER OWN TWIST
ON THINGS.
♪
OH, MY GOODNESS!
AAH! HI!
(Ashley) WALKING INTO THIS ROOM,
I AM BLOWN AWAY.
I CAN'T BELIEVE HOW MUCH MINDY
HAS PUT TOGETHER SINCE WE MET.
OH, MY GOODNESS. THIS IS...
LOOK AT THE CHANDELIERS.
I AM DYING.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
PREPARE YOURSELF.
SO MANY THINGS
ARE CATCHING MY EYE--
THE TABLES, THE SEATING.
I SEE THE CAKE IN THE DISTANCE.
I CANNOT WAIT TO SEE EVERYTHING,
BUT FIRST,
I NEED TO SEE THE FLOWERS.
EVERY GIRL WANTS TO SEE
THE FLOWERS.
(singsongy) THIS IS MARK.
HEY, MINDY,
HOW ARE YOU?
(Mindy)
WHEN IT COMES TO FLOWERS,
I'VE WORKED WITH MARK
FROM MARK'S GARDEN.
WHEN YOU THINK OF A WEDDING,
YOU THINK OF FLOWERS.
THIS IS ONE EXAMPLE.
I KNOW YOU LIKE THE WHITES
AND THE CREAMS.
YES.
THIS IS YOUR WHITE FLOWERS,
YOUR CREAM FLOWERS,
BUT WE PUNCHED IT UP
WITH A LITTLE BIT OF GREEN,
LIKE THESE
GREAT GREEN ROSES.
THEY'RE JADE ROSES.
WOW.
(Ashley)
THE FLOWERS ARE JUST BEYOND
ANYTHING THAT
WE COULD HAVE EVER THOUGHT.
I MEAN, THIS IS JUST CRAZY.
SO BEAUTIFUL.
I'VE NEVER SEEN, LIKE,
WEDDING CLOTHES FOR DOGS BEFORE.
(gasps)
(laughs)
(Mindy)
ASHLEY AND J.P.'s DOG BOO
IS SO IMPORTANT TO THEM,
SO I'VE SET UP
A LITTLE FASHION SHOW TABLE
OF DIFFERENT STYLES THAT
BOO COULD WEAR AT THE WEDDING.
THEY USE ALL VINTAGE.
THAT'S GREAT.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
LOOK AT THIS TRAIN.
THEY USE ALL VINTAGE.
THIS IS $7,500...
COME ON.
FOR JUST THIS LITTLE--
I MEAN, THAT'S MORE
THAN MY BRIDES' WEDDING GOWNS.
THIS IS ALL FOR YOU, BOO.
YES, ALL OF IT.
LET'S JUST SEE WHAT
IT LOOKS LIKE.
A LITTLE VEIL...
(speaks indistinctly)
OH, MY GOD. (laughs)
OH! BOO.
OH, COME ON.
THERE CAN ONLY BE ONE BRIDE,
I'M TELLING YOU.
LOOK HOW PRETTY SHE IS.
THERE COULD BE ONLY--
YOU WANNA TRY
SOMETHING ELSE?
GOOD JOB.
LOOK AT THE TRAIN, BOO.
(laughs) OH, MY GOD.
OKAY,
MAYBE IT'S A LITTLE MUCH.
(laughs) IT'S A LITTLE MUCH.
IT MIGHT BE A LITTLE MUCH.
ARE YOU EXCITED FOR MOM AND DAD
TO GET MARRIED?
SO WE HAVE THREE
DIFFERENT PACKAGES HERE
OF YOUR FORGET-ME-NOTS.
WE WANTED TO BE ABLE TO SHARE
OUR LOVE WITH OUR GUESTS,
SO WE DECIDED TO HAND OUT
FORGET-ME-NOTS
FOR EACH ONE OF OUR GUESTS
AND FOR THEM TO TAKE IT HOME
AND PLANT IT
IN THEIR OWN GARDENS,
AND HOPEFULLY HAVE THE LOVE
BLOOMING FOREVER.
READ THE POEM WE WROTE FOR YOU
IF YOU CAN READ THAT.
(clears throat)
"PLEASE PLANT
THESE FORGET-ME-NOTS
"TO MAKE SURE THIS EVENING
IS NOT FORGOTTEN.
"MAY THEY GROW FOREVER
AND FLOWERS YOU WILL SEE,
GIVEN WITH LOVE
BY ASHLEY AND J.P."
(gasps)
THAT IS BEAUTIFUL.
DO YOU LIKE THAT?
"PLEASE--"
NO MORE TEARS.
(laughs)
YOU GONNA CRY?
NO.
YOU SURE? IT'S OKAY.
YOU CAN CRY.
I MIGHT--I MIGHT CRY.
THAT IS REALLY BEAUTIFUL.
NO, IT'S OKAY.
THERE WAS SOMETHING SO SURREAL
ABOUT STANDING AT THAT TABLE,
MINDY TO MY LEFT,
J.P. TO MY RIGHT,
AND THEN JUST READING THAT POEM.
I DON'T KNOW.
THE WORDS WERE JUST SO SPECIAL.
I LOVE IT. I LOVE IT.
YEAH.
EVERYTHING ABOUT TODAY HAS BEEN
BEYOND WHAT WE COULD HAVE
EVER DREAMED.
OKAY, HERE'S
THE REALLY GOOD PART, GUYS...
AH. (laughs)
THAT USUALLY THE GROOMS LIKE.
YUMMY.
YOU GUYS SIT OVER THERE.
OKAY.
ASHLEY DIDN'T WANT
JUST ONE CAKE, OF COURSE,
AND--AND ME BEING THE FOODIE
THAT I AM,
GIVE ME A DOZEN CAKES.
I MEAN, IT DOESN'T MATTER.
MMM!
RED VELVET'S KINDA ONE
OF THE MORE POPULAR CAKES.
I THINK CUTTING INTO
THE RED VELVET MAKES SENSE
'CAUSE IT'S RED
AND IT'S EYE-CATCHING.
VIS--
IT'S VISUAL.
VISUALLY, IT'S A--
IT'S FILLED WITH LOVE.
FILLED WITH LOVE.
(mouth full) MM. YOU'RE GONNA
HAVE TO STOP ME, BY THE WAY.
I'M GONNA HAVE ONE MORE.
I NEED TO MAKE SURE THAT THIS
ONE IS GOOD. I WASN'T SURE.
I'M GONNA TRY IT AGAIN.
OKAY, SO I'M GONNA
LEAVE YOU GUYS.
EAT THE REST OF THE CAKE.
(both laugh)
I HAVE A LOT OF WORK TO DO NOW
TO PUT ALL THIS TOGETHER...
(singsongy)
AND I'LL SEE YOU GUYS SOON.
ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, MINDY.
THANK YOU FOR EVERYTHING.
THANK YOU.
WITH PLANNING A WEDDING,
OBVIOUSLY, THERE ARE
A LOT OF STRESSES.
JUST KNOWING THAT MINDY HAS DONE
SUCH A FABULOUS JOB,
WE CAN REALLY FOCUS IN
ON THE MOST IMPORTANT PART
OF THE DAY,
WHICH IS
BECOMING HUSBAND AND WIFE.
I FEEL LIKE IT'S ALL BECOMING
SO REAL NOW.
I KNOW WE SAY THAT
EVERY TIME...
I KNOW.
WE MOVE A STEP FURTHER,
BUT THIS IS--
IT'S COMING TO LIFE.
I FEEL LIKE EVERY TIME
WE SEE MINDY,
IT FEELS...
THAT MUCH MORE REAL.
I KNOW.
SHE--SHE KINDA TIES
EVERYTHING TOGETHER
AND BRINGS EVERYTHING
WE THINK ABOUT TO LIFE.
RIGHT.
I DO HAVE ONE MORE IMPORTANT
QUESTION FOR YOU, THOUGH.
WHAT?
CAN I HAVE MORE CAKE?
(laughs) I GUESS.
TO TELL REAL PEOPLE ABOUT
OUR NEW 15 UNDER $15 MENU.
OH MY GOODNESS!
OH MY GOSH,
THIS LOOKS AMAZING!
[ Male Announcer ]
OUR NEW MAINE STAYS!
15 ENTREES UNDER $15,
SEAFOOD, CHICKEN AND MORE!
OO! THE TILAPIA
WITH ROASTED VEGETABLES!
I'M ACTUALLY LOOKING AT
THE WOOD GRILLED CHICKEN
WITH PORTOBELLO WINE SAUCE.
THAT PORK CHOP
WAS GREAT!
NO MORE
FAST FOOD FRIDAY'S!
WE'RE GOING TO GO
TO RED LOBSTER.
YEP.
[ Male Announcer ]
COME TRY OUR NEW MENU
AND SEA FOOD DIFFERENTLY!
AND INTRODUCING 7 LUNCH CHOICES
FOR JUST $7.99.
SALAD, SANDWICHES, AND MORE.
WELCOME HOME.
SHE LOVES IT.
NINTENDO 3DS XL!
NAILED IT.
DAD, I'M ACTUALLY
TOTALLY SATISFIED AND
HAVE NO COMPLAINTS.
HO, HO, HO!
SO SMART WITH YOUR MONEY!
PLUS FREE SHIPPING
AT TARGET.COM.
WITH YOUR RED CARD
GET AN EXTRA 5% OFF
OUR EVERYDAY LOW PRICES...
PLUS FREE SHIPPING.
I AM THE GHOST
OF COOKIES PAST. RESIDUE.
SO GROSS.
WELL YOU DIDN'T USE
NEW PAM,
SO IT LOOKS LIKE
YOU'RE "STUCK" WITH ME.
[ Female Announcer ]
BARGAIN BRAND COOKING SPRAY
LEAVES ANNOYING RESIDUE.
THAT'S WHY THERE'S NEW PAM.
♪
WELCOME BACK
TO A SPECIAL EDITION
OF "THE BACHELOR."
THIS WEDDING LOCATION IS
DEFINITELY A SPECTACULAR SITE,
BUT ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT
THINGS ABOUT A WEDDING
IS THE THING THAT ALL BRIDES
DREAM ABOUT THE MOST--
THE WEDDING DRESS.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
♪
(Ashley) TODAY I'M MEETING
MY MOTHER, MY SISTER,
AND J.P.'s MOM ILENE TO DO
THE LAST WEDDING DRESS FITTING.
LADIES!
(all) HI!
GROUP HUG!
COME HERE.
OH! (laughs)
HOW ARE YOU GUYS?
HOW ARE YOU?
I'M SO HAPPY YOU'RE HERE!
LOOK AT YOU.
THANK YOU GUYS SO MUCH
FOR COMING.
THIS IS RANDI RAHM'S STUDIO.
ISN'T IS SO CUTE?
IT IS BEAUTIFUL.
I LOVE IT.
WE WORKED TOGETHER,
AND WE DESIGNED
A REALLY SIMPLE
AND ELEGANT DRESS,
SO I'M SO EXCITED
FOR YOU GUYS... (singsongy)
TO FINALLY SEE THE DRESS!
(singsongy) WE CAN'T WAIT.
I'LL BE BACK.
WHEN I THINK
ABOUT MY WEDDING DAY
AND VISION THAT MOMENT WHERE
J.P. SEES ME FOR THE FIRST TIME
IN MY WEDDING DRESS,
AND IT'S ALL BECOMING
SO MUCH MORE REAL TODAY
'CAUSE I'M PUTTING IT ON
FOR THE LAST TIME
BEFORE WE BECOME
HUSBAND AND WIFE.
I HOPE IT FITS PERFECTLY.
ARE YOU GUYS READY?
YES.
YES. CAN'T WAIT.
OKAY.
OH, MY GOSH.
OH! (laughs)
OH, MY GOODNESS.
THAT'S GORGEOUS.
(Ilene) BEAUTIFUL.
ASH.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
AW.
(Ashley) DO YOU LOVE IT?
(laughs)
THIS IS THE DRESS.
(Ilene) IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
YOU LOOK SO BEAUTIFUL.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
(Laurie)
OH, THAT'S BEAUTIFUL.
ASHLEY. BEAUTIFUL.
OH, THANK YOU.
(Ilene) SEEING ASHLEY
IN THAT WEDDING GOWN
WAS... MIND-BLOWING.
SHE IS JUST MAGNIFICENT.
THE DRESS IS SO HER.
CAN WE SEE THE SHOES?
OH, YEAH.
LET'S SEE THE SHOES.
OH, MY GOODNESS!
OHH!
THOSE ARE BEAUTIFUL.
(laughter)
SO ADORABLE.
I WAS EXPECTING, LIKE,
WHITE, OR...
(women) OH!
THAT IS SO CUTE.
ASHLEY, THEY ARE BEAUTIFUL.
THANK YOU.
I LOVE IT.
STUNNING.
IT'S PERFECT.
DO YOU LIKE IT?
J.P. WILL LOVE IT.
MM.
J.P. WILL BE SO OVERCOME...
(Laurie laughs)
LOVE IT.
TO SEE YOU IN THIS DRESS,
I CAN'T IMAGINE WHAT HE
WOULD FEEL LIKE. I CAN'T.
NOW I'M REALLY,
REALLY EXCITED.
OH, YEAH.
SO SOON.
THE NEXT TIME I'LL BE WEARING
MY WEDDING DRESS,
J.P. WILL BE STUDLY IN HIS TUX,
AND WE WILL BE SO CLOSE
TO BECOMING HUSBAND AND WIFE.
♪
(laughter)
THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S VERY ELVIS.
I WAS HOPING, LIKE,
JAMES BOND.
(spy theme playing)
NOT BAD.
A LITTLE MORE MY STYLE.
(Peter) OH, BOY.
MY FATHER
AND MY BEST FRIEND SEAN
ARE ACCOMPANYING ME TO HUGO BOSS
TO TRY ON TUXEDOES.
IT HAS REALLY PERFECT LINES.
HOW DO YOU KNOW
IT'S NOT ME?
DEFINITELY A LITTLE BIT YOU.
(laughter)
THIS IS DEFINITELY THE MOST FUN
I'VE HAD
IN THE WHOLE WEDDING PLANNING
PROCESS SO FAR.
THAT'S SHARP.
OH, THAT'S ELEGANT.
I MEAN, I'VE BEEN SMILING
SINCE I GOT HERE.
I CAN SEE MYSELF
GETTING MARRIED IN THIS TUX.
ASHLEY WILL LIKE THAT ONE
THE BEST.
I THINK SHE WILL.
I'LL PICK OUT THE TUX,
ASHLEY WILL PICK OUT THE DRESS,
BUT PICKING OUT THE RINGS--
IT'S SOMETHING WHERE WE'RE BOTH
GONNA HAVE FULL INPUT.
HEY.
HOW ARE YOU?
HOW YOU DOING?
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
AND NEIL LANE IS PART
OF ALL THAT.
SHOULD WE DO ME FIRST OR YOU?
I THINK WE GO
BACK AND FORTH.
OKAY.
LET'S DO YOU FIRST.
I THINK WE'RE--
OH, MY GOODNESS.
THEY'RE ALL GORGEOUS.
OKAY, WHERE DO I EVEN BEGIN?
WHAT... BABE, I NEED YOU.
OH, NO, NO, NO. (laughs)
AND THESE ARE SO BEAUTIFUL.
WHY DON'T WE LET YOU, LIKE,
PICK OUT AND TRY ON
AND SEE WHAT YOU LIKE.
(Ashley) PICKING OUT
THE WEDDING BAND TODAY
IS SO IMPORTANT BECAUSE
IT REALLY DOES REPRESENT
AN ETERNITY OF LIFE TOGETHER.
I DO NOT KNOW HOW
I GOT THIS LUCKY,
BUT WHATEVER IT IS,
I'M SO GRATEFUL FOR IT.
I ALREADY KNOW WHICH ONE
J.P.'s GONNA PICK.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
NO, I FEEL LIKE YOU'RE PEEKING.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
GO AHEAD. GO.
HE'S GONNA PICK THAT ONE.
OKAY, LET'S SEE.
OKAY.
READY, J.P.?
YOU--YOU LOOK.
(J.P.) I CAN'T WAIT
TO MARRY ASHLEY.
I MAY START CRYING.
I DON'T KNOW.
I CAN'T WAIT FOR THAT--
FOR THAT MOMENT
WHEN... I FINALLY PUT THE RING
ON HER FINGER.
I KNOW WHICH ONE I WANT.
THIS ONE'S MY FAVORITE.
YOU KNOW, SHE CHOSE THAT BEFORE
WHEN YOUR BACK WAS TURNED.
DID YOU?
YES.
SHE DID.
PEOPLE SAY FAIRY TALES
DON'T COME TRUE,
BUT THIS ONE CAME TRUE.
IT CAME TRUE FOR ME.
IT CAME TRUE FOR ASHLEY.
I WANT HER TO KNOW
THAT I WILL NEVER, EVER
TAKE THAT FOR GRANTED.
DON'T FREAK OUT. (laughs)
I WILL NOT FREAK OUT.
UP NEXT--
FAST CARS AND SEXY MOVES.
READY TO PARTY?
IT'S ASHLEY AND J.P.'s
WILD BACHELOR
AND BACHELORETTE PARTIES.
AND WE'LL CATCH UP WITH SOME
OF YOUR FAVORITE
"BACHELOR" COUPLES.
WE'VE GOT A BABY ON THE WAY.
AW.
(laughs)
HOW FAR ALONG? BOY? GIRL?
DO WE KNOW ANY OF THIS?
DOES IT LOOK
ODDLY FAMILIAR?
IT'S CLEARLY
NOT AS PINK.
RIGHT?
(laughs)
(cheering)
AND THEN DON'T MISS
A SPECIAL SNEAK PEEK
AT THE EXCITING NEW SEASON...
WHOO!
OF "THE BACHELOR."
IT'S, LIKE, GETTING
OUT OF CONTROL.
(women screams)
OH, MY GOD.
(crying) I CAN'T BELIEVE
THEY DID THIS TO ME.
IT'S ALL COMING UP NEXT.
YOUR MOUTH HAS BEEN
SIPPING, SNACKING, YELLOWING.
NUTCRACKING, GIFT STACKING,
YELLOWING.
MISTLETOE'ING, HO HO HO'ING,
AND EVERY HOLIDAY SEASON,
YOUR TEETH HAVE BEEN YELLOWING.
FACT IS IF YOU'RE NOT
WHITENING, YOU'RE YELLOWING.
CREST 3D WHITE WHITESTRIPS
REMOVE OVER 10 YEARS OF STAINS,
AND WHITEN 25 TIMES BETTER
THAN A LEADING
WHITENING TOOTHPASTE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
IN A HURRY?
TRY 2 HOUR EXPRESS WHITESTRIPS,
JUST IN TIME
FOR A WHITE HOLIDAY.
But we can eliminate
deductibles.
Nationwide Insurance members who
add vanishing deductible
get $100 off for
every year of safe driving.
We put members first
because we don't have
shareholders.
Join the Nation where
deductibles go...
♪ Nationwide Is On Your Side
YOU'RE NOT USING TOO MUCH
ARE YOU, HON?
♪
NOPE.
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT IS SO SOFT
YOU'LL HAVE TO REMIND
YOUR FAMILY THEY CAN USE LESS.
CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT
IS MADE WITH EXTRA CUSHIONS
THAT ARE SOFT
AND MORE ABSORBENT.
PLUS YOU CAN USE
FOUR TIMES LESS
VERSUS THE LEADING
VALUE BRAND.
DON'T WORRY, THERE'S PLENTY LEFT
FOR YOU DAD.
WE ALL GO.
WHY NOT ENJOY THE GO
WITH CHARMIN ULTRA SOFT?
♪
(indistinct conversations)
I MEAN, NICK AND I--
WE KNEW THEY WERE PERFECT,
BUT WE WERE ON THE SHOW
WHEN WE REALIZED IT.
I MEAN, THEY'RE SO CUTE.
I'M HAPPY FOR 'EM.
(woman) ABSOLUTELY.
WELCOME BACK
TO WHAT PROMISES TO BE
ONE OF THE MOST ROMANTIC EVENTS
EVER ON "THE BACHELOR"--
THE MOMENT WHEN
ASHLEY AND J.P. GET MARRIED.
ASHLEY AND J.P.'s
FAMILY AND FRIENDS
ARE BEGINNING TO ARRIVE HERE
FOR THE WEDDING,
BUT THEY'VE ALSO INVITED
SOME FAN FAVORITES.
THREE YEARS AGO, WE ALL WATCHED
AS JASON AND MOLLY
EXCHANGED THEIR VOWS
AND BECAME HUSBAND AND WIFE.
HOW HAVE THEY BEEN DOING SINCE?
LET'S FIND OUT.
JASON AND MOLLY,
GOOD TO SEE YOU GUYS.
HELLO. GOOD TO SEE YOU, TOO.
BEEN A WHILE.
YEAH.
IT'S BEEN A VERY LONG TIME.
ANYTHING NEW?
WE'VE GOT A BABY ON THE WAY.
(laughs)
AW.
YOU GUYS ARE PREGNANT.
YEAH.
HOW FAR ALONG? BOY? GIRL?
DO WE KNOW ANY OF THIS?
WE'RE NOT FINDING OUT.
OKAY.
WE'RE GOING OLD SCHOOL.
DON'T BE THOSE PEOPLE.
WE ARE THOSE PEOPLE.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'RE GOING OLD SCHOOL.
WANT A LOT OF ATTENTION
TYPE THING.
SO YOUR BOY TY--
UH, EXCITED
ABOUT HAVING
A BABY BROTHER OR SISTER?
SUPER PUMPED.
I MEAN, EVER SINCE
HE WAS PROBABLY 3,
HE'S BEEN ASKING WHEN HE--WHEN
THIS MOMENT WAS GONNA HAPPEN.
HE GONNA HELP
PICK OUT NAMES?
UH--
HE'S HAD A FEW SUGGESTIONS.
HE WANTS THE BABY
TO BE CALLED "TY JR."
YEAH.
(laughs)
WHY NOT?
KEEP IT IN THE FAMILY.
HE SAID IF IT'S A GIRL,
"MOLLY JR."
IF IT'S A BOY, "TY JR."
YEAH. RIGHT. (laughs)
WELL, WE ARE ABOUT TO GO THROUGH
THIS, UH, JOURNEY AGAIN.
OBVIOUSLY,
SEAN IS OUR NEW BACHELOR.
I DON'T KNOW IF YOU GUYS
KNOW HIM OR NOT,
BUT WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT HIM
BEING THE NEW GUY?
OH, I'M PRETTY EXCITED.
HE WAS--HE WAS MY PICK
FOR LAST SEASON,
SO I'M EXCITED FOR HIM.
I DON'T KNOW.
HIS ABS LOOK AMAZING.
(both laugh)
THAT'S ALL...
SHE SEEMED A LITTLE
TOO EXCITED ABOUT THAT.
YEAH, I KNOW. I KNOW.
I WAS--THAT WAS ANSWERING
FROM MOLLY'S SIDE.
YEAH.
YOU'VE BEEN IN THOSE SHOES.
MAYBE NOT THOSE ABS.
(laughs)
RIGHT. (laughs)
ANY ADVICE FOR HIM?
UH...
I DON'T KNOW. I THINK IF YOU
REALLY GO FROM THE HEART...
YEAH.
I MEAN, IT'S HARD TO DO
WHAT EVERYBODY WANTS YOU TO DO,
OF COURSE.
EXACTLY.
BUT IF YOU GO FROM WHAT YOU--
WHAT'S BEST FOR YOU
AND YOUR FAMILY
AND WHAT YOU THINK,
LIKE, YOU CAN'T GO WRONG.
WELL, IT'S SO GOOD
TO SEE YOU GUYS.
THANK YOU.
I KNOW ASHLEY AND J.P.
ARE GRATEFUL YOU'RE HERE.
YEAH.
I'M HAPPY YOU'RE HERE,
AND BEHALF OF ALL OF US HERE
AT "THE BACHELOR," THE BEST...
RIGHT.
FOR LITTLE CHRIS
OR CHRISTINA.
WHICHEVER ONE.
YOU--YOU CHOOSE.
OR--OR TY JR.
YEAH. (laughs)
THANKS, CHRIS.
WELL, NOW AS WE'VE SEEN
HERE TODAY,
PLANNING A WEDDING
IS A LOT OF WORK,
BUT ASHLEY AND J.P. HAVE ALSO
HAD PLENTY OF TIME TO PLAY,
ESPECIALLY AT THEIR BACHELOR
AND BACHELORETTE PARTIES.
♪
(Ashley) I'M SO EXCITED
TO BE HERE IN SCOTTSDALE.
J.P. AND I FIGURED IT WOULD BE
THE PERFECT PLACE TO GET AWAY
FOR OUR BACHELOR
AND BACHELORETTE PARTIES.
WOW. THIS LOOKS NICE.
VERY NICE.
WE ARE STAYING AT
THE W SCOTTSDALE THIS WEEKEND.
HAVE FUN.
YOU, TOO, BABE.
MM-HMM.
BYE.
AND I DON'T EVER
WANNA LEAVE J.P.,
BUT I'M SO EXCITED TO SEE
EVERYONE THAT'S HERE TODAY.
THIS IS GONNA BE
THE BEST WEEKEND EVER.
LADIES!
(cheering)
READY TO PARTY?!
(laughter)
THANK YOU GUYS SO MUCH
FOR COMING.
I'M SO EXCITED.
(woman) YEAH!
THIS IS GONNA BE AWESOME.
(pop)
WHOO!
(laughter)
THIS IS MY IDEA
OF A PERFECT DAY.
WE HAVE MIMOSAS,
MANICURES, PEDICURES--
SUCH A GIRLS' SPA DAY.
MWAH. PERFECT.
LET'S GET READY
FOR OUR DAY OF FUN.
CHEERS!
(woman) WHOO!
CHEERS.
(glasses clink)
ALL RIGHT. WHAT'S THAT?
WHAT... IS GOING ON?
(woman) LET'S SEE IT.
OH, MY GOODNESS.
THAT IS NOT J.P.'s FACE!
(laughter)
I'M DYING!
OH! HE LOOKS SO CUTE IN IT!
(laughter)
SO WE WANTED TO MAKE THIS
A MANICURE TO REMEMBER.
WE WANTED TO MAKE THIS WHOLE DAY
A DAY TO REMEMBER, SO...
I LOVE IT. THAT IS BEAUTIFUL.
HE'S GONNA LOVE THIS.
I MEAN, I'VE ALWAYS THOUGHT
THAT I HAD J.P. WRAPPED
AROUND MY FINGER,
BUT NOW I REALLY DO.
LOOK AT THIS. CUTE, RIGHT?
ASHLEY, DO YOU KNOW WHAT
J.P.'s DOING RIGHT NOW?
I'M NOT SURE. I WONDER
IF HE'S GETTING A MANICURE.
(laughter)
MAN-ICURE.
♪
(engine roaring)
(tires screech)
YEAH!
OH, MY GOD.
(laughter)
TODAY WE ARE GOING TO START OUT
BY RACING
HIGH PERFORMANCE VEHICLES.
♪
IT'S THE ULTIMATE
BACHELOR PARTY EVENT.
(engine revving)
♪
YOU'RE DOING 150 MILES AN HOUR,
AND YOU FREAK OUT A LITTLE BIT.
AND FOR A SECOND, LIKE,
YOU FEEL LIKE YOU'RE GONNA
HEAD INTO A WALL,
AND IT'S INTENSE.
♪
YOUR ADRENALINE IS JUST PUMPING.
THERE'S NO WAY
ASHLEY'S BACHELORETTE PARTY
IS THIS OFF-THE-WALL CRAZY.
♪
OOH! SEXY!
(women) YEAH!
J.P. WILL LIKE THESE.
(laughter)
MOM, EARMUFFS.
I THINK I HAVE A PAIR
OF THOSE, ACTUALLY.
(laughter)
HI.
(woman) HI.
I HEARD SOMEBODY'S
HAVING A BACHELORETTE PARTY,
IS THAT RIGHT?
(women cheering)
WE'RE GONNA DO
SOME POLE DANCING. SOUND GOOD?
♪
(cheering)
WHAT?
♪
WOW!
(woman) YEAH!
ASHLEY.
(laughter)
GET UP HERE.
(women hooting)
POLE DANCING WAS SO MUCH FUN.
(women cheering)
(woman) OH, THERE YOU GO.
(cheering continues)
J.P. IS A LUCKY MAN.
AFTER ALL THIS WEDDING PLANNING
THAT WE'RE DOING,
FINALLY, WE'RE DOING SOMETHING
TO PREPARE FOR THE HONEYMOON.
I WANT J.P. TO GET ME
A POLE NOW.
(cheering)
(woman) THERE WE GO.
♪
IS THIS SCOTCH RIGHT HERE?
(man) YEAH.
RACING CARS, DRINKING SCOTCH--
I MEAN, IT DOESN'T GET
ANY MORE MANLY THAN THAT.
(glasses clink,
laughter and clapping)
BUT I HONESTLY MISS ASHLEY
WHEN I'M NOT WITH HER.
AND EVEN THIS WEEKEND,
WHEN IT'S SUPPOSED TO BE
A BOYS' WEEKEND,
LIKE, I WANNA SEE HER.
IT'S HOW MY BRAIN WORKS.
IT'S HOW MY HEART WORKS.
I LOVE HER.
♪
YOU LOOK GORGEOUS.
HI, BABY.
MMM.
HOW ARE YOU?
GOOD. HOW ARE YOU?
I MISSED YOU.
YOU GUYS HAVING FUN?
MM-HMM. ARE YOU?
YOU KNOW...
HOW YOU FEELING NOW?
IT'S ALL GIRLS STUFF, BABE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
YOU WANNA SKATE FOR A MINUTE?
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
WHICH PAIR ARE MINE?
THOSE ARE YOURS.
HEY, BUT SHOULDN'T YOU
PUT THEM ON ME FOR ME?
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
AHH!
(laughs)
WHAT DO YOU THINK
OF MY FOOT?
DO YOU LIKE MY FOOT?
WHAT? IS THAT ME?
(both laugh)
BABY, I GOT A PEDICURE.
DON'T YOU THINK IT'S CUTE?
THAT'S GREAT. (laughs)
(laughs)
ASHLEY'S BEEN MAKING ME
A BETTER PERSON
SINCE THE DAY I MET HER.
FORGET ABOUT MAKING ME HAPPY.
I MEAN, SHE MAKES ME
OVER-THE-MOON ECSTATIC.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S A QUALITY
THAT YOU WANNA HAVE IN THE WOMAN
THAT YOU'RE GONNA SPEND
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE WITH.
THIS FEELS NICE!
HMM.
DO YOU REMEMBER WHEN WE
WERE ROLLER SKATING,
AND WE STOOD IN THE MIDDLE
AND DID THIS? REMEMBER THAT?
UH-HUH.
UM...
IT'S THE SAME THING.
AND NOW HERE WE ARE...
ABOUT TO GET MARRIED.
SO SOON. IT'S, LIKE,
RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER.
I KNOW. ARE YOU EXCITED?
IT'S KINDA CHEESY TO SAY
I CAN'T WAIT TO MARRY YOU,
BUT I REALLY--
I CAN'T WAIT TO MARRY YOU.
I REALLY CAN'T.
OH, BABE.
J.P. IS JUST
THE MOST AMAZING MAN
THAT I'VE EVER MET,
AND STANDING HERE WITH HIM,
LOOKING INTO HIS EYES,
IT REALLY MADE ME REALIZE
JUST HOW LUCKY I AM
AND HOW I CAN'T WAIT TO SPEND
THE REST OF MY LIFE WITH HIM.
I LOVE YOU, BABY.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
♪
IT'S FINALLY HERE...
...THE PETSMART
COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS SALE.
SAVE UP TO 50% ON
ALL PETHOLIDAY® PRODUCTS,
DECEMBER 13TH
THROUGH THE 24TH.
AND HELP HOMELESS PETS
WHEN YOU PURCHASE
CHANCE & LUCKY GIFT CARDS!
AT PETSMART®.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
TO PRACTICE MATH
MORE?
I LOVE MATH!
BUT TWO iPADS
MEANS TWO DATA PLANS?
THAT'S CRAZY.
MAYBE NOT.
WITH AT&T MOBILE SHARE,
ADDING AN iPAD
IS JUST $10 A MONTH.
BUT HONESTLY, MOM AND DAD'S LOVE
IS ALL I REALLY NEED.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE
FOR US.
WE SHOULD KEEP THESE.
WHAT?!
[ Male Announcer ]
AT&T MOBILE SHARE.
ADD AN iPAD
FOR JUST $10 A MONTH.
ONE PLAN. UP TO 10 DEVICES.
AT&T. RETHINK POSSIBLE.
♪
WELCOME BACK TO
THE ROMANTIC EVENT OF THE YEAR--
ASHLEY AND J.P.'s WEDDING.
BUT NINE YEARS AGO,
IT WAS TRISTA AND RYAN,
JOINING ME NOW.
HAPPY ANNIVERSARY, FIRST OF ALL.
THANK YOU.
THANKS, CHRIS.
MEMORIES FROM THAT DAY?
GOOD?
OH, YEAH, GREAT MEMORIES.
BEST DAY OF MY LIFE.
DOES IT LOOK ODDLY FAMILIAR?
IT'S CLEARLY
NOT AS PINK.
(laughs)
RIGHT?
THERE'S NO SUCH THING.
OURS WAS WAY MORE PINK
THAN THIS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT ASHLEY AND J.P.?
I KNOW YOU GUYS HAVE SPENT
A LITTLE TIME TOGETHER.
I-I JUST--I ADORE HER.
RIGHT.
SHE'S JUST PURE JOY.
YEAH.
AND I HAD REALLY HIGH HOPES
FOR ASHLEY AND J.P.,
AND NOW WE'RE HERE.
YOU KINDA SENSE YOURSELF
IN THEM A LITTLE BIT.
(both) YEAH.
AND OBVIOUSLY
A MUCH, MUCH YOUNGER SELF.
FOR SURE.
BUT I'M REALLY--
I'M VERY HOPEFUL FOR THEM.
I'M JUST REALLY,
REALLY HAPPY FOR THEM
AND HAPPY TO BE HERE.
YOU KNOW THAT, UH,
WE HAVE A NEW BACHELOR.
YES.
SEAN--ABOUT TO START
HIS JOURNEY.
RIGHT.
UM, THOUGHTS?
LOVE HIM.
YEAH?
YES. MM-HMM.
(laughs)
HE IS PRETTY TO LOOK AT.
UM, NO.
I-I JUST THINK
HE'S A QUALITY GUY.
HE SEEMS LIKE VERY GENTLE,
KIND OF LIKE RYAN.
SO I'M--I'M REALLY HOPING THAT--
THAT HE FOUND SOMEONE.
I KNOW YOU'LL BE WATCHING.
WILL YOU WATCH EVER?
EVERY NOW AND THEN, IF I WANNA
SPEND TIME WITH MY WIFE
ON MONDAY NIGHTS
OR WHATEVER NIGHT THEY HAPPEN
TO CHOOSE THIS WEEK.
I-I ACTUALLY DO ENJOY
WATCHING IT.
IT'S, YOU KNOW, SO MANY
MEMORIES ARE ASSOCIATED WITH IT
IN OUR LIVES.
GUYS, ALWAYS GOOD SEEING YOU.
GREAT HANGING WITH YOU,
AND FROM ALL OF US,
HAPPY NINTH ANNIVERSARY TO YOU.
THANKS.
AW.
HOPEFULLY TODAY WILL GO
AS SMOOTHLY AS YOURS DID
NINE YEARS AGO.
ASHLEY AND J.P. ARE
ABOUT TO GET MARRIED,
AND I HAVE TO SAY
I AM VERY HONORED
TO BE THE ONE MARRYING THEM.
YES, I WILL BE OFFICIATING
THEIR WEDDING TODAY.
ALTHOUGH I HAVE TO ADMIT
THAT I HAD A LOT OF QUESTIONS
FOR THE COUPLE THAT NEEDED
TO BE ANSWERED FIRST.
♪
YOU GUYS ASKED ME
TO OFFICIATE THIS WEDDING.
MM-HMM.
UM...
FIRST OF ALL, WHY?
(both laugh)
I'M VERY--I'M VERY HONORED,
UH, BUT--BUT WHY?
WHAT--WHAT BROUGHT YOU
TO THAT?
WE SPOKE IN DEPTH ABOUT IT,
AND YOU WERE AT THE TOP
OF OUR LIST
ALMOST FROM DAY ONE.
WE JUST FEEL VERY, VERY
COMFORTABLE WITH YOU UP THERE.
ONE THING WE WANT
IN OUR CEREMONY
IS WE WANT IT TO BE HEARTFELT.
WE WANT IT TO BE PERSONAL,
AND WE WANTED SOMEBODY
THAT KNEW US.
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH A LOT
TOGETHER.
YOU ALWAYS HAVE THE BEST ADVICE.
YOU'VE KNOWN US FROM THE START
OF OUR RELATIONSHIP,
AND EVEN AFTER THE SHOW
WAS OVER,
WE MAINTAINED THIS RELATIONSHIP.
RIGHT.
(voice breaks)
VERY SPECIAL TO ME. (laughs)
YOU KNOW I CRY ALL THE TIME.
(laughs)
I KNOW YOU DO.
UM, AND AS MUCH
AS I LOVE YOU GUYS,
IT'S LIKE I DON'T WANT TO DO IT
AS THE HOST OF "THE BACHELOR."
NO.
NO, NO.
WE REALLY DON'T WANT YOU
TO FEEL THAT WAY, BECAUSE...
YEAH.
THAT IS--COULDN'T BE ANYTHING
FURTHER FROM--FROM THE TRUTH.
WE WANT YOU THERE AS A FRIEND,
AS SOMEBODY
THAT WE'VE ALWAYS TRUSTED--
SOMEBODY THAT'S ALWAYS,
YOU KNOW, BEEN ON OUR SIDE,
SOMEBODY THAT KNOWS US
EACH PERSONALLY,
INDIVIDUALLY AND TOGETHER.
YOU KNOW I LOVE
THE TWO OF YOU.
I LOVE THE TWO OF YOU
TOGETHER.
I CONSIDER BOTH OF YOU
VERY DEAR FRIENDS,
BUT I JUST REALLY
WANNA MAKE SURE
YOU TWO ARE TRULY COMMITTED
TO WHAT MARRIAGE MEANS,
AND SO I WANNA ASK YOU GUYS
SOME QUESTIONS
AND TALK TO YOU GUYS
AS A COUPLE.
ABSOLUTELY.
DO YOU FEEL LIKE
YOU KNOW EACH OTHER?
IS THERE ANYTHING YOU FEEL
LIKE HE MAY NOT KNOW?
I'M NOT GOOD WITH THIS
KIND OF STUFF.
OKAY, HOLD ON.
WHAT DON'T YOU KNOW?
WAIT. HOLD ON. THIS IS TOUGH.
(laughs) IT IS.
I FEEL LIKE I KNOW
EVERYTHING ABOUT YOU.
SOMEBODY YOU DON'T KNOW
ABOUT ME.
WHAT--WHAT IS--
WHAT'S IMPORTANT TO YOU
AS YOUR WEDDING COMES UP?
BUT THAT'S SUCH AN AMBIGU--
THAT'S, LIKE, SET--
I MEAN, THAT'S SUCH
A BLANKET STATEMENT.
WAIT. BUT SHOULDN'T I--
SHOULDN'T I--I SHOULD
KNOW THAT ALREADY.
WHAT ARE THE THINGS
THAT MAKE YOU GUYS
TALK AND WORRY AND DISCUSS
AND...
WE REALLY DON'T WORRY ABOUT...
US.
DO YOU KNOW AND TRUST
WITHOUT A SHADOW OF A DOUBT
THIS PERSON IS HERE
FOR YOU?
OH. I NEVER QUESTION THAT.
DO YOU EVER QUESTION THAT?
NOT FOR A SECOND.
YOU NEVER WORRIED
ABOUT JEALOUSY?
WORRIED ABOUT...
NEVER. NEVER.
I'VE NEVER HAD A DOUBT.
I'VE NEVER HAD A MOMENT OF...
INSECURITY OR JEALOUSY.
I MEAN, NEVER.
DO YOU EVER HAVE--
NO, AND IT'S SUCH
A... RELIEF.
IT'S WEIRD.
I MEAN, YES, WE'RE GONNA
HAVE OBSTACLES,
BUT I'VE NEVER DOUBTED
HER FEELINGS FOR ME.
IT JUST--
IT JUST FEELS RIGHT.
BUT WHEN LIFE DOES SET IN,
AND LIFE HAS SET IN
FOR YOU GUYS,
THERE'S ISSUES.
WHAT ARE THEY?
YOU KNOW WHEN MY SISTER
HAD SOME ISSUES WITH J.P.?
RIGHT.
SHE SAID WE WERE TOO DIFFERENT.
HE'S OLDER,
AND HE'S FROM NEW YORK.
HE'S JUST DIFFERENT.
YEAH.
WE GET IT.
WE ARE VERY, VERY DIFFERENT.
SHE'S RIGHT.
BUT WE BALANCE EACH OTHER OUT.
SO IS THAT RIGHT?
SHE'S HIT THE NAIL
ON THE HEAD. ABSOLUTELY.
SHE'S THE STRONGEST WOMAN
I KNOW.
I MEAN, THIS GIRL--ANY ADVERSITY
THAT'S THROWN IN FRONT OF HER,
SHE CAN HANDLE. SHE CAN HANDLE
ENOUGH FOR THE BOTH OF US.
I JUST--I LOVE HER STRENGTH.
I LOVE HER SINCERITY.
YEAH.
I MEAN, I CAN GO ON AND ON
AND ON ABOUT HER.
I MEAN, SHE'S A CONSTANT
UPLIFTING PRESENCE.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S THAT CLICHE,
"WHEN YOU KNOW, YOU KNOW."
RIGHT.
BUT IT'S SO TRUE.
LIKE, WHEN YOU KNOW,
YOU KNOW.
IT'S JUST SOMETHING YOU FEEL
IS RIGHT.
I MEAN,
EVERY STEP OF THE WAY,
EVEN, YOU KNOW,
THE PROPOSAL,
EVERYONE COMMENTS,
"WHOA, YOU PROPOSED SO SOON."
BUT IT JUST FELT RIGHT.
THIS FEELS RIGHT. SHE'S WHO
I'M SUPPOSED TO BE WITH,
AND--AND THAT'S
THE BEST ANSWER I CAN GIVE.
WHAT'S THAT FEELING
FOR YOU?
I THINK THERE ARE
A LOT OF THINGS IN LIFE
THAT THE BRAIN
DOESN'T UNDERSTAND
BUT THE HEART FEELS,
AND I THINK THAT--
GOOD ANSWER.
(laughs) AND I THINK THAT
THAT'S KIND OF WHAT WE HAVE,
AND THERE'S NOBODY IN THE WORLD
I RATHER BE WITH THAN HIM.
LIKE, THROUGH THE GOOD,
THE BAD, THE UGLY.
LIKE,
EVERYTHING THAT WE GO THROUGH,
THERE'S--I THINK
WHEN YOU CAN SAY THAT,
THEN YOU'VE REALLY--
YOU'VE REALLY FIGURED IT OUT.
HAVE YOU GUYS TALKED
ABOUT NUMBER OF KIDS? WHEN?
TWO.
ONE.
NO. WE DON'T KNOW. PROBABLY--
WE'LL PROBABLY
HOPEFULLY HAVE TWO, BUT I MEAN,
I DEFINITELY HAVE BABY FEVER.
I'M NOT GONNA LIE.
THAT IS THE UNDERSTATEMENT
OF THE CENTURY.
(laughs)
HOW SOON?
AND HOW--
A YEAR?
YEAR AND A HALF?
I DON'T KNOW. HOPEFULLY.
AND YOU'RE... ON BOARD?
IT--ALL--ALL'S KIND OF
A GREAT PLAN.
YEAH.
AND WHEN THINGS CHANGE,
THEY CHANGE,
BUT RIGHT NOW SHE'LL FINISH
HER RESIDENCY,
HAVE A KID.
MM-HMM.
AND SHE'LL GET ON
WITH HER CAREER.
MAYBE HAVE ANOTHER ONE.
WHOA. HE'S GOT A PLAN, TOO.
YEAH.
WE'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
LIFE'S ABOUT PLANNING.
WELL, I WAS HONORED WHEN YOU
GUYS ASKED ME TO OFFICIATE.
AND HONESTLY,
IN TALKING TO YOU GUYS,
YOU KNOW,
THERE'S NO RELUCTANCE AT ALL.
I'M, LIKE, REALLY HONORED,
AND HONESTLY, GENUINELY,
JUST EXCITED
TO BE UP THERE WITH YOU GUYS
AND TO SPEND THE DAY WITH YOU
AND TO DO THIS.
AND SO, YOU KNOW,
I LOVE YOU GUYS,
AND I FEEL GREAT ABOUT IT.
THANKS, CHRIS. WE LOVE YOU, TOO.
WE LOVE YOU, TOO.
SO CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS, CHRIS.
NOTHING BUT LOVE
FOR YOU GUYS.
WE'RE SO EXCITED.
BYE.
SO GOOD TO SEE YOU.
ALL RIGHT, BUD.
THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT, MAN.
I'VE KNOWN ASHLEY AND J.P.
FOR QUITE SOME TIME.
WE'RE ALL REALLY GOOD FRIENDS,
AND I'M HONORED
THAT THEY ASKED ME
TO OFFICIATE THIS WEDDING.
BUT MARRIAGE CHANGES THINGS,
AND I WANNA MAKE SURE
THAT THEY HAVE REALLY UNDERSTOOD
THE STEPS THEY'RE ABOUT TO TAKE,
AND I THINK NOW, AFTER
WE'VE SPOKEN, THEY'RE READY.
UM, THEY'RE VERY MUCH IN LOVE.
THEY'RE VERY HAPPY,
AND IT'S GONNA BE
A BEAUTIFUL WEDDING.
THIS IS WHERE
IT'S ALL HAPPENING.
UNREAL.
(whispers) WOW.
CAN YOU SEE IT?
I CAN SEE IT.
♪ AH
(laughs)
BABY...
(speaks indistinctly)
I'M SO EXCITED!
(grunts)
LOOK AT THIS.
ALL OUR FRIENDS AND FAMILY
WILL BE RIGHT HERE.
THIS IS GONNA BE...
AMAZING.
AND SOMETHING ELSE
WE SHOULD WORK ON.
WHAT?
WHAT KIND OF KISS
DO YOU WANT?
WOW.
THAT'S A GOOD QUESTION.
I'M JUST GONNA GO...
(kisses)
NO! COME ON.
LET'S TRY THIS.
NO. DO YOU GO IN TWICE?
I-I THINK SO.
THAT'S HOW WE KISS, TOO.
DO YOU DO TWICE, TOO?
I THINK IT SHOULD JUST BE
ONE LONG ONE.
NO, BUT WE--THAT'S NOT US.
I KNOW, BUT YOU CAN'T GO...
(makes kissing sounds)
YES, YOU--NO,
TWO OF THE SAME THING.
SO IT'S KINDA LIKE--HERE.
NO, I THINK WE SHOULD DO
THE ONE.
I LIKE TWICE.
ONE KISS.
I'M NOT KIDDING.
YOU WANT TWO KIDS.
I WANT ONE KID.
YOU WANT TWO KISSES.
I WANT ONE KISS.
WELL, THEN THE FIRST ONE'S
GOTTA BE A LITTLE MORE...
OKAY, LET'S DO IT.
JUST GO BIG THEN.
NOT THAT KISSING YOU
ISN'T MEMORABLE.
IT ALWAYS IS, BUT I'M JUST--
OKAY, LET'S TRY IT AGAIN.
READY?
ONE OR TWO?
ONE.
I JUST ALWAYS WANT TWO.
I DON'T KNOW WHY.
YOU CAN HAVE ONE LATER.
MM.
CAN I GET THIS ONE TO GO?
SO WE'RE JUST DOING ONE?
I THINK WE'LL JUST DO ONE.
ALL RIGHT. SHALL WE?
I'M STANDING HERE WITH J.P.,
AND ALL WE CAN THINK IS
THE NEXT TIME
WE'RE STANDING HERE,
WE'LL HAVE ALL OF OUR FAMILY
AND FRIENDS SURROUNDING US,
AND WE WILL BE EXCHANGING VOWS
AND BECOMING HUSBAND AND WIFE.
CAN'T WAIT.
AND THEN I'M GONNA WALK UP
TO YOU AND GO... WHOO!
(laughs)
I COULD NOT THINK OF A MORE
PERFECT PLACE TO GET MARRIED.
CARRY ME.
(grunts)
(grunts) WHOO-HOO!
CAN YOU START THE DAY
THE WAY YOU WANT?
CAN ORENCIA HELP?
COULD YOUR "I WANT"
BECOME "I CAN"?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
ORENCIA REDUCES
MANY RA SYMPTOMS
LIKE PAIN, MORNING STIFFNESS
AND PROGRESSION
OF JOINT DAMAGE.
IT'S HELPED NEW RA PATIENTS
AND THOSE NOT HELPED ENOUGH
BY OTHER TREATMENTS.
DO NOT TAKE ORENCIA
WITH ANOTHER BIOLOGIC MEDICINE
FOR RA
DUE TO AN INCREASED RISK
OF SERIOUS INFECTION.
SERIOUS SIDE EFFECTS CAN OCCUR
INCLUDING FATAL INFECTIONS.
CASES OF LYMPHOMA AND
LUNG CANCER HAVE BEEN REPORTED.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR IF YOU ARE
PRONE TO OR HAVE ANY INFECTION
LIKE AN OPEN SORE OR THE FLU
OR A HISTORY OF COPD,
A CHRONIC LUNG DISEASE.
ORENCIA MAY WORSEN YOUR COPD.
[ Male Announcer ]
NOW LEARN ABOUT A PROGRAM
COMMITTED TO YOU
AND COPAY ASSISTANCE THAT CAN
REDUCE MONTHLY ORENCIA
OUT-OF-POCKET
DRUG COST TO $5.
IF YOU'RE
NOT SATISFIED
AFTER 6 MONTHS,
YOU GET
THAT MONEY BACK.
CALL 1-800-ORENCIA.
Uh...
Um...
Hm...
Umm...
Uh...
Oh !
The Windows Phone 8X
by HTC on Verizon.
It features easy
to navigate live tiles
that are simple
to customize.
Just pin what matters most
right to your homescreen.
Exclusively with Data Sense--
a feature that makes the most
of you plan.
Only on Verizon.
she doesn't
Even though our really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
Who's your mommy now?
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
♪
(indistinct conversations)
WELCOME BACK TO THE MOMENT
WE'VE ALL BEEN WAITING FOR--
ASHLEY AND J.P.'s WEDDING.
BUT BEFORE
THE CEREMONY STARTS,
THERE IS ONE MORE SPECIAL GUEST
WITH ME HERE.
THAT'S RIGHT--
OUR NEW BACHELOR, SEAN LOWE.
GOOD TO SEE YOU, BUDDY.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
WELCOME.
THANK YOU.
THIS COULD BE YOU SOON.
MAYBE.
IT COULD BE.
YOU KNOW, THIS PUTS IT
ALL IN PERSPECTIVE.
THIS IS WHY I SIGNED UP
TO DO "THE BACHELOR."
I WANTED TO FIND THE WOMAN
OF MY DREAMS,
AND, YOU KNOW, THE LOVE
THAT ASHLEY AND J.P.
HAVE FOR ONE ANOTHER--
IT'S REAL,
AND I KNOW IT CAN HAPPEN
FOR ME, TOO.
YOUR SEASON OF "THE BACHELOR"
STARTS JANUARY 7th
RIGHT HERE ON ABC.
UM, A LOT HAS ALREADY
TAKEN PLACE.
SO GIVE US JUST
A BRIEF GLIMPSE.
UH, NIGHT ONE, 25 WOMEN.
DID YOU SEE YOUR WIFE
IN THAT ROOM?
NIGHT ONE, I THINK I COULD
DEFINITELY SEE MY WIFE
IN THAT ROOM.
REALLY?
YEAH. I MEAN,
I WAS ABSOLUTELY BLOWN AWAY
BY HOW WELL ACCOMPLISHED
THESE WOMEN WERE,
UH, HOW FUNNY THEY ARE,
YOU KNOW,
HOW INTELLIGENT THEY ARE.
I DID NOT KNOW
THAT THE QUALITY
OF WOMEN WOULD BE SO GREAT.
ARE YOU HAPPY THAT YOU
NOT ONLY BECAME THE BACHELOR
BUT HOW THIS ENDED FOR YOU?
YEAH. I'M--I'M VERY HAPPY.
I'M HAPPY WITH WHERE I AM NOW.
THE JOURNEY ITSELF
WAS SO REWARDING.
YEAH.
AND I WOULDN'T TRADE IT
FOR ANYTHING.
ALL RIGHT, THANKS, SEAN.
I KNOW ALL OF AMERICA IS ANXIOUS
TO FIND OUT WHETHER OR NOT
YOU HAVE FOUND LOVE,
AND THEY'LL ALL HAVE TO WAIT
UNTIL JANUARY 7th,
RIGHT HERE ON ABC.
ALL RIGHT, THE WEDDING
IS ABOUT TO START,
BUT FIRST, LET'S TAKE A LOOK
AT HOW ASHLEY AND J.P.
SPENT THEIR MORNING
AND HOW THEY GOT READY
FOR THE MOST IMPORTANT DAY
OF THEIR LIVES.
♪
(singsongy) HEY!
(women, singsongy) HI!
OH, MY GOODNESS!
(laughter)
ALL RIGHT, WHO DID THIS?
I'M REALLY LOOKING FORWARD TO
THIS BRIDAL BRUNCH THIS MORNING.
IT REALLY IS ALL THE WOMEN
I LOVE IN ONE ROOM.
SO NICE.
THIS IS AWESOME.
THERE'S SOMETHING THAT'S SO NICE
ABOUT SITTING DOWN
WITH YOUR GIRLFRIENDS
RIGHT BEFORE YOU'RE ABOUT TO
COMMIT YOUR LIFE TO SOMEBODY
AND JUST HAVE GIRL TIME.
I DID FIND A LITTLE NOTE
THAT YOU HAD WRITTEN
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
IT WENT LIKE THIS--
THAT IN 20 YEARS,
YOU SAW YOURSELF
BEING MARRIED.
YOU WERE GONNA LIVE
IN JACKSONVILLE, FLORIDA.
(laughter)
YOU WERE GOING TO HAVE
AN AQUA CONVERTIBLE.
I DON'T KNOW WHERE
THAT CAME FROM.
(laughter)
AND YOU WERE GONNA HAVE
THREE CHILDREN.
YOU WERE GONNA BE SO EXHAUSTED
WITH YOUR THREE CHILDREN.
(laughter)
YOU ACTUALLY USED
THE WORD "EXHAUSTED."
(laughter)
YOU SAY THE ENVIRONMENT
IS GOING TO BE GREAT.
EVERYONE'S GONNA
HAVE GOOD JOBS.
I WAS THINKING--
I WAS THINKING POSITIVELY.
(laughter)
BUT BASICALLY, ASH, I JUST WANNA
TELL YOU HOW PROUD I AM
OF THE BEAUTIFUL YOUNG LADY
YOU'VE BECOME.
I JUST LOVE YOU
AND I WISH YOU THE BEST--
HEALTH, HAPPINESS,
AND EVERYTHING
THAT COMES WITH THAT.
CHEERS TO THAT.
CHEERS TO THE ENVIRONMENT.
(laughter)
(all speaking at once)
(Ashley) CHEERS.
I'M SO GLAD WE CAN ALL BE HERE
TOGETHER TODAY AND CELEBRATE,
AND I'M ALSO SO HAPPY
THAT SHE FOUND J.P.
I WAS A LITTLE SKEPTICAL
AT FIRST,
BUT ONLY--NOT BECAUSE, UM...
(voice breaking)
NOW I'M, LIKE, CRYING.
(laughter)
BUT ONLY BECAUSE I WANTED
THE BEST FOR ASH.
I NEVER WANT HER--
I NEVER WANT TO SEE HER HURT.
UM, NEVER WANNA SEE HER
GO THROUGH ANY PAIN.
BUT... IN THE LAST
18 MONTHS...
IT'S OBVIOUS THAT THEY'RE
PERFECT FOR EACH OTHER
AND THAT SHE WILL NOT SEE
THE PAIN
THAT I WAS SO SCARED OF.
(laughter)
I THINK THE SECOND DAY WE GOT
BACK FROM THE SHOW,
J.P. LOOKED AT ME AND SAID,
"YOUR SISTER WAS RIGHT."
(laughter)
"YOU ARE TOO MUCH TO HANDLE."
MORE MIMOSAS.
(laughter)
YES, PLEASE.
♪
I'M GETTING MARRIED TODAY.
IT'S THE BIGGEST MOMENT
IN MY LIFE.
ASHLEY IS MY... EVERYTHING.
I COULD GO ON AND ON.
SHE'S MY EVERYTHING.
SHE'S MY PERSON.
SHE IS... THE ONE.
AND I'M THE LUCKIEST MAN
IN THE WORLD.
♪
MY GOODNESS,
ONLY A FEW SHORT HOURS!
AAH!
I CAN'T BELIEVE
IT'S MY WEDDING DAY.
I THINK IT'S ONLY GONNA
REALLY SET IN
ONCE I PUT ON THE DRESS.
♪
THERE'S SO MUCH GOING ON
AROUND US.
THE BRIDESMAIDS GETTING
THEIR HAIR DONE.
I MEAN,
EVERYTHING IS JUST CRAZY.
EEE! I'M EXCITED.
WILL YOU DO ME A FAVOR?
SURE.
CAN YOU GO DELIVER THIS
TO MY BRIDE?
ABSOLUTELY. WHAT IS IT?
IT IS A CHARM BRACELET.
AND ALL THE DIFFERENT CHARMS
SYMBOLIZE
A LITTLE DIFFERENT PART
OF OUR LIVES.
WE HAVE A ROSE WHERE
WE OBVIOUSLY FIRST MET.
THAT'S WHAT THAT SYMBOLIZES.
VERY IMPORTANT.
ALL THE STUFF
SHE'S GONNA LOVE, SO--
I WILL ABSOLUTELY DO IT.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
ALL RIGHT.
NO PROBLEM. I'M ON MY WAY.
CAROL SHAW IS DOING
MY MAKEUP TODAY,
AND I KNOW SHE'S GONNA DO
A FABULOUS JOB.
I'LL JUST GIVE YOU
ONE LAST SPRAY.
OKAY.
AND PAUL FROM SALLY HERSHBERGER
IS HERE TODAY TO DO MY HAIR.
OH, YES, PAUL!
LOOKS GOOD.
I CAN SEE IT. I LOVE IT!
ASHLEY...
HI, ROY!
YOU LOOK SO HANDSOME.
THANK YOU.
WHAT A NICE SURPRISE.
I HAVE A SPECIAL
PRESENT FOR YOU...
OKAY.
FROM J.P.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, ROY.
I'LL SEE YOU SOON, OKAY?
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
WE'LL SEE YOU SOON, ROY.
SEE YOU SOON.
WHAT IS THIS?
OH, MY GOODNESS.
(gasps) AWW!
LOOK AT THIS. (gasps)
ROSE, CUPCAKE...
THERE'S A TOOTH ON THERE!
(laughter)
HE IS THE BEST. AWW!
READ IT OUT LOUD.
(gasps)
"MY DEAREST ASHLEY,
I'M SO EXCITED THAT OUR
WEDDING DAY IS FINALLY HERE..."
(voice breaking) "AND THAT I GET
TO MARRY THE WOMAN OF MY DREAMS.
"I COULD NEVER FIND
JUST ONE THING
"THAT WOULD ENCAPSULATE
ALL THAT YOU ARE,
"BUT IT DEFINITELY SHOWS
A FEW OF MY FAVORITE.
LOVE, J.P."
OH, MY GOODNESS!
HOW AM I SUPPOSED TO KEEP
MAKEUP ON?
I THINK THERE'S GONNA BE
SOME TEARS SHED.
MANY TEARS SHED.
♪
OH, MY GOODNESS,
THIS IS SO BEAUTIFUL!
THERE ARE SO MANY COMPONENTS
TO A WEDDING.
EXTERNALLY,
IT IS GONNA BE BEAUTIFUL.
(singsongy) HEY, GUYS!
(normal voice) EVERYTHING'S
REALLY COMING TOGETHER.
WE WERE LOOK--
WE WERE PEEKING--
WAIT, CAN WE SEE?
CAN WE SEE IF EVERYTHING'S
GETTING READY?
(gasps) CAN YOU SEE?
YEAH, IT'S OUTSIDE.
BUT THERE'S ALSO SOMETHING
SO PEACEFUL
AND CALMING AND REASSURING
TO KNOW THAT
THE RELATIONSHIP
IS GONNA LAST FOREVER.
YOU CAN SEE IT'S RIGHT THERE.
I'M NOT--I JUST WANNA PEEK.
(speaks indistinctly)
OH, MY GOODNESS!
(gasps) THIS IS
REALLY GORGEOUS.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
(indistinct conversations)
OH, WOW, IT'S FINALLY HERE.
(J.P.) I'VE NEVER MET ANYONE
LIKE ASHLEY.
MY LOVE WITH ASHLEY
HAS CHANGED MY LIFE,
AND OUR LOVE HAS JUST GOTTEN
STRONGER AND STRONGER.
ASHLEY AND I WILL BE
TOGETHER FOREVER.
(cork pops)
THERE WE GO.
NICE.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL THE PLANNING
AND ALL OF THE--
THE LITTLE DETAILS--
THE FLOWERS, THE FAMILY,
THE RINGS--I MEAN, IT'S--
IT'S ALL PART OF THE STORY.
BUT TODAY
IT'S ONLY ABOUT TRUE LOVE.
IT'S ABOUT ME AND ASHLEY.
IT'S ABOUT FALLING IN LOVE.
IT'S GONNA BE A BEAUTIFUL DAY,
A BEAUTIFUL BRIDE.
♪
(sniffling)
OH...
HI!
(speaking indistinctly)
I THINK IN LIFE
WE GO THROUGH RELATIONSHIPS
AND WE GO THROUGH HARD THINGS.
WE GO THROUGH GREAT THINGS.
WE LEARN SO MUCH
ABOUT OURSELVES.
BUT I THINK IT'S ONLY
WHEN YOU FIND SOMEBODY
THAT IS YOUR PERFECT MATCH THAT
YOU REALLY UNDERSTAND YOURSELF
AND YOU REALLY UNDERSTAND
WHAT IT IS
TO UNCONDITIONALLY
LOVE SOMEBODY
AND NEVER HAVE TO QUESTION,
NEVER HAVE TO--TO WORRY.
AND I CAN'T WAIT
TO BECOME HIS WIFE.
♪
WELL, THE LAST OF THE GUESTS
HAVE ARRIVED.
J.P. IS GETTING INTO PLACE.
ASHLEY IS MAKING HER WAY
TO THE CEREMONY SITE.
AND, YES, IT'S TIME FOR ME
TO TAKE MY PLACE
ON THE WEDDING STAGE
AS WELL.
WHEN WE RETURN,
THE WEDDING WE'VE ALL BEEN
WAITING FOR WILL BEGIN.
STAY WITH US.
IF YOU'D LIKE TO DATE THE NEXT
BACHELOR OR BACHELORETTE,
GO TO abc.com
AND CLICK "APPLY."
PREGO?!
BUT I'VE BOUGHT RAGU FOR YEARS.
[ Thinking ] WONDER WHAT OTHER
QUESTIONABLE CHOICES I'VE MADE?
I CHOOSE DATE NUMBER 2!
WHOOO!
[ sigh of relief ]
[ Male Announcer ]
CHOOSE TASTE. CHOOSE PREGO.
♪
BOO! I AM THE GHOST
OF MEALS PAST.
WHEN YOU DON'T USE NEW PAM,
THIS IS WHAT YOU GET.
RESIDUE.
[ Female Announcer ]
BARGAIN BRAND COOKING SPRAY
LEAVES ANNOYING RESIDUE.
THAT'S WHY THERE'S NEW PAM.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
TAKE NOTES ON THE SPOT.
CATCH EVERY DETAIL
WITH VIDEO ZOOM.
♪
AND NOW RUN TWO APPS
AT THE SAME TIME
ON THE SAME SCREEN.
THE FREEDOM TO DO WHAT YOU WANT
WHEN YOU WANT.
LET'S GO AGAIN.
[ Male Announcer ] WITH THE
QUAD-CORE-POWERED LG OPTIMUS G.
AVAILABLE FROM SPRINT.
♪
(indistinct conversations)
(woman) AHH!
(guests murmuring)
(piano playing
"Pachelbel's Canon in D")
(camera shutters clicking)
♪
GOOD LUCK.
(lowered voice) HOW YOU DOING?
EVERYTHING GOOD?
(whispers) YEAH.
GOOD?
YEAH. REAL GOOD.
♪
(whispers indistinctly)
(guests murmuring)
(Chrystie chuckles)
(chuckles)
(song ends)
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IF YOU WOULD, PLEASE RISE.
("Can't Help Falling In Love"
playing)
(breathes deeply)
(Lisa Donnelly)
♪ WISE MEN SAY
♪ ONLY FOOLS RUSH IN
♪ I CAN'T HELP
♪ FALLING IN LOVE
♪ WITH YOU
♪ SHALL I STAY?
(sniffling)
♪ WOULD IT BE A SIN
♪ OH, IF I
♪ CAN'T HELP
♪ FALLING IN LOVE
(sniffling)
♪ WITH YOU?
♪ LIKE A RIVER FLOWS
♪ SURELY TO THE SEA
(kiss)
♪ DARLING, SO IT GOES
♪ SOME THINGS
♪ WERE MEANT TO BE
♪ SO
(whispers)
YOU ARE BEAUTIFUL.
(camera shutters clicking)
(whispering indistinctly)
♪ TAKE MY HAND
♪ TAKE MY WHOLE LIFE
♪ TOO
♪ OH, 'CAUSE I CAN'T HELP
(Ashley laughs
and speaks indistinctly)
♪ FALLING IN LOVE
(speaks indistinctly)
♪ IN LOVE WITH YOU
♪ I CAN'T HELP
(laughing)
TOO LATE.
(laughs)
(laughter)
♪ IN LOVE
WAIT FOR IT.
BREAK THE RULES.
CAN WE GET ONE
OUT OF THE WAY?
(Chris) WAIT FOR IT.
♪ FALLING IN LOVE
♪ WITH YOU
(song ends)
(exhales nervously)
(whispers) YOU GUYS,
REMEMBER TO ENJOY THIS.
MM.
THANK YOU. PLEASE BE SEATED.
WELCOME.
SO WE HAVE GATHERED HERE TODAY
TO WITNESS AND CELEBRATE
THE WEDDING
OF ASHLEY LYNN HEBERT
AND JORDAN PAUL ROSENBAUM,
OR AS THE "BACHELOR" WORLD
KNOWS AND LOVES YOU AS, J.P.
MARRIAGE IS THE PROMISE OF HOPE
BETWEEN TWO PEOPLE
WHO LOVE EACH OTHER SINCERELY,
WHO HONOR EACH OTHER
AS INDIVIDUALS,
AND WHO WISH TO UNITE
THEIR LIVES
AND SHARE THEIR FUTURES
TOGETHER.
AND TODAY'S MARRIAGE CEREMONY
MARKS THE BEGINNING
OF A LIFETIME OF
WONDERFUL HUMAN EXPERIENCES
TO BE SHARED
AS HUSBAND AND WIFE.
ASHLEY AND J.P.,
BEFORE WE START,
I JUST WANT TO SAY PERSONALLY
IN FRONT OF ALL
OF YOUR FAMILY AND FRIENDS
HOW HONORED I AM TO BE
ASKED TO STAND HERE BEFORE YOU
AND HOW MUCH I FULLY
APPRECIATE THIS HONOR,
THIS CEREMONY, AND THIS UNION.
J.P., WE ALL WATCHED
AS YOU GOT OUT OF THE LIMO
THAT FIRST NIGHT,
WALKED ACROSS THE DRIVEWAY,
AND REALLY AWKWARDLY...
(laughter)
HUGGED ASHLEY THAT FIRST NIGHT.
AND THEN THE ROMANCE BEGAN,
AND WE STARTED
TO TRAVEL THE WORLD.
SUDDENLY,
WE'RE ON A BEACH IN FIJI.
UNDERNEATH A SPECTACULAR SUNSET,
YOU GET DOWN ON ONE KNEE
AND PROPOSE MARRIAGE.
THE MORE I'VE GOTTEN
TO KNOW YOU TWO
AND CONSIDER YOU
VERY GOOD FRIENDS,
I REALLY THINK
THE OLD ADAGE IS TRUE--
OPPOSITES ATTRACT.
ASHLEY, SO FULL OF LIFE,
PASSION...
EMOTION.
(laughter)
UH...
AND THEN THERE'S J.P.
SOME WOULD SAY A SERIOUS MAN.
OTHERS MIGHT SAY A VERY,
VERY SERIOUS MAN.
(laughter)
BUT IN THIS RELATIONSHIP,
IT WORKS.
I'VE SEEN YOU TWO TOGETHER.
YOU ARE HER ROCK.
YOU ARE HER CENTER.
AND WE ARE ALL HONORED
TO BE HERE FOR YOU TODAY
AS YOU BECOME HUSBAND AND WIFE.
BUT BEFORE WE GO ANY FURTHER
WITH THIS CEREMONY,
IT IS A TIME-HONORED
TRADITION TO ASK,
IS THERE ANYONE HERE TODAY
WHO OBJECTS TO THE MARRIAGE
OF THIS MAN AND THIS WOMAN?
IF SO, SPEAK NOW...
(laughter)
OR FOREVER HOLD YOUR PEACE.
(Ashley laughs)
WE'RE GOOD?
KEEP GOING.
(laughing)
THEN AT THIS TIME...
LET'S START THE CEREMONY...
MM.
THAT WILL JOIN THIS COUPLE
IN MARRIAGE.
J.P., DO YOU TAKE THIS WOMAN
TO BE
YOUR LAWFULLY WEDDED WIFE?
I DO.
AND, ASHLEY,
DO YOU TAKE THIS MAN TO BE
YOUR LAWFULLY WEDDED HUSBAND?
I DO.
ASHLEY AND J.P. HAVE CHOSEN
TO INCLUDE
AS PART OF THEIR CEREMONY
THE TRADITIONAL CELTIC CUSTOM
OF HANDFASTING.
THIS TRADITION IS LITERALLY
WHERE THE PHRASE
"TYING THE KNOT" COMES FROM.
J.P.'s MOTHER ILENE
AND ASHLEY'S MOTHER LAURIE
WILL READ THE BLESSING.
LADIES, IF YOU WOULD,
COME JOIN US UP HERE, PLEASE.
(Ashley speaks indistinctly)
(exhales)
"THESE ARE THE HANDS..."
(whispers) WAIT.
(normal voice)
"THESE ARE THE HANDS
"THAT WILL WORK
ALONGSIDE YOURS
"AS TOGETHER YOU BUILD
YOUR FIRST HOME,
"PLANT YOUR FIRST GARDEN,
"AND WALK FORWARD, HAND IN HAND,
INTO YOUR FUTURE.
"THESE ARE THE HANDS
THAT WILL PASSIONATELY LOVE YOU
"AND CHERISH YOU,
THE ONLY ONES
"WITH THE ABILITY
TO COMFORT YOU
LIKE NO ONE ELSE CAN."
(breathes deeply)
(voice breaking)
"THESE ARE THE HANDS
"THAT WILL TENDERLY HOLD
YOUR FIRST CHILD,
"THE HANDS THAT HOLD
YOUR FAMILY TOGETHER AS ONE.
"AND LASTLY,
THESE ARE THE HANDS
"THAT,
EVEN WHEN WRINKLED AND AGED,
"WILL STILL BE REACHING
FOR YOURS
"AS THEY HOLD YOU HERE NOW,
PROMISING YOU THEY WILL NEVER,
EVER LET YOU GO."
EVERYONE HERE TODAY
HAS TRAVELED
GREAT DISTANCES
TO WITNESS THIS MOMENT.
AND AS FRIENDS AND FAMILY
OF ASHLEY AND J.P.,
IT IS OUR RESPONSIBILITY
TO SUPPORT THIS COUPLE
IN THEIR FUTURE JOURNEY
AS HUSBAND AND WIFE.
WILL YOU ALL PLEASE RISE?
DOES EVERYONE HERE TODAY
AGREE TO LOVE, RESPECT,
AND HELP NURTURE ASHLEY AND J.P.
AS THEY BEGIN THEIR JOURNEY
AS HUSBAND AND WIFE?
IF SO, PLEASE SAY "WE WILL."
(guests) WE WILL.
(Chris) THANK YOU.
PLEASE BE SEATED.
LADIES.
COMING UP--
ASHLEY AND J.P. EXCHANGE
THEIR EMOTIONAL WEDDING VOWS,
WHEN THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"THE BACHELORETTE" CONTINUES.
♪
SantHo, Ho, Ho!anta!
Santa!
Want to see some magic?
Watch this! Merry Chr...
(Crash) Ow!
I landed on my keys.
Did you get that?
Oh yeah.
That was amazing.
Here you go.
That was a fun trick!
See? Santa's okay.
Walk it off Santa.
Share videos instantly
with S Beam.
On the Galaxy SIII
and Note II.
For a limited time get two flip
covers for the price of one.
Exclusively at Verizon.
I made the clear choice.
I'm getting Claritin Clear
with Claritin-D.
Nasal congestion keep me away ?
Not since I made
the clear choice.
Non-drowsy Claritin-D.
Decongestant products on
the shelf can take hours
to start working.
Claritin-D starts to work
in just 30 minutes.
I can't wait hours for
a nasal decongestant.
That's why I made the clear
choice and got Claritin-D.
It has the best
decongestant for colds.
This cold season, get Claritin-D
at the pharmacy counter.
Live Claritin Clear.
ASHLEY AND J.P.,
WE HAVE ALL COME HERE TOGETHER
TO CELEBRATE WITH YOU
THE LOVE YOU HAVE DISCOVERED
IN EACH OTHER,
AND WE WHOLEHEARTEDLY SUPPORT
YOUR DECISION
TO CONTINUE YOUR JOURNEY
TOGETHER AS HUSBAND AND WIFE.
TODAY, YOUR WEDDING DAY,
JUST ONE BRIEF DAY IN TIME,
AND ALTHOUGH YOUR VOWS ARE
SPOKEN IN A MATTER OF MINUTES,
THEY ARE PROMISES
THAT WILL LAST A LIFETIME.
AND THINGS WILL NEVER QUITE
BE THE SAME BETWEEN YOU,
FOR AFTER THESE VOWS,
YOU SHALL SAY TO THE WORLD,
"THIS IS MY HUSBAND."
"THIS IS MY WIFE."
NOW ASHLEY AND J.P.
WILL READ VOWS
THEY'VE PREPARED FOR EACH OTHER.
WHO'S GOING FIRST?
(whispers) J.P.
I'LL GO FIRST.
(speaks indistinctly)
WHATEVER YOU...
I HAVE TO ADMIT I WAS NEVER
A BIG BELIEVER IN FATE.
NEVER THOUGHT
THAT ONE WOMAN AND ONE MAN
WERE PUT ON THIS WORLD
TO MEET EACH OTHER...
(exhales deeply)
AND THEN I MET YOU.
(sniffles)
WHAT ARE THE ODDS
THAT A SMALL-TOWN GIRL
FROM SOMEWHERE--
YOU GOTTA HOLD IT TOGETHER,
'CAUSE I'M NOT GONNA
HOLD IT TOGETHER FOR YOU.
(laughter)
SORRY. (chuckles)
WHAT ARE--
WHAT ARE THE ODDS
THAT A SMALL-TOWN GIRL
FROM SOMEWHERE
CLOSE TO THE NORTH POLE...
(laughter)
WOULD EVER, EVER FIND
AND FALL IN LOVE
WITH A BORN-AND-BRED
NEW YORKER?
IF THAT'S NOT
AN EXAMPLE OF FATE,
I DON'T KNOW WHAT IS.
ASHLEY, YOU ARE
THE KINDEST, WARMEST,
MOST BEAUTIFUL PERSON,
INSIDE AND OUT,
I HAVE EVER KNOWN.
AND YOU MAKE ME, BY FAR,
A MUCH, MUCH BETTER MAN.
I CAN'T PICTURE MY LIFE
WITHOUT YOU.
(sniffles)
EVERY SINGLE DAY,
I HAVE ASKED MYSELF
WHAT HAVE I DONE TO DESERVE
SOMEONE LIKE YOU?
WELL, THE TRUTH OF THE MATTER IS
I PROBABLY DON'T DESERVE YOU,
BUT NOW THAT I'VE GOT YOU,
NOW THAT WE'VE FOUND EACH OTHER
AND FALLEN IN LOVE,
I HOPE YOU KNOW THAT I WILL
NEVER, EVER LET YOU GO.
(exhales deeply)
NOT ONLY ARE YOU
MY ONE TRUE LOVE,
BUT YOU'RE MY BEST FRIEND.
YOU ARE
MY ABSOLUTE EVERYTHING.
AND I PROMISE TO CHERISH
OUR LOVE AND YOU
FOR THE REST OF OUR LIVES.
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
(whispers)
I LOVE YOU, TOO, BABY.
(exhales deeply)
J.P...
FROM THE FIRST TIME WE MET,
MY HEART HAS BEEN DRAWN TO YOU.
WITH EACH GLANCE, YOUR SPARKLY
SMILE ENLIGHTENS MY LIFE,
AND I PROMISE
TO LOOK AT IT EACH DAY
AND REMEMBER
THAT NO MATTER WHAT...
NO MATTER WHAT,
HAPPINESS WILL ALWAYS LIE
WITHIN US.
YOUR DEDICATION TO FAMILY
AND OUR FUTURE FAMILY
INSPIRES ME
AND REMINDS ME
THAT RELATIONSHIPS ARE
THE MOST IMPORTANT THING
IN LIFE.
I PROMISE
TO NEVER FORGET THIS.
THE WAY YOU KEEP UP
WITH MY UNSTOPPABLE ENERGY,
SOMETIMES
NOT-SO-FUNNY JOKES...
(laughs)
AND WALK
MY TEACUP YORKIE BOO...
OUR.
OUR YORKIE BOO...
(laughter)
ASSURES ME THAT YOU ARE
MY PERFECT MATCH.
IN TODAY AND EVERY DAY,
I PROMISE TO ALWAYS
CHOOSE HAPPINESS,
NO MATTER
WHAT THE CIRCUMSTANCE.
I PROMISE TO WAKE UP
EVERY MORNING
AND FALL IN LOVE WITH YOU
ALL OVER AGAIN.
I PROMISE THAT EVERY DAY
WE ARE TOGETHER
WILL BE THE GREATEST DAY
OF MY LIFE.
I LOVE YOU, BOO BOO.
(whispers indistinctly)
CAN'T KISS.
(laughter)
WE'LL GET TO THAT PART,
I PROMISE.
I PROMISE WE'LL GET THERE.
(clears throat)
ASHLEY AND J.P.,
THESE RINGS ARE NOW TO BE GIVEN
AND RECEIVED
AS BONDS OF NEVER-ENDING LOVE
AND DEVOTED FRIENDSHIP,
CIRCLES OF LIFE,
CIRCLES OF LOVE.
MAY THESE RINGS BE BLESSED
AS THE SYMBOLS OF THIS UNION.
J.P., PLEASE TAKE ASHLEY'S RING.
PUT IT ON HER FINGER.
AND REPEAT AFTER ME.
"THIS RING IS OUR SYMBOL..."
THIS RING IS OUR SYMBOL...
"THAT YOU ARE
MY CHOSEN ONE ..."
THAT YOU ARE
MY CHOSEN ONE...
"IN ALL TIMES,
IN ALL PLACES ..."
IN ALL TIMES,
IN ALL PLACES...
"AND IN ALWAYS FOREVER."
AND ALWAYS FOREVER.
"AND WITH THIS RING,
I MARRY YOU."
AND WITH THIS RING,
I MARRY YOU.
ASHLEY, TAKE J.P.'s RING.
PLEASE PLACE IT ON HIS FINGER
AND REPEAT AFTER ME.
"THIS RING IS OUR SYMBOL...
THIS RING IS OUR SYMBOL...
"THAT YOU ARE
MY CHOSEN ONE..."
THAT YOU ARE
MY CHOSEN ONE...
"IN ALL TIMES,
IN ALL PLACES..."
IN ALL TIMES,
IN ALL PLACES...
"AND IN ALWAYS FOREVER."
AND IN ALWAYS FOREVER.
"AND WITH THIS RING,
I MARRY YOU."
AND WITH THIS RING,
I MARRY YOU.
(camera shutter clicks)
FOR AS MUCH AS J.P. AND ASHLEY
HAVE CONSENTED TOGETHER
TO JOIN THEIR LIVES
IN THE BONDS OF MATRIMONY...
(mouths words)
AND HAVE PLEDGED THEIR LOVE
AND LOYALTY TO EACH OTHER,
I THEREFORE,
BY THE POWER VESTED IN ME,
NOW PRONOUNCE YOU
HUSBAND AND WIFE.
J.P.,
YOU MAY NOW KISS YOUR BRIDE.
(laughter)
(cheers, applause, and whistles)
(J.P. speaks indistinctly)
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IT IS MY HONOR
TO ANNOUNCE TO YOU
MR. AND MRS. ROSENBAUM.
(cheering)
♪ I REMEMBER THE DAY WE MET
♪ I KNEW I WOULD NEVER FORGET
THAT SMILE ♪
♪ LA, LA, LA, LA, LA
♪ YOU WALKED UP TO ME
♪ SAW RIGHT THROUGH ME
♪ TROUBLE'S OUT OF THE WAY
♪ OUR LOVE IS HERE TO STAY
♪ AND IT WAS WORTH THE FIGHT
♪ BA, BA, BA, DA
♪ I JUST CAN'T WAIT TO SAY
♪ THOSE WORDS, A PROMISE MINE
♪ OH, I WILL MAKE YOU MINE
♪ BA, BA, BA, DA
♪ I JUST CAN'T WAIT TO SAY
WHOO!
♪ AND I WILL MAKE YOU MINE
♪ BA, BA, BA, DA
YOU'RE GOOD.
(laughs)
♪ AND I JUST WANT YOU
TO KNOW, BABY ♪
WHOO!
♪ THAT WHEN
BABY!
♪ YOU CAME ALONG
BABY, I WANTED TO KISS YOU
THE WHOLE TIME.
(laughs)
♪ TROUBLE'S OUT OF THE WAY
(Ashley) MM.
♪ OUR LOVE IS HERE TO STAY
MMM!
♪ AND IT WAS
WE'RE MARRIED.
(laughs)
YEAH! I LOVE YOU.
I AM--THIS--
YOU LOOK UNBELIEVABLY STUNNING.
HOW'S IT FEEL?
HOW'S IT FEEL TO BE
A MARRIED MAN?
DOES IT FEEL SO GOOD?
FEELS GREAT.
(speaks indistinctly)
♪ AND I WILL MAKE YOU MINE
(laughs)
♪ BA, BA, BA, DA
♪ I'LL MAKE YOU MINE
MM. I LOVE YOU.
(whispers) I LOVE YOU, TOO.
(kiss)
COMING UP, IT'S THE EXCLUSIVE
WEDDING RECEPTION
EVERYONE WILL BE TALKING ABOUT.
OH, MY GOD!
THIS IS STUNNING!
(amplified voice)
MR. AND MRS. ROSENBAUM.
(cheering)
SO HOT! SO HOT!
AAH!
AND A SPECIAL SNEAK PEEK
AT THE EXCITING NEW SEASON
OF "THE BACHELOR."
I LOVE YOU.
WHEN "ASHLEY & J.P.'s WEDDING"
CONTINUES.
♪
[ Female Announcer ]
THE ONE FOR ALL.
MCDONALD'S DOLLAR MENU.
HOME OF THE MEATY, MELTY
MCDOUBLE YOU LOVE.
AND OTHER AMAZING TASTES
FOR JUST A DOLLAR EACH.
♪
EVERY DAY, AS ALWAYS,
THERE'S A LOT TO LOVE
FOR A LITTLE
ON MCDONALD'S DOLLAR MENU.
♪
SCOTLAND!
AYE...AND DO YOU KNOW WHERE
YOUR LEUKEMIA TREATMENT
WAS DISCOVERED?
ST. JUDE!
RIGHT!
AFTER THREE UNSUCCESSFUL
MARROW TRANSPLANTS,
ST. JUDE CHILDREN'S RESEARCH
HOSPITAL DEVELOPED
A BOLD NEW FOURTH TRANSPLANT
THAT HELPED SAVE BRENNAN.
FORE!
I SAID FOUR. WHY YOU YELLING?
GOOD ONE!
GIVE THANKS FOR THE HEALTHY
KIDS IN YOUR LIFE.
AND GIVE TO THOSE WHO ARE
NOT. GO TO ST. JUDE DOT ORG
OR SHOP WHERE EVER YOU SEE
THE ST. JUDE LOGO.
♪
WELCOME BACK TO THIS SPECIAL
EDITION OF "THE BACHELOR."
ASHLEY AND J.P.
HAVE GOTTEN MARRIED.
IT WAS A LONG AND SOMETIMES
EMOTIONAL JOURNEY FOR OUR COUPLE
TO GET TO THIS DAY,
AND NOW ALL OF THEIR
ROMANTIC DREAMS HAVE COME TRUE.
BUT THE DAY ISN'T OVER YET.
IT'S NOW TIME
FOR THE PARTY OF A LIFETIME.
♪
(indistinct conversations)
OH, MY GOD!
THIS IS STUNNING!
TODAY WAS ONE OF
THE MOST INCREDIBLE WEDDINGS
I'VE EVER BEEN TO--
TO BE THERE, AND TO FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE GONNA BREAK DOWN AND CRY
'CAUSE YOU'RE SO HAPPY
FOR THOSE TWO PEOPLE.
THERE'S SUCH LOVE IN THE ROOM
FOR THIS BEAUTIFUL COUPLE.
ASHLEY LOOKED STUNNING.
SHE LOOKED--
WHAT A BEAUTIFUL BRIDE.
(amplified voice)
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IF I COULD HAVE YOUR ATTENTION,
ONCE AGAIN, IT IS MY HONOR
TO INTRODUCE TO YOU
MR. AND MRS. ROSENBAUM.
(cheers and whistles)
SO HOT! SO HOT!
THEY LOOK LIKE
THE PURE DEFINITION
OF HAPPINESS AND JOY...
AND LOVE.
AND IN LOVE. YEAH.
MM-HMM.
I MEAN, THEY LOOK SO WONDERFUL,
AND IT WAS SO GREAT TO SEE.
AAH!
GET OVER HERE!
ASHLEY IS STUNNING,
AND IT MAKES ME WANT
TO BE 15, 10 YEARS YOUNGER.
(laughs)
AND DOING THIS AGAIN.
I'M SOMEONE'S WHO'S BEEN IN LOVE
A COUPLE TIMES
AND HAS HAD IT NOT WORK OUT
A COUPLE TIMES.
SEEING HOW HAPPY
ASHLEY AND J.P. ARE,
IT REALLY MAKES ME HAVE
A RENEWED FAITH IN IT,
AND--AND--AND THINK
MAYBE I SHOULDN'T, YOU KNOW,
THROW IN THE TOWEL JUST YET.
HI!
HI.
CONGRATULATIONS!
OH, MY GOD! SO AMAZING.
THANK YOU.
I'M SO HAPPY FOR YOU.
THANKS.
J.P. AND ASHLEY LOOK SO IN LOVE.
I MEAN, THE KIND OF LOVE
THAT PEOPLE SEE,
AND THEY JUST--
THEY CAN FEEL IT.
BOO WAS SO--
I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE BEST.
SHE WAS REAL SWEET, RIGHT,
AND REAL CUTE?
SHE WAS THE BEST.
OKAY.
I KNOW IT'S REAL
WHEN I LOOK AT THEM,
AND IT JUST--IT'S AWESOME.
ALL RIGHT, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
IF I COULD HAVE YOUR ATTENTION,
IT IS TIME FOR THE FIRST DANCE.
ASH, J.P., COME JOIN ME
ON THE DANCE FLOOR.
THEY WILL BE DANCING TO "LOVE"
PERFORMED BY MR. MATT WHITE.
TAKE IT AWAY.
(speaks indistinctly)
SORRY.
♪ AND LOVE
♪ SUCH A SILLY GAME
WE'VE PLAYED ♪
♪
SITTING THERE, WATCHING ASHLEY
AND J.P. AND THEIR FIRST DANCE,
I REALLY DID--I GOT CHILLS.
THEY LOOKED SO IN LOVE
AND JUST SO PEACEFUL TOGETHER,
AND THAT'S SOMETHING THAT
I THINK EVERY GIRL LOOKS FOR.
♪ AND NOW I SEE
MM.
♪ I WAS SO UPSET
CAN I TWIRL YOU?
SURE. I DON'T KNOW IT'S--
HOW'S IT'S GONNA TURN OUT.
♪ YOU WALK AWAY
♪ IT HURTS
BUT I JUST WANT TO SAY ♪
♪ OH, OH, OH, OH, LOVE
♪
♪ I CAN FEEL IT IN OUR KISS
♪ IT IS SOMETHING I WILL MISS
♪ WHAT IS LOVE? WHAT IS LOVE?
♪ I JUST WANTED TO BE LOVED
(cheering)
ONE OF THE THINGS THAT
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO THE MOST
IS ASHLEY AND J.P.
HAVING CHILDREN.
I WANT MORE COUSINS
IN THE FAMILY.
I WANT MORE CHRISTMASES
AND THANKSGIVINGS
AND MORE FAMILY REUNIONS.
I JUST LOOK FORWARD
TO EVERYTHING
THAT'S TO COME FOR THEM.
(Jillian) WHEN YOU MEET SOMEBODY
LIKE ASHLEY AND J.P.,
YOU ONLY WISH HAPPINESS.
WHATEVER YOU FEEL TONIGHT,
WHICH IS THAT ENERGY AND LOVE,
I WANT THAT TO BE WITH THEM
UNTIL THE DAY THEY DIE,
YOU KNOW, FOREVER.
PARTY!
(laughs)
WELL,
THE PARTY CONTINUES INSIDE,
BUT UNFORTUNATELY,
WE HAVE TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
I WAS TRULY GRATEFUL TO BE
A PART OF THIS DAY.
AND FOR ALL OF US HERE
AT "THE BACHELOR,"
WE WISH ASHLEY AND J.P.
NOTHING BUT THE VERY BEST.
THE GOOD NEWS--THE EXCITEMENT
DOESN'T STOP HERE.
THE NEW SEASON OF "THE BACHELOR"
WITH SEAN LOWE
PREMIERES JANUARY 7th,
RIGHT HERE ON ABC.
THIS SEASON ON...
(women scream)
(Sean) WOW. THERE ARE
SO MANY BEAUTIFUL WOMEN.
THIS IS BEAUTIFUL.
I'M SO OPTIMISTIC
THAT I WILL FIND LOVE
WITH ONE OF THESE WOMEN.
AAH!
(woman) THIS IS SO AMAZING.
(Sean) I CAN'T THINK OF
ANY OTHER PLACE I'D RATHER BE.
(all screaming)
(woman) I JUST THINK I'M
THE LUCKIEST GIRL IN THE WORLD.
(Sean) I'M THE LUCKIEST GUY IN
THE WORLD TO BE HERE RIGHT NOW.
(woman) SEAN'S THE PERFECT GUY.
(laughs)
THIS IS UNFORGETTABLE.
(woman) MY FAIRY TALE WITH SEAN
HAS BEGUN.
♪
(Sean) THIS IS GORGEOUS, HUH?
(woman) THIS IS AMAZING.
(woman) I ALWAYS ENVISIONED
A PERFECT FAIRY TALE
BEING LIKE THIS.
I JUST SEE SOMETHING
IN YOUR EYES
THAT IS JUST VERY SWEET
AND GENUINE.
AAH!
WHOO!
I'M CRAZY ABOUT YOU.
(woman) I'VE NEVER FELT
SO SPECIAL, SO CARED FOR,
IN MY ENTIRE LIFE.
I PROMISE YOU,
I'M GONNA MAKE YOU SO HAPPY.
WHEN YOU PUT A BUNCH OF GIRLS
TOGETHER,
THERE'S GONNA BE DRAMA.
(woman)
JUST DON'T INTERRUPT ME.
REALLY? ARE YOU
IN HIGH SCHOOL STILL?
WHAT'S COMING OUT HAS TO DO WITH
THE BURDEN OF HOLDING A SECRET.
SHE SAID THAT THERE WERE
OTHER MEN.
(woman) SHE HAS A BOYFRIEND.
(woman) WOW.
(Sean) THERE ARE WOMEN HERE
THAT AREN'T HERE
FOR THE RIGHT REASONS.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
BECAUSE I LOVE YOU.
(Sean) WHOA.
(man) I'M NOT LEAVING
WITHOUT YOU.
OH, MY GOD.
I'M SO CONFUSED RIGHT NOW.
CAN YOU GIVE US A MINUTE?
DON'T PUT YOUR HANDS ON ME.
(woman) THESE GIRLS ARE CRAZY.
WHO MADE THESE?
THEY TASTE LIKE (bleep).
(woman) TIERRA'S A BITCH.
(woman) SHE WANTS THE ROSE.
SHE DOESN'T WANT SEAN.
HE SHOULD KNOW.
WHO YOU GET IS
A COMPLETELY DIFFERENT GIRL
THAN THE HOUSE GETS.
(Tierra) I'M NOT FRIENDS WITH
GIRLS WHO LIKE MY BOYFRIENDS.
I'M NOT.
SHE'S THE GIRL THAT WANTS
PEOPLE TO BE JEALOUS OF HER.
YOU WONDER WHY YOU DON'T VIBE
WITH ANY OF THE GIRLS?
YOU'RE JUST NEGATIVE.
I'M ABOVE EVERYONE ELSE, AND I'M
DONE WITH THIS CONVERSATION.
(Tierra) I'M NOT GONNA LET
ANY GIRL STOP ME
FROM BEING WITH SEAN.
IT'S, LIKE,
GETTING OUT OF CONTROL.
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH,
BECAUSE I WILL BITE.
(woman) ALL RIGHT, BITCH.
GAME ON.
(Tierra screams)
OH, MY GOD.
(Tierra crying) I CAN'T BELIEVE
THEY DID THIS TO ME.
(sirens wail, horn blares)
IT'S SO MESSED UP.
(woman) SHE'S NOT OKAY.
SERIOUSLY, THIS IS SO STUPID.
(man) WHERE'S IT HURT?
I CAN'T BE TORTURED LIKE THIS.
(crying) I HOPE THE GIRLS GOT
WHAT THEY WANTED.
(crying)
(woman) THIS IS REALLY CRAZY.
I MEAN, SERIOUSLY,
THIS IS THE END OF IT.
(crying)
(exhales deeply)
(Sean) I DIDN'T PLAN ON THIS.
(sniffles)
I'M JUST STUNNED, AND I DON'T
KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
(groans)
IT BLINDSIDED ME SO BADLY.
I CAME HERE HOPING TO FIND
THE WOMAN I'M SUPPOSED TO SPEND
THE REST OF MY LIFE WITH.
(woman) I JUST THINK
THE WORLD OF YOU.
(Sean) FOR A SECOND THERE,
I THOUGHT, IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
(woman) THERE IS SOMETHING
THAT I DO WANT TO TELL YOU.
BUT IF YOU PERSEVERE
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES,
YOU CAN FIND LOVE.
(woman) I LOVE YOU.
I KNOW WITHOUT A SHADOW
OF A DOUBT WHO MY WIFE IS.
I CAN PICTURE US SPENDING
THE REST OF OUR LIVES TOGETHER.
I WANT HER TO HAVE MY HEART,
I WANT TO BE HER BEST FRIEND,
AND I JUST WANT TO BE THE MAN
THAT SHE WANTS ME TO BE.
I'M GONNA SPEND THE REST
OF MY LIFE WITH THIS ONE WOMAN,
AND I CAN'T WAIT.
(cheering)
(man)
♪ HAVA NAGILA, HAVA NAGILA ♪
AAH!
♪ HAVA NAGILA, VENIS'MECHA ♪
♪ HAVA NAGILA, HAVA NAGILA
♪ HAVA NAGILA, VENIS'MECHA
♪ HAVA NERANENA,
HAVA NERANENA ♪
[ Female Announcer ]
At Yoplait,
we want you to feel
even better
about your favorite flavors.
So when you call, tweet,
and post, we listen.
That's why Yoplait Light
and Yoplait Original
are now made with
no high fructose corn syrup.
And why we use
only natural colors
and natural flavors
in Yoplait Original.
So, anything else we can do
for you, let us know.