ALEX TREBEK!
THANK YOU, JOHNNY.
THANK YOU, LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
AND WELCOME TO OUR SHOW.
I START OFF TODAY
BY WARNI--
I'M GOING TO BE
ON MY VERY BEST BEHAVIOR,
BECAUSE THERE ARE THREE VERY
IMPORTANT MEMBERS OF MY FAMILY,
WHO ARE SEATED IN THE AUDIENCE--
MY BEAUTIFUL WIFE JEAN,
MY 91-YEAR-OLD MOM LUCILLE,
AND MY ONLY
AMERICAN COUSIN DOLORES,
WHO IS VISITING
WITH US FROM FLORIDA.
GOOD TO HAVE
ALL THREE OF THEM HERE TODAY.
BOOMIE IS OUR CHAMPION. HE HAS
HAD TWO RUNAWAY GAMES IN A ROW.
CAN HE MAKE IT THREE
AGAINST SILAS AND BETH?
LET'S START FINDING OUT.
GOOD LUCK, PLAYERS.
HERE WE GO--
THE JEOPARDY! ROUND,
AND THESE ARE GOING TO BE
YOUR CATEGORIES...
EACH CORRECT RESPONSE BEGINNING
WITH THAT LETTER, OF COURSE.
BOOMIE, START US.
DIALECTS FOR $200, PLEASE.
WHAT IS JAPANESE?
UH, DIALECTS FOR $400.
WHAT IS ARABIC?
DIALECTS, $600.
WHAT IS GERMAN?
UH, DIALECTS FOR $800.
WHAT IS SPANISH?
DIALECTS, $1,000.
WHAT IS THE PHILIPPINES?
"S" AS IN SIMILE FOR $200.
WHAT IS SNUG?
SIMILE FOR $400.
WHAT IS SLIPPERY?
SIMILE--"S" AS IN SIMILE
FOR $600.
WHAT IS SHARP?
SIMILE, $800.
WHAT IS STUBBORN?
"S" AS IN SIMILE FOR $1,000.
WHAT IS STILL?
YOU DOUBLE
YOUR SCORE TO $2,000.
UH, BURNS, BABY, BURNS,
FOR $200.
WHAT IS SC?
UH, BURNS FOR $400.
WHOTLAND"AULD LANG SYNE"?
UH, BURNS FOR $600.
WHAT IS REQUIRE?
NO. BOOMIE.
WHAT IS "DESIRE"?
BURNS FOR $1,000.
AND YOU'RE
IN THE LEAD.
I'D LIKE TO WAGER $1,200.
ALL RIGHTY,
HERE IS THE CLUE...
WHAT ARE "MICE AND MEN"?
THAT'S IT,
AT
ADDS TO YOUR MARGIN.
YOU'RE AT $5,400,
AND WE'RE AT OUR FIRST
COMMERCIAL BREAK,
WHICH MEANS WE'LL BE BACK
IN A MOMENT OR TWO.
AND TH
AND BETH WATKINS FIRST
IS FROM SAVANNAH, GEORGIA.
SHE IS A GRADUATE STUDENT
OF MEDIEVAL STUDIES.
NOTICE HOW I
PRONOUNCED THAT CORRECTLY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
NOW YOU TRAVEL
WITH A GOOD-LUCK CHARM
OF SOME KIND.
YES.
TELL US ABOUT THAT.
UH, IT'S A SMALL
STUFFED ORANGE FISH, UH,
THAT MY SISTER GOT
AS A PRIZE OUT OF A CEREAL BOX.
AND SO IT'S A WAY OF TRAVELING--
I ACTUALLY HAVE IT WITH ME--
TRAVELING WITH IT
WHEN I GO AROUND THE COUNTRY
WHEN I VISIT.
SHOW THE AUDIENCE.
THERE WE GO.
IT'S VERY NICE.
THAT'S RIGHT.
DOES IT USUALLY WORK?
OR
IT DOES WO
UM, AND YOU KNOW, HE'S--
WE'VE GONE TO MANY PLACES
TOGETHER, SO...
OKAY, GOOD.
SILAS CRAWFORD,
ATTORNEY FROM FLORIDA,
BROKE HIS TOE
PLAYING WHATRK,
PLAYING DRUMS.
I'M A NOVICE DRUMMER,
AND ONE DAY
AND I WAS RUNNIN I WAS AT HOME,
PLAYING WHATRK,
AND I WAS RUNNING A BATH.
SO I THOUGHT I'D
SIT DOWN IN MY FLIP-FLOPS
AND HIT THE ?
MINUTES AND GOT CARRIED AWAY.
REMEMBERED THE WATER,
JUMPED UP, RAN,
HIT MY FOOT
ON THE HI-HAT STAND,
AND BROKE MY LITTLE TOE.
OH, GOSH.
WELL, YOU DIDN'T
KICK THE HI-HAT STAND
AFTER HURTING YOUR TOE,
DID YOU?
OH, NO.
'CAUSE THAT HAPPENS
SO OFTEN WHEN WE STUB OUR TOE.
WE GET ANGRY,
AND JUST...
NO, ONE TOE WAS ENOUGH.
ONE TOE IS ENOUGH. ALL RIGHT.
BOOMIE AGLIETTI IS OUR CHAMPION.
MET AN ATTRACTIVE SWISS GIRL
IN NEW YORK CITY.
DIDN'T GENAME,
BUT INTELLIGENT YOUNG FELLOW
THAT HE IS,
DID WHAT TO TRY
AND TRACK HER DOWN?
SO I WENT
BACK TO THE LOBBY
OF THE DORM
WHERE SHE LIVED
AND I KIND OF SNUCK MY WAY IN
THROUGH THE--THROUGH THE GUARDS,
AND I POSTED A SIGN
THAT SAID,
"MISSING--BEAUTIFUL FRENCH, UH,
BEAUTIFUL SWISS GIRL" IN FRENCH.
AND, UH, I LEFT KIND OF
A DUMMY E-MAIL ADDRESS
JUST IN CASE SHE HAPPENED
TO SEE IT, AND SHE DID RESPOND.
AND THEN SOME--FOR SOME REASON,
I MOVED OUT OF NEW YORK.
SO I DON'T KNOW WHY.
YOU'RE A WRITER.
YEAH.
YEAH. GREAT BEGINNING,
LOUSY ENDING.
TERRIBLE, TERRIBLE.
OKAY, MAAS WE CONTINUE.
UH, ENTERTAINER'S TWITTER BIO
FOR $200, PLEASE.
FIRST CLUE
IN THE CATEGORY...
WHO IS CHARLIE SHEEN?
TWITTER BIOS FOR $400.
AND THAT'S
THE GREAT HUMOR
OF JIMMY FALLON.
SILAS, GO AGAIN.
RTAINER'S BIOS FOR $600.
WHO IS O'BRIEN?
CONAN O'BRIEN, YES.
TWITTER FOR $800.
WHO IS KATHY GRIFFIN?
FINISH THE CATEGORY.
WHO IS KIM KARDASHIAN?
PASTIMES FOR $200.
WHAT IS PEZ?
UH, PASTIMES FOR $400.
TAKE A PAGE
FROM THIS PASTIME
SEEN HERE.
WHAT IS SCRAPBOOKING?
UH, PASTIMES, $600.
WHAT IS CROSSWORD PUZZLE?
PASTIMES, $800.
WHAT IS HAM RADIO?
COMPANY LOGOS FOR $200.
WHAT IS ALLSTA
COMPANY LOGOS FOR $400.
WHAT IS TARGET?
UH, COMPANY LOGOS, $800.
WHAT IS TEXACO?
NO. SILAS.
WHAT IS MOBIL?
COMPANY LOGOS FOR $1,000.
AND THAT'S BURGER KING.
NOW THE LAST CLUE--
$1,000 IN PASTIMES...
WHAT IS PURL?
GOOD FOR $1,000,
TAKING YOU TO $4,800.
YOU'RE IN SECOND PLACE.
SIING FIRST
IN DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
AND THAT ROUND
WILL BEGIN AFTER THIS.
CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED IN PART BY...
AS WE BEGIN
THE DOUBLE JEOPARDY! ROUND,
WE'RE GOING BACK, BACK, BACK
FOR OUR FIRST CATEGORY.
'S CALLED...
THE "B" IN QUOTATION MARKS...
GIVE US THE TV SHOW...
THE LETTER T WILL BE
EXACTLY IN THE MIDDLE
OF EACH CORRECT RESPONSE.
ALL RIGHT, LETS GO TO WORK.
SILAS, START.
TV SHOW SUPPORTING CHARACTERS
FOR $400.
WHAT IS "THE SIMPSONS"?
TV SHOW CHARACTERS, $800.
WHAT IS "LOST"?
CHARACTERS, $1,200.
THAT'S "DESPERATE HOUSEWIVES."
I KNEW THAT. BOOMIE.
COULD I GET THE BIRDS & THE "B"s
FOR $400, PL
WHAT IS BLACKBIRD?
"B"s FOR $800.
WHAT IS A BISMARCK?
UH, BIRDS & "B"s, $1,200.
WHAT IS A BUDGIE?
BIRDS & "B"s, $1,600.
WHAT IS THE BOOBY?
BIRDS FOR $2,000.
WHAT IS THE BUZZARD?
GOOD FOR $2,000.
UH, TV SHOW, $1,600.
WHAT IS "ENTOURAGE"?
SUPPORTING CHARA $2,000.
WHAT IS "HOUSE"?
HOUSE, M.D.,
TAKING YOU TO $8,600.
PLAYING MIDDLE T, $400.
WHAT IS ALTAR?
THE T IS IN THE MIDDLE
OF THAT WORD.
MIDDLE T, $800.
WHAT IS ABSTAIN?
MIDDLE T, $1,200.
WHAT IS AUCTION?
DDLE T, $1,600.
WHAT IS THETA?
NO. BOOMIE.
WHAT IS ETA?
MIDDLE T, $2,000.
WHAT'S A LYCANTHROPE?
UH, CHURCHES & CATHEDRALS, $400.
WHAT IS PRAGUE?
CHURCHES, $800.
A STATUE OF LEIF ERIKSSON
IS OUT FRONT OF
THE HALLGRíMSKIRKJA CHURCH--
ONE OF THIS COUNTRY'S
TALLEST BUILDINGS.
WHAT IS ICELAND?
CHURCHES, $1,200.
AND YOU ARE
A SHADE OFF THE LEAD.
YOU TRAIL BOOMIE
BY $2,200.
I'LL RISK, UH, $3,000.
$3,000. ALL RIGHT,
THE LEAD WILL BE YOURS,
IF YOU ARE
CORRECT ON THIS...
WHAT IS
THE NATIONAL CATHEDRAL?
NATIONAL CATHEDRAL
IN OUR NATION'S CAPITAL,
WASHINGTON, D.C.
GOOD FOR YOU.
UH, CHURCHES, $1,600.
HERE'S SARAH.
SITES CORRESPONDING
TO THE TENTH THROUGH FINAL
STATIONS OF THE CROSS
ARE WITHIN
THE CHURCH OF THE HOLY THIS--
ANOTHER WORD FOR A TOMB.
IT'S BEEN CALLED CHRISTIANITY'S
MOST HALLOWED GROUND.
WHAT IS SEPULCHRE?
CHURCHES, $2,000.
WHAT IS THE HAGIA SOPHIA?
LET'S GO TIMES PAST
FOR $1,200, PLEASE.
WHAT ARE CHARIOTS?
UH, TIMES PAST, UH, $1,600.
AND YOU
STILL HAVE THE LEAD.
ALL RIGHT,
UM, I'LL RISK $2,000.
$2,000 IT IS.
HERE IS THE CLUE...
UH, WHAT IS PARIS?
NO. THE CONGRESS OF VIENNA,
THE CONGRESS OF VIENNA,
AFTER THE DEFEAT
OF NAPOLéON.
YOU ARE JUST OFF
THE LEAD NOW.
YOU TRAIL BOOMIE BY $400.
GO AGAIN.
UH, TIMES PAST, $2,000.
WHAT IS WESSEX?
YOU'RE IN
THE LEAD AGAIN.
UH, TIMES PAST, $800.
AND THAT PROVINCE
WOULD BE QUE
BETH.
UH, TIMES PAST, $400.
BEC.
BETH.
WHO IS MAO?
FABRICS FOR $800, PLEASE.
WHAT IS BURLAP?
FABRICS ,200.
WHAT IS CREPE?
FABRICS FOR $2,000.
WHAT ARE THE HEBRIDES?
FABRIC, $1,600.
WHATYON?
YOU PICKED
THE RIGHT ONE,
AND NOW
THE LAST CLUE...
WHAT IS THE BARK?
AND THAT PUTS YOU
INTO A TIE WITH BETH
FOR THE LEAD.
SILAS ON THE BOARD
WITH A VERY IMPRESSIVE $8,600.
IT'S COMING DOWN
TO FINAL.
HERE'S THE CATEGORY
FOR THE THREE OF YOU--
AMERICAN AUTHORS.
THINK ABOUT THAT.
MAKE YOUR WAGERS.
WE'LL RETURN SHORTLY.
PERHAPS FITTINGLY
FOR SUCH A HOLY SITE,
THE CHURCH
OF THE HOLY SEPULCHRE
DOESN'T BELONG TO ANY
ONE CHRISTIAN DENOMINATION.
CATHOLICS,
GREEK ORTHODOX, ARMENIANS,
COPTS, SYRIAN JACOBITES,
AND ETHIOPIANS
ALL CLAIM PART OF THE CHURCH
OR HOLD SERVICES IN IT,
BUT ANYONE CAN COME
TO WORSHIP AND BE AMAZED.
YOU NOTICE SOMETHING DIFFERENT
ABOUT THESE TOYS?
THE PRICES ARE SO LOW.
ARE WE DREAMING?
I GOT AN IDEA.
KICK ME IN THE SHIN.
IF I FEEL IT,
WE KNOW THE PRICES ARE REAL.
YEP, THEY'RE REAL.
WE'VE GOT MORE ROLLBACKS ON TOYS
ALL DECEMBER.
WAIT, WAS THAT REAL?
[ Male Announcer ]
THIS CHRISTMAS, GET
THE HOTTEST BRANDS
AND ROLLBACKS
ON THE SEASON'S HOTTEST TOYS,
LIKE THE BEYBLADE
DESTROYER DOME,
ONLY $34.96,
THE NERF ELITE
HAILFIRE, ONLY $29.88
OR SELECT PLAYDOH SETS,
ONLY TEN DOLLARS.
ALL BACK   BY OUR LOW .
AMERICA'S GIFT HEADQUARTERS.
Walmart.
ALL BACK   BY OUR LOW .
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve sED
ttalk about the options on the..
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the political spin.traih
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
Let's keep Medicare...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
E THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
WE ARE LOOKING FOR
AN AMERICAN AUTHOR,
AND TO HELP YOU
AND OUR CONTESTANTS,
HERE IS THE CLUE...
30 SECONDS, PLAYERS.
GOOD LUCK.
♪
I HOPE YOU WERE THINKING
OF THE RIGHT
REVOLUTIONARY WAR HERO.
SILAS, WE COME
TO YOU FIRST.
WHICH AMERICAN AUTHOR
DID YOU COME UP WITH?
YOU WROTE DOWN
"WHO IS WASHINGTON IRVING?"
NAMED FOR GEORGE WASHINGTON.
YOU ARE CORRECT, SIR.
AND YOUR WAGER?
$8,000.
THAT BRINGS YOU
UP TO $16,600.
LET'S GO
TO BETH WATKINS NOW.
SHE WAS
TIED FOR THE LEAD,
AND SHE CAME UP
WITH THE CORRECT RESPONSE.
AND HER WAGER?
HELLO.
$37,200,
AS SHE
MOVES INTO THE LEAD.
AND NOW OVER TO BOOMIE.
WHAT DID HE
COME UP WITH?
HAE INSTEAD,
AND WHAT WILL IT COST YOU?
OOH, YOU WOULD HAVE
BEEN TIED WITH BETH.
WE'D HAVE
HAD CO-CHAMPIONS,
BUT INSTEAD, BETH WATKINS,
YOU ARE THE ONLY PLAYER
COMING BACK TOMORROW
AS OUR "JEOPARDY!" CHAMPION
TO WRAP UP THE WEEK.
WE'LL SEE YOU THEN.
$37,200. WOW. TILL THEN.
SO LONG, EVERYBODY.
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
DONE.
>> I GUESS I STEP BACK AND SAY,
LET'S SAY WE GET TO SOMETHING BY
THE END OF THE YEAR.
YOU HOPE THAT WHATEVER
COMPROMISE THEY COME UP WITH IT
DOES ACHIEVE A GREATER GOOD FOR
THE COUNTRY.
WHATEVER THE FINAL NUMBERS, YOU
HOPE THAT PEOPLE DON'T JUST SIT
AROUND AND APPLAUD THAT WE GOT A
COMPROMISE IF IT DOESN'T
ACCOMPLISH MUCH IN GETTING THE
NATION'S FISCAL HOUSE IN ORDER.
SO IT'S GREAT WE GOT A
COMPROMISE BUT WHAT DO YOU
REALLY ACCOMPLISH?
FISCAL HEALTH OF THE COUNTRY.
>> IT WOULD BE DISHEARTENING IF
THAT WERE THE CASE, IF IT
WEREN'T FOR THE BETTERMENT OF
THE COUNTRY.
>>> IN THE WINDY CITY, A YOUNG
MAN TRYING TO TAKE A PICTURE OF
THE CHICAGO SKYLINES FELL TO HIS
DEATH INSIDE A SMOKESTACK.
HE AND HIS GIRLFRIEND CLIMBED TO
THE ROOF OF THE INTERCONTINENTAL
HOTEL WHEN HE WENT TO THE TOP OF
THAT SMOKESTACK AND LOST HIS
FOOTING.
IT TOOK FIRST RESPONDERS FOUR
HOURS TO CUT THROUGH THE STEEL
BOTTOM OF THE SHAFT TO REACH
HIM, BUT THEY WERE TOO LATE.
>>> POLICE IN TEXAS PULLED OVER
A WOMAN FOR DRIVING ERRATICALLY
AND FOUND HER 8-MONTH-OLD
DAUGHTER IN THE BACK SEAT OF HER
CAR.
SHE ADMITTED SHE DRANK A BEER,
TOOK SOME PROZAC AND XANAX AND
TOLD POLICE HER ROOMMATE WAS
BABYSITTING HER 12-YEAR-OLD SON
BUT COULDN'T REMEMBER THE
ROOMMATE'S NAME.
THAT LITTLE 8-MONTH-OLD JUST
BURIED IN JUNK.
NOT A MOTHER OF THE YEAR AWARD.
>> THAT IS HEART BREAKING.
>>> A POPULAR CHAIN RESTAURANT
IN WYOMING MAY BE TO BLAME FOR A
VIRUS OUTBREAK THAT'S SPREADING
THROUGH THAT CITY NOW.
HEALTH INSPECTORS SAY ABOUT 200
CUSTOMERS BECAME SICK AFTER
EATING AT THE GOLDEN CORRAL
BUFFET.
THE RESTAURANT IS VOLUNTARILY
CLOSING ITS DOORS FOR 24 HOURS
SO IT CAN BE CLEANED AND
DISINFECTED FROM TOP TO BOTTOM.
PUBLIC HEALTH EXPERTS BELIEVE
IT'S INFECTED WITH THE NURO
VIRUS.
>> IT'S THE NUMBER ONE MOST
COMMON FOOD BORN ILLNESS IN THE
UNITED STATES.
IT'S EVERYWHERE.
IT'S BEEN IN THE COMMUNITY FOR
MONTHS.
BUT IT'S SPORADIC.
>> THE VIRUS CAUSES VOMITING,
DIARRHEA, HEADACHES, EVEN FEVER
AND USUALLY LASTS ABOUT 48 HOURS
OR SO.
THE GOLDEN CORRAL WILL REOPEN
AFTER A HEALTH DEPARTMENT
INSPECTION.
>> HOPE THAT STEAK AND FRIED
CHICKEN WAS WORTH IT.
WHATEVER WAS AT THE BUFFET.
>> I DOUBT IT.
>>> HERE'S YOUR FRIDAY FORECAST.
SHOWERS IN SAN DIEGO.
HEAVY RAIN FROM LAS VEGAS TO
ALBUQUERQUE.
MORE THAN A FOOT OF MOUNTAIN
SNOW FROM ARIZONA TO SOUTHERN
UTAH.
THUNDERSTORMS AROUND WICHITA,
OKLAHOMA CITY AND DALLAS.
>> 70s IN DALLAS AND NEW
ORLEANS.
MOSTLY 40s IN THE NORTHEAST
MIDWEST AND PACIFIC NORTHWEST.
57 IN PHOENIX AND 37 IN SALT
LAKE.
>>> TWO COSTCO WORKERS NEAR
BOSTON JUST GOT THE BIGGEST
PAYDAY OF THEIR LIVES.
THEY ARE SPLITTING THE LATEST
POWERBALL JACKPOT.
>> I THINK SHE BOUGHT THESE
TICKETS IN BULK.
ROSA AND REGINALD WON
WEDNESDAY'S $50 BILLION PRIZE.
THEY'RE TAKING THE LUMP SUM
PAYMENT.
SO AFTER TAXES, THAT'S MORE THAN
$11 MILLION EACH.
RIGHT, ROB?
BUT THEY HAVE YET TO DECIDE IF
THEY'RE GOING TO QUIT THEIR JOB.
>> YEAH, OKAY.
SHE PLANS TO BUY A HOME AND TAKE
CARE OF HER CHILDREN AND SIX
GRANDKIDS.
>> HE IS MISSING SEVERAL FRONT
TEETH SAYS DENTAL WORK IS ON HIS
AGENDA.
>> LET'S NOT GO THERE.
THEY'VE BEEN PLAYING POWERBALL
TWICE A WEEK FOR THE PAST TEN
MONTHS.
YOU CAN'T MAKE THIS STUFF UP,
FOLKS.
>> HE SAID IT.
DON'T WRITE US ON FACEBOOK.
NO ONE IS MAKING FUN, HE SAID
THAT HE'S GOING TO GET HIS
CHOMPERS TOGETHER.
>> THAT'S TOUCHING.
>> NOT GOING THERE.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, SEARCHING
FOR TRENDS AMONG THE BIG
NOMINEES OF THIS YEAR'S GOLDEN
GLOBE --
>>> SEARCHING FOR LAST-MINUTE
DEALS AS HOLIDAY AIRFARES GO
SKY HIGH.
HOW YOU CAN SAVE SOME MONEY WITH
EXPERT ADVICE.
KEEP SMILING.
"WORLD NEWS NOW" CONTINUES.
>>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" WEATHER
BROUGHT TO YOU BY CONSUMER
CELLULAR.
>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" WEATHER
BROUGHT TO YOU BY CONSUMER
CELLULAR.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
IF YOU'VE STARTED LOOKING AT
AIRLINE FARES, YOU KNOW PRICES
ARE WAY UP.
YOU JUST WAITED TOO LONG.
>> THAT'S IT.
THE LONGER YOU WAIT TO BOOK YOUR
FLIGHT, THE MORE YOU'LL COUGH
UP.
BUT THERE ARE SOME STRATEGIES TO
HELP YOU SAVE HUNDREDS OF BUCKS.
WITH MORE ON THAT, HERE'S ABC'S
JIM AVILA.
>> Reporter: PLANES ARE FULL,
AND THAT MEANS HIGHER PRICES FOR
HOLIDAY TRAVEL.
A NEW REPORT FROM THE AIRLINE
TRADE GROUP SHOWS DEMAND STRONG
AND PLANES FLYING AT 85% TO 90%
CAPACITY.
NONSTOP TICKET PRICES CHRISTMAS
WEEK ARE NEARLY DOUBLE WHAT THEY
WERE AT THE BEGINNING OF THE
MONTH.
AND RISING BY THE DAY.
>> EVERY DAY YOU WAIT, ADD ABOUT
$7 TO $8 EACH DAY YOU WAIT.
>> Reporter: THE AVERAGE
DOMESTIC AIRFARE IS NOW $414
ACCORDING TO TRAVELOCITY.
A 9% JUMP OVER LAST YEAR'S
HOLIDAY SEASON.
THE MOST EXPENSIVE DAYS TO FLY,
UP TO $500 MORE A TICKET ARE
DECEMBER 21, 22, AND ON THE
RETURN DECEMBER 30, 31 AND NEW
YEAR'S DAY.
THESE ARE THE CHEAPER DAYS TO
FLY.
CHRISTMAS DAY AND THE THREE DAYS
AFTER.
FLYING THEN CAN SAVE AS MUCH AS
$330.
>> WE'RE GOING TO SACRIFICE
PRICE FOR CONVENIENCE.
BUT YOU'LL ALSO ENCOUNTER FEWER
CROWDS AT THE AIRPORT.
>> Reporter: IT'S NOT JUST
AIRFARES MAKING THIS A
PROFITABLE SEASON FOR AIRLINES.
IF YOU'RE CHECKING BAGS, MAKE
SURE THEY'RE NOT OVERWEIGHT BY
USING A HOME SCALE.
AIRLINES CHARGE EXCESSIVE
BAGGAGE SURCHARGES THAT START AT
$90 ON TOP OF THE NORMAL BAGGAGE
FEE.
AND THE SCALES AT THE AIRPORT
ARE NOT ALWAYS ACCURATE.
AN ABC NEWS INVESTIGATION LAST
YEAR AT THIS TIME SHOWED 5% OF
AIRPORT SCALES CHECKED
NATIONWIDE WERE OFF IN ONE
DIRECTION OR THE OTHER BY AT
LEAST HALF AN OUNCE.
ENOUGH TO ADD COSTS.
ADDING INJURY TO THE ALREADY
INSULTING HIGH HOLIDAY FARES.
JIM AVILA, ABC NEWS, WASHINGTON.
>> THAT HANDHELD SCALE IS COOL.
>> THAT SAVES YOU SOME BUCKS
POTENTIALLY.
FLYING SUCKS THESE DAYS.
I'LL SAY IT.
>> THAT'S GOING TO BRING US TO
OUR FACEBOOK QUESTION OF THE
DAY.
>> WE WANT TO KNOW WHAT DO YOU
DO TO SAVE MONEY WHEN YOU TRAVEL
DURING THE HOLIDAYS?
LOGON TO OUR FACEBOOK PAGE AND
LET US KNOW AND SHARE YOUR TIPS
WITH OTHERS.
>> JUST DON'T TRAVEL.
>> THAT'S MY TIP.
I HAVE TO SAY IT.
>> SCROOGE.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, THE GUEST
WHO WAS NOT ALLOWED TO RETURN TO
JON STEWART'S SHOW AND WHY.
>> JON HAD SOME HARSH WORDS.
AND A BAD BOY ACTOR AND HIS
HEARTFELT ACT OF GOOD WILL.
ALL COMING UP NEXT IN "THE
SKINNY."
>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" CONTINUES
AFTER THIS FROM OUR ABC
STATIONS.
♪
♪ SKIPPY, SO SKINNY
>>> THIS IS WILLIS' FAVORITE
SEGMENT.
GOLDEN GLOBE NOMINATIONS WERE
ANNOUNCED YESTERDAY.
LOTS TO GET TO HERE.
LET'S JUST HOP INTO IT.
THE BIG DEAL IS THAT THIS IS A
PRECURSOR TO THE OSCARS.
WE'RE GETTING INTO AWARDS SEASON
NOW.
HERE WE GO.
APPARENTLY THE DAY BELONGED TO
THE MOVIE "LINCOLN."
NOT A SHOCKER HERE.
EVERYONE IS RAVING ABOUT THIS
MOVIE, FOR THE MOST PART.
>> WHICH NONE OF US HAVE SEEN
YET.
>> I'M DYING TO.
JUST SLOW GETTING TO THE MOVIES.
AND "ARGO" BEN AFFLECK'S MOVIE
DID VERY WELL.
BOTH OF THEM GOT NOMINATED FOR
BEST PICTURE DRAMA.
ON TOP OF "LIFE OF PIE," "ZERO
DARK THIRTY."
BEST ACTRESS, JESSICA CHASTAIN,
HELEN MIRREN, NAOMI WATTS,
RACHEL WISE.
BEST ACTOR DRAMA --
DANIEL DAY LEWIS FOR "LINCOLN."
RICHARD GERE, JOHN HAWKS,
JAUQUIN PHOENIX AND DENZEL
WASHINGTON FOR "FLIGHT."
SO THOSE ARE THE HIGHLIGHTS.
AND FOR THE SAKE OF THE COMMISH,
DO WANT TO POINT OUT, FOR BEST
TELEVISION DRAMA, "BREAKING BAD"
"BOARDWALK EMPIRE" "DOUBTING
ABBY," "HOMELAND" AND "THE
NEWSROOM."
JUST WANTED TO ADD THAT IN
THERE.
FOR A SHOW I LOVE THAT HE HATES.
BUT WE HAVE THAT ONGOING FEUD.
>> I LOVE THAT CLAP.
HOW IS THAT JACK?
>> IT'S A GOOD SHOW.
>> THAT I HEAR IS GREAT.
>> WILLIS AND THE COMMISH CAN
HAVE A VIEWING PARTY.
>>> GREAT THING HAPPENING IN NEW
YORK CITY LAST NIGHT.
THEY HAD THE SANDY BENEFIT.
YOU SAW BON JOVI, BRUCE
SPRINGSTEEN, EVERYBODY
COLLABORATING FOR THE VICTIMS.
BUT SOMETHING MICK JAGGER SAID
ON STAGE IS A LITTLE
INSENSITIVE.
HERE'S WHAT HE SAID.
AND HE'S DRAWING ONLY IRE AND
RAGE FROM SOME PEOPLE.
HE SAID THIS HAS TO BE THE
LARGEST COLLECTION OF OLD
ENGLISH MUSICIANS EVER ASSEMBLED
IN MADISON SQUARE GARDEN.
BUT IF IT RAINS IN LONDON,
YOU'VE GOT TO COME AND HELP US.
SO BASICALLY COMPARING HURRICANE
SANDY, WHICH KILLED 140 PEOPLE,
AND REBUILDING IS EXPECTED TO
REACH $70 BILLION, COMPARING
THAT TO RAIN.
>> I'M SURE HE MEANT IT AS A
JOKE.
>> IT WAS A BAD JOKE.
>> DIDN'T REALIZE HOW IT WOULD
COME ACROSS.
>>> JON STEWART HAS SOME HARSH
WORDS.
THERE'S ONE PERSON NEVER ALOUD
TO COME BACK TO HIS SHOW, THAT'S
ACTOR HUGH GRANT.
HUGH WAS ON THE SHOW IN 2009 AND
STEWART WAS AT AN EVENT IN
JERSEY AND WAS TELLING THE
AUDIENCE, HIS QUOTE WAS, HE'S
GIVING EVERYONE THE WORD AND
HE'S A BIG PAIN IN THE A WORD,
JON SAID.
APPARENTLY THERE WAS A CLIP THE
PUBLICIST OF THE MOVIE THAT HUGH
WAS PROMOTING AT THE SEEM AND
SAID OH, IT'S A TERRIBLE CLIP.
STEWART SAID, MAKE A BETTER
"F"-ING MOVIE.
SO NO LOVE LOSS THERE.
>> CHARLIE SHEEN GAVE $100,000
TO LINDSAY LOHAN, WHO SEEMS TO
BE A HOPELESS CAUSE RIGHT NOW
AND GAVE $75,000 AND HIS BODY
DOUBLE GAVE $25,000 TO A CANCER
STRICKEN DAUGHTER OF A HERMOSA
BEACH POLICE OFFICER.
HE JUST HEARD ABOUT IT OVER THE
WEEKEND AND SAID NO PARENT
SHOULD HAVE TO WATCH THEIR KID
GO THROUGH THAT AND GAVE HIM
$75,000, $100,000 TOTAL.
>> NOT BAD, CHARLIE.
CONGRATULATIONS TO HUGH JACKMAN.
YESTERDAY GOT HIS STAR ON THE
HOLLYWOOD WALK OF FAME.
CONGRATULATIONS TO PAULA'S
FANTASY MAN.
Every time someone chooses
Finish over Cascade,
it sparks a movement.
Because people can't
keep it to themselves.
Look !
No ugly spots !
Awesome!
Incredible shine.
I'm switching for good.
Love, love, love Finish!
Over a million people
have switched to Finish.
Visit us on Facebook.
♪
>>> FINALLY THIS HALF HOUR, THE
UNFORGETTABLE HEADLINES OF THIS
PAST WEEK.
>> FROM HIGH PROFILE TRAGEDY TO
POLITICAL FRUSTRATION, HERE IS
OUR FRIDAY REWIND.
>> I DON'T THINK THAT ANYONE
COULD HAVE EXPECTED OR FORESEEN
WHAT WAS GOING TO HAPPEN.
>> THERE'S NOT A MINUTE THAT
GOES BY WE DON'T THINK ABOUT
THAT FAMILY AND WHAT THEY MUST
BE GOING THROUGH AND THE THOUGHT
THAT WE MAY HAVE PLAYED A PART
IN THAT IS GUT WRENCHING.
>> SUCH A BIG SHOCK TO THE
FAMILY.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
SOMETHING THAT MOST PEOPLE THAT
KNOW MY SISTER, SHE WAS A VERY
STRONG PERSON.
>> SHE WAS A PERSONALITY.
SHE WAS A BUSINESSWOMAN.
SHE WAS BEGINNING TO CROSS OVER
INTO THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE
MARKET.
>> JERRY BROWN WAS MY DEAR BEST
BROWN.
I'M JUST DEALING WITH HIS DEATH
RIGHT NOW.
>> FIVE SECONDS LATER, WE HEARD
RAPID FIRE, BANG, BANG, BANG.
AND I TOOK OFF RUNNING.
>> EVERYTHING BECAME SO REAL.
IT WAS A LOT LIKE VIRGINIA TECH
AND COLUMBINE.
HE CAME IN WITH A HOCKEY MASK
ON.
SO OBVIOUSLY CAME WITH THE
INTENT TO KILL.
>> ANY TIME YOU GOT TWO GUYS
TANGOING, YOU'VE GOT A CHANCE TO
GET IT DONE.
>> I'M PRETTY CONFIDENT
REPUBLICANS WILL NOT HOLD MIDDLE
CLASS TAXES HOSTAGE TO TRY TO
PROTECT TAX CUTS FROM
HIGH-INCOME INDIVIDUALS.
>> THERE IS A GROWING GROUP OF
FOLKS THAT ARE LOOKING AT THIS
AND REALIZING THAT WE DON'T HAVE
A LOT OF CARDS AS IT RELATES TO
THE TAX ISSUE.
>> IT WAS REAL SCARY.
EVERYTHING WAS JUST FLYING.
JUST TOSSED AROUND.
>> I GREW UP IN A HOUSE WITH
THREE SISTERS, SO I THINK IT'S
GREAT FOR MY BOYS TO HAVE A GIRL
IN THE HOUSE, JUST TO UNDERSTAND
AT LEAST A LITTLE BIT OF WHAT
MAKES A WOMAN TICK.
>> WINNER OF THE HEISMAN
MEMORIAL TROPHY IS JOHNNY
MANZIEL.
>> GRANDPA, ALL THE TIMES WE
USED TO PLAY IN THE HALLWAY AND
THROW THE BALL UNTIL WE COULDN'T
ANYMORE, I LOVE YOU WITH ALL MY
HEART AND YOU INSPIRED ME TO
PLAY FOOTBALL.
AND GRANDMA, I'M SORRY FOR ALL
THE THINGS WE BROKE IN THE
HOUSE.
>> FIRST FRESHMAN TO WIN.
THAT'S GREAT.
AND CHRISTMAS IS A GREAT TIME TO
MAKE MEMORIES.
>> BETWEEN THE EGGNOG AND THOSE
SILLY SWEATERS, IT'S A BETTER
TIME TO MAKE SOME EMBARRASSING
MEMORIES.
SOME OF THE BEST EMBARRASSING
MEMORIES INVOLVE SANTA, YEAH,
GOT TO LIKE THIS ONE.
THIS IS MIA FROM MICHIGAN, WHO
APPARENTLY DID NOT ENJOY HER
FIRST MEETING WITH JOLLY OLD ST.
NICK.
>> IF YOU HAVE SOME AWKWARD
CHRISTMAS PICS, WE ASK YOU TO
SEND THEM TO US.
>> AND WE'LL SHOW THEM ON THE
AIR AND LAUGH AT YOUR
EXPENSE.
EXPERIENCE.
♪
>>> THIS MORNING ON "WORLD NEWS
NOW," A CALL FOR HELP.
DOZENS OF TOP EXECUTIVES JOIN
NORTHEAST GOVERNORS IN DEMANDING
CONGRESS COME UP WITH BILLIONS
OF DOLLARS IN SANDY AID AND DO
IT NOW.
>> NEARLY SEVEN WEEKS AFTER THE
STORM, THEY'RE TELLING LAWMAKERS
NOT TO LEAVE WASHINGTON FOR THE
HOLIDAYS WITHOUT APPROVING THAT
MONEY.
IT 'S FRIDAY, DECEMBER 14.
>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS "WORLD
NEWS NOW."
>> GOOD FRIDAY MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
I'M ROB NELSON.
>> AND I'M PAULA FARIS.
CONGRESS IS FEELING NEW PRESSURE
TO PASS THAT HURRICANE SANDY AID
LEGISLATION.
THAT IS OUR TOP STORY.
>>> ALSO AHEAD, SUSAN RICE
SHAPING UP THE SELECTION PROCESS
FOR THE NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
WHY THE U.N. AMBASSADOR, THE
FRONTRUNNER TO REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON, NOW SAYS SHE DOESN'T
WANT THE JOB.
>>> AND THEN THE STARS ALL HAVE
THEIR STYLISTS, OF COURSE.
BUT YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE SOME
RICH, POWERFUL CELEBRITY TO FIND
SOMEONE TO MAKE YOU LOOK LIKE A
MILLION BUCKS.
>>> AND LATER, HOLIDAY SHOPPING
FOR TECH GADGETS.
IF YOU'RE RUNNING OUT OF MONEY
AND TIME, WE HAVE SOME OF THE
BEST TECH STOCKING STUFFERS OF
THE SEASON.
>> THERE WE GO.
I SAW THAT PHONE THERE.
OKAY.
SUNNY HOSTIN HAS ONE OF THOSE.
THAT'S WHY IT RANG OUT TO ME,
THE ACTUAL PHONE THAT YOU PLUG
THAT LOOKS LIKE YOUR OLD SCHOOL
PHONE AS OPPOSED TO THE HEADLESS
THING.
EVER SEEN THEM BEFORE?
>> NO, I HAVEN'T.
BUT I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO
SEEING IT FOR THE FIRST TIME.
>> OH, REALLY?
NICE.
>>> BUT FIRST, FURY AFTER THE
STORM.
THREE FED UP GOVERNORS ARE
CALLING ON CONGRESS TO FREE UP
AID FOR VICTIMS OF SUPER STORM
SANDY.
>> MORE THAN 125 CEOs ARE
JOINING THAT EFFORT TO LIGHT THE
FIRE UNDER LAWMAKERS BEFORE
CHRISTMAS, PUSHING FOR IMMEDIATE
PASSAGE OF A $60 BILLION AID
PACKAGE.
AS ABC'S DAVID CURLY REPORTS,
THE DELAY FOR AID IS
PAINSTAKING.
>> Reporter: SIX WEEKS AFTER
SANDY IN LONG BEACH, NEW YORK,
JANET PETERS AND HER MOTHER ARE
STILL DEALING WITH THIS.
WONDERING, WHO IS HELPING.
>> NO ONE CAN TELL YOU WHAT THAT
NEW MONEY IS SLATED FOR.
NO ONE SEEMS TO HAVE ANY
ANSWERS.
>> Reporter: WITH THE HOSPITAL
STILL DOWN, THE WATER AND SEWER
SYSTEM NOT FIXED, THE CITY
MANAGER WORRIES HIS LOCAL
ECONOMY WILL TANK.
>> IT'S CRUCIAL WE GET THESE
FUNDS RIGHT AWAY.
EVERY DAY THAT GOES BY WE'RE NOT
ACTIVELY REPAIRING THIS CRITICAL
INFRASTRUCTURE IS A SCARY AND
SAD DAY FOR US.
>> Reporter: WHICH IS WHY THREE
GOVERNORS --
>> WE'RE NOT GOING TO ALLOW ANY
POLITICAL FORCES IN WASHINGTON,
D.C. TO DIVIDE AND CONQUER US.
>> Reporter: WROTE IN THE
WASHINGTON POST THAT CONGRESS
CAN'T BELIEVE BEFORE THE
HOLIDAYS WITHOUT HELP, POINTING
OUT AID WAS APPROVED TWO WEEKS
AFTER KATRINA.
IN NEW JERSEY, WITH 72,000 HOMES
AND BUSINESSES DAMAGED OR
DESTROYED, THE GOVERNOR WANTS $5
BILLION TO REBUILD HOMES, $8
BILLION TO REBUILD BUSINESSES.
BUT THE SANDY PACKAGE TOTALING
$60 BILLION IS STUCK IN
WASHINGTON.
REPUBLICANS ACCUSING THE
PRESIDENT OF LOADING UP THE BILL
WITH MILLIONS NOT RELATED TO THE
STORM.
>> THIS IS PART OF THIS PROCESS
OF THEY'RE THROWING IN
EVERYTHING BUT THE KITCHEN SINK
BECAUSE THEY KNOW CONGRESS CAN'T
TURN DOWN REQUEST FOR SANDY.
>> Reporter: EXAMPLES.
$2 MILLION FOR SMITHSONIAN
MUSEUM LEAKING ROOFS IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
BUT MUSEUM OFFICIALS ADMIT THEY
HAD A LEAK BEFORE THE STORM.
$10 MILLION TO REPAIR PRISONS.
BUT ONE OF THEM IS IN WEST
VIRGINIA, WHICH SANDY BARELY
TOUCHED.
AND $13 BILLION TO PROTECT
AGAINST FUTURE STORMS.
>> WE DON'T WANT TO REBUILD A
TUNNEL SO THAT THE SAME STORM
WATER CAN FLOOD IN.
WE WANT TO BUILD IT BETTER SO
THERE'S MORE PROTECTION.
>> Reporter: WHILE THEY ARGUE,
JANET PETERS WONDERS WHO IS
GOING TO HELP?
DAVID CURLY, ABC NEWS,
WASHINGTON.
>> AND NEW YORK SENATOR CHUCK
SCHUMER MADE AN INTERESTING
POINT YESTERDAY.
HE SAID WE MEMBERS OF THE NEW
YORK, NEW JERSEY DELEGATION,
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS, HAVE
ALWAYS BEEN THERE WHEN OTHER
PARTS OF THE NATION WERE STRUCK
BY DISASTER.
NEW YORK TAX DOLLARS WENT TO THE
GULF AND FOREST FIRES OUT WEST
AND FLOODING IN MISSOURI AND THE
MISSISSIPPI VALLEY.
UNFORTUNATELY, WE'VE BEEN STRUCK
AND WE HOPE AND EXPECT OUR
COLLEAGUES TO SHOW THE SAME
COURTESY TO US.
>> AS WAS MENTIONED WITH
KATRINA, THAT MONEY WAS RELEASED
WITHIN A COUPLE WEEKS.
>> TEN DAYS.
>> $4 MILLION TO REPAIR SAND
BERMS AT THE KENNEDY SPACE
CENTER IN FLORIDA.
$41 MILLION FOR CLEANUP AND
REPAIRS AT EIGHT MILITARY BASES
ALONG THE STORM'S PATH.
THERE'S SOME PORK.
>> BOTH SIDES ALWAYS DO THAT FOR
MONEY YOU CANNOT VOTE AGAINST,
THEY STUFF ALL THAT STUFF IN
THERE TO GET OTHER PET PROJECTS
DONE.
>> $10 FOR NEW CHAIRS FOR US ON
OUR SET.
>> WE DO NEED SOME NEW CHAIRS.
THESE ARE GETTING OLD.
>>> FISCAL CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS
INCHED FORWARD EVER SO SLIGHTLY
YESTERDAY.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
VISITED THE WHITE HOUSE WITH HIS
FIRST FACE-TO-FACE MEETING WITH
THE PRESIDENT SINCE SUNDAY.
BOTH SIDES CALLED THE TALKS
FRANK, BUT THEIR PUBLIC
POSITIONS HAVEN'T CHANGED A BIT.
HUGE TAX INCREASES AND BUDGET
CUTS WILL KICK IN JANUARY 1
UNLESS THEY CAN FIND AN
ALTERNATIVE.
>>> THERE'S A NEW HIGH-PROFILE
DEMOCRAT THIS MORNING, CHARLIE
CRISP, FLORIDA'S FORMER
REPUBLICAN GOVERNOR WHO TURNED
INDEPENDENT FOR A FAILED ATTEMPT
TO RUN FOR THE SENATE, FILED
PAPERS YESTERDAY TO OFFICIALLY
SWITCH HIS PARTY TO DEMOCRAT.
HE SAYS HE FEELS MORE
COMFORTABLE AS A DEMOCRAT NOW,
BUT THERE'S TALK HE MAY RUN FOR
HIS OLD JOB AS GOVERNOR AGAIN.
BUT THIS TIME AS A DEMOCRAT.
>>> CALLING THE PROCESS BITTER
AND COSTLY, U.N. AMBASSADOR
SUSAN RICE SAYS SHE'S STEPPING
ASIDE, WITHDRAWING FROM
CONSIDERATION TO BE THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
RICE MADE THE SURPRISE
ANNOUNCEMENT THURSDAY, BOWING TO
EXTREME CRITICISM FROM
REPUBLICAN SENATORS WHO VOW TO
FIGHT HER NOMINATION.
SHE'S BEEN UNDER EXTREME FIRE
FOR HER HANDLING OF THE CRISIS
IN LIBYA, AND THE ATTACK IN
BENGHAZI THAT KILLED AMBASSADOR
CHRIS STEPHENS.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY DISTRACTING,
AND VERY DISRUPTIVE.
BECAUSE THERE ARE SO MANY THINGS
WE NEED TO GET DONE AS A
COUNTRY.
>> MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR JOHN
KERRY AND FORMER REPUBLICAN
SENATOR CHUCK HAGEL OF NEBRASKA
ARE NOW CONSIDERED THE
FRONT-RUNNERS TO REPLACE HILLARY
CLINTON WHEN SHE OFFICIALLY
STEPS DOWN.
>>> IN OREGON, THE SHOPPING MALL
THAT BECAME THE SCENE OF A
DEADLY SHOOTING RAMPAGE DAYS AGO
IS SET TO REOPEN THIS MORNING.
A CANDLELIGHT VIGIL FOR THE
VICTIMS WILL BE HELD TONIGHT.
TWO PEOPLE WERE KILLED AND THE
15-YEAR-OLD GIRL WAS WOUNDED
WHEN 22-YEAR-OLD JACOB ROBERTS
OPENED FIRE INSIDE THE CLACKAMAS
TOWN CENTER ON TUESDAY.
ROBERTS THEN KILLED HIMSELF.
THERE IS STILL NO MOTIVE FOR THE
SHOOTING.
>>> A MUCH CALMER DAY IS IN
STORE FOR SAN DIEGO AFTER A
POUNDING RAINSTORM DRENCHED THAT
CITY.
THE RAIN CAME DOWN SO FAST AND
FURIOUS, IN FACT, IT FLOODED
BUSINESSES AND MAJOR
INTERSECTIONS, LEAVING DRIVERS
STRANDED IN THE ROAD.
SOME PEOPLE EVEN HAD TO BE
RESCUED FROM THE FLOOD WATERS.
>>> AND THE SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
MOUNTAINS ARE BURIED UNDER A
FRESH COAT OF SNOW THIS MORNING.
AND IT IS STILL COMING DOWN IN
FACT.
TIRE CHAINS WERE MANDATORY FOR
DRIVERS HEADING INTO MOUNTAIN
PASSES AND RESORTS LIKE BIG
BEAR.
EVEN WITH CHAINS, THEY SAY THE
ROADS WERE STILL PRETTY
TREACHEROUS.
>>> WE HAVE A STUNNING, STUNNING
REVELATION, THANKS TO SOME OF
THE NATION'S TOP SCIENTISTS.
>> HEY.
I FIGURED I WOULD COME BY FOR
THIS ONE.
>> THIS IS BIG.
>> EARTH SHATTERING.
>> BRACE YOURSELF.
>> WE HAVE -- I'VE JUST BEEN
HANDED SOME SHOCKING NEWS THAT
AMAZINGLY HAS COME FROM SOME OF
THE NATION'S TOP SCIENTISTS AND
TOOK A LOOK AT 20 YEARS WORTH OF
INFORMATION.
>> WHAT DID THEY FIND?
>> WHAT THEY FOUND WAS, ARE YOU
READY?
BREAKING NEWS.
THE FURTHER NORTH YOU LIVE IN
THE U.S., THE BETTER CHANCE YOU
HAVE TO HAVE A WHITE CHRISTMAS.
>> SERIOUSLY?
>> YEP.
>> OH, MY DEAR LORD.
>> PAULA, ROB, JUST CHECK THE
MAP.
THE AREAS THAT ARE IN WHITE,
WHICH SHOCKINGLY ENOUGH ARE IN
THE NORTH, HAVE A BETTER CHANCE
OF HAVING AN INCH OF SNOW ON
CHRISTMAS THAN THE AREAS IN
BLUE, WHICH, OBVIOUSLY, ARE IN
THE SOUTH.
>> WE NEED TO PASS THIS
INFORMATION ON TO OUR
METEOROLOGISTS.
>> WRITE IT DOWN.
>> I'M SHOCKED.
>> WE'VE GOT TO DO A SPECIAL
REPORT.
THIS IS INSANE.
SO JACK, CLEAR THIS UP FOR US.
LET FOLKS KNOW WHAT'S GOING ON.
>> LET'S BE CLEAR ABOUT THIS.
>> THAT MEANS MAINE AND
MICHIGAN --
>> FOLKS IN THE NORTH.
>> YES.
SNOW ON CHRISTMAS.
KEY WEST, OH, NO, PUT AWAY YOUR
BIG COATS AND THERMAL DRAWERS.
NO SNOW FOR YOU THIS YEAR.
>> GRAB ANOTHER MAI THAI AND GET
THE COCOA BUTTER READY AND ENJOY
YOUR CHRISTMAS.
THAT'S IT.
>> SHOCKED AND STUNNED.
>> BREAKING NEWS.
STREAMING IN AS WE'RE ON THE
AIR.
I'VE GOT TO GO.
>> THIS WAS A LEGIT STORY.
HOW MUCH WE SPENT ON THAT STUDY?
THAT WAS A LEGITIMATE STUDY.
>> I'M GLAD WE STUDIED THAT.
WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT -- MAN!
>> HERE'S A LOOK AT YOUR
WEATHER.
JUST FACTOR INTO CONSIDERATION
EVERYTHING WE SHOWED YOU.
SHOWERS FROM SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA
TO SEATTLE.
HEAVY DOWNPOURS AROUND VEGAS,
PHOENIX AND ALBUQUERQUE.
MOUNTAIN SNOW IN THE FOUR
CORNERS OF THE SOUTHWEST
BREAKING FROM THAT TREND IN THE
NORTH.
THUNDERSTORMS AROUND DALLAS AND
WICHITA.
>> 50s IN KANSAS CITY AND FROM
BOSTON TO BALTIMORE, 40s.
30s FROM SALT LAKE CITY TO FARGO
AND BLIZZARD WHITEOUT CONDITIONS
IN TAMPA.
YES.
I'M STUNNED.
>>> SPORTS STARS DO MANY THINGS
TO PLEASE THEIR FANS.
BUT THE HOUSTON ROCKETS' LATEST
EFFORT TO SING IS PRETTY
EMBARRASSING AND THUSLY IS OUR
FAVORITE STORY OF THE DAY.
♪ I MADE IT OUT OF CLAY AND WHEN
IT'S DRY AND READY ♪
♪ THEN DREIDEL I --
OH, MY GOSH.
>> JEREMY LIN STUMBLING THROUGH
THE LYRICS IN THE FAVORITE
HANUKKAH SONG.
>> OY VAY.
>> SHOOTING BRICKS.
>> LINSANITY.
THERE WE GO, FOLKS.
I STILL CAN'T GET OVER THAT
WEATHER NEWS.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, WHAT YOUR
LAST NAME COULD BE WORTH.
A FLORIDA GUY SOLD HIS LAST NAME
FOR $45,000.
>> REALLY?
>> $45,000.
>> I'M THINKING NELSON WOULD GO
FOR --
>> NICKELS.
>>> AND LOOKING LIKE A MILLION
BUCKS WITH HELP FROM ONE OF
HOLLYWOOD'S TOP GLAMOUR EXPERTS.
GET YOUR STYLE ON, IT'S ALL
COMING UP.
>>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" WEATHER
BROUGHT TO YOU BY FABREEZE AIR
EFFECTS.
O YOU BY FERBREEZE AIR
WHAT THEY THOUGHT.
ED REAL PEOPLE
TAKE A DEEP BREATH FOR ME.
DESCRIBE THE SMELL.
IT'S VERY PLEASANT.
FRESH.
SOME KIND OF FLOWER MAYBE?
REMOVE THE BLINDFOLD...
AWWW, OH YUCK!
I DIDN'T SMELL ANY OF THAT!
FEBREZE AIR EFFECTS
DOESN'T MIX,
IT ACTUALLY REMOVES ODORS.
[ laughs ]
WOW, THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
JUST ANOTHER WAY FEBREZE
HELPS YOU BREATHE HAPPY.
THIS IS ANOTHER!
TA-DAA!
TRY CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG.
IT CLEANS SO WELL AND YOU CAN
USE UP TO FOUR TIMES LESS
THAN THE LEADING VALUE
BRAND.
OH! THERE IT IS.
THANKS SON.
HEY!
[ Female Announcer ]
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG
HAS A DURACLEAN TEXTURE
THAT CAN HELP YOU GET CLEAN
WHILE STILL USING LESS.
AND IT'S FOUR TIMES STRONGER
VERSUS THE LEADING VALUE BRAND.
CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG HELPS KEEP
YOU AND YOUR UNDERWEAR CLEAN.
WE ALL GO. WHY NOT ENJOY THE GO
WITH CHARMIN ULTRA STRONG?
And one wedding,
2 kids,
43 bottles
of Olay Total Effects
And many birthdays later,
Still looks amazing.
Thanks to the trusted
performance of Olay.
>>> FOR SOME FOLKS, SHOPPING CAN
BE CONFUSING OR DOWNRIGHT
IRRITATING.
>> I JUST LIKE TO BUY WHATEVER
IS ON THE MANNEQUIN.
BECAUSE I CAN'T THINK IT
THROUGH.
IT IS HARD TO PICK THE PERFECT
WARDROBE AND FIND THE RIGHT
LOOKS FOR THE RIGHT OCCASION.
AS I DISCOVERED, YOU DON'T HAVE
TO.
FROM SOPHIA'S RED CARPET
PERFECTION TO EMMA STONE'S
SULTRY GLAMOUR, THESE CELEBS,
AND SO MANY MORE, HAVE A SECRET
WEAPON TO ACHIEVE THAT LOOK.
A STYLIST.
AND NOW YOU TOO CAN GET
FASHIONABLE LOOKS WITH A STYLIST
FOR A FRACTION OF THE PRICE.
FROM $75 TO $300 AN HOUR, NEW
COMPANIES ARE OFFERING REAL
WOMEN A CHANCE AT HAVING THEIR
OWN STYLIST WITHOUT BUSTING
THEIR BANK ACCOUNTS.
>> I CAN TAKE SOMEBODY WHO
DOESN'T HAVE ANY CONFIDENCE AND
GIVE THEM ALL THE CONFIDENCE IN
THE WORLD.
AND IT'S EXTREMELY REWARDING.
>> Reporter: ALISON RUNS AN
AGENCY AND WORKS WITH CLIENTS ON
ALL SORTS OF BUDGETS.
SHE CONNECTED LIZ WITH SAMANTHA,
WHO HELPED LIZ TO STOP WORRYING
ABOUT WHAT TO WEAR.
>> THE SAME TOP IN FIVE COLORS.
IT WASN'T REALLY REPRESENTATIVE
OF WHAT I WANTED TO LOOK LIKE.
BUT I WAS ESSENTIALLY WEARING
THE SAME THING EVERY DAY.
>> Reporter: THE FIRST ORDER OF
BUSINESS, A MAJOR CLOSET
OVERHAUL.
HOW MANY OF HER CLOTHES DID YOU
GET RID OF?
>> WE PROBABLY PURGED ABOUT 20%
OF HER WARDROBE.
>> Reporter: NEXT COMES THE FUN
PART, SHOPPING.
TODAY THEY'RE BROWSING ELIZABETH
CHARLES FOR A FEW SPECIAL
PIECES, THINGS LIZ WOULD NEVER
PICK FOR HERSELF.
>> I FEEL LIKE THIS BRIGHT BLUE
WOULD BE FLATTERING AND YOU CAN
MULTIPURPOSE THIS.
>> I FEEL LIKE THE UNDERLYING
THEME IS LESS IS MORE, FEWER
CLOTHES BUT CLOTHES THAT WORK
TOGETHER.
>> AND CLOTHES THAT FIT.
>> I LIKE THE BACK.
>> THE BACK LOOKS GREAT.
I LOVE THESE PANELS ALSO.
>> Reporter: BUT INVESTING IN
HER OWN STYLIST HAS GIVEN LIZ
MORE CONFIDENCE.
SHE LOOKS GREAT AND WHAT'S MORE,
SHE'S GAINED A BFF.
>> NO.
DO YOU HAVE A STYLIST?
>> WE DON'T.
>> I DON'T NEED ONE.
>> HELLO!
>> THAT'S ME.
>> IF YOU EVER WONDERED WHAT ROB
LOOKS LIKE IN BOY SHORTS, THAT
IS IT.
>> OR WHAT I LOOK LIKE IN PHOTO
SHOP.
>>> STILL AHEAD, IF YOU WANT TO
GIVE A TECH GIFT THIS YEAR, YOU
DON'T HAVE TO BREAK THE BANK.
>> SUNNY HOSTIN IS HERE NEXT TO
SHOW US STOCKING STUFFERS FOR
ALL OF YOU GADGET GEEKS AND ALL
COSTING LESS THAN $100.
IT'S ALL COMING UP ON "WORLD
NEWS NOW."
LD
♪
>>> TEAK GEAR IS AT THE TOP OF
MOST EVERYONE'S HOLIDAY WISH
LIST, INCLUDING MOST EVERYONE
YOU HAVE TO BUY A GIFT FOR.
BUT YOU DON'T HAVE TO BREAK THE
BANK TO MAKE THEM HAPPY.
TINA TRINH IS HERE THIS MORNING
WITH SOME STOCKING STUFFERS THAT
ARE, GET THIS, UNDER $100.
GOOD MORNING, TINA.
TELL ME WHAT YOU'VE BROUGHT FOR
US.
>> A LOT OF GOOD STUFF.
FIRST UP IS DIGITS.
THESE ARE BASICALLY PINS THAT
TURN YOUR GLOVES INTO TOUCH
SCREEN FRIENDLY GLOVES.
>> WHICH IS GREAT.
BECAUSE BEFORE YOU HAD TO BUY
THE GLOVES.
>> YOU CAN STICK THESE ON ANY
GLOVES YOU HAVE AND TALK AWAY ON
YOUR iPHONE.
>> HOW MUCH?
>> $12.
>> WHAT'S NEXT?
>> THESE ARE REMOTE SHUTTERS.
AND YOU STICK YOUR iPHONE IN,
TAKE A PICTURE BY CLICKING DOWN
ON THE OTHER BUTTON HERE,
WITHOUT -- IT LETS YOU BASICALLY
TAKE PICTURES WITHOUT CAUSING
HAND SHAKE BLURRINESS.
>> WHICH IS WONDERFUL, BECAUSE
MOST PEOPLE'S PICTURES -- MINE
ESPECIALLY HAVE THAT BLURRY
LOOK.
>> AND THEY'RE REALLY CUTE, TOO.
THESE ARE RETRO POP PHONES FROM
NATIVE UNION.
I LOVE THEM.
>> LOVE, LOVE, LOVE.
>> SO MUCH FUN.
30 BUCKS, WHY NOT?
>> I HAVE ONE.
>> THEY'RE SO EASY TO USE.
JUST STICK THEM INTO YOUR PHONE,
START TALKING ON THE OTHER END,
YOU'RE CUTTING DOWN ON CELL
PHONE RADIATION.
SO FORM AND FUNCTION.
I LOVE IT.
THIS IS A CHARGING STATION,
BELIEVE IT OR NOT.
>> SHOCKING.
>> YOU CAN STICK ANYTHING THAT
IS CONNECTED TO A WIRE THAT
NEEDS TO BE CHARGED IN HERE, AND
IT DOES A REALLY GREAT JOB.
IT'S FUN.
IT DOES A GOOD JOB OF HIDING ALL
THE WIRES.
SO NO MORE TANGLED MESS.
HEADPHONES ARE KEY FOR MUSIC
LOVERS.
AND THE GOOD NEWS IS, YOU DON'T
HAVE TO SPEND $300 TO GET A GOOD
PAIR.
THESE ARE $55.
EVERY BIT AS GOOD AS THE FANCY
ONES.
>> WHAT ABOUT CHARGING YOUR
PHONE?
>> CHARGING YOUR PHONE, LIKE
VERY, VERY IMPORTANT.
YOU NEVER WANT TO BE CAUGHT WITH
A DEAD PHONE.
THESE ARE BACKUP BATTERIES FROM
ANCHOR.
THIS IS CALLED THE SLIM TALK.
IT'S 25 BUCKS.
CHARGE IT ON YOUR COMPUTER,
THROW IT IN YOUR BAG, CHARGE
YOUR PHONE WHEN YOU'RE ON THE
GO, YOU'RE ALL SET.
>> WHAT ABOUT THIS ONE?
>> THIS IS A KEY CHAIN ACTUALLY.
AND ONE END GOES INTO THE
COMPUTER TO CHARGE WHEN YOU'RE
DONE CHARGING, THROW IT IN YOUR
BAG ON KEY CHAIN.
THIS CHARGES YOUR PHONE ON THE
GO.
NO OUTLET NEEDED.
>> WHAT IS THIS IN THE FRONT?
>> THIS IS AWESOME.
HOOK IT UP TO YOUR TV, TURN YOUR
PLAIN TV INTO A WEB CONNECTED TV
AND INSTANTLY START STREAMING
VIDEOS, MOVIES, TV SHOWS,
NETFLIX, YOU NAME IT.
>> THAT SOUNDS EXPENSIVE.
>> 50 BUCKS.
>> THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
I KNOW ABOUT THIS, BECAUSE I
HAVE ONE.
EXPLAIN WHAT THIS IS ABOUT.
>> FOR PEOPLE LOOKING TO GET IN
SHAPE, THIS IS PROBABLY THE
EASIEST WAY TO DO IT.
CLIP IT ON YOUR SHIRT, YOUR
PANTS, FORGET ABOUT IT.
IT TRACKS YOUR CALORIES,
DISTANCE, SYNCS TO YOUR COMPUTER
OR iPHONE.
>> AND YOU ALWAYS FEEL LIKE
YOU'RE WORKING OUT.
>> GREAT MOTIVATION.
>> AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST.
>> I LOVE THIS CUTE LITTLE
TABLET AND IT'S ONLY $70.
SO IF YOUR TEENAGER, YOUR KID IS
BEGGING YOU FOR A TABLET AND YOU
DON'T WANT TO SPEND HUNDREDS,
THAT'S A PERFECT OPTION.
>> THAT'S WONDERFUL.
SO YOU CAN USE THAT LIKE YOU
WOULD USE A MINI iPAD.
>> YEP.
IT RUNS ANDROID.
IT DOES EVERYTHING A NORMAL
TABLET WOULD.
>> FANTASTIC.
WELL, THANKS TO TINA TRINH FOR A
LOOK AT SOME AFFORDABLE TECH
GIFTS.
FOR A LOOK AT THESE PRODUCTS,
CHECK OUT OUR FACEBOOK PAGE.
WNNFANS.COM.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
HD 3
3Q
Lysol believes no toilet
is complete,
until it's completely clean.
Lysol Toilet Bowl Cleaner
gives you maximum coverage
from the rim down to
the water line
to kill 99.9% of germs.
And removes stains better
than Clorox Toilet Bowl Cleaner
with Bleach.
So if you want to do
the whole job,
Lysol's got you covered.
Lysol.
Mission for Health.
And for an incredibly clean
and fresh bowl with every flush,
try the No Mess Automatic
Toilet Bowl Cleaner.
>>> YOU'VE GOT TO LOVE THE
CORPORATIZATION OF OUR CULTURE
HERE.
THERE IS THIS GUY IN FLORIDA WHO
HAS SOLD HIS LAST NAME FOR
$46,000 TO HEADSETS.COM.
SO FROM NOW ON HE IS JASON
HEADSETS.COM.
HE'LL GET PAID TO MARKET THAT
NAME.
OBVIOUSLY PUBLICITY LIKE THE
KIND WE'RE GIVING HIM RIGHT NOW.
THEN HE'LL DO HIS THING ON
TWITTER AND FACEBOOK AND THIS IS
A WEBSITE THAT SELLS YEAH,
HEADSETS.
SO HE PUT IT OUT THERE FOR BID
AND $45,500 GOT HIM THE JOB.
HE'S DONE THIS BEFORE WITH
T-SHIRTS AND STUFF.
BUT HE'S LITERALLY ON HIS BIRTH
CERTIFICATE CHANGED HIS NAME FOR
50,000 BUCKS.
>>> SO THIS IS WHAT WE CALL
GOOD, CLEAN FUN.
IT HAPPENED AT BRIGHAM YOUNG
UNIVERSITY.
STUDENTS WANTED TO SEE IF
KISSING UNDER THE MISTLETOE IS
ALIVE AND WELL.
SO THEY WERE POSING AS HOLIDAY
QUESTIONERS AND THEY ASKED
RANDOM HOLIDAY SURVEY QUESTIONS.
WHEN THE MISTLETOE WAS HUNG,
THEY WANTED TO SEE IF PEOPLE
ACTUALLY KISSED.
MOST PEOPLE BIT.
SHE WAS LIKING IT.
>> SHE WENT IN TWICE.
>> I GUESS IT'S TIME.
HOW LONG WE GOT?
>> THIS ISN'T A PRANK.
IT'S THE POLKA.
♪
>>> THIS MORNING ON "WORLD NEWS
NOW," STEPPING ASIDE.
THE PRESIDENT'S NUMBER ONE
CHOICE FOR SECRETARY OF STATE
DECIDES TO DODGE A MAJOR
POLITICAL BULLET.
>> SUSAN RICE'S ABRUPT MOVE AND
WHO MAY BE CONSIDERED NEXT TO
REPLACE HILLARY CLINTON.
IT IS FRIDAY, DECEMBER 14.
>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS "WORLD
NEWS NOW."
>>> GOOD FRIDAY MORNING,
EVERYBODY.
I'M ROB NELSON.
>> WE MADE IT, DIDN'T WE?
>> ANOTHER WEEK IN THE BOOKS.
>> I'M PAULA FARIS.
WE'RE GOING TO HEAR FROM SUSAN
RICE WHO FACED AN UPHILL BATTLE
ON CAPITOL HILL.
AND FROM CAPITOL HILL TO THE
WHITE HOUSE FROM HOUSE SPEAKER
JOHN BOEHNER AND PRESIDENT OBAMA
TRIED TO FIND SOME COMMON GROUND
IN FISCAL CLIFF NEGOTIATIONS
LAST NIGHT.
WAS THERE PROGRESS OF ANY SORTS?
WE'RE GOING TO TELL YOU.
>> WE'RE COVERING EVERY LITTLE
INCH OF THE BACK AND FORTH.
AT LEAST AT THIS POINT, NOTHING
CONCRETE.
AGAIN, THE BIG ISSUE IS WHAT IS
BEING TALKED ABOUT PRIVATELY,
NOT PUBLICLY.
WE'LL SEE IF THEY HAVE SOMETHING
UP THEIR SLEEVES.
THE CLOCK IS TICKING.
>>> ALSO, FROM A LEGAL DEBATE TO
A HEALTH ISSUE.
WHAT DOCTORS ARE SAYING ABOUT
THE BENEFITS OF SAME-SEX
MARRIAGE.
THEY STUDIED HOW COUPLES FEEL
AFTER MAKING THEIR RELATIONSHIPS
LEGAL.
>>> AND LATER, ODD BALL UPSCALE
AND ONE OF A KIND.
THE HOT NEW WEBSITE OFFERING
SOME VERY UNUSUAL GIFTS AND WE
STRESS THE WORD "UNUSUAL."
OUR TECH EDITOR DISCOVER WHAT'S
DIFFERENT ABOUT FAB.COM.
DON'T GO TO THAT WEBSITE YET.
>> WHY NOT?
>> BECAUSE THEN THEY WON'T WATCH
THE SHOW.
>> OH, SMART.
>>> FIRST, A MAJOR SETBACK FOR
PRESIDENT OBAMA THIS MORNING.
>> BOWING TO EXTREME PRESSURE,
U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE MADE
A SURPRISE ANNOUNCEMENT,
WITHDRAWING HER NAME FROM
CONSIDERATION AS THE NEXT
SECRETARY OF STATE.
SO THAT LEAVES THE DOOR OPEN FOR
THE MAN CONSIDERED THE
PRESIDENT'S SECOND CHOICE TO
TAKE OVER THE JOB FROM HILLARY
CLINTON.
OUR OWN SUNNY HOSTIN HAS THE
LATEST.
GOOD MORNING.
>> Reporter: U.N. AMBASSADOR
SUSAN RICE HAS WITHDRAWN FROM
CONSIDERATION FOR SECRETARY OF
STATE AMID SUSTAINED CRITICISM
FROM REPUBLICANS OVER HER
REMARKS AFTER THE ATTACK ON THE
U.S. CONSULATE IN BENGHAZI.
SUSAN RICE NOTIFIED PRESIDENT
OBAMA BY LETTER THAT SHE'S
CROSSING HER NAME OFF THE LIST
TO BE THE NATION'S TOP DIPLOMAT.
SHE WROTE, THE POSITION OF
SECRETARY OF STATE SHOULD NEVER
BE POLITICIZED.
I AM SADDENED THAT WE HAVE
REACHED THIS POINT, EVEN BEFORE
YOU HAVE DECIDED WHOM TO
NOMINATE.
IN AN INTERVIEW WITH NBC'S ROCK
CENTER, SHE ADDED --
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY DISTRACTING,
AND VERY DISRUPTIVE.
BECAUSE THERE ARE SO MANY THINGS
WE NEED TO GET DONE AS A
COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: CURRENTLY, THE U.S.
AMBASSADOR TO THE UNITED
NATIONS, SUSAN RICE WAS
CONSIDERED FIRST IN LINE TO
SUCCEED HILLARY CLINTON AS
SECRETARY OF STATE.
BUT REPUBLICAN OPPOSITION
MOUNTED AFTER SHE LED THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION'S RESPONSE TO THE
TERRORIST ATTACK ON THE U.S.
CONSULATE IN BENGHAZI, LIBYA.
>> WHAT THIS BEGAN AS WAS A
SPONTANEOUS, NOT PREMEDITATED
RESPONSE TO WHAT TRANSPIRED IN
CAIRO.
>> Reporter: REPUBLICANS SAY HER
ANSWERS WERE UNTRUTHFUL.
>> WE ARE SIGNIFICANTLY TROUBLED
BY MANY OF THE ANSWERS WE GOT
AND SOME WE DIDN'T GET.
>> Reporter: PRESIDENT OBAMA
ISSUED A STATEMENT PRAISING RICE
AND CITING "UNFAIR AND
MISLEADING ATTACKS ON HER."
RICE'S WITHDRAWAL MAKES
MASSACHUSETTS SENATOR JOHN KERRY
THE LEADING CONTENDER TO BE
NOMINATED AS SECRETARY OF STATE.
KERRY SAID LITTLE.
SUSAN RICE WILL REMAIN AS
AMBASSADOR TO THE UNITED
NATIONS.
IN WHAT IS BEING PERCEIVED AS A
PRESIDENTIAL GESTURE OF SUPPORT,
PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL MEET WITH
AMBASSADOR RICE.
SUNNY HOSTIN, ABC NEWS, NEW
YORK.
>>> OTHER BIG POLITICAL NEWS
THIS MORNING, STATE GOVERNMENTS
MUST DECIDE BY TODAY IF THEY
WILL RUN THEIR OWN INSURANCE
EXCHANGES UNDER THE PRESIDENT'S
HEALTH CARE OVERHAUL.
THOSE EXCHANGES WILL SERVE
MILLIONS OF UP INSURED AMERICANS
IN LESS THAN A YEAR.
19 STATES DECIDED AGAINST
RUNNING THEIR OWN PROGRAMS.
THAT MEANS THE FEDS WILL COME IN
AND DO IT FOR THEM.
17 STATES AND THE DISTRICT OF
COLUMBIA WILL TAKE ON THE TASK.
EIGHT STATES WANT A PARTNERSHIP
TO GET THIS DONE AND SIX HAVE
MADE NO DECISION AND WILL HAVE
UNTIL TODAY TO DO SO, INCLUDING
VIRGINIA, AS WELL AS FLORIDA
HAVE YET TO OFFICIALLY DECIDE.
BUT TODAY IS THE DEADLINE DAY.
THAT SHOULD BE INTERESTING.
>> BUT IT DOESN'T GO INTO EFFECT
UNTIL 2014, BUT THEY HAVE TO
MAKE THIS DECISION.
IF THEY DON'T DECIDE, AND THEY
HAVE TO BY LAW, IF THEY DON'T,
BASICALLY THE FEDS WILL COME IN
AND DO IT FOR THEM.
IT'S ALL STIPULATED ON THIS
HEALTH INSURANCE EXCHANGE.
THAT'S THE KEY STIPULATION OF
THE NEW HEALTH CARE LAW.
BASICALLY THEY'RE GOING TO OFFER
CONSUMERS AN INTERNET BASED
MARKETPLACE FOR PURCHASING
PRIVATE HEALTH CARE.
>> IT'S AN INTERNET BASED SYSTEM
TO GO FIND YOUR OWN PRIVATE
HEALTH CARE ONCE THE LAW TAKES
EFFECT.
ALL OF THIS FELL ON PARTY LINES.
SO IF YOU LIVE IN A RED STATE,
MOST LIKELY YOUR STATE
GOVERNMENT SAID NO, LET THE FEDS
DO IT.
FIVE STATES DID BREAK PARTY
LINES.
IOWA, MISSISSIPPI, IDAHO, NEW
MEXICO AND NEVADA ALL BROKE
PARTY LINES TO GET IT DONE.
SO TODAY'S DECISION DAY AND IT'S
A BIG COMPONENT.
SO THOSE ARE THE NUMBERS.
WE'LL SEE WHERE IT STANDS.
>> INTERESTING TO SEE HOW THAT
SHAKES OUT.
>>> NOW TO THE OTHER POLITICAL
MESS IN WASHINGTON.
THERE'S SO MANY OF THEM.
THE LOOMING FISCAL CLIFF.
>> THE TWO PRINCIPALS FACED OFF
YET AGAIN.
AND KAREN TRAVERSE HAS OUR
DAILY PROGRESS REPORT.
GOOD MORNING, KAREN.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING, ROB.
GOOD MORNING, PAULA.
MORE SIGNS THAT THEY'RE NO
CLOSER TO A DEAL TO THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
BUT AT LEAST YESTERDAY,
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER SAT DOWN
AND TALKED.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER PAID
A VISIT TO THE WHITE HOUSE FOR A
NEARLY HOUR-LONG MEETING WITH
PRESIDENT OBAMA.
IT WAS THEIR SECOND FACE-TO-FACE
SESSION IN THE PAST FIVE DAYS.
THE PRESIDENT WAS ASKED IF HE'S
FEELING OPTIMISTIC.
>> IT'S A WORK IN PROGRESS.
>> Reporter: VERY MUCH IN
PROGRESS.
RIGHT NOW THERE'S EVEN
DISAGREEMENT ON WHAT THEY'RE
DISAGREEING ABOUT.
IS IT TAX RATES FOR THE WEALTHY?
>> THERE ARE SOME CLEAR, YOU
KNOW, RED LINES WHEN IT COMES TO
HOW WE BUILD A BROADER DEFICIT
REDUCTION PACKAGE.
>> Reporter: OR IS IT SPENDING
CUTS?
>> IT'S CLEAR THE PRESIDENT IS
NOT SERIOUS ABOUT CUTTING
SPENDING, BUT SPENDING IS THE
PROBLEM.
>> Reporter: IN TEN MINUTES,
BOEHNER HAMMERED HOME THAT POINT
NEARLY TWO DOZEN TIMES AND
SIGNALED THERE MAY BE ROOM FOR
FLEXIBILITY.
>> IF THE PRESIDENT WILL SHOW US
HE'S WILLING TO MAKE THE
SPENDING CUTS NEEDED, I THINK WE
CAN DO SOME REAL GOOD IN THE
DAYS AHEAD.
>> Reporter: THERE MAY BE NO
PLACE MORE PESSIMISTIC THAN
RIGHT HERE IN WASHINGTON.
SPEAKER BOEHNER HAS WARNED HIS
MEMBERS THAT THEY MAY
BE READY TO STAY HERE THROUGH
CHRISTMAS AND MAYBE NEW YEAR'S.
ROB AND PAULA, BACK TO YOU.
>> JUST IN TIME FOR THE
HOLIDAYS, SECURITY GUARDS AT NEW
YORK'S KENNEDY AIRPORT ARE
THREATENING TO GO ON STRIKE.
ABOUT 100 GUARDS SAY THEY WILL
WALK OFF THEIR JOBS NEXT
THURSDAY.
THEY'RE UPSET OVER EQUIPMENT AND
TRAINING.
THE GUARDS DIRECT TRAFFIC AND
PROTECT THE TARMACS.
ANOTHER SECURITY UNION AT
KENNEDY WILL TAKE A STRIKE VOTE
LATER TODAY.
>>> AND SINGER JENNI RIVERA HAS
COME HOME.
THE REMAINS WERE RELEASED TO HER
FAMILY.
THEY FLEW HER HOME FROM MEXICO
ON A CHARTERED JET.
SHE DIED SUNDAY WHEN HER PLANE
CRASHED INTO A MOUNTAIN IN
MEXICO AND NEARLY DISINTEGRATED.
TWO POLICE OFFICERS HAVE BEEN
ARRESTED ON SUSPICION OF
STEALING FROM THE CRASH SITE AND
LEAKING GRUESOME PHOTOGRAPHS TO
THE MEDIA.
>>> SYRIA'S RUTHLESS REGIME MAY
HAVE LITTLE TIME LEFT.
PRESIDENT ASSAD IS LOSING HIS
COUNTRY'S BLOODY CIVIL WAR AND
NOW THE FOREIGN MINISTRY DENIES
THAT STATEMENT THIS MORNING.
THE REBELS ARE OUTSIDE THE
CAPITAL AND GAINING GROUND, BUT
MANY GROUPS WITH COMPETING
INTERESTS AMONG THE RANKS AND
ASSAD'S FALL WOULD NOT MEAN AN
END TO THE FIGHTING.
>> DON'T REALLY HAVE A GOOD
SENSE.
TO THE EXTENT THAT EXTERNAL
ORGANIZATIONS ARE IN THERE IN
SOME EXTREMIST FORM, THE WORRY
IS THE RETRIBUTION AFTERWARDS
AND ACCESS TO CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
>> THIS WEEK, THE U.S., EUROPE
AND ALLIES RECOGNIZED THE
OPPOSITION, WHICH COULD SPEED UP
INTERNATIONAL AID.
BUT SOME FACTIONS OF THE REBELS
ARE KNOWN TO HAVE TIES TO AL
QAEDA.
THAT IS THE LINGERING QUESTION,
YOU KNOCK OUT THE LEADER, BUT
WHAT IS LEFT, BUILDING A NEW
COUNTRY SOMETIMES IS THE MORE
DIFFICULT PART COMPARED TO
GETTING RID OF THE DICTATOR.
LOOK AT EGYPT AND THE MESS
THEY'RE GOING THROUGH.
>> BUT THE STATE DEPARTMENT IS
ENCOURAGING RUSSIA TO WITHDRAW
THEIR SUPPORT AND JOIN WITH THE
U.S. IN IMPLEMENTING A POLITICAL
TRANSITION.
THAT HAS NOT HAPPENED YET.
BUT THIS WAS VERY SIGNIFICANT
THEY CAME OUT AND SAID THIS.
>> WE'VE SEEN HOW BRUTAL ASSAD
HAS BEEN.
TWO YEARS IN THE CIVIL WAR.
STILL A VOLATILE SITUATION.
>>> LOOK HOW THEY SETTLE THEIR
DIFFERENCES IN UKRAINE'S
CAPITAL.
A FULL-BLOWN BRAWL BROKEUTE IN
PARLIAMENT IN KIEV.
GROWN MEN PUSHING, SHOVING AND
PUNCHING OVER THE ELECTION OVER
A NEW SPEAKER.
IS THAT A MOSH PIT GOING ON,
TOO?
THE HEAD OF THE OPPOSITION
HAPPENS TO BE THE WORLD
HEAVYWEIGHT BOXING CHAMP.
FORTUNATELY, HE DECIDED TO SIT
THIS ONE OUT.
WOW.
THEY WERE ROLLING THEIR SLEEVES
UP AND GOING AT IT.
DING, NEXT ROUND.
>> LOOKS LIKE ONE OF OUR STAFF
MEETINGS.
>> WE ONLY HAVE FIVE PEOPLE.
>>> TODAY'S PLAY OF THE DAY IS
ALSO A NEW CONTENDER FOR MOST
EMBARRASSING NFL PLAY OF THE
SEASON.
THIS IS GREAT.
>> COURTESY OF THE EAGLES.
LOOK AT THIS, PUNTS THE BALL
RIGHT INTO HIS OWN BLOCKER.
BEEN THAT KIND OF YEAR FOR THE
EAGLES.
THEY GOT BLOWN OUT, 34-13.
THEIR RECORD IS A DREADFUL 4-10.
THE BENGALS ARE 8-6, WITH A SHOT
AT THE PLAYOFFS.
>> YOU ROOT FOR THE BEARS AND
BENGALS, RIGHT?
>> I DO.
I WORKED IN CINCINNATI FOR THREE
YEARS AND I LIVED AND WORKED IN
CHICAGO FOR SIX YEARS.
BUT I GREW UP IN MICHIGAN.
>> EAGLES ARE MY SECOND FAVORITE
TEAM.
THAT'S AN EMBARRASSING MOMENT TO
SEE.
BUT THEY'RE HAVING THE KIND OF
SEASON WHERE IT DOESN'T MATTER
AT THIS POINT.
>>> COMING UP NEXT AFTER THE
BREAK, NEW HEALTH CONCERNS FOR
BABIES BORN BY C-SECTION AND
WHAT PARENTS OUT THERE NEED TO
KNOW.
>>> AND UNUSUAL YET FABULOUS
GIFTS JUST A FEW CLICKS AWAY.
THE MERCHANDISE THAT SETS THIS
WEBSITE APART FROM ALL THE REST.
WE'RE GOING TO TELL YOU ALL
ABOUT IT ON "WORLD NEWS NOW."
>>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" WEATHER
BROUGHT TO YOU BY NO NO HAIR
REMOVAL.
.
[ roasting firewood ]
♪
MANY HOT DOGS
ARE WITHIN YOU.
TRY PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO,
IT'S THE POWER OF PEPTO,
BUT IT FITS IN YOUR POCKET.
NOW TELL THE WORLD
DANIEL...
OF PEPTO-BISMOL TO-GO.
♪
>>> AN IMPORTANT MEDICAL
HEADLINE THIS MORNING FOR
MOTHERS WHO DELIVERED BABIES VIA
C-SECTION.
THOSE CHILDREN MAY HAVE A 33%
GREATER RISK OF OBESITY COMPARED
TO CHILDREN BORN VAGINALLY.
RESEARCHERS IN CHINA LOOKED AT
PREVIOUS STUDIES ON OBESITY AND
THOUSANDS OF BIRTHS AND SAY THAT
HEALTH RISKS MUST BE TAKEN
SERIOUSLY.
PREVIOUS STUDIES LINKED
C-SECTION BIRTHS TO ALLERGIES
AND DIABETES LATER IN LIFE.
WE FOUND ONE GUY ON OUR STAFF
DELIVERED C-SECTION AND IS ONE
OF THE FITTEST GUYS ON OUR
STAFF.
>> HE WEIGHED TEN POUNDS AT THE
TIME.
BIG BABY.
>> HE'S BUFF.
NOT OVERWEIGHT.
>>> IN OTHER NEWS, MARRIAGE IS
GOOD FOR PEOPLE.
GAY AND STRAIGHT IN FACT.
THAT'S THE FINDING OF A NEW
STUDY.
IT SHOWS SAME-SEX COUPLES
MARRIED ENJOY THE SAME
PSYCHOLOGICAL BENEFITS AS
HETEROSEXUAL COUPLES.
MORE FROM ABC SENIOR MEDICAL
CONTRIBUTOR.
>> Reporter: AS SAME-SEX COUPLES
WAIT TO HEAR WHAT THE SUPREME
COURT SAYS ABOUT THEIR MARRYING,
A STUDY IN THE AMERICAN JOURNAL
OF PUBLIC HEALTH HAS ALREADY
OFFERED AN OPINION.
THE STUDY LOOKED AT DATA FROM
THE 2009 CALIFORNIA HEALTH
INTERVIEW SURVEY, WHICH INCLUDED
47,000 PARTICIPANTS, BOTH MEN
AND WOMEN, AGES 18 TO 70, AND
BOTH HOMOSEXUALS AND
HETEROSEXUALS.
THE AUTHORS SAY MARRIED GAY,
LESBIAN AND BISEXUAL PEOPLE
HAVE SIGNIFICANTLY LESS
PSYCHOLOGICAL STRESS THAN THEIR
NONMARRIED COUNTERPARTS.
THEY FOUND NO DIFFERENCE.
THE AUTHORS CONCLUDE THAT FOR
BOTH HETEROSEXUALS AND
HOMOSEXUALS, MARRIAGE IS
ASSOCIATED WITH INCREASED
PSYCHOLOGICAL WELL-BEING.
I'M DR. TIMOTHY JOHNSON.
>> OF COURSE, THE SUPREME COURT
BIG DECISION COMING UP IN JUNE
ON GAY MARRIAGE.
SO STAY TUNED FOR THAT.
>>> STILL AHEAD, ONE OF THE MOST
POPULAR PLACES TO SHOP THAT YOU
MAY NEVER HAVE HEARD OF.
>> WE'RE GOING TO TURN YOU ON TO
FAB.COM AND TELL YOU HOW YOU CAN
SAVE A FEW BUCKS HERE AND THERE
JUST BY WATCHING OUR SHOW.
STICK AROUND.
>>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" CONTINUES
AFTER THIS FROM OUR ABC
HIGH SPEED INTERNET AT HOME
ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOU CAN COUNT ON.
INTRODUCING AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
WITH MORE SPEED OPTIONS,
RELIABILITY
AND Wi-Fi HOT SPOTS THAN EVER.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW TO GET
U-verse HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
IT'S ALL THE SPEED YOU NEED
ALL AT A GREAT PRICE.
OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network
GIVES YOU MORE
OF WHAT YOU ENJOY ONLINE.
AND WITH AT&T,
OUR WIRELESS GATEWAY
TURNS YOUR HOME
INTO A PRIVATE Wi-Fi HOT SPOT
THAT CONNECTS
YOUR Wi-Fi DEVICES
AND CAN EVEN SAVE ON YOUR
SMART PHONE DATA USAGE AT HOME.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW
TO GET AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT INCLUDES ACCESS ON-THE-GO
TO OUR ENTIRE NATIONAL
Wi-Fi HOT SPOT NETWORK,
WITH OVER 30,000 HOT SPOTS.
AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET.
NOW ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOUR WHOLE HOUSE
CAN COUNT ON.
♪
>>> SOMETIMES THE BEST HOLIDAY
GIFTS ARE THINGS YOU NEVER YOU
NEEDED OR WANTED.
ENTER FAB.COM.
>> IN LESS THAN TWO YEARS, THE
WEBSITE HAS BECOME AN E-COMMERCE
STAR BY SELLING THINGS LIKE
VINTAGE PAN AM BAGS AND SOME
QUIRKY HOME DECORATIONS, AS
WELL.
SO TECHNOLOGY EDITOR JOANNA
STERN LOOKS AT THE SITE'S
SUCCESS.
>> Reporter: 'TIS THE SEASON TO
GO SHOPPING.
THERE'S A NEW PLACE TO SHOP
EITHER ON YOUR PHONE, YOUR
TABLET OR ON YOUR LAPTOP.
EVEN ON FACEBOOK AND THEY HAVE A
LOT OF COOL STUFF.
IT'S FAB, LITERALLY.
I'M HERE TO FIND OUT WHY THIS
HAS BECOME THE COOLEST PLACE TO
SHOP.
I'M A BIG FAN OF FAB, BUT FOR
THOSE THAT DON'T KNOW, WHAT IS
FAB?
>> FAB IS VERY SIMPLE.
FAB IS EVERYDAY DESIGN.
WE'RE THE WORLD'S LARGEST ONLINE
DESIGN RETAILER.
WE TALK ABOUT THINGS BIG AND
SMALL, ALL PRICE POINTS.
ALL CATEGORIES.
FOR US, DESIGN IS ABOUT EVERYDAY
AFFORDABLE, FUN, COLORFUL STUFF.
>> WE'LL GET TO ALL THAT FUN AND
COLORFUL STUFF.
BUT THE THING THAT SET FAB APART
IS HOW IT'S USING MOBILE APPs
AND SOCIAL MEDIA.
IT'S GONE FROM A MILLION USERS
AT THIS TIME LAST YEAR TO OVER
10 MILLION NOW.
THAT'S HUGE GROWTH.
>> WE LOOK AT SOCIAL COMMERCE
NOT AS SOMETHING AS WHERE IT'S
AT THE END OF A PAGE PUT A LIKE
BUTTON OR SHARE BUTTON, BUT MAKE
IT PART OF THE CORE
FUNCTIONALITY OF THE SITE.
A BIG PART OF THE FAB EXPERIENCE
IS SEEING WHAT OTHER PEOPLE ARE
BUYING RIGHT NOW.
SEE WHAT THEY'RE FAVORITING
RIGHT NOW.
>> Reporter: THERE'S ANOTHER
THING THAT'S MADE FAB POPULAR.
REALLY AWESOME STUFF TO BUY.
WHERE ELSE CAN YOU BUY THE
WORLD'S LARGEST GUMMY BEAR, A
ROLLING ALARM CLOCK AND A BANANA
THAT'S A USB KEY OR THAT?
ANY CHANCE YOU MIGHT EVER WANT
TO GO TO THE BRICK AND MORTAR
TYPE OF RETAIL LOCATION?
>> I WOULD LOVE TO OPEN UP A
PHYSICAL STORE.
I MAKE NO BONES ABOUT IT.
WE SHOULD BE MULTIPLATFORM AND
WHERE THE SHOPPER IS.
>> Reporter: SO THERE YOU HAVE
IT.
FAB IS CLEARLY GROWING BY THE
DAY IN TERMS OF USERS AND COOL
PRODUCTS.
NOW WE JUST NEED THEM TO OPEN UP
THE STORES SO EVERYONE CAN PLAY
WITH THE LEGOS AND TRY ON THE
CLOTHING.
>> GOOD ASSIGNMENT.
>> AND HERE'S SOMETHING.
IF YOU LIKE WHAT YOU JUST SAW,
FAB.COM IS OFFERING "WORLD NEWS
NOW" VIEWERS $10 OFF THEIR
PURCHASE.
$10.
>> REALLY?
>> YES.
>> HOW WILL THEY KNOW THEY'RE
"WORLD NEWS NOW" VIEWERS?
>> GO TO FAB.COM/ABC2012 AND
IT'S NOT GOING TO BE REFLECTED
UNTIL YOU PUT IT IN YOUR CART.
>> UNDERSTOOD.
>> PUT THE JUNK IN THE TRUNK.
>> THERE ARE FINALLY SOME PERKS
TO WATCHING OUR SHOW.
WE'LL BE BACK.
FINALLY SOME PERKS
TO WATCHING OUR SHOW.
WE'LL BE BACK.
>>> TIME FOR OUR FRIDAY MORNING
EDITION OF "INSOMNIAC THEATER."
>> WITH A PAIR OF MOVIES VERY
DIFFERENT FROM EACH OTHER, "THE
HOBBIT" OPENS THIS WEEKEND, BUT
LET'S LOOK AT "STAND UP GUYS"
ABOUT A TRIO OF VETERAN
GANGSTERS.
I LIKE THE PLOT OF THIS ONE.
IT STARS SOME HEAVYWEIGHTS.
AL PACINO'S CHARACTER GETS OUT
OF PRISON AFTER 30 YEARS.
HE GETS PICKED UP IN JAIL BY HIS
BEST FRIEND, DOC PLAYED BY
CHRISTOPHER WALKEN.
TEAM UP WITH ANOTHER ONE OF
THEIR BUDDIES.
ONE OF THE THREE DUDES HERE IS
KEEPING A DANGEROUS SECRET
LINKED TO A FORMER MOB BOSS.
THAT'S WHERE THE DRAMA ENSUES
HERE.
GREAT CAST.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> REMEMBER ME?
I DO THIS, HUH?
>> WHAT TIME IS IT?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT TIME IS IT?
>> IT'S TIME TO KICK ASS OR CHEW
GUM.
AND GUESS WHAT?
I'M ALL OUT OF GUM.
>> RAW TOMATO FOLKS DO NOT
AGREE.
ONLY GETTING 50% THUMBS UP RIGHT
NOW.
SO THAT'S NOT TOO GREAT, BUT
THIS LINE SUMMED UP BEST.
THE FILM IS CLEVER IN THE WAY IT
DEALS WITH THE HIGH COST OF MOB
CONNECTIONS AND THE HIGHER COST
OF OLD AGE.
GREAT CAST.
CHECK IT OUT.
>> NOW TO ONE OF THE MOST HIGHLY
ANTICIPATED MOVIES OF THE YEAR,
"THE HOBBIT."
WHAT SETS THIS FILM APART, 48
FRAMES PER SECOND.
IT'S A LITTLE TOO MUCH FOR SOME
PEOPLE.
BUT THIS IS A PREQUEL TO THE
ORIGINAL TRILOGY.
HE HAS TO RECLAIM THE LOST DWARF
KINGDOM AND, FIRST, HE HAS TO
ESCAPE THE GOBLIN TUNNELS.
MEETS THE CREATURE.
THAT WILL CHANGE HIS LIFE
FOREVER.
TAKE A LISTEN.
>> SO I'M A HUGE FAN OF THE
SERIES.
ROTTEN TOMATO ONLY GIVING IT 69%
APPROVAL.
AND ONLY 461 THEATERS OUT OF
4,000 ARE GOING TO SHOW THE
EXPEDITED VERSION OF THE 48
FRAMES PER SECOND.
IT MAKES A LOT OF PEOPLE
NAUSEOUS.
>> DON'T THROW UP IN YOUR
POPCORN, FOLKS.
hañ;ñ;ñ;ñ;ñ;ñ$x
>>> THIS MORNING ON "WORLD NEWS
NOW," SYRIA ON THE BRINK.
IT APPEARS TO BE ONLY A MATTER
OF TIME BEFORE PRESIDENT ASSAD
AND HIS RUTHLESS REGIME ARE
OVERRUN BY THE REBELS.
>> SYRIA'S INTERNATIONAL SUPPORT
IS FALLING APART, BUT THERE'S
SOME QUESTION ABOUT SUPPORT FROM
ASSAD'S BIGGEST ALLY.
IT IS FRIDAY, DECEMBER 14 th.
>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS "WORLD
NEWS NOW."
>> HAPPY FRIDAY.
I'M PAULA FARIS.
>> AND I'M ROB NELSON.
SEE HOW THE OPPOSITION IS
STARTING TO GET THE UPPER HAND
IN SYRIA AND WHAT THAT MEANS TO
THE WORLD.
IT COULD BE A MATTER OF DAYS OR
WEEKS, BUT SEEMS LIKE WE'RE
GETTING CLOSE TO A TIPPING POINT
THERE.
>>> ALSO THIS HALF HOUR, A NASTY
VIRUS RACES THROUGH A TOWN.
A COUPLE HUNDRED PEOPLE ALREADY
SICK.
WHAT A POPULAR CHAIN RESTAURANT,
RIGHT THERE YOU SEE IT, WHAT
THEY'RE DOING TO CONFRONT THE
OUTBREAK.
>> EATEN THERE ON SEVERAL
OCCASIONS.
NOT THAT PARTICULAR ONE, BUT
THAT PARTICULAR CHAIN AND I WAS
FINE.
>>> THEN AIRFARES ARE TAKING ON
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON, BUT EVEN
WITH THE PRICE OF FLIGHTS
CLIMBING, YOU CAN STILL SAVE
SOME MONEY ON TICKETS IF YOU
FOLLOW OUR EXPERT'S ADVICE.
JUST STAY HOME.
>>> AND LATER IN THIS HALF HOUR,
MICK JAGGER SWINGING HIS HIPS,
FLAPPING THOSE LIPS AT THE
12-12-12 CONCERT.
HOW HE'S SET OFF A STORM OF
CONTROVERSY, COMING UP IN "THE
SKINNY."
SAID SOMETHING DURING THE SHOW
THAT SOME FOLKS DID NOT LIKE,
MR. JAGGER.
SO WE'LL GET TO THAT.
>>> BUT FIRST TO THAT MAJOR TURN
IN SYRIA.
INTERNATIONAL SUPPORT FOR
SYRIA'S PRESIDENT BASHIR AL
ASSAD APPEARS TO BE FADING.
>> A RUSSIAN DIPLOMAT SAID ASSAD
WAS ON HIS WAY OUT.
THIS MORNING, RUSSIA'S FOREIGN
MINISTER DENIES THOSE
STATEMENTS.
BUT NATO SAYS THE END IS NEAR.
MARTHA RADDATZ REPORTS.
>> Reporter: IT COULD ALL END
SOON HERE IN DAMASCUS BECAUSE
WHILE ASSAD IS IN CONTROL IN THE
CAPITAL, REBELS ARE MOVING
CLOSER.
NOW, JUST OUTSIDE IN THE
SUBURBS.
THE BATTLE IS BLOODY.
AT THE REGIME'S MILITARY
HOSPITAL, THERE ARE SAID TO BE
40 WOUNDED TREATED A DAY, WHILE
THE REBELS, LIKE THIS FIGHTER
WHO LOST BOTH FEET, RECEIVED
TREATMENT FROM A DENTIST.
THEIR HOSPITAL BOMBED.
>> THE REBELS HAVE SHOWN THAT
THEY HAVE A STOMACH FOR A FIGHT.
THEY'VE SHOWN THEY CAN ENDURE
PAIN, AND THEY HAVE THE
CONVICTION THAT IF THEY DON'T
FIGHT ON, THEY'LL BE KILLED.
>> Reporter: SOME 200 OF THEIR
RECRUITS TRAINING AT AN ARMY
BASE THEY SAID THEY CAPTURED.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK WILL HAPPEN
TO ASSAD?
>> KILLED.
MUST BE KILLED.
>> Reporter: BUT WHO EXACTLY ARE
THESE REBELS?
>> WE DON'T HAVE A GOOD SENSE.
AND TO THE EXTENT THAT EXTERNAL
ORGANIZATIONS ARE IN THERE AND
IN SOME EXTREMIST FORM, THE
WORRY IS BOTH THE RETRIBUTION
AFTERWARDS AND THE POTENTIAL
ACCESS TO CHEMICAL WEAPONS.
>> Reporter: A THREAT TO AMERICA
AND THE WORLD AND A THREAT TO
THE PEOPLE OF SYRIA LONGING TO
BE FREE OF VIOLENCE.
OFFICIALS I'VE SPOKEN TO FEAR
THIS COULD BE A LONG AND BLOODY
CONFLICT.
EVEN IF ASSAD FALLS.
THOUGH SOME STILL HOLD OUT HOPE
A POLITICAL SOLUTION CAN BE
FOUND, IF ASSAD FINALLY REALIZES
HIS DAYS ARE NUMBERED.
MARTHA RADDATZ, ABC NEWS,
WASHINGTON.
>> THANK YOU, MARTHA.
>>> U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE
IS STEPPING ASIDE, WITHDRAWING
HER NAME FROM CONSIDERATION TO
BECOME THE NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE FOR THE U.S.
IN A LETTER TO PRESIDENT OBAMA,
RICE SAID THE CONFIRMATION
PROCESS WOULD BE LENGTHY,
DISRUPTIVE, AND COSTLY.
SHE SAYS IN THE END, THE
TRADEOFF WOULD BE UNFAIR TO THE
COUNTRY.
REPUBLICAN SENATORS HAVE
ATTACKED RICE FOR HER HANDLING
OF THE CRISIS IN LIBYA AND THE
DEATH OF AMBASSADOR CHRIS
STEPHENS.
SO A LITTLE BIT OF A POLITICAL
BLACK EYE FOR THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION.
THIS WAS HIS FIRST CHOICE, NOW
LOOKING LIKE SENATOR JOHN KERRY
OF MASSACHUSETTS WILL BE THE
LIKELY AT THIS POINT.
>> AND SUSAN RICE TWEETING
YESTERDAY, THOSE OF YOU WHO KNOW
ME KNOW I'M A FIGHTER, BUT NOT
AT THE COST OF WHAT'S RIGHT FOR
OUR COUNTRY.
SHE JUST WROTE AN OP-ED IN "THE
WASHINGTON POST" AND SAID I
CONCLUDED IT WOULD BE WRONG TO
ALLOW THIS DEBATE TO KEEP
DISTRACTING FROM URGENT
NATIONAL PRIORITIES LIKE
IMMIGRATION AND GROWING OUR
ECONOMY.
>> BENGHAZI WAS AN ISSUE.
BUT ALSO SOME OF HER DECISIONS
AND DIPLOMATIC SKILLS HAVE
BECOME AN ISSUE, AS WELL.
SOME FINANCIAL TIES SHE HAD.
SOME INVESTMENTS SHE HAD BECAME
AN ISSUE.
SO IT WAS MORE THAN THE BENGHAZI
ISSUE.
THAL WAS THE CORE ISSUE HERE.
BUT OBAMA IS LIKELY TO NAME HER
AS HIS NEXT NATIONAL SECURITY
ADVISER, A JOB WITH LESS
PRESTIGE BUT IN SOME CASES EVEN
MORE INFLUENCE THAN THE
SECRETARY OF STATE.
SO BY NO MEANS IS SHE OFF THE
SCENE BY ANY STRETCH.
SO SHE'LL STILL BE HEAVILY
INVOLVED IN THE ADMINISTRATION.
>>> MOVING ON THIS MORNING.
SLOW PROGRESS IN WASHINGTON AS
THE NATION CREEPS CLOSER TO THE
FISCAL CLIFF JUST 18 DAYS AWAY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER MET AT THE
WHITE HOUSE FOR LESS THAN AN
HOUR THURSDAY.
SPOKESMEN ON BOTH SIDES SAID THE
TWO HAD A FRANK DISCUSSION,
THEIR FIRST FACE-TO-FACE SINCE
SUNDAY.
WITHOUT A DECISION, MANDATORY
TAX HIKES AND BUDGET CUTS WILL
TAKE EFFECT AT THE START OF THE
YEAR.
THIS SEEMS LIKE WE'RE NOT
GETTING ANY MAJOR HEADWAY, JUST
BABY STEPS.
>> THEY SAY THE LINES OF
COMMUNICATION ARE OPEN, BUT ONLY
UNDER MY RULES.
IT SEEMS LIKE THAT'S WHAT I'M
GETTING FROM BOTH SIDES.
BUT 50 MINUTES AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
SO HOPEFULLY THEY CAN GET IT
DONE.
>> I GUESS I STEP BACK AND SAY,
LET'S SAY WE GET TO SOMETHING BY
THE END OF THE YEAR.
YOU HOPE THAT WHATEVER
COMPROMISE THEY COME UP WITH IT
DOES ACHIEVE A GREATER GOOD FOR
THE COUNTRY.
WHATEVER THE FINAL NUMBERS, YOU
HOPE THAT PEOPLE DON'T JUST SIT
AROUND AND APPLAUD THAT WE GOT A
COMPROMISE IF IT DOESN'T
ACCOMPLISH MUCH IN GETTING THE
NATION'S FISCAL HOUSE IN ORDER.
SO IT'S GREAT WE GOT A
COMPROMISE BUT WHAT DO YOU
REALLY ACCOMPLISH?
FISCAL HEALTH OF THE COUNTRY.
>> IT WOULD BE DISHEARTENING IF
THAT WERE THE CASE, IF IT
WEREN'T FOR THE BETTERMENT OF
THE COUNTRY.
>>> IN THE WINDY CITY, A YOUNG
MAN TRYING TO TAKE A PICTURE OF
THE CHICAGO SKYLINE FELL TO HIS
DEATH INSIDE A SMOKESTACK.
HE AND HIS GIRLFRIEND CLIMBED TO
THE ROOF OF THE INTERCONTINENTAL
HOTEL MORE THAN 40 STORIES UP
WHEN HE WENT UP A LADDER TO THE
TOP OF THAT SMOKESTACK AND LOST
HIS FOOTING.
IT TOOK FIRST RESPONDERS FOUR
HOURS TO CUT THROUGH THE STEEL
BOTTOM OF THE SHAFT TO REACH
HIM, BUT THEY WERE TOO LATE.
>>> POLICE IN TEXAS PULLED OVER
A WOMAN FOR DRIVING ERRATICALLY
AND FOUND HER 8-MONTH-OLD
DAUGHTER IN THE BACK SEAT OF HER
CAR.
SHE ADMITTED SHE DRANK A BEER,
TOOK SOME PROZAC AND XANAX AND
SMOKED POTPOURRI
TOLD POLICE HER ROOMMATE WAS
BABYSITTING HER 12-YEAR-OLD SON
BUT COULDN'T REMEMBER THE
ROOMMATE'S NAME.
THAT LITTLE 8-MONTH-OLD JUST
BURIED IN JUNK.
NOT A MOTHER OF THE YEAR AWARD.
>> THAT IS HEART BREAKING.
>>> A POPULAR CHAIN RESTAURANT
IN CASPAR, WYOMING, MAY BE TO
BLAME FOR A VIRUS OUTBREAK
THAT'S SPREADING THROUGH THAT
CITY NOW.
HEALTH INSPECTORS SAY ABOUT 200
CUSTOMERS BECAME SICK AFTER
EATING AT THE GOLDEN CORRAL
BUFFET.
THE RESTAURANT IS VOLUNTARILY
CLOSING ITS DOORS FOR 24 HOURS
SO IT CAN BE CLEANED AND
DISINFECTED FROM TOP TO BOTTOM.
PUBLIC HEALTH EXPERTS BELIEVE
IT'S INFECTED WITH THE NURO
VIRUS.
>> IT'S THE NUMBER ONE MOST
COMMON FOOD BORN ILLNESS IN THE
UNITED STATES.
IT'S EVERYWHERE.
IT'S BEEN IN THE COMMUNITY FOR
MONTHS.
BUT IT'S SPORADIC.
>> THE VIRUS CAUSES VOMITING,
DIARRHEA, HEADACHES, EVEN FEVER
AND USUALLY LASTS ABOUT 48 HOURS
OR SO.
THE GOLDEN CORRAL WILL REOPEN
AFTER A HEALTH DEPARTMENT
INSPECTION.
>> HOPE THAT STEAK AND FRIED
CHICKEN WAS WORTH IT.
WHATEVER WAS AT THE BUFFET.
>> I DOUBT IT.
>>> HERE'S YOUR FRIDAY FORECAST.
SHOWERS IN SAN DIEGO.
HEAVY RAIN FROM LAS VEGAS TO
ALBUQUERQUE.
MORE THAN A FOOT OF MOUNTAIN
SNOW FROM ARIZONA TO SOUTHERN
UTAH.
THUNDERSTORMS AROUND WICHITA,
OKLAHOMA CITY AND DALLAS.
>> 70s IN DALLAS AND NEW
ORLEANS.
MOSTLY 40s IN THE NORTHEAST
MIDWEST AND PACIFIC NORTHWEST.
57 IN PHOENIX AND 38 IN SALT
LAKE.
>>> TWO COSTCO WORKERS NEAR
BOSTON JUST GOT THE BIGGEST
PAYDAY OF THEIR LIVES.
THEY ARE SPLITTING THE LATEST
POWERBALL JACKPOT.
>> I THINK SHE BOUGHT THESE
TICKETS IN BULK.
ROSA AND REGINALD WON
WEDNESDAY'S $50 MILLION PRIZE.
THEY'RE TAKING THE LUMP SUM
PAYMENT.
SO AFTER TAXES, THAT'S MORE THAN
$11 MILLION EACH.
RIGHT, ROB?
BUT THEY HAVE YET TO DECIDE IF
THEY'RE GOING TO QUIT THEIR JOB.
>> YEAH, OKAY.
SHE PLANS TO BUY A HOME AND TAKE
CARE OF HER CHILDREN AND SIX
GRANDKIDS.
>> HE IS MISSING SEVERAL FRONT
TEETH SAYS DENTAL WORK IS ON HIS
AGENDA.
>> LET'S NOT GO THERE.
THEY'VE BEEN PLAYING POWERBALL
TWICE A WEEK FOR THE PAST TEN
MONTHS.
YOU CAN'T MAKE THIS STUFF UP,
FOLKS.
>> HE SAID IT.
DON'T WRITE US ON FACEBOOK.
NO ONE IS MAKING FUN, HE SAID
THAT HE'S GOING TO GET HIS
CHOMPERS TOGETHER.
>> THAT'S TOUCHING.
>> NOT GOING THERE.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, SEARCHING
FOR TRENDS AMONG THE BIG
NOMINEES OF THIS YEAR'S GOLDEN
GLOBE --
>>> SEARCHING FOR LAST-MINUTE
DEALS AS HOLIDAY AIRFARES GO
SKY HIGH.
HOW YOU CAN SAVE SOME MONEY WITH
EXPERT ADVICE.
KEEP SMILING.
"WORLD NEWS NOW" CONTINUES.
>>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" WEATHER
BROUGHT TO YOU BY CONSUMER
CELLULAR.
>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" WEATHER
BROUGHT TO YOU BY CONSUMER
CELLULAR.
>>> WELCOME BACK.
IF YOU'VE STARTED LOOKING AT
AIRLINE FARES, YOU KNOW PRICES
ARE WAY UP.
YOU JUST WAITED TOO LONG.
>> THAT'S IT.
THE LONGER YOU WAIT TO BOOK YOUR
FLIGHT, THE MORE YOU'LL COUGH
UP.
BUT THERE ARE SOME STRATEGIES TO
HELP YOU SAVE HUNDREDS OF BUCKS.
WITH MORE ON THAT, HERE'S ABC'S
JIM AVILA.
>> Reporter: PLANES ARE FULL,
AND THAT MEANS HIGHER PRICES FOR
HOLIDAY TRAVEL.
A NEW REPORT FROM THE AIRLINE
TRADE GROUP SHOWS DEMAND STRONG
AND PLANES FLYING AT 85% TO 90%
CAPACITY.
NONSTOP TICKET PRICES CHRISTMAS
WEEK ARE NEARLY DOUBLE WHAT THEY
WERE AT THE BEGINNING OF THE
MONTH.
AND RISING BY THE DAY.
>> EVERY DAY YOU WAIT, ADD ABOUT
$7 TO $8 EACH DAY YOU WAIT.
>> Reporter: THE AVERAGE
DOMESTIC AIRFARE IS NOW $414
ACCORDING TO TRAVELOCITY.
A 9% JUMP OVER LAST YEAR'S
HOLIDAY SEASON.
THE MOST EXPENSIVE DAYS TO FLY,
UP TO $500 MORE A TICKET ARE
DECEMBER 21, 22, AND ON THE
RETURN DECEMBER 30, 31 AND NEW
YEAR'S DAY.
THESE ARE THE CHEAPER DAYS TO
FLY.
CHRISTMAS DAY AND THE THREE DAYS
AFTER.
FLYING THEN CAN SAVE AS MUCH AS
$330.
>> WE'RE GOING TO SACRIFICE
PRICE FOR CONVENIENCE.
BUT YOU'LL ALSO ENCOUNTER FEWER
CROWDS AT THE AIRPORT.
>> Reporter: IT'S NOT JUST
AIRFARES MAKING THIS A
PROFITABLE SEASON FOR AIRLINES.
IF YOU'RE CHECKING BAGS, MAKE
SURE THEY'RE NOT OVERWEIGHT BY
USING A HOME SCALE.
AIRLINES CHARGE EXCESSIVE
BAGGAGE SURCHARGES THAT START AT
$90 ON TOP OF THE NORMAL BAGGAGE
FEE.
AND THE SCALES AT THE AIRPORT
ARE NOT ALWAYS ACCURATE.
AN ABC NEWS INVESTIGATION LAST
YEAR AT THIS TIME SHOWED 5% OF
AIRPORT SCALES CHECKED
NATIONWIDE WERE OFF IN ONE
DIRECTION OR THE OTHER BY AT
LEAST HALF AN OUNCE.
ENOUGH TO ADD COSTS.
ADDING INJURY TO THE ALREADY
INSULTING HIGH HOLIDAY FARES.
JIM AVILA, ABC NEWS, WASHINGTON.
>> THAT HANDHELD SCALE IS COOL.
>> THAT SAVES YOU SOME BUCKS
POTENTIALLY.
FLYING SUCKS THESE DAYS.
I'LL SAY IT.
>> THAT'S GOING TO BRING US TO
OUR FACEBOOK QUESTION OF THE
DAY.
>> WE WANT TO KNOW WHAT DO YOU
DO TO SAVE MONEY WHEN YOU TRAVEL
DURING THE HOLIDAYS?
LOGON TO OUR FACEBOOK PAGE AND
LET US KNOW AND SHARE YOUR TIPS
WITH OTHERS.
>> JUST DON'T TRAVEL.
>> THAT'S MY TIP.
I HAVE TO SAY IT.
>> SCROOGE.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, THE GUEST
WHO WAS NOT ALLOWED TO RETURN TO
JON STEWART'S SHOW AND WHY.
>> JON HAD SOME HARSH WORDS.
AND A BAD BOY ACTOR AND HIS
HEARTFELT ACT OF GOOD WILL.
ALL COMING UP NEXT IN "THE
SKINNY."
>> "WORLD NEWS NOW" CONTINUES
AFTER THIS FROM OUR ABC
STATIONS.
♪
♪ SKIP, SO
>>> THIS IS WILLIS' FAVORITE
SEGMENT.
GOLDEN GLOBE NOMINATIONS WERE
ANNOUNCED YESTERDAY.
LOTS TO GET TO HERE.
LET'S JUST HOP INTO IT.
THE BIG DEAL IS THAT THIS IS A
PRECURSOR TO THE OSCARS.
WE'RE GETTING INTO AWARDS SEASON
NOW.
HERE WE GO.
APPARENTLY THE DAY BELONGED TO
THE MOVIE "LINCOLN."
NOT A SHOCKER HERE.
EVERYONE IS RAVING ABOUT THIS
MOVIE, FOR THE MOST PART.
>> WHICH NONE OF US HAVE SEEN
YET.
>> I'M DYING TO.
JUST SLOW GETTING TO THE MOVIES.
AND "ARGO" BEN AFFLECK'S MOVIE
DID VERY WELL.
BOTH OF THEM GOT NOMINATED FOR
BEST PICTURE DRAMA.
ON TOP OF "LIFE OF PIE," "ZERO
DARK THIRTY."
BEST ACTRESS, JESSICA CHASTAIN,
HELEN MIRREN, NAOMI WATTS,
RACHEL WISE.
BEST ACTOR DRAMA --
DANIEL DAY LEWIS FOR "LINCOLN."
RICHARD GERE, JOHN HAWKS,
JAUQUIN PHOENIX AND DENZEL
WASHINGTON FOR "FLIGHT."
SO THOSE ARE THE HIGHLIGHTS.
AND FOR THE SAKE OF THE COMMISH,
DO WANT TO POINT OUT, FOR BEST
TELEVISION DRAMA, "BREAKING BAD"
"BOARDWALK EMPIRE" "DOUBTING
ABBY," "HOMELAND" AND "THE
NEWSROOM."
JUST WANTED TO ADD THAT IN
THERE.
FOR A SHOW I LOVE THAT HE HATES.
BUT WE HAVE THAT ONGOING FEUD.
>> I LOVE THAT CLAP.
HOW IS THAT JACK?
>> IT'S A GOOD SHOW.
>> THAT I HEAR IS GREAT.
>> WILLIS AND THE COMMISH CAN
HAVE A VIEWING PARTY.
>>> GREAT THING HAPPENING IN NEW
YORK CITY LAST NIGHT.
THEY HAD THE SANDY BENEFIT.
YOU SAW BON JOVI, BRUCE
SPRINGSTEEN, EVERYBODY
COLLABORATING FOR THE VICTIMS.
BUT SOMETHING MICK JAGGER SAID
ON STAGE IS A LITTLE
INSENSITIVE.
HERE'S WHAT HE SAID.
AND HE'S DRAWING ONLY IRE AND
RAGE FROM SOME PEOPLE.
HE SAID THIS HAS TO BE THE
LARGEST COLLECTION OF OLD
ENGLISH MUSICIANS EVER ASSEMBLED
IN MADISON SQUARE GARDEN.
BUT IF IT RAINS IN LONDON,
YOU'VE GOT TO COME AND HELP US.
SO BASICALLY COMPARING HURRICANE
SANDY, WHICH KILLED 140 PEOPLE,
AND REBUILDING IS EXPECTED TO
REACH $70 BILLION, COMPARING
THAT TO RAIN.
>> I'M SURE HE MEANT IT AS A
JOKE.
>> IT WAS A BAD JOKE.
>> DIDN'T REALIZE HOW IT WOULD
COME ACROSS.
>>> JON STEWART HAS SOME HARSH
WORDS.
THERE'S ONE PERSON NEVER ALLOWED
TO COME BACK TO HIS SHOW, THAT'S
ACTOR HUGH GRANT.
HUGH WAS ON THE SHOW IN 2009 AND
STEWART WAS AT AN EVENT IN
JERSEY AND WAS TELLING THE
AUDIENCE, HIS QUOTE WAS, HE'S
GIVING EVERYONE THE WORD AND
HE'S A BIG PAIN IN THE A WORD,
JON SAID.
APPARENTLY THERE WAS A CLIP THE
PUBLICIST OF THE MOVIE THAT HUGH
WAS PROMOTING AT THE TIME AND
SAID OH, IT'S A TERRIBLE CLIP.
STEWART SAID, MAKE A BETTER
"F"-ING MOVIE.
SO NO LOVE LOSS THERE.
>> CHARLIE SHEEN GAVE $100,000
TO LINDSAY LOHAN, WHO SEEMS TO
BE A HOPELESS CAUSE RIGHT NOW
AND GAVE $75,000 AND HIS BODY
DOUBLE GAVE $25,000 TO A CANCER
STRICKEN DAUGHTER OF A HERMOSA
BEACH POLICE OFFICER.
HE JUST HEARD ABOUT IT OVER THE
WEEKEND AND SAID NO PARENT
SHOULD HAVE TO WATCH THEIR KID
GO THROUGH THAT AND GAVE HIM
$75,000, $100,000 TOTAL.
>> NOT BAD, CHARLIE.
CONGRATULATIONS TO HUGH JACKMAN.
YESTERDAY GOT HIS STAR ON THE
HOLLYWOOD WALK OF FAME.
CONGRATULATIONS TO PAULA'S
FANTASY MAN.
Every time someone chooses
Finish over Cascade,
it sparks a movement.
Because people can't
keep it to themselves.
Look !
No ugly spots !
Awesome!
Incredible shine.
I'm switching for good.
Love, love, love Finish!
Over a million people
have switched to Finish.
Visit us on Facebook.
♪
>>> FINALLY THIS HALF HOUR, THE
UNFORGETTABLE HEADLINES OF THIS
PAST WEEK.
>> FROM HIGH PROFILE TRAGEDY TO
POLITICAL FRUSTRATION, HERE IS
OUR FRIDAY REWIND.
>> I DON'T THINK THAT ANYONE
COULD HAVE EXPECTED OR FORESEEN
WHAT WAS GOING TO HAPPEN.
>> THERE'S NOT A MINUTE THAT
GOES BY WE DON'T THINK ABOUT
HER FAMILY AND WHAT THEY MUST
BE GOING THROUGH AND THE THOUGHT
THAT WE MAY HAVE PLAYED A PART
IN THAT IS GUT WRENCHING.
>> SUCH A BIG SHOCK TO THE
FAMILY.
IT'S INCREDIBLE.
SOMETHING THAT MOST PEOPLE THAT
KNOW MY SISTER, SHE WAS A VERY
STRONG PERSON.
>> SHE WAS A PERSONALITY.
SHE WAS A BUSINESSWOMAN.
SHE WAS BEGINNING TO CROSS OVER
INTO THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE
MARKET.
>> JERRY BROWN WAS MY DEAR BEST
BROWN.
I'M JUST DEALING WITH HIS DEATH
RIGHT NOW.
>> FIVE SECONDS LATER, WE HEARD
RAPID FIRE, BANG, BANG, BANG.
AND I TOOK OFF RUNNING.
>> EVERYTHING BECAME SO REAL.
IT WAS A LOT LIKE VIRGINIA TECH
AND COLUMBINE.
HE CAME IN WITH A HOCKEY MASK
ON.
SO OBVIOUSLY CAME WITH THE
INTENT TO KILL.
>> ANY TIME YOU GOT TWO GUYS
TANGOING, YOU'VE GOT A CHANCE TO
GET IT DONE.
>> I'M PRETTY CONFIDENT
REPUBLICANS WILL NOT HOLD MIDDLE
CLASS TAXES HOSTAGE TO TRY TO
PROTECT TAX CUTS FROM
HIGH-INCOME INDIVIDUALS.
>> THERE IS A GROWING GROUP OF
FOLKS THAT ARE LOOKING AT THIS
AND REALIZING THAT WE DON'T HAVE
A LOT OF CARDS AS IT RELATES TO
THE TAX ISSUE.
>> IT WAS REAL SCARY.
EVERYTHING WAS JUST FLYING.
JUST TOSSED AROUND.
>> I GREW UP IN A HOUSE WITH
THREE SISTERS, SO I THINK IT'S
GREAT FOR MY BOYS TO HAVE A GIRL
IN THE HOUSE, JUST TO UNDERSTAND
AT LEAST A LITTLE BIT OF WHAT
MAKES A WOMAN TICK.
>> WINNER OF THE HEISMAN
MEMORIAL TROPHY IS JOHNNY
MANZIEL.
>> GRANDPA, ALL THE TIMES WE
USED TO PLAY IN THE HALLWAY AND
THROW THE BALL UNTIL WE COULDN'T
ANYMORE, I LOVE YOU WITH ALL MY
HEART AND YOU INSPIRED ME TO
PLAY FOOTBALL.
AND GRANDMA, I'M SORRY FOR ALL
THE THINGS WE BROKE IN THE
HOUSE.
>> FIRST FRESHMAN TO WIN.
THAT'S GREAT.
AND CHRISTMAS IS A GREAT TIME TO
MAKE MEMORIES.
>> BETWEEN THE EGGNOG AND THOSE
SILLY SWEATERS, IT'S A BETTER
TIME TO MAKE SOME EMBARRASSING
MEMORIES.
SOME OF THE BEST EMBARRASSING
MEMORIES INVOLVE SANTA, YEAH,
GOT TO LIKE THIS ONE.
THIS IS MIA FROM MICHIGAN, WHO
APPARENTLY DID NOT ENJOY HER
FIRST MEETING WITH JOLLY OLD ST.
NICK.
>> IF YOU HAVE SOME AWKWARD
CHRISTMAS PICS, WE ASK YOU TO
SEND THEM TO US.
>> TWITTER WORKS BEST.
#WNN
>> AND WE'LL SHOW THEM ON THE
AIR AND LAUGH AT YOUR
EXPENSE.
♪
>>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
BREAKING RIGHT NOW, TWO, LARGE
EARTHQUAKES OFF CALIFORNIA, WAKE
UP THOUSANDS ALONG THE WEST
>> REPORTS SAY PATRIOT MISSILES
ARE HEADING TO TURKEY TO GUARD
AGAINST POSSIBLE ATTACKS.
>>> ALSO, U.N. AMBASSADOR SUSAN
RICE, NOW OUT OF THE RUNNING TO
BECOME THE NEXT SECRETARY OF
STATE.
THE QUESTION, NOW, IS WHO IS
GOING TO BE THE NATION'S NEXT
TOP DIPLOMAT?
>>> A STUNNING DEATH, HIGH ABOVE
CHICAGO'S MAGNIFICENT MILE.
A MAN IS DEAD AFTER A TERRIFYING
TUMBLE DOWN THAT SMOKESTACK.
>>> AND A STRONG REACTION TO A