69-YEAR-OLD MICK JAGGER ROCKS
THE STAGE LAST NIGHT.
AND WE ASK HIM THE SECRET OF
STILL BEING ABLE TO DO THIS AND
THIS.
>>> GOOD EVENING.
WE BEGIN WITH BREAKING NEWS.
THE WOMAN WHO WITHSTOOD
FEROCIOUS FIRE FROM POLITICAL
OPPONENTS IN WASHINGTON TODAY
SAID ENOUGH.
SUSAN RICE, THE AMBASSADOR TO
THE U.N., SO EMBATTLED OVER THE
TRAGEDY IN BENGHAZI, SAID SHE
WILL NOT GO THROUGH A BRUISING
NOMINATION FIGHT TO SUCCEED
HILLARY CLINTON AS SECRETARY OF
STATE.
SO, WHAT HAPPENED BEHIND CLOSED
DOORS?
WHY NOW?
AND WHOM WILL THE PRESIDENT PICK
TO REPRESENT AMERICA ON THE
WORLD STAGE?
ABC'S SENIOR WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT JAKE TAPPER HAS
ALL THE DETAILS RIGHT NOW.
JAKE?
>> Reporter: GOOD EVENING,
DIANE.
WELL, AMBASSADOR SUSAN RICE
WITHDREW HER NAME FROM
CONSIDERATION TO BE SECRETARY OF
STATE AFTER WEEKS OF BRUISING
POLITICAL BATTLES AND A
CACOPHONY OF CRITICISM.
IN A LETTER TO THE PRESIDENT
TODAY, U.S. AMBASSADOR TO THE
UNITED NATIONS SUSAN RICE WROTE,
"THE POSITION OF SECRETARY OF
STATE SHOULD NEVER BE
POLITICIZED.
I AM SADDENED THAT WE HAVE
REACHED THIS POINT EVEN BEFORE
YOU HAVE DECIDED WHOM TO
NOMINATE."
AND SHE SHARED THE NEWS ON NBC.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO SEE A
CONFIRMATION PROCESS THAT WAS
VERY PROLONGED, VERY
POLITICIZED, VERY DISTRACTING
AND VERY DISRUPTIVE, BECAUSE
THERE ARE SO MANY THINGS WE NEED
TO GET DONE AS A COUNTRY.
>> Reporter: JUST WEEKS AGO,
RICE, A TOUGH AND SMART RISING
STAR IN THE OBAMA
ADMINISTRATION, WAS THE
PRESIDENT'S TOP CHOICE TO SERVE
AS THE NEXT SECRETARY OF STATE.
BUT SHE DREW A LIGHTNING STORM
OF REPUBLICAN CRITICISM FOR
REPEATING TALKING POINTS FROM
THE INTELLIGENCE COMMUNITY THAT
SEEMED TO CRITICS TO DOWNPLAY
THE TERRORIST ATTACK ON THE
DIPLOMATIC COMPOUND IN BENGHAZI,
LIBYA.
>> WHAT THIS BEGAN AS WAS A
SPONTANEOUS --
>> THE CONCERNS I HAVE ARE
GREATER TODAY THAN THEY WERE
BEFORE AND WE'RE NOT EVEN CLOSE
TO GETTING BASIC ANSWERS.
>> IT IS CLEAR THAT THE
INFORMATION THAT SHE GAVE THE
AMERICAN PEOPLE WAS INCORRECT.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT, IN A
STATEMENT TODAY, PRAISED RICE,
WHO WILL STAY AT HER U.N. POST.
AND EXPRESSED REGRET FOR "THE
UNFAIR AND MISLEADING ATTACKS ON
HER."
ABC NEWS HAS LEARNED THAT BEFORE
HER WITHDRAWAL, PRESIDENT OBAMA
HAD CONCLUDED THAT SENATOR JOHN
KERRY WOULD BE A BETTER CHOICE
TO BE THE NATION'S TOP DIPLOMAT.
WITH KERRY ALMOST CERTAIN TO BE
TAPPED, SOURCES SAY FORMER
SENATOR CHUCK HAGEL, A NEBRASKA
REPUBLICAN, SEEMS TO TODAY HAVE
AN EDGE TO BE THE NEXT DEFENSE
SECRETARY.
AND IN WHAT IS BEING PERCEIVED
AS AN EXPRESSION OF PRESIDENTIAL
SUPPORT, PRESIDENT OBAMA WILL
TOMORROW MEET HERE AT THE WHITE
HOUSE WITH AMBASSADOR RICE,
DIANE.
>> ALL RIGHT, I WANT TO TURN TO
ANOTHER MEETING, THOUGH, NOW,
JAKE, BECAUSE BEHIND YOU
TONIGHT, BEHIND THOSE WHITE
HOUSE DOORS, THE PRESIDENT MET
WITH SPEAKER BOEHNER ABOUT THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> Reporter: IT WAS DESCRIBED AS
A FRANK AND CANDID EXCHANGE OF
VIEWS WITH HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN
BOEHNER COMING HERE, INVITED BY
THE PRESIDENT TO TALK ABOUT THIS
IMPASSE THEY SEEM TO HAVE
REACHED, WITH BOEHNER SAYING
THAT THE PRESIDENT HASN'T AGREED
TO ENOUGH SPENDING CUTS,
PRESIDENT OBAMA STILL PUSHING ON
INCREASING TAX RATES ON THE
WEALTHIEST AMERICANS.
WE DO NOT HAVE ANY NEWS TO
SUGGEST THAT ANY DECISION OR
AGREEMENT HAS BEEN REACHED.
BUT AT LEAST THEY'RE STILL
TALKING, DIANE.
>> TWO AND A HALF WEEKS AWAY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, JAKE.
>>> AND NOW, WE GO TO SYRIA.
TINDERBOX TONIGHT AS EVEN ALLIES
OF THE RULING REGIME ARE
SIGNALING THE END MAY BE NEAR
FOR PRESIDENT ASSAD.
AND THE POWERFUL HEAD OF NATO IS
ALSO SIGNALING CHANGE IS COMING.
ABC'S SENIOR FOREIGN AFFAIRS
CORRESPONDENT MARTHA RADDATZ ON
THE END GAME AND WHAT DANGER IT
POSES FOR THE UNITED STATES.
>> Reporter: IT COULD ALL END
SOON HERE IN DAMASCUS.
WITH THE STARTLING WORD FROM
NATO AND NOW EVEN PRESIDENT
ASSAD'S STAUNCH ALLY RUSSIA,
THAT THE BRUTAL DICTATOR'S DAYS
ARE NUMBERED.
THAT'S BECAUSE WHILE ASSAD IS
STILL IN CONTROL IN THE CAPITAL,
REBELS ARE MOVING CLOSER.
NOW, JUST OUTSIDE IN THE
SUBURBS.
OUR BBC COLLEAGUE JEREMY BOWEN
SAW IT FIRST HAND, IN A
NEIGHBORHOOD WHERE ASSAD'S
FORCES HAVE TRIED TO STOP THE
REBEL ADVANCE, POUNDING THE
BUILDINGS AND HOMES WITH AIR
STRIKES AND ARTILLERY.
THE BATTLE IS BLOODY.
AT THE REGIME'S MILITARY
HOSPITAL, THERE ARE SAID TO BE
40 WOUNDED, TREATED A DAY.
WHILE THE REBELS, LIKE THIS
FIGHTER WHO LOST BOTH FEET,
RECEIVED TREATMENT FROM A
DENTIST.
THEIR HOSPITAL, BOMBED.
>> THE REBELS HAVE SHOWN THAT
THEY HAVE THE STOMACH FOR A
FIGHT.
THEY'VE SHOWN THAT THEY CAN
ENDURE PAIN.
AND THEY HAVE THE CONVICTION
THAT IF THEY DON'T FIGHT ON,
THEY'LL BE KILLED.
>> Reporter: BOWEN MET SOME 200
OF THEIR RECRUITS, TRAINING AT
AN ARMY BASE THEY SAID THEY
CAPTURED.
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK WILL HAPPEN
TO ASSAD?
>> KILLED.
MUST BE KILLED.
>> Reporter: BUT WHO EXACTLY ARE
THESE REBELS?
THE FIGHTER SAYS HIS GROUP IS
NOT AFFILIATED WITH AL QAEDA.
BUT WE KNOW OTHER REBELS ARE
INCLUDING A WING OF AL QAEDA
THAT HAS ATTACKED U.S. SOLDIERS
IN IRAQ.
AND WITHIN THE REBEL RANKS,
THERE ARE DOZENS OF COMPETING
GROUPS WITH DIFFERENT, SOMETIMES
MURKY GOALS.
>> WE DON'T REALLY HAVE A GOOD
SENSE, TO THE EXTENT THAT
EXTERNAL ORGANIZATIONS ARE IN
THERE AND IN SOME EXTREMIST
FORM.
THE WORRY IS BOTH THE
RETRIBUTION AFTERWARDS AND THE
POTENTIAL OF ACCESS TO CHEMICAL
WEAPONS.
>> Reporter: A THREAT TO AMERICA
AND THE WORLD.
AND A THREAT TO THE PEOPLE OF
SYRIA, LONGING TO BE FREE OF
VIOLENCE.
OFFICIALS I HAVE SPOKEN TO FEAR
THIS COULD BE A LONG AND BLOODY
CONFLICT, EVEN IF ASSAD FALLS.
ALTHOUGH SOME STILL HOLD OUT
HOPE THAT A POLITICAL SOLUTION
CAN BE FOUND, IF ASSAD FINALLY
REALIZES HIS DAYS ARE NUMBERED,
DIANE.
>> ALL RIGHT, ON THE STORY FOR
US, MARTHA RADDATZ.
THANK YOU, MARTHA.
>>> AND NOW, BACK HERE AT HOME,
AS WE KNOW, 11 DAYS UNTIL
HOLIDAY TRAVELERS HIT THE ROAD,
AND TODAY, WE LEARNED THIS YEAR
COULD BE THE BUSIEST IN A LONG
TIME.
1 IN 4 OF US, MORE THAN 93
MILLION AMERICANS, EXPECTED TO
TRAVEL 50 MILES OR MORE.
AND A NEW REPORT OUT TODAY WARNS
OF HOLIDAY GRIDLOCK.
ABC'S SENIOR NATIONAL
CORRESPONDENT JIM AVILA TELLS US
HOW TO NAVIGATE AROUND IT.
>> Reporter: PLANES ARE FULL,
AND THAT MEANS EVEN HIGHER
PRICES FOR HOLIDAY TRAVEL.
A NEW REPORT FROM THE AIRLINE
TRADE GROUP RELEASED TODAY SHOWS
DEMAND STRONG AND PLANES FLYING
AT 85% TO 90% CAPACITY.
NON-STOP TICKET PRICES CHRISTMAS
WEEK ARE NEARLY DOUBLE WHAT THEY
WERE AT THE BEGINNING OF THE
MONTH.
AND RISING BY THE DAY.
>> EVERY DAY YOU WAIT FOR YOUR
VIRTUAL AIRLINE TICKET, ADD
ABOUT $7 OR $8 FOR EACH DAY THAT
YOU WAIT.
>> Reporter: THE AVERAGE
DOMESTIC AIR FARE IS NOW
$414 ACCORDING TO TRAVELOCITY --
A 9% JUMP OVER LAST YEAR'S
HOLIDAY SEASON.
THE MOST EXPENSIVE DAYS TO FLY?
UP TO $500 MORE A TICKET ARE
DECEMBER 21st, 22nd AND ON THE
RETURN, DECEMBER 30th, 31st AND
NEW YEAR'S DAY.
THESE ARE THE CHEAPER DAYS TO
FLY -- CHRISTMAS DAY AND THE
THREE DAYS AFTER.
FLYING THEN CAN SAVE AS MUCH AS
$330.
>> YOU'RE GOING TO SACRIFICE
PRICE FOR CONVENIENCE, BUT
YOU'LL ALSO ENCOUNTER FEWER
CROWDS AT THE AIRPORT.
>> Reporter: AND IT'S NOT JUST
AIR FARES THAT ARE MAKING THIS A
PROFITABLE SEASON FOR AIRLINES.
IF YOU'RE CHECKING BAGS, MAKE
SURE THEY'RE NOT OVERWEIGHT BY
USING A HOME SCALE.
AIRLINES CHARGE EXCESSIVE
BAGGAGE SURCHARGES THAT START AT
$90 ON TOP OF THE NOW NORMAL
BAGGAGE FEE.
AND THE SCALES AT THE AIRPORT
ARE NOT ALWAYS ACCURATE.
>> IT SAID 50 POUNDS WHEN I
FIRST PUT IT ON.
NOW IT SAYS 47.
>> Reporter: AN ABC NEWS
INVESTIGATION LAST YEAR AT THIS
TIME SHOWED 5% OF AIRPORT SCALES
CHECKED NATIONWIDE WERE OFF IN
ONE DIRECTION OR ANOTHER, BY AT
LEAST HALF AN OUNCE -- ENOUGH TO
ADD COSTS.
ADDING INJURY TO THE ALREADY
INSULTING HIGH HOLIDAY FARES.
JIM AVILA, ABC NEWS, WASHINGTON.
>>> AND NOW, LAST NIGHT, THERE
WAS AN EPIC CONCERT, A PANTHEON
OF ROCK LEGENDS GATHERING TO
RAISE MONEY FOR THOSE HARDEST
HIT BY HURRICANE SANDY.
♪ BABY WE WERE BORN TO RUN
>> 2 BILLION PEOPLE AROUND THE
GLOBE WATCHED THE CAVALCADE.
$30 MILLION RAISED IN TICKET
SALES.
BUT THOSE SUFFERING FROM SANDY
WERE ALSO PROMISED A LOT OF HELP
FROM THE U.S. GOVERNMENT, AND
THAT MONEY IS STALLED, IN
CONGRESS.
SO, ABC'S DAVID KERLEY DECIDED
TO FIND OUT WHY.
>> Reporter: SIX WEEKS AFTER
SANDY IN LONG BEACH, NEW YORK,
JANET PETERS AND HER ELDERLY
MOTHER ARE STILL DEALING WITH
THIS, WONDERING, WHO IS HELPING?
>> NO ONE CAN TELL YOU WHERE
THAT NEW MONEY IS SLATED FOR.
NO ONE SEEMS TO HAVE ANSWERS.
>> Reporter: WITH THE HOSPITAL
STILL DOWN, THE WATER AND SEWER
SYSTEM NOT FIXED, THE CITY
MANAGER WORRIES HIS LOCAL
ECONOMY WILL TANK.
>> JUST CRUCIAL THAT WE GET
THESE FUNDS RIGHT AWAY.
EVERY DAY THAT GOES BY THAT
WE'RE NOT ACTIVELY REPAIRING
THIS CRITICAL INFRASTRUCTURE IS
A SCARY AND A SAD DAY FOR US.
>> Reporter: WHICH IS WHY THREE
GOVERNORS --
>> WE'RE NOT GOING TO ALLOW ANY
POLITICAL FORCES IN WASHINGTON,
D.C. TO DIVIDE AND CONQUER US.
>> Reporter: -- WROTE IN "THE
WASHINGTON POST" THAT CONGRESS
CAN'T LEAVE BEFORE THE HOLIDAYS
WITHOUT APPROVING HELP.
POINTING OUT THAT AID WAS
APPROVED JUST TWO WEEKS AFTER
KATRINA.
IN NEW JERSEY TONIGHT, WITH
72,000 HOMES AND BUSINESSES
DAMAGED OR DESTROYED, THE
GOVERNOR WANTS $5 BILLION TO
REBUILD HOMES.
$8 BILLION TO REBUILD
BUSINESSES.
BUT THE SANDY PACKAGE, TOTALING
$60 BILLION, IS STUCK IN
WASHINGTON.
REPUBLICANS ACCUSING THE
PRESIDENT OF LOADING UP THE BILL
WITH MILLIONS NOT RELATED TO THE
STORM.
>> THIS IS PART OF THIS PROCESS
OF THEY THROWING IN EVERYTHING
BUT THE KITCHEN SINK BECAUSE
THEY KNOW CONGRESS CAN'T TURN
DOWN A REQUEST FOR SANDY.
>> Reporter: EXAMPLES?
$2 MILLION FOR SMITHSONIAN
MUSEUM LEAKING ROOFS IN
WASHINGTON, D.C.
BUT MUSEUM OFFICIALS ADMIT THEY
HAD A LEAK BEFORE THE STORM.
$10 MILLION TO REPAIR PRISONS,
BUT ONE OF THEM IS IN WEST
VIRGINIA, WHICH SANDY BARELY
TOUCHED.
AND $13 BILLION TO PROTECT
AGAINST FUTURE STORMS.
>> WE DON'T WANT TO REBUILD A
TUNNEL SO THAT THE SAME STORM
WATER CAN FLOOD IN.
WE WANT TO BUILD IT BETTER SO
THERE'S MORE PROTECTION.
>> Reporter: WHILE THEY ARGUE,
JANET PETERS WONDERS WHO IS
GOING TO HELP.
DAVID KERLEY, ABC NEWS,
WASHINGTON.
>>> AND FOR ALL OF US WATCHING
TELEVISION TONIGHT, SOMETHING IS
DIFFERENT.
A NEW LAW TOOK EFFECT TODAY,
LOWERING THE VOLUME OF THOSE
LOUDEST COMMERCIALS.
LET'S SHOW YOU.
LET'S SAY A TV PROGRAM IS ABOUT
THE SOUND OF THIS.
IT'S THE REGULAR NOISE IN A
RESTAURANT.
BUT THEN, SUDDENLY, A GARBAGE
DISPOSAL, 20 DECIBELS LOUDER.
WELL, THAT'S ABOUT THE JARRING
SPIKE IN NOISE COMMERCIALS HAVE
BEEN DELIVERING.
SOME OF THEM.
BUT AS OF TONIGHT, THOSE ADS ARE
SUPPOSED TO BE ABOUT THE SAME
LEVEL AS THE SHOW YOU ARE
WATCHING.
SO, CHECK IT OUT.
>>> AND STILL AHEAD ON "WORLD
NEWS," THE POPULAR REALITY SHOW
ACCUSED OF FAKING SOME BIG MONEY
MOMENTS.
>> WHOA!
>> WHY SOME OF TV'S TOP SHOWS
ARE FACING TOUGH QUESTIONS
TONIGHT.
IT'S THE LITTLE THINGS IN LIFE
THAT MAKE ME SMILE.
SPENDING THE DAY
WITH MY NIECE.
I DON'T USE SUPER POLIGRIP
FOR HOLD
BECAUSE MY DENTURES FIT WELL.
BEFORE THOSE LITTLE PIECES
WOULD GET IN BETWEEN
MY DENTURES AND MY GUM
AND IT WAS UNCOMFORTABLE.
EVEN WELL-FITTING DENTURES
LET IN FOOD PARTICLES.
SUPER POLIGRIP IS ZINC FREE.
WITH JUST A FEW DABS,
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO SEAL OUT MORE FOOD PARTICLES
SO YOU'RE MORE COMFORTABLE
AND CONFIDENT WHILE YOU EAT.
SO IT'S NOT ABOUT
KEEPING MY DENTURES IN,
IT'S ABOUT KEEPING
THE FOOD PARTICLES OUT.
[ Charlie ]
TRY ZINC FREE SUPER POLIGRIP.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
WHY LET CONSTIPATION
STRY MIRALAX.?
MIRLAX WORKS
DIFFERENTLY THAN
OTHER LAXATIVES.
IT DRAWS WATER INTO YOUR COLON
TO UNBLOCK YOUR
SYSTEM NATURALLY.
DON'T WAIT TO FEEL GREAT.
MIRALAX.
TO THE BEST VACATION
SP(ALL) THE GULF!
IT DOESN'T MATTER WHICH OF
OUR GREAT STATES FOLKS VISIT.
MISSISSIPPI,
ALABAMA,
LOUISIANA
OR FLORIDA,
THEY'RE GONNA LOVE IT.
SHAUL, YOUR ALABAMA
HOSPITALITY IS INCREDIBLE.
THANKS, KAREN.
LOVE YOUR MISSISSIPPI OUTDOORS.
I VOTE FOR YOUR
FLORIDA BEACHES, DAWN.
BILL, THIS LOUISIANA
SEAFOOD IS DELICIOUS.
WE'RE HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR ON THE GULF,
WE'VE DECIDED TO PUT
ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
NOW IS THE PERFECT TIME TO
VISIT ANYONE OF OUR STATES.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE, GO FISHING
OR JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
WE'VE GOT COASTLINE TO EXPLORE
AND WILDLIFE TO PHOTOGRAPH.
AND THERE'S WORLD CLASS DINING
WITH OUR WORLD FAMOUS SEAFOOD.
SO FOR A GREAT VACATION
THIS YEAR, COME TO THE GULF.
ITS ALL FABULOUS BUT
I GIVE FLORIDA THE EDGE.
RIGHT AFTER MISSISSIPPI.
YOU MEAN ALABAMA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
THIS INVITATION IS
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP
AND ALL OF US WHO
CALL THE GULF HOME.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
IN FACT, IN A RECENT SURVEY,
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
>>> TONIGHT, WE LEARNED THAT THE
4 MILLION PEOPLE WHO WATCH ONE
OF THE MOST POPULAR REALITY
SHOWS ON TELEVISION MIGHT BE
GETTING FOOLED.
THE SHOW IS "STORAGE WARS,"
WHERE PEOPLE BID ON SUPPOSEDLY
SECRET CONTENTS OF ABANDONED
LOCKERS.
BUT NOW, A FORMER STAR SAYS THE
SHOW IS NOT AS IT SEEMS AND WE
WONDERED IF OTHER SHOWS COULD BE
FOOLING EVERYONE, TOO.
ABC'S DAN HARRIS READS THE FINE
PRINT.
>> Reporter: IN "STORAGE WARS,"
PEOPLE BID ON AUCTIONS OF
ABANDONED STORAGE LOCKERS WITH
DREAMS OF FINDING VALUABLE ITEMS
THEY CAN THEN RE-SELL.
BUT NOW, A STAR STORAGE WARRIOR,
DAVID HESTER, KNOWN ON THE SHOW
AS "THE MOGUL" HAS FILED A
LAWSUIT ALLEGING A&E, WHICH AIRS
THE SHOW, "HAS COMMITTED A FRAUD
ON THE PUBLIC."
HESTER SAYS THE PRODUCERS
"REGULARLY SALT OR PLANT THE
STORAGE LOCKERS WITH VALUABLE OR
UNUSUAL ITEMS TO CREATE DRAMA
AND SUSPENSE."
HE POINTS TO SPECIFIC EXAMPLES
SUCH AS THIS CAR, FOUND UNDER A
PILE OF TRASH.
>> WHOA!
>> IT'S A BMW.
>> Reporter: A&E, WHICH IS
HALF-OWNED BY DISNEY, THE PARENT
COMPANY OF ABC, TOLD US TODAY
THEY WILL NOT COMMENT ON PENDING
LAWSUITS.
BUT ONE OF THE SHOW'S PRODUCERS
DID SAY THIS RECENTLY.
>> I CAN HONESTLY TELL YOU THAT
THE STUFF FOUND IN THOSE
CONTAINERS ARE FOUND IN STORAGE
CONTAINERS.
>> Reporter: ALTHOUGH HE DID
ADMIT THEY SOMETIME MOVE ITEMS
FROM ONE STORAGE LOCKER TO
ANOTHER.
THIS IS NOT THE FIRST TIME THE
LEVEL OF REALITY IN REALITY TV
HAS BEEN QUESTIONED.
RECENTLY, A FORMER PARTICIPANT
ON HGTV'S "HOUSE HUNTERS," WHICH
FOLLOWS FAMILIES CHOOSING A NEW
HOME, SAID PRODUCERS KNEW SHE
AND HER HUSBAND HAD ALREADY
PURCHASED THEIR NEW HOME BEFORE
THEY TAPED THE SHOW IN 2006.
>> IT FELT LIKE WE JUST HAD A
FEW DAYS TO SCROUNGE UP SOME
HOUSES TO LOOK AT, AND IT WAS
OUR RESPONSIBILITY TO FIND THE
HOUSES.
>> Reporter: IN A STATEMENT,
HGTV SAID, "WE AREN'T SHOWING A
DOCUMENTARY, WE'RE SIMPLY
ENTERTAINING OUR VIEWERS."
BACK IN THE 1950s, CONTESTANTS
ON SOME POPULAR QUIZ SHOWS WERE
SECRETLY GIVEN THE ANSWERS.
CONGRESS HELD HEARINGS AND MADE
MADE DOING THAT ILLEGAL.
NO ONE ALLEGES THAT LEVEL OF
FIXING ON THE TODAY'S REALITY
SHOWS AND EXPERTS WE SPOKE TO
DON'T THINK THE PRODUCERS OF
"STORAGE WARS" ARE IN CRIMINAL
TROUBLE.
>> I DON'T SEE THIS AS A CONTEST
WITH A PRIZE.
>> Reporter: BUT THERE IS STILL
THE COURT OF PUBLIC OPINION.
IF ENOUGH PEOPLE BELIEVE THE
MOGUL IS TELLING THE TRUTH, THE
AUDIENCE COULD HUNT ELSEWHERE
FOR ITS VICARIOUS THRILLS.
DAN HARRIS, ABC NEWS, NEW YORK.
>>> AND, COMING UP HERE, A VISIT
TO SANTA'S LAP THAT IS ROCKETING
AROUND THE WORLD.
WE HAVE THE STORY BEHIND THIS
PICTURE.
IT'S OUR "INSTANT INDEX," NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] CAMPBELL'S
GREEN BEAN CASSEROLE.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO
get Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
And the only one I use
to relieve my cold symptoms
without raising my blood
pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
of Washington about the future
of Medicare and Social Security.
ANNCR: But you deserve straight
talk about the options on the...
table and what they mean for you
and your family.
ANCR: AARP is cutting through
all the political spin.
Because for our 37 million
members, only one word counts.
Get the facts at earnedasay.org.
Let's keep Medicare...
and Social Security strong for
generations to come.
>>> AND OUR "INSTANT INDEX"
TONIGHT STARTS WITH SOMETHING
FOR EVERYONE DREAMING OF A WHITE
CHRISTMAS.
TAKE A LOOK AT THE MAP.
THE NATION'S TOP SCIENTISTS
LOOKED AT 20 YEARS OF DATA AND
ESTIMATE THE STATE BY STATE
CHANCE OF A WHITE CHRISTMAS.
AND IF YOU LIVE IN ANY OF THE
AREAS THAT ARE SNOW WHITE ON THE
MAP, YOU HAVE A GOOD CHANCE OF
AT LEAST ONE INCH OF SNOW ON
DECEMBER 25th.
FOR INSTANCE, AUGUSTA, MAINE, UP
THERE IN THE RIGHT HAND CORNER,
HAS A 90% CHANCE OF A CHRISTMAS
SNOW.
THOSE OF US WHO LIVE IN THE
SOUTH SHOULD START LOWERING
EXPECTATIONS.
>>> AND, THIS PICTURE IS A KIND
OF CHRISTMAS POSTCARD ROCKETING
THROUGH OUR INBOXES TODAY.
DID YOU SEE IT?
IT'S A FULLY HUMAN VARIATION ON
THOSE OLD DEPARTMENT STORE
PORTRAITS OF SANTA.
A BABY FELL ASLEEP WAITING FOR
HIS TURN FOR SANTA'S LAP AT A
MALL IN BOISE, IDAHO.
SO, SANTA IMPROVISED, PRETENDING
TO NOD OFF, TOO.
THE CROWD ERUPTED IN CHEERS AND
A NEW CHRISTMAS CLASSIC WAS
BORN.
>>> AND, OUR PERSON IN THE NEWS
IS SOMEONE WHO HAS INFLUENCED
YOUR LIFE.
CAN YOU GUESS WHAT NORMAN
WOODLAND DID FOR YOU?
WELL, HE WAS THE ENGINEER WHO
INVENTED THE BAR CODE.
HE DID IT WHEN HE HEARD A GROCER
COMPLAIN THAT THE CHECKOUT LINE
SHOULD BE AUTOMATED.
THEY'LL BE FASTER.
SO, HE TURNED THE MORSE CODE HE
LEARNED AS A BOY SCOUT INTO
SOMETHING NEW.
AND INVENTED THE PATTERNS THAT
IDENTIFY PRODUCTS.
5 BILLION BAR CODES ARE SCANNED
BY COMPUTER EVERY DAY.
WOODLAND DIED OF ALZHEIMER'S AT
THE AGE OF 91.
>>> AND, DON'T FORGET, WE WANT
TO KNOW WHAT YOU THINK, SO,
TWEET ME YOUR THOUGHTS FOR
"INSTANT INDEX," @DIANESAWYER,
EVERY DAY.
>>> AND A PROGRAM NOTE.
WE TOLD YOU IN A PREVIOUS INDEX
THAT THE TWO STARS OF "GREASE"
WERE GETTING TOGETHER AGAIN?
WELL, GET READY.
♪ YOU'RE THE ONE THAT I WANT
>> WHO CAN FORGET THAT DANCE?
WELL, TOMORROW NIGHT, TRAVOLTA,
NEWTON JOHN, SHOWING US HOW THEY
DID IT.
JOHN THAT VOLUME THAT, OLIVIA
NEWTON JOHN SINGING FOR THE
HOLIDAYS, AND THEY'LL BE OUR
"PERSON OF THE WEEK" TOMORROW
NIGHT.
>>> AND, SPEAKING OF SOMEONE
WITH MOVES, DID YOU SEE HIM LAST
NIGHT?
69-YEAR-OLD MICK JAGGER, THE
ENERGY OF A TEENAGER?
WE ASK HIM THE SECRET, NEXT.
LET'S GIVE THANKS -
FOR AN IDEA.
A GRAND IDEA CALLED AMERICA.
THE IDEA THAT
IF YOU WORK HARD,
IF YOU HAVE A DREAM,
IF YOU WORK WITH
YOUR NEIGHBORS...
YOU CAN DO MOST ANYTHING.
THIS LED TO OTHER IDEAS
LIKE LIBERTY
AND ROCK 'N' ROLL.
TO FREE MARKETS,
FREE ENTERPRISE,
AND FREE REFILLS.
IT PUT A MAN ON THE MOON
AND A PHONE IN YOUR POCKET.
OUR COUNTRY'S GONE THROUGH A LOT
OVER THE CENTURIES AND A HALF.
BUT THIS IDEA ISN'T FRAGILE.
WHEN TIMES GET TOUGH,
IT RALLIES US AS ONE.
EVERY DAY, MORE PEOPLE
BELIEVE IN THE AMERICAN IDEA
AND WHEN THEY DO,
THE DREAM COMES TRUE.
WE'RE GRATEFUL
TO BE A PART OF IT.
AND YOU SEE THE WOMAN
YOU FELL IN LOVE WITH.
SHE'S EVERYTHING TO YOU.
BUT YOUR ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION -
THAT COULD BE A QUESTION
OF BLOOD FLOW.
CIALIS TADALAFIL
FOR DAILY USE
HELPS YOU BE READY
ANYTIME THE
MOMENT'S RIGHT.
YOU CAN BE
MORE CONFIDENT
IN YOUR ABILITY
TO BE READY.
AND THE SAME CIALIS IS THE
ONLY DAILY ED TABLET APPROVED
TO TREAT ED AND
SYMPTOMS OF BPH,
LIKE NEEDING TO GO
FREQUENTLY OR URGENTLY.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT
ALL YOUR MEDICAL CONDITIONS
AND MEDICATIONS,
AND ASK IF YOUR HEART IS HEALTHY
ENOUGH FOR SEXUAL ACTIVITY.
DO NOT TAKE CIALIS IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN,
AS THIS MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE
DROP IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
DO NOT DRINK ALCOHOL
IN EXCESS WITH CIALIS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, UPSET STOMACH,
DELAYED BACKACHE OR MUSCLE ACHE.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION LASTING
MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
IF YOU HAVE ANY SUDDEN DECREASE
OR LOSS IN HEARING OR VISION,
OR IF YOU HAVE ANY ALLERGIC
REACTIONS SUCH AS RASH,
HIVES, SWELLING OF THE LIPS,
TONGUE OR THROAT,
OR DIFFICULTY BREATHING
OR SWALLOWING,
STOP TAKING CIALIS AND
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY.
ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CIALIS
FOR DAILY USE
AND A 30-TABLET FREE TRIAL.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
♪ ALL RIGHT
♪ JUMP JACK FLASH
♪ IS A GAS, GAS, GAS
>>> AND FINALLY, FROM HERE, WE
MENTIONED EARLIER, THERE WAS
THAT BIG CONCERT FOR HURRICANE
SANDY VICTIMS LAST NIGHT.
BUT THE TALK ALL DAY WAS ABOUT
MICK JAGGER, ALMOST 70, WITH THE
ENERGY OF A 30-YEAR-OLD.
SO, WE WANTED TO KNOW HIS
SECRET, AND ABC'S BILL WEIR
SPOKE WITH THE ROLLING STONE.
♪
>> Reporter: YOU'VE HEARD OF DOG
YEARS?
WELL, THIS IS WHAT AGE 69 LOOKS
LIKE IN STONES YEARS.
♪ JUMPING JACK FLASH
♪ IS A GAS, GAS, GAS
>> Reporter: AND BEFORE YOU
DISMISS MICK JAGGER'S ENERGY AT
LAST NIGHT'S SANDY BENEFIT AS A
TWO-SONG FLUKE --
♪ HEY, YOU
>> Reporter: KNOW THAT IN RECENT
WEEKS HE HAS BEEN RIPPING UP THE
STAGE LIKE THIS FOR TWO AND A
HALF HOURS A NIGHT.
HOW DO YOU DO IT?
I WAS SORE THE NEXT DAY FROM
WATCHING.
HOW DO YOU DO IT?
>> IT'S WHAT I DO, REALLY.
♪ TAKE A DRIVE DOWNTOWN
>> Reporter: PEOPLE ARE WILLING
TO PAY, YOU KNOW, $500, $600 FOR
A SEAT, JUST THINK WHAT THEY
WOULD PAY FOR MICK JAGGER
ELIXIR, YOUR FITNESS REGIMEN.
>> I DON'T REALLY HAVE MUCH OF A
FITNESS REGIMEN, TO BE HONEST.
I MEAN, I DO HAVE ONE --
>> Reporter: YES, A BAND WITH AN
AVERAGE AGE OLDER THAN THE
SUPREME COURT REHEARSED EIGHT
GRUELING WEEKS TO PLAY JUST FIVE
SHOWS, A WORK ETHIC THAT SOMEHOW
SURVIVED ALL THOSE YEARS AND
MILES, WOMEN AND DRUGS.
KEITH RICHARDS STILL ENJOYS A
DRINK OR THREE, BUT RONNIE WOOD
HAS BEEN SOBER FOR YEARS NOW AND
ADMITS THIS TOUR IS A REAL TEST
OF WILLPOWER.
>> WE HIT THEM WITH CLARITY AND
FOCUS NOW.
BEFORE, IT WAS EYES DOWN AND
MEET YOU AT THE END, YOU KNOW?
AND LIKE, "OH, NO.
HOW AM I GOING TO GET OUT OF
THIS?"
A LITTLE BIT OF THAT STILL GOES
ON.
>> Reporter: SO, DESPITE THE
STRUGGLES FOR SOBRIETY AND BAND
HARMONY, THEY'VE DISCOVERED
THEIR REAL SECRET IS SIMPLY
DOING WHAT THEY LOVE.
RETIREMENT WOULD BE A DEATH
SENTENCE.
AND THERE'S NO BETTER FOUNTAIN
OF YOUTH THAN AN ARENA FULL OF
ADORATION.
>> PEOPLE SAY, "WELL, WHY ARE
YOU STILL TOGETHER?"
AND I SAY, "WELL, IT -- BECAUSE
PEOPLE LIKE US."
OF COURSE, WE LOVE PLAYING.
BUT YOU HAVE TO HAVE BOTH OF THE
PART OF THE EQUATION.
>> Reporter: SO, FOR THOSE
INCLINED TO ORDER SATURDAY'S PAY
PER VIEW FINALE WITH BRUCE
SPRIN
SPRINGSTEEN AND LADY GAGA,
THINKING THIS COULD BE THE LAST
TIME, KEEP IN MIND THE TOUR IS
CALLED "50 AND COUNTING."
BILL WEIR, ABC NEWS, NEW YORK.
>> AND YOU CAN SEE MORE OF BILL
WEIR, TALKING TO MICK JAGGER
TONIGHT ON "NIGHTLINE."
AND THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
AND NOW, WE'RE GOING TO LEAVE
YOU WITH A TRUE WONDERLAND IN
MOTION, IN KANSAS CITY,
MISSOURI, WHERE I LOVE ARTHUR
BRAND'S BARBECUE, BY THE WAY.
AND THANKS TO OUR AFFILIATE KMBC
TV, BRINGING US THE PLAZA LIGHTS
GLOWING DOWNTOWN.
BEAUTIFUL SIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT TO EVERYBODY IN
KANSAS CITY.
GOOD NIGHT.
>> A WAREHOUSE FIRE THAT FORCED
NEIGHBORS TO EVACUATE.
>> A DEVELOPMENTAL DISABLED --
THE CONCERNS OF WORRIED
FAMILIES.
>> A STORY YOU'LL SEE ONLY ON
ABC 7 NEWS.
A FAMILY REACHES A SETTLEMENT
OVER A TRAGEDY IN THEIR BAY AREA
HOME.
>> SCANDAL, REHAB AND
RECONCILIATION FOR TROUBLED EX
LOVERS SERVING TEXTS
>>> FROM SKY 7HD, YOU CAN SEE
THE EXTENT OF THE DAMAGE FROM A
FIRE THAT ATE ITS WAY THROUGH.
NEARBY WORKERS HAD TO BE
EVACUATED, BUT THE GOOD NEWS, AT
LEAST, NO ONE WAS HURT.
GOOD EVENING.
I'M DAN ASHLEY.
>> I'M CAROLYN JOHNSON THAT.
FIRE BEGAN AROUND 1:30 WITH
THICK DARK SMOKE CHOKING THE
AREA, NOT FAR FROM INTERSTATE
680 IN FREMONT.
NOW MORE FROM THE SCENE WHERE
FIREFIGHTERS ARE STILL MOPPING
UP TONIGHT.
>> Reporter: NOBODY IS GOING
HOME TONIGHT.
FIREFIGHTERS ARE STILL CLEANING
UP.
I HAVE TO SAY, IT WAS A
DIFFICULT FIRE BECAUSE THERE WAS
SO MUCH HEAVY SMOKE AND A LOT OF
FLAMES AND THEY COULDN'T GET
INSIDE THAT BUILDING.
SO THEY HAD TO ATTACK IT OR HIT
IT FROM ABOVE.
NOW, THE ROOF EVENTUALLY
COLLAPSED.
FORTUNATELY THE 60 OR SO
EMPLOYEES INSIDE THAT BUILDING
HAD ALREADY BEEN EVACUATED.
I TELL YOU, THERE WAS A LOT OF
FLAMMABLE STUFF INSIDE.
>> YOU COULD SEE THAT THERE IS A
PLAQUE CARD ON THE CORNER OF THE
BUILDING IDENTIFYING THERE ARE
HAZARDOUS MATERIALS INSIDE.
SO IT JUST MADE IT THAT MUCH
MORE TOXIC.
>> Reporter: AND IT'S THERE TO
LET THEM KNOW THERE ARE
IMUSSIBLE AND FLAMMABLE -- COME
BUZZIBLE AND FLAMMABLE MATERIALS
INSIDE.
YOU ARE SEE THE INSIDE OF THE
BUILDING COMPLETELY OPEN BECAUSE