TONIGHT?
ABOUT SAM AND NAOMI.
THERE'S NOTHING TO DO.
ARE--ARE YOU WITH PETE?
CONFERENCE CALL.
REMEMBER THE GOOD OLD DAYS--
SAM AND NAOMI TOGETHER,
THE PRACTICE
RUNNING IN HARMONY?
YOU--YOU DIDN'T
WORK HERE THEN.
THAT'S NOT THE POINT.
THE POINT IS WE MUST RETURN
TO THE WAY IT WAS.
DAYS OF YESTERYEAR? BAD IDEA.
NO, NO, ACTUALLY,
IT'S A--IT'S A GREAT IDEA.
Hold on.
I'm gonna get Coop.
NO, DON'T GET COOP.
(telephone rings)
HOW COME I DIDN'T KNOW
ANY NAUGHTY SCHOOLGIRLS
IN HIGH SCHOOL?
I DID.
PETE, ARE YOU AT VIOLET'S?
NO. TECHNOLOGY.
CONFERENCE CALL.
WE'RE DOING
AN INTERVENTION.
ENDING THE WAR--SAM AND NAOMI,
PEACE AT THE OFFICE.
OH, I'M IN.
VOLVED,
PEOPLE.
WE ARE GONNA PUT THEM
IN A ROOM
AND CREATE A SUPPORTIVE,
NONTHREATENING ENVIRONMENT.
I NEED SOMEONE
TO LICK MY LOLLIPOP.
I GOTTA GO.
D-DON'T HANG UP.
(doorbell ringing)
ARE--ARE WE AGREED?
YEP, TOMORROW,
FIRST THING--
OPERATION "GET NAOMI AND SAM
BACK TOGETHER."
I GOTTA GO.
UH, KEVIN'S HERE.
IF YOU HANG UP,
DOES THAT MEAN--
(dial tone drones)
HEY.
CHINESE TAKEOUT,
BOTTLE OF WINE,
FANCY SUBTITLED MOVIE,
HOT ACTION MOVIE--
WHICHEVER YOU NEED
TO BE HAPPY.
THIS IS EXACTLY
WHAT I NEED.
♪
HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT RULES?
YOU THINK WE SHOULD SET RULES
FOR NAOMI AND SAM?
NO, NO.
RULES ABOUT DATING.
SEX RULES?
MM-HMM, YES, THAT'S RIGHT.
IS THIS YOU
TRYING TO BOND WITH ME?
NO, I'M SEEKING
YOUR PROFESSIONAL OPINION.
I'M THINKING ABOUT SETTING
SOME RULES FOR MYSELF.
IS THIS ABOUT
THE S.W.A.T. GUY?
MM-HMM.
YOU TWO HAVEN'T...
NOPE.
WOW. YOU'RE ONE OF
THOSE WOMEN.
I'M NOT ONE OF THOSE WOMEN.
I'M CAUTIOUS.
I'M TRYING TO BE CAUTIOUS.
SO YOU DON'T LIKE HIM?
I DO LIKE HIM. I JUST...
ONCE YOU SLEEP WITH SOMEONE--
I DON'T KNOW, IN THE PAST,
I-I MESSED UP.
I JUST DON'T WANT TO
DO THAT AGAIN, SO I THOUGHT
IF I MADE SOME RULES--
BUT YOU WANT
TO SLEEP WITH HIM?
YES, BUT MY RULES, I--
WHAT RULES?
YOU NEED TO SEE
A THERAPIST.
THERAPISTS ARE OVERRATED.
UH...
OKAY, JUST SAW 'EM IN THE LOBBY.
THEY'RE ON THE WAY UP.
TOGETHER? THAT'S A GOOD SIGN.
YEAH, BUT THEY'RE
NOT TALKING AT ALL.
WELL, THAT'S A BAD SIGN.
HEY, YOU'RE BACK.
I AM, I AM, FULL-TIME
AS OF TODAY. OKAY, OKAY.
SEE? BACK TO THE WAY
IT WAS.
(elevator bell dings)
ALL RIGHT, BE STRONG,
BE FIRM
AND DON'T TAKE NO
FOR AN ANSWER.
I THOUGHT WE SAID
NO MORE SECRET MEETINGS.
IT'S NOT SECRET.
WHOSE CUPCAKES?
WHAT IS THIS?
IT'S AN INTERVENTION.
SOMEBODY HAVE A PROBLEM
THAT I'M NOT AWARE OF?
OH, NO, NO, NO. IT'S FOR YOU,
FOR BOTH OF YOU.
TO GET YOU TWO BACK...
TO THE WAY IT USED TO BE--
OUR LEADERS, TOGETHER.
NO.
NO, THAT'S--
THAT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
SORRY.
OKAY, I WAS BEING POLITE.
THAT IS EXACTLY
WHAT IS GOING TO HAPPEN.
WE CANCELED
YOUR MORNING PATIENTS.
YOU TWO ARE GONNA SIT
IN THIS ROOM,
YOU'RE GONNA EAT THE CUPCAKES,
AND YOU'RE GONNA REMEMBER
WHY IT IS THAT YOU STARTED
THIS PRACTICE
IN THE FIRST PLACE TOGETHER.
AND THEN YOU ARE GOING TO AGREE
ON A WAY TO MOVE FORWARD,
WITH THIS PRACTICE,
TOGETHER AS A FAMILY.
DON'T COME OUT
UNTIL YOU'RE DONE.
(woman) BRADEN DOESN'T SPEAK,
DOESN'T UNDERSTAND WHEN I DO.
WE'VE BEEN TO FIVE DOCTORS.
MY FRIEND BETH SAID YOU WERE
AMAZING WITH HER DAUGHTER.
CHECK THIS OUT.
LOOK AT THAT.
IT'S GOT A LADDER.
IT'S GOT A LITTLE GUY IN THERE.
HMM?
PLEASE DON'T JUST TELL ME
HE'S AUTISTIC.
BRADEN MIGHT BE PROCESSING
MORE THAN YOU THINK,
AND IF HE IS--
AUGMENTATIVE
COMMUNICATION THERAPY,
SENSORY INTEGRATION PROGRAMS--
THEY HAVEN'T WORKED FOR HIM.
SO HE STARTED SPEAKING
AND... HE JUST STOPPED AT 4?
SO NOW YE ENVIRONMENTAL,
IT COULD BE GENETIC,
IT COULD BE ANYTHING.
SOMETIMES KIDS
JUST BECOME AUTISTIC.
UNFORTUNATELY, IT'S ONE OF
THOSE DISORDERS
THAT JUST ISN'T
THAT WELL UNDERSTOOD.
YOU KNOW, YOU LOOK FAMILIAR.
DO WE KNOW EACH OTHER
FROM SOMEWHERE?
DO WE?
I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE I JUST WANT TO KNOW YOU.
SO YOU'LL DO SOMETHING
FOR BRADEN.
I'LL TAKE A LOOK,
I'LL SEE WHAT WE CAN FIND,
AND I WILL DO WHAT I CAN.
I PROMISE.
OKAY.
HEY, BRADEN.
CAN YOU FOLLOW
THE LIGHT FOR ME?
CAN YOU LOOK UP?
WHOA.
HERE. THERE YOU GO.
IT'S WORKING, NAYSAYER.
IT IS WHAT IT IS.
WHAT DOES THAT
EVEN MEAN?
YOU THINK WE'RE BACK?
I THINK WE MIGHT BE BACK.
HEY, WELL, WE AGREE.
YOU SEE?
WE'RE ALL GONNA VOTE...
MY WAY OR NAOMI'S.
WHAT? NO.
YOU CHOOSE WHICH ONE OF US
RUNS THE PRACTICE.
AND WE'LL ABIDE BY
THE DECISION.
THIS IS A BAD IDEA.
THIS IS GONNA TEAR US APART.
I WARNED YOU.
LOOK, YOU WE
WE CAN'T KEEP ON THE WAY
THINGS HAVE BEEN GOING.
SO WE WILL CAMPAIGN FAIRLY.
RIGHT, NO DIRTY TRICKS,
NO BRIBERY.
CIVIL, DEMOCRATIC--THE WAY
THE PRACTICE SHOULD BE RUN.
ARE YOU SUGGESTING THAT
I WANT ANYTHING ELSE?
DO I GET A VOTE? I MEAN,
I AM PART OF THE PRACTICE.
THAT WAS THE DEAL, RIGHT?
YEAH, OF COURSE YOU ARE.
RIGHT. I-I WOULDN'T HAVE IT
ANY OTHER WAY.
SO, UH, TOMORROW
AT THE CLOSE OF BUSINESS.
RIGHT.
WE VOTE... TOMORROW.
ALL RIGHT?
(chuckles)
SO SEEING AS YOU'RE
GONNA NEED VOTES,
I WANT TO START SHADOWING.
I DON'T HAVE YOUR VOTE?
AFTER I BULLIED SAM
INTO TAKING YOU BACK?
YOU WERE THE REASON
THAT I LEFT.
YOU'RE DOING A GAMETE
MICROMANIPULATION ON FRIDAY.
I WANT TO ASSIST.
OH, UH, THE COLES.
UM, THAT'S--THAT'S DIFFICULT.
IT IS WHAT YOU PROMISED.
I NEED TO GET THE HOURS FOR
MY MIDWIFE CERTIFICATION.
I KNOW.
IT'S JUST THAT THE COLES, UH,
CAN BE A LITTLE BIT JUMPY.
INK ABOUT IT, OKAY?
YOU THINK ABOUT IT.
VOTE'S TOMORROW.
SHARB--
SHARBAT QALZAI?
I AM SHARBAT'S FATHER,
IDREES QALZAI.
HELLO. HOW DO YOU DO?
I'M DR. MONTGOMERY.
SHARBAT IDENTIFIED YOU
AS THE TOP DOCTOR
THERE IS FOR LADIES.
I WOULD LIKE FOR YOU
TO GIVE HER THE EXAM
YOU GIVE
YOUR VERY BEST PATIENTS.
ALL OF MY PATIENTS
GET THE VERY BEST,
AND SHARBAT WILL BE
NO EXCEPTION.
SO WHY DON'T, UH,
WHY DON'T YOU COME BACK?
(whispers)
STAY RIGHT HERE.
OH, HEY. I'M NOT GONNA--
I'M NOT GONNA KNOW ANYTHING
TILL I GET HIS LABS BACK.
I RELE?
OW YOU FROM.
NICOLE?
YOU'RE THE ONE IN THE PICTURES,
NAKED, ON THAT WEB SITE.
WHAT?
THE DATING SITE
FOR ADULTS.
YOU SAW THAT?
YOU ARE A DOCTOR,
A PEDIATRICIAN--
PLEASE, NICOLE--
HOW CAN YOU WORK
WITH CHILDREN?
OKAY, THAT SITE
HAS NOTHING TO...
MY PERSONAL LIFE DOES NOT IMPACT
THE CARE I GIVE MY PATIENTS.
HOW CAN IT NOT?
YOU SHOULD NOT BE A DOCTOR.
SO YOU'VE BEEN HAVING
SOME DISCOMFORT?
SORT OF.
WHERE EXACTLY ARE YOU
FEELING PAIN?
I KNOW DISCUSSING THESE THINGS
CAN BE UNCOMFORTABLE.
BUT LET'S SEE IF I CAN HELP?
MY DAUGHTER WAS ATTACKED
BY A MAN.
OH.
WHEN DID THIS HAPPEN?
A FEW MONTHS AGO.
AND, UH, IS THIS SOMETHING
THAT YOU REPORTED?
NO.
THAT'S NOT WHAT I WANT.
IT IS NOT SOMETHING WE DO.
BUT IF...
IF YOU WERE RAPED,
SHARBAT, YOU REALLY SHOULD
SPEAK TO SOMEONE.
WE HAVE A PSYCHIATRIST HERE--
THAT'S NOT WHY I CAME HERE.
OKAY.
ARE--ARE YOU STILL FEELING
PAIN FROM THE ATTACK?
THERE IS NO PAIN.
WELL--
NO, PLEASE.
I NEED YOU...
TO MAKE ME
A VIRGIN AGAIN.
BUT ALL YOU NOTICE IS HER
BEAUTIFUL, HEALTHY SKIN.
ULTRA HEALING
JERGENS ULTRA HEALING
MOISTURIZER
MAKES EVEN YOUR DRIEST SKIN
LOOK HEALTHIER, INSTANTLY.
WITH BEAUTIFUL SKIN
FROM JERGENS,
YOU'LL ALWAYS MAKE AN ENTRANCE.
JERGENS®.
THE BEAUTIFUL DIFFERENCE.
I made the clear choice.
I'm getting Claritin Clear
with Claritin-D.
Nasal congestion keep me away ?
.
the clear choice.
Non-drowsy Claritin-D.
Decongestant products on
the shelf can take hours
to start working.
Claritin-D starts to work
in just 30 minutes.
I can't wait hours for
a nasal decongestant.
That's why I made the clear
choice and got Claritin-D.
It has the best
decongestant for colds.
This cold season, get Claritin-D
at the pharmacy counter.
Live Claritin Clear.
WE WABOUT SOMETHING NO ONE
ASKIWANTS TO TALK ABOUT.ANKLY
IT'S TIME TO GET REAL ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE BATHROOM.
STOP ALL THE CUTESY STUFF
OUT
AND START TALKING ABOUT
WHAT YOU REALLY WANT
FROM YOUR TOILET PAPER.
IT'S TIME TO TALK ABOUT CLEAN.
FEELING CLEAN IS SO IMPORTANT.
QUILTED NORTHERN SOFT AND STRONG
IS STRONGER THAN THE
LEADING VALUE BRAND,
TO HELP PROTECT
AGAINST BREAKTHROUGH.
FOR MYSELF, FOR MY FAMILY,
IT KEEPS US CLEAN.
I USE QUILTED NORTHERN.
QUILTED NORTHERN
SOFT AND STRONG,
PROTECTION FOR A CONFIDENT
CLEAN OR YOUR MO
YOU'VE BEEN THERE.
YOU PICK OUT A MAKEUP
THINKING IT'S YOUR SHADE...
UNTIL YOU ACTUALLY
TRY IT OUT.
NOW, I HAVE A MAKEUP
THAT ALWAYS GETS IT RIGHT.
SMART SHADE MAKEUP
INSTANTLY ADJUSTS
TO MATCH PERFECTLY
TO YOUR SKIN.
ALMAY SMART SHADE MAKEUP.
ONLY FROM ALMAY.
ONLY FOR ME.
I HAVE A COLD,
AND I TOOK NYQUIL,
BUT I'M STILL "STUBBED" UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
IT DOESN'T HAVE A DECONGESTANT.
NO WAY.
[ Male Announcer ] SORRY.
Alka-Seltzer Plus FIGHTS
YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A FAST ACTING
DECONGESTANT
TO RELIEVE YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
[ sighs ] THANKS!
[ Male Announcer ]
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus.
IS! ♪ THE COLD TRUTH!
[ Male Announcer ]
WHAT A RELIEF IT IS! ♪.
[ Male Announcer ] TO LEARN
MORE ABOUT THE COLD TRUTH
AND SAVE $1
VISIT Alka-Seltzer ON FACEBOOK.
YOU CAN MAKE HER VIRGIN AGAIN.
I-I KNOW IT'S POSSIBLE.
IN OUR CULTURE,
SOMETIMES IT IS DONE.
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
HYMENOPLASTY?
THAT'S NOT SOMETHING
TO BE DONE LIGHTLY.
IT IS A REAL SURGERY WITH
REAL POTENTIAL COMPLICATIONS,
IT DOESN'T MAKE YOU
A VIRGIN.
I AM ENGAGED TO A MAN
IN AFGHANISTAN.
HE WILL TAKE ME AND MY PARENTS
BACK TO OUR COUNTRY,
WHERE WE WILL BE MARRIED,
WHERE HE WILL TAKE CARE OF US.
AND HE DOESN'T KNOW ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
I HAVE NOT MET HIM YET.
HE CAN'T KNOW.
HER STATUS, IT...
IT IS CHECKED.
AND ISLAMIC LAW SAYS SEX
BEFORE MARRIAGE IS NOT ALLOWED.
WE WOULD BE DISGRACED.
I UNDERSTAND.
IS NOT YOUR FAULT?
I NEED TO BE PURE.
CAN YOU HELP ME?
COOP, DO YOU THINK
MAYBE WE SHOULD--
SORRY, MAN.
UH, A LITTLE LATER.IS AFT.
JUST NEED A COUPLE MINUTES,
BIG GUY. THANKS.
HIS VOTE IS SPOKEN FOR.
IT'S FOR NAOMI.
WAIT, NOTHING'S DECIDED
UNTIL ELECTION DAY, VIOLET.
THIS IS A CAMPAIGN
AB-ABOUT IDEAS. YOU HEAR ME? I--
LOST CAUSE.
NO. NOBODY'S A LOST CAUSE,
EXCEPT FOR MAYBE DELL.
DELL IS A RED STATE.
I'M NOT GETTIN' INVOLVED.
I DID GIVE HIM HIS JOB BACK,
BUT HE AND NAI...
IT'S GONNA BE HARD
TO GET OVER WHAT THEY HAD.
I'M NOT GETTING INVOLVED.
YOU KNOW,
HE QUIT BECAUSE OF HER.
SHOULD I REMIND HIM OF THAT?
I THOUGHT YOU SAID
IT WAS GONNA BE CIVIL.
SO CIVILLY, I'LL REMIND HIM
OF HOW BAD IT WAS.
BAD TIMING, COOP.
IGWIGS IN,
T A COUPLE
OF BIGWIGS IN,
AND IF I GET ONE MORE COMPLAINT
ABOUT HOW MANY SURGERIES
I SHOULD BE--
I AM NOT IN THE MOOD.
MY DAY'S WORSE. I DON'T FEEL
LIKE HAVING SEX EVER AGAIN.
THEN WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
I CAME TO TALK.
YOU WANTED TO TALK.
YOU'RE NOT TALKING.
DO YOU THINK I'M A PERVERT?
I AM TOO BUSY FOR THIS.
HEY, DOES THIS
NOT BOTHER YOU?
WE'RE BOTH IN THE MIDDLE
OF TOUGH DAYS,
WE CAN'T EVEN DISCUSS IT
WITH ONE ANOTHER?
I DON'T WANT
TO DISCUSS IT, COOPER.
I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO GET THROUGHNED?
A PATIENT'S MOTHER
RECOGNIZED ME
FROM AN ADULT WEB SITE.
SHE DOES NOT WANT ME
TO TREAT HER SON.
THAT'S ABSURD.
YOU DON'T WORRY ABOUT THAT,
A PATIENT RECOGNIZING YOU
FROM YOUR PRIVATE LIFE?
ONE HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH THE OTHER.
BESIDES, I TOOK MINE DOWN.
YOU DIDN'T?
HOW MANY SITES
ARE YOU ON, COOP?
TWO? FIVE?
TEN?
ISH.
YOUR PATIENT MIGHT BE RIGHT.
THERE IS
SOMETHING WRONG WITH YOU.
I'M A GOOD DOCTOR.
I WANT TO HELP THIS KID.
SHE WANTS
TO BE REVIRGINIZED?
ESSENTIALLY, YES.
BUT I JUST CAN'T SEE
SEWING HER BACK UP.
IT JUST FEELS WRONG.
OKAY, S-SO WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE GOING TO DEPRIVE THIS
GIRL OF THE LIFE THAT SHE WANTS
BECAUSE YOU HAVE ISSUES
WITH IT?
I--
SHE'S A VICTIM,
AND YOU'RE NOT GONNA HELP HER?
I JUST FEEL LIKE I AM COLLUDING
WITH THE WHOLE SYSTEM.
WELL, YOU ARE.
YOU HAVE TO TELL HER NO.
ON WHAT GROUNDS?
LEGAL, MORAL, HUMANITARIAN.
WHAT'D YOU GET
IN MEDICAL ETHICS?
THE TEST IS BENEFICENCE
AND AUTONOMY.
WHAT IS BENEFICENT ABOUT
HELPING A YOUNG GIRL
INDULGE A CHAUVINIST FANTASY
BY SEWING UP HER VAGINA?
YEAH, BUT THE QUESTION IS NOT
WHETHER THE DOCTOR
THINKS IT'S RIGHT, IS IT?
IT'S WHETHER THE PATIENT DOES.
SOMEONE.
REALLY
TALK TO SOMEONE.
IF YOU WANT TO BRING HER IN...
I ALREADY ASKED.
SHE'S NOT INTERESTED.
SHE WON'T EVEN CALL
THE POLICE.
CALL THE POLICE ABOUT WHAT?
(Pete) ADDISON HAS A PATIENT
WHO WANTS TO BE REVIRGINIZED.
SO SHE CAN MARRY A MAN
SHE'S NEVER MET.
AND THAT'S AGAINST THE LAW?
SHE WAS RAPED, SAM.
OH. WELL, THAT'S AWFUL.
YEAH, IT'S AWFUL.
BUT IF ADDISON DOES THIS,
THEN THE GIRL GOES BACK TO KABUL
TO MARRY A MAN SHE DOESN'T KNOW,
WHO'LL ONLY HAVE HER
IF HER HYMEN IS UNTOUCHED?
THAT'S WRONG.
IT'S LIKE VIOLATING HER TWICE.
YEAH, BUT IT'S HER CHOICE,
ISN'T IT?
CHOICE? THAT GIRL WILL LIKELY
LIVE UNDER A VEIL IN A CLAY HUT
NED
ERE SHE COULD BE STONED
FOR LISTENING
TO A MADONNA ALBUM.
YOU THINK SHE UNDERSTANDS
SHE'S CHOOSING THAT?
MEG?
HELLO, PETER.
MEG.
DID HE EVER MENTION HER
TO ANYONE?
IF YOU VOTE FOR ME, I PROMISE
TO TELL YOU EVERYTHING I KNOW.
SAM.
I'M JUST KIDDING.
WHO IS SHE? SHE WAS, UH...
.
(Dell) SHE WAS SOMETHING.
(gasps)
OH.
OOH.
HMM.
(Violet) WHERE DO YOU THINK
HE KNOWS HER FROM?
ADDISON?
SO YOU WILL DO THIS?
PLEASE SIT.
I RAN YOUR LABS.
IS SOMEONE STILL HURTING YOU?
NO.
YOU SAID YOU WERE RAPED
MONTHS AGO,
BUT THERE ARE TRACES
OF SPERM, SHARBAT,
WHICH INDICATES
SOMETHING IS STILL HAPPENING.
IT'S NOT RAPE.
THERE WAS NEVER A RAPE.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO LIE,
TO TAKE IT THIS FAR.
I HAVE A BOYFRIEND HERE,
AND I LOVE HIM.
BUT YOUR FATHER ARRANGED
A MARRIAGE TO SOMEONE ELSE.
MY PARENTS--
THEY DID NOT KNOW ABOUT THE BOY.
HE'S NOT FROM OUR CULTURE.
HER I'D BEEN RAPED.OTHER--
I TOLD HER I'D BEEN RAPED.
I THOUGHT SHE'D UNDERSTAND
THAT THIS MEANT
I COULD NOT MARRY THIS MAN,
ONLY SHE FOUND A WAY...
A WAY FOR US ALL TO BE HAPPY.
HAPPY?
MY FATHER DRIVES A CAB.
HE USED TO TEACH UNIVERSITY.
MY MOTHER, SHE IS LONELY.
THEY CAME HERE FOR ME,
BUT THEY ARE MISERABLE.
THIS MAN, HE WILL BRING US
ALL BACK AND TAKE CARE OF US.
BUT ONLY IF YOU'RE A VIRGIN.
IF I'M A VIRGIN, WE CAN GO.
WE CAN BE HAPPY.
I WANT THEM TO BE HAPPY.
UH, I JUST WANTED TO APOLOGIZE
FOR PUSHING YOU SO HARD
WHEN I FIRST TOOK OVER.
THAT--THAT WAS WRONG,
AND, UH, OKAY, LOOK,
I KNOW THAT YOU AND VIOLET
ARE JOINED AT THE HIP,
AND SHE'S GONNA GO FOR NAOMI,
BUT YOU ARE YOUR OWN MAN,
AND I'VE GOT A LOT
OF GREAT IDEAS--
DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT ACQUIRED APHASIA?
AC--UH, A BIT.
THIS KID CAME IN.
HE PRESENTED WITH WHAT LOOKED
LIKE LATE ONSET AUTISM,
BUT I THINK IT MIGHT BE
SOMETHING ELSE.
WHY?
WELL, WE HAD THIS MOMENT
OF... EYE CONTACT.
ALL RIGHT. WELL, AUTISTIC KIDS
MAKE EYE CONTACT.
I KNOW, BUT THIS WAS REAL.
IT REALLY SEEMED LIKE
HE WAS CONNECTING.
KID STOPPED TALKING AT 4.
YOU THINK THERE'S ANY CHANCE
HE'S HAVING SEIZURES IN HIS
SLEEP, SO MAYBE NOBODY NOTICED?
YOU THINK I'M GRASPING?
UH, I THINK
YOU'RE A GOOD DOCTOR,
THEN THERE PROBABLY IS.
G
MAKES YOU AND NAOMI NICER.E THIG
WELL, NOT EVERYTHING
IS ABOUT THE VOTE.
YOU'RE A GOOD DOCTOR.
YOU'LL FIGURE IT OUT.
(Meg) BIG OFFICE,
OH, VIEW OF THE OCEAN,
PATIENTS WHO CAN, UH,
PAY THE BILLS--
SO WHAT'S WRONG?
YOU SAID YOU WERE HERE FOR
A DEVELOPING NATIONS CONFERENCE.
YOU NEVER MENTIONED
PSYCHOANALYSIS.
I THOUGHT I'D STOP IN
WHILE I WAS IN TOWN,
BUT LOOK AT YOU.
YOU NEED HELP--YOUR EYES,
YOUR--YOUR FACE, YOUR ENERGY.
'S... (sigh)
IT'S... (sigh)
THE PRACTICE IS GOING THROUGH
A ROUGH PATCH.
YOU'RE GOING THROUGH
YOU KNOW, UH...
I ALWAYS HATED THE WAY
YOU DID THAT,
KNEW EVERYTHING.
IT'S A CURSE.
BUT COME ON.
YOU NEED A CHANGE.
LIKE WHAT,
AID MISSION
TO THE CONGO?
GHANA. I'M GOING TO NALERIGU
TO ORGANIZE A MALARIA PROGRAM.
OH, THE PETER I REMEMBER
NEVER HESITATED.
HE JUMPED IN
AND DID WHAT NEEDED DOING.
THEN AGAIN,
THE PETER I REMEMBER
WOULD'VE THROWN ME DOWN
ON THIS DESK
TEN SECONDS AFTER I WALKED IN.
HAVE THEY COME OUT
OF PETE'S OFFICE YET?
TH-THE... BLINDS
ARE STILL DRAWN.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
WE WAIT UNTIL THEY COME OUT,
AND THEN WE INTERROGATE HIM
OR HER.
NO, ABOUT MY PATIENT SHARBAT.
SHE LIED.
SHE WASN'T RAPED.
SHE LIED?
SHE HAS A BOYFRIEND.
SHE FREAKED OUUTH,
HER PARENTS THE TRUTH,
KNEW THAT IT WOULD COME OUT.
Y-YOU DON'T LIE
ABOUT RAPE, EVER.
I KNOW, BUT--
NO, THERE'S NO BUTS. THAT'S
WHAT MAKES PEOPLE DOUBT WOMEN.
ONE WOMAN DOES THAT--
I DON'T CARE THE REASON--
IT'S--IT'S BAD FOR EVERYBODY.
DAMN IT. I HATE THAT.
(sighs)
YOU SHOULDN'T DO THIS,
THE SURGERY.
BUT I THOUGHT THAT--
SHE LIED, ADDISON.
IF SHE'S SOME GIRL WHO'S
SLEEPING AROUND AND TELLING LIES
AND MAKING REAL VICTIMS
LOOK BAD, NO, SHE MADE HER BED.
YOU DON'T LIE ABOUT RAPE.
THAT'S ONE OF MY RULES.
I'm mom at the playground
AND the dog park.
The kids get trail mix...
And YOU get a delicious Milo's
Kitchen Chicken Meatball.
They're 100% real...
I wish you liked MY
cooking that much.
The Best Treats Come
From The Kitchen.
Milo's Kitchen home-style
dog treats.
Ziploc CELEBRATES GIVING
WITH STYLE.
FOR THE FRESHEST GOODIES
WITH THE FRESHEST HOLIDAY LOOK,
THE LIMITED EDITION
Ziploc Holiday Collection,
AVAILABLE NOW.
SC Johnson.
YOU PICK O BEEN THERE.W.
YOU PICK OUT A MAKEUP
THINKING IT'S YOUR SHADE...
UNTIL YOU ACTUALLY
TRY IT OUT.
NOW, I HAVE A MAKEUP
THAT ALWAYS GETS IT RIGHT.
SMART SHADE MAKEUP
INSTANTLY ADJUSTS
TO MATCH PERFECTLY
TO YOUR SKIN.
ALMAY SMART SHADE MAKEUP.
ONLY FROM ALMAY.
ONLY FOR ME.
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERY TIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPKIN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS...
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
[ Female Announcer ] THE NEWEST
SEASONAL FLAVORS ARE HERE.
TRY NEW SUGAR FREE
PUMPKIN SPICE...
AND PECAN PRALINE.
♪
GET YOUR COUPON TODAY
AT TASTELIFT.COFFEE-MATE.COM.
Get ready for a feeling of
clean like nothing else.
Extreme Clean from Aquafresh.
It showers your whole
mouth with rich
Micro-Active foam.
Thousands of
germ-killing bubbles
seek out hard to reach places
and help kill the
sources of bad breath
then rinse clean away
Leaving a cool tingling
that just won't quit
Extreme Clean from Aquafresh.
Take the feeling of
clean to the extreme.
IS THE PERFECT CHOICE
FOR HOLIDAY GATHERINGS.
MARTINELLI'S IS NON-ALCOHOLIC,
FESTIVE LIKE CHAMPAGNE,
AND TASTES GREAT!
MARTINELLI'S: SINCE 1868.
NOW THAT'S THE PETER
I REMEMBER.
JUST DOING
WHAT HAS TO BE DONE.
(laughs)
WHAT'S THAT ON YOUR BACK?
I DON'T KNOW.
SAND FLY BITE.
I GET 'EM ALL THE TIME.
YOU GET SAND FLY BITES
ALL THE TIME?
YEAH, I LIVE 20 METERS OFF
THE KUNU RIVER IN NIGERIA.
THAT'S THE LEAST
OF MY PROBLEMS THERE.
SAND FLY BITES DON'T HAVE
ANNULAR LESIONS LIKE THIS.
STOP WORRYING.
IT'S A BITE.
(chuckles)
IT'S AN INSECT BITE,
RIGHT?
WOW. WHAT BIT YOU
AND DID THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
PROBABLY A SAND FLY.
I'VE BEEN LIVING
IN NIGERIA.
(water running)
SO HOW DO YOU KNOW PETE?
WE WERE RESIDENTS TOGETHER.
THEN WE DID
DOCTORS WITHOUT BORDERS
FOR A COUPLE OF YEARS
BEFORE HE MOVED HERE.
WHOA, WHOA. PETE DID
DOCTORS WITHOUT BORDERS?
WHEN WAS THAT?
15 YEARS AGO. HE WAS SUPPOSED
TO TAKE A COUPLE MONTHS OFF,
BUT THEN HE MET SOMEBODY,
MARRIED HER,
SETTLED... DOWN HERE.
HE NEVER TOLD YOU ABOUT IT?
NO, BUT YOU CAN TELL US.
PETE'S A VERY PRIVATE PERSON.
HE'S VERY SHY. HE'S VERY SHY.
HE DOESN'T LIKE TO BRAG.
UH, TRUST ME.
HE'S NOT SHY.
WELL, I-I DIDN'T MEAN SHY
IN THE--THE "SHY" SENSE.
SO WHAT WAS HE LIKE THEN?
AMAZING.
AMAZING DOCTOR.
WELL, YOU KNOW.
WE'VE ONLY SEEN PETE
DO EASTERN MEDICINE.
WE'VE NEVER SEEN HIM
IN ACTION.
OH.
ONE TIME WE WERE, UH, TREATING
THESE CHILDREN IN BOSNIA.
THE ORPHANAGE
WAS UNDER MORTAR FIRE.
AN EVACUATION WAS ORDERED,
BUT IT WAS IMPOSSIBLE
TO GET THE KIDS OUT.
PETER REFUSED TO LEAVE
THE KIDS BEHIND.
HE STAYED WITH 'EM
THROUGH THE NIGHT.
MOST OF THE KIDS SURVIVED
BECAUSE OF HIM.
PETE DID THAT?
OUR PETE?
YOU KNOW, IT'S FUNNY...
"PETE."
TO ME HE WAS ALWAYS "PETER."
PETER.
HEY, YOU GOT A MINUTE?
TO SNOOP ABOUT MEG,
OR HOCK ME FOR A VOTE?
THIS IS NOT ABOUT THE VOTE.
THIS IS ABOUT THE PRACTICE...
OKAY.
AND THE DIRECTION
THAT IT IS HEADED IN.
NAI--
AND I THINK THAT I CAN SUM UP
EVERYTHING YOU NEED TO KNOW
ABOUT THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN SAM AND ME
AND THE WAY WE SEE THIS PRACTICE
INTO ONE WORD--DEFATALATOR.
DEFATALATOR?
IT WAS AN EXPERIMENT,
A LEAD-IN
TO A TOTAL WELLNESS PROGRAM.
IT'S A SHAME YOU DIDN'T
HAVE IT IN WEST AFRICA.
HE DIDN'T HAVE
MUCH OF A CHOICE.
ANOTHER DOCTOR IN THE PRACTICE
WAS PRESSING HIM INTO TRYING
TO BRING IN BUSINESS--
SOMETHING I WOULD NEVER DO.
HI, I'M NAOMI BENNETT.
SHE'S CAMPAIGNING.
AND YOU'RE
THE ANTI-DEFATALATOR CANDIDATE?
IT'S A LITTLE MORE COMPLICATED
THAN THAT.
IS IT?
(knock on door)
HEY.
TO WHAT DO I OWE
THIS SURPRISE?
I'VE GOT
THIS COMING WEEKEND OFF,
AND I WAS THINKING YOU, ME,
CABO SAN LUCAS.
A WEEKEND AWAY--
PALMILLA, VERY FANCY,
PERFECT, CLEAR BLUE WATERS.
WE COULD GET AWAY.
MM.
(chuckles)
TOO MUCH?
NO. YES.
NO. YE--
YES. (chuckles) NO. HERE--
HERE'S THE THING--
UM, WE'VE BEEN OUT
A FEW TIMES,
AND, UM, IT'S--IT'S--
IT'S BEEN GREAT.
I... I REALLY LIKE YOU--
IS THIS WHERE YOU
BREAK UP WITH ME?
NO, NO.
IT'S JUST, UM...
I HAVE THESE RULES.
THEY'RE STUPID RULES,
REALLY.
BUT, UM, IN THE PAST,
WHEN I DIDN'T HAVE RULES,
IT--IT--
IT DIDN'T GO SO WELL.
MY--MY--MY POINT IS THAT
NOW THAT I HAVE MY RULES...
MM-HMM.
I DON'T WANT TO BREAK THEM.
YOU KNOW?
YEAH, I HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT.
(laughs)
I WANT TO KNOW,
BUT, UM, RULES?
SEX RULES.
RULES ABOUT SEX.
YOU KNOW, A HOTEL MEANS
A ROOM, A ROOM MEANS A BED,
A BED MEANS--
YOU HAVE SEX RULES.
I'M WAITING.
UNTIL MARRIAGE?
NO! NO. (laughs)
(laughs)
NO, NO. I--
JUST TILL, UM...
UNTIL IT FEELS RIGHT,
UNTIL I'M... SURE.
OKAY.
SO WE'LL WAIT.
I'M GOOD WITH WAITING.
I'M HAPPY WITH WAITING.
REALLY?
NO, BUT I CAN WAIT.
(laughs)
AND I AM SURE.
GO AWAY.
THIS WILL JUST TAKE
ONE SECOND.
NALIZATIONS.
O HEAR
YOUR RATIONALIZATIONS.
(knocks on door)
BRADEN MIGHT NOT BE AUTISTIC.
IS THIS SOME SICK IDEA--
NO.
HE MIGHT HAVE SOMETHING CALLED
LANDAU-KLEFFNER SYNDROME.
IN KIDS LIKE BRADEN, THAT LOSE
THE ABILITY TO COMMUNICATE,
THEY MIGHT BE HAVING SEIZURES.
AT NIGHT. YOU DON'T NOTICE THEM,
BUT IT CAUSES PROBLEMS WITH
THE SYNAPSES IN THEIR BRAIN.
THEY START MISFIRING. IT IMPAIRS
THEIR ABILITY TO COMMUNICATE,
AND WHEN THEY CAN'T COMMUNICATE,
THEY WITHDRAW.
AND THE THING IS,
WITH CORTICOSTEROIDS,
WITH ANTICONVULSANTS,
IT MIGHT BE TREATABLE.
THE FIRST PAGE HAS THE NAME OF
THREE EXCELLENT PEDIATRICIANS.
THE REST IS ALL THE RESEARCH
I COULD FIND.
(door closes)
(jingles keys)
YOU KNOW, WE WERE BOTH
ON THE WEB SITE.
IN ORDER TO KNOW
I WAS ON THE WEB SITE,
YOU HAD TO BE
ON THE WEB SITE, TOO.
SO, YOU KNOW, I'M JUST SAYING,
YOU'RE THE POT CALLING
THE KETTLE... PERVERT.
I'M A GOOD DOCTOR.
I WANT TO HELP YOUR SON.
♪
DELL,
I'VE BEEN THINKING A LOT
ABOUT WHAT YOU ASKED
THIS MORNING,
AND I STILL DON'T THINK THAT
YOU ASSISTING WITH THE COLES
IS A GOOD IDEA,
BUT THE HENNESSEYS ARE COMING IN
FOR A SIMILAR PROCEDURE.
HOW ABOUT SHADOWING ME THEN?
YEAH. THAT WOULD BE NICE.
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
LOOK, DELL, I KNOW
WE'VE HAD A DIFFICULT PATCH,
BUT WE HAVE A HISTORY.
AND, UH, I HOPE YOU KNOW
HOW IMPORTANT YOU ARE TO ME
AND TO THE PRACTICE.
(Sam) THOUGH I'M THE ONE
WHO GAVE YOU YOUR JOB BACK.
YEAH, WELL,
AFTER I BEGGED YOU TO.
EXCUSE ME.
DELL, I KNOW
THAT YOU'RE THE PERSON
THAT KEEPS
THIS PRACTICE RUNNING.
AND I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU
WANT TO BE DOING MORE.
UH-HUH.
I THINK YOAND I THINK YOU SHOUL.
I THINK YOU'RE READY FOR IT,
READY FOR MORE
THAN JUST "SHADOWING."
SAM.
RE TALKING, SO--
, DELL AND I
WERE TALKING, SO--
OH, I'M SORRY. ALL RIGHT. WELL,
WHEN YOU'RE DONE WITH ALL--
STOP BY MY OFFICE FOR A FEW,
ALL RIGHT?
OKAY.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
SAM DOESN'T CARE ABOUT YOU.
ALL HE CARES ABOUT
IS THE BOTTOM LINE.
OH, WELL, YOU'VE SEEN
WHAT THE BOTTOM LINE
WITH NAOMI IS, RIGHT?
YOU KEEP HER SECRETS,
YOU HIDE HER MISTAKES,
THEN YOU JUST WAIT
FOR THE AX TO DROP.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
SAM DOESN'T CARE ABOUT WHAT
THIS PLACE IS SUPPOSED TO BE.
WELL, THIS PLACE WHING BUT BRE
IF SHE'S RUNNING THINGS.
IS THIS HOW YOU EXPECT
TO GET MY VOTE?
♪
YOU CAN'T CHANGE WHAT YOU DID.
YOU KNOW, AND WE CAN'T LIVE
WITH WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
WHY ARE YOU FIGHTING WITH ME?
I'M MAKING PROGRESS HERE,
ALL RIGHT?
I'M GETTING US
UP OUT OF THIS HOLE.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
BECAUSE PEOPLE AREN'T HAPPY.
PEOPLE AREN'T HAPPY,
OR YOU'RE NOT HAPPY
BECAUSE IT'S NOT YOUR WAY?
MY WAY?
WELL, THAT'S WHAT IT ALL
COMES DOWN TO, RIGHT?
AT LEAST I HAVE A WAY...
DEMOCRACY IN ACTION.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST ADMIT IT?
I'M THE ONE WHO DID
EVERYTHING IN THE BEGINNING!
with hand-layered pasta,
tomatoes,
and real mozzarella cheese.
But what makes us even
prouder...
is what our real
dinners can do for your family.
Stouffer's.
Let's fix dinner.
BUT THEY HAVEN'T EXPERIENCED
EXTRA STRENGTH
Bayer Advanced Aspirin.
95% OF PEOPLE
WHO TRIED IT AGREED
THAT IT RELIEVED
THEIR HEADACHE FAST.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
TODAY FOR
A SPECIAL TRIAL OFFER.
VISIT FastReliefChallenge.com
YOU'VE BEEN THERE.
YOU PICK OUT A MAKEUP
THINKING IT'S YOUR SHADE...
UNTIL YOU ACTUALLY
TRY IT OUT.
NOW, I HAVE A MAKEUP
THAT ALWAYS GETS IT RIGHT.
SMART SHADE MAKEUP
INSTANTLY ADJUSTS
TO MATCH PERFECTLY
TO YOUR SKIN.
ALMAY SMART SHADE MAKEUP.
ONLY FROM ALMAY.
ONLY FOR ME.
WE WABOUT SOMETHING NO ONE
ASKIWANTS TO TALK ABOUT.ANKLY
IT'S TIME TO GET REAL ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE BATHROOM.
STOP ALL THE CUTESY STUFF
AND START TALKING ABOUT
WHAT YOU REALLY WANT
FROM YOUR TOILET PAPER.
IT'S TIME TO TALK ABOUT CLEAN.
FEELING CLEAN IS SO IMPORTANT.
QUILTED NORTHERN SOFT AND STRONG
IS STRONGER THAN THE
LEADING VALUE BRAND,
TO HELP PROTECT
AGAINST BREAKTHROUGH.
FOR MYSELF, FOR MY FAMILY,
IT KEEPS US CLEAN.
I USE QUILTED NORTHERN.
QUILTED NORTHERN
SOFT AND STRONG,
PROTECTION FOR A CONFIDENT
CLEAN OR YOUR MONEY BACK.
EVERYTHING THAT'S
IN THEIR PRODUCTS.
BUT SC Johnson
ISN'T JUST A COMPANY.
WE'RE A FAMILY
WHO CARES ABOUT YOURS.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE WORKING
TO SHARE ALL OF OUR INGREDIENTS,
RIGHT DOWN TO THE FRAGRANCES
AND DYES.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOU'RE BRINGING
INTO YOUR HOME.
GOING BEYOND
THE INDUSTRY STANDARD --
THAT'S THE FAMILY STANDARD.
♪
BUT ALL YOU NOTICE IS HER
BEAUTIFUL, HEALTHY SKIN.RD.
JERGENS ULTRA HEALING
MOISTURIZER
MAKES EVEN YOUR DRIEST SKIN
LOOK HEALTHIER, INSTANTLY.
WITH BEAUTIFUL SKIN
FROM JERGENS,
YOU'LL ALWAYS MAKE AN ENTRANCE.
JERGENS®.
THE BEAUTIFUL DIFFERENCE.
I THINK LIES ARE CONTAGIOUS.
PETE NOT TELLING US
ABOUT HIS PAST IS NOT A LIE.
IT'S AN OMISSION.
FINE, THAT'S ONE THING.
YOU LIED ABOUT CHARLOTTE.
I TOLD YOU.
AND NOW I HAVE TO NOT TELL
EVERYBODY ELSE. THAT'S A LIE.
SAM?
SECRETLY SLEEPING
WITH NAOMI.
LIE. LIE.
DELL?
KEPT NAOMI'S SECRET.
OMISSION. LIE.
ADDISON?
WELL, HER PATIENT LIED
ABOUT BEING RAPED.
OH.
BUT I GUESS I CAN'T
HOLD THAT AGAINST HER.
YOU KNOW WHAT, ADDISON?
YOU MAY HY.
THAT'S TRUSTWORTHY.
LOW BAR.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
YOU CAN HELP HIM?
IF WE GIVE BRADEN
PREDNISONE NOW,
IT'LL ABSORB
INTO HIS BLOODSTREAM
IN A MATTER OF HOURS.
BEFORE HE GOES TO BED,
WE COULD KNOW IF IT'LL HELP.
DID YOU REALLY
WORK IN AFRICA
TREATING KIDS
WITH RIVER BLINDNESS?
HAVE YOU HEARD THE STORY ABOUT
HIM AND THE BOSNIAN ORPHANS?
NO!
WHERE DID YOU
HEAR ABOUT THAT?
IN THE LADIES ROOM.
WHAT DO YOU PEOPLE
DO IN THERE?
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL US
YOU HAD THIS WHOLE PAST, PETE?
PETER.
PETER?
IT WAS A LONG TIME AGO.
YOU REALLY LIKE HER.
LOOK...
SHARBAT...
I KNOW YOU WANT THIS.
YOU THINK YOU WANT THIS.
IT'S THE ONLY WAY.
IT MAY BE THE ONLY WAY
FOR THIS MAN YOU'RE SUPPOSED
TO MARRY, BUT FOR YOU--
YOU NEED TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT'S RIGHT FOR YOU.
LOOK, YOU TOLD YOUR MOTHER
ABOUT THE RAPE.
TELL HER ABOUT THIS BOY
YOU LOVE.
DO YOU REALLY WANT
YOUR FUTURE
TO BE BASED ON A LIE?
HAVE YOU BEEN HAVING FATIGUE,
HEADACHE, JOINT PAINS?
I'VE BEEN ON AND OFF AIRPLANES
ALL MONTH
IN HALF A DOZEN
DIFFERENT TIME ZONES.
Y-YES, I HAVE.
OH, COME ON, SAM.
WHAT IS IT?
THERE WE GO.
THIS.
THAT WAS IN MY BACK?
OF A TICK.
THE REMNANTS
PROBABLY BEEN IN THERE
A WEEK OR SO.
PETE WAS RIGHT.
THESE THINGS CAN CAUSE
A NASTY INFECTION.
IF YOU WOULD'VE LET IT
LAST ANY LONGER,
YOU COULD HAVE WOUND UP
WITH SERIOUS CARDIAC PROBLEMS,
ENCEPHALITIS--
WELL, THANK YOU.
WELL, YOU CAN THANK PETER.
I DON'T SUPPOSE I COULD
PAY YOU OFF
TO SAY IT WAS
A SAND FLY BITE?
(laughs)
OH. (exhales slowly)
YOU DECIDE WHAT TO DO?
I DECIDED THE TRUTH
SEEMED BETTER.
HEY, SPEAKING OF WHICH, UH,
WHY IS IT THAT NO ONE SEEMS
TO KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT YOU?
YOU KNOW ME.
APPARENTLY WE DON'T EVEN
KNOW YOUR NAME... PETER.
LOOK, THE PAST IS THE PAST.
I'M NOT ONE TO DWELL ON IT.
BUT MEG--SHE SEEMS LIKE
A GOOD PART OF YOUR PAST.
SHE'S HERE NOW.
THEN SHE'LL BE GONE.
SO... IT IS WHAT IT IS.
YOU COULD NOT LET HER GO.
YOU KNOW WHAT YOUR PROBLEM IS?
YOU ARE A ROMANTIC.
YOU DON'T WANT THEM
RUNNING THIS PLACE TOGETHER.
YOU WANT THEM TOGETHER--
SAM AND NAOMI THE WAY IT WAS,
YOU AND NAOMI
THE WAY IT WAS.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH THAT?
I LIKE THE WAY IT WAS.
(door opens)
THANK YOU.
WHAT SHARBAT
IS ASKING FOR,
WHAT SHE WANTS TO GIVE UP
IS A LOT.
AND I THOUGHT
YOU SHOULD KNOW THE TRUTH.
I KNEW.
MOTHERS ARE MOTHERS.
WHAT SHE COULDN'T TELL ME,
I KNEW.
I'M SORRY.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
YOU LET HER SAY
SHE WAS RAPED?
IF SHE BROKE THE TRUST
THAT HER FATHER AND I HAVE
IN HER, IT WOULD BE HER SIN.
SHE WOULD HAVE FELT SHAME.
IT WAS EASIER FOR HER TO SAY
IT WAS SOMEONE ELSE'S.
WE'VE TALKED.
NOW WILL YOU DO
THE SURGERY?
UH...
SHARBAT,
NO MATTER WHAT I DO,
I CAN'T MAKE YOU FORGET
WHAT YOU HAD HERE.
I LOVE MY PARENTS MORE
THAN ANYTHING IN THIS WORLD.
I JUST WANT
TO TAKE THEM HOME.
PLEASE, IF I DON'T BURY
MY PAST,
MY FAMILY WILL HAVE
NO FUTURE.
NO, NO, NO,
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT--
STOP, STOP TALKING.
JUST LISTEN--LISTEN TO
WHAT I'M SAYING.
WAIT, NO, NO, NO.
I'M GONNA TELL YOU WHAT.
YOU GOT ME OUT OF THE MARRIAGE.
NOW WHAT YOU CAN DO
IS OVER THE PRACTICE.GO AHEAD
AND TAKE OVER THE PRACTICE.
FOR THE LAST TIME--
PROBABLY NOT THE LAST TIME...
MAYBE I'LL GO WORK
OVER AT ST. AMBROSE.
BECAUSE WE'LL PROBABLY HAVE THIS
ARGUMENT MAYBE NINE MORE TIMES
BEFORE THE END OF THE DAY...
NO, REALLY, I'M SURE THAT I
COULD FIND A JOB THERE...
SINCE WE'VE ALREADY HAAVE A PRIG
TO HAVE A PRIVATE CONVERSATION.
I DON'T CARE.
GREAT.
LOOK, MAYBE THIS IS MY FAULT.
I PUSHED US TO TRY
TO RECAPTURE THE PAST,
WHAT WE HAD,
WHAT THIS PLACE USED TO BE.
BUT THE PAST IS CLUTTERED
WITH ANGER AND MISTAKES,
AND WE NEED TO BURY THAT.
IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHO DID WHAT WHEN.
IT MATTERS
WHAT WE WANT TO DO NOW,
WHAT WE WANT THIS PLACE
TO BE GOING FORWARD.
WE NEED TO FOCUS ON PATIENTS,
AND WE NEED TO EARN MONEY.
WE NEED NAOMI AND WE NEED SAM,
THE BEST OF BOTH OF YOU.
AND THIS VOTE,A,
AN IDEA THAT WE MIGHT NEVER
RECOVER FROM.
WE SHOULDN'T DO IT.
LET'S SIT DOWN AND FIGURE OUT
WHAT WE WANT
THIS PLACE TO BE, TOGETHER.
IF YOU FORCE US TO CHOOSE
BETWEEN YOU,
THAT WILL CREATE SCARS
THAT WON'T HEAL.
WE NEED TO MOVE
NOT BACK.
WE VOTE
AT THE END OF THE DAY.
(sighs)
CLOSED CAPTIONING
FOR PRIVATE PRACTICE
IN SPONSORED BY...
SHARBAT...
ARE YOU READY?
HE'S JUST A BOY.
HE'S A NICE BOY,
BUT WE WOULD NOT LAST.
HE'S YOUNG,
HE'S GOT COLLEGE,
HE'S SO AMERICAN.
HE'S NOT MY FUTURE.
I WANT TO DO THIS.
SO, YES, I AM READY.
DOC... TOR?
THANK YOU...
FOR THE TRUCK.
(chuckles) YOU'RE WELCOME.
(voice breaking)
HE STARTED 45 MINUTES AGO.
HE WOKE UP.
WHATEVER YOU ARE,
YOU ARE A WONDERFUL DOCTOR.
SO WE'RE REALLY
GONNA DO THIS?
I'M NOT VOTING.
I WON'T BE PART OF THIS.
WELL, LET'S JUST--LET'S COUNT
THE VOTES WE HAVE.
SAM. (clears throat)
NAOMI.
ADDISON.
OKAY, WHOEVER DID THAT,
IT IS NOT FUNNY.
ADDISON.
NO. NO, NO, NO, NO,
NO, NO, NO.
NO. NO.
NICE SPEECH.
IT WON MY VOTE.
CONGRATULATIONS, BOSS.
EVEN YOU VOTED FOR ME?
IF EITHER ONE OF THAD W,
THIS PLACE STILL
WOULD HAVE BEEN DIVIDED.
OH.
WHAT AM I
SUPPOSED TO DO NOW?
FIGURE OUT
WHAT THE FUTURE IS.
WHAT THE NEW RULES ARE.
YOU THINK RULES REALLY WORK?
SO LONG AS YOU REMEMBER
THEY'RE MEANT TO BE BROKEN.
HEY, VIOLET...
ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED
IN YOUR OFFICE--
I DON'T--I DON'T
WANT TO TALK ABOUT THAT.
ARE YOU SURE?
YEAH. WE'RE NOT--WE'RE NOT
GOING THERE, ADDISON.
IT IS WHAT IT IS.
(exhales deeply)
I'M SORRY, NAOMI.
IF I COULD GO BACK
AND CHANGE WHAT I DID...
HOW I TREATED YOU...
I MESSED UP.
I'M SORRY.
♪
THANK YOU...
FOR WORRYING ABOUT ME.
♪
YOU KNOW, I REALLY COULD
USE YOU IN GHANA.
DON'T YOU REMEMBER
WHAT IT WAS LIKE?
NO MATTER WHAT GODFORSAKEN
PART OF THE WORLD WE WERE IN,
NO MATTER WHAT DISASTER
OR DISEASE WE WERE FIGHTING,
PEOPLE ALWAYS
RESPONDED TO YOU.
THAT'S A GIFT.
DON'T WASTE IT HERE.
I'M PART OF SOMETHING
I BELIEVE IN--
BUILDING IT, MAKING IT WORK.
I LIKE IT HERE.
♪
I ALSO LIKE YOU HERE.
YEAH,
EX.
I FORGOT YOU CAME
WITH CIGARETTES.
SO IS THAT AN INVITATION?
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
BUT YOU GOTTA QUIT SMOKING.
I DON'T CHANGE
FOR ANYONE.
♪
(laughs)
NICE OUTFIT, FRAULEIN.
♪
GET OVER HERE.
NO.
♪
DO I LOOK LIKE A PERSON
WHO TAKES NO FOR AN ANSWER?
I WOULD VERY MUCH LIKE IT
IF WE COULD SPEND
THE EVENING... TALKING.
I'M SERI
AGAIN WITH THE T
I'M SERIOUS. WE'RE GONNA
GET TO KNOW EACH OTHER.
WHY?
BECAUSE, HERR CHARLOTTE,
I WANT US TO BE
ABOUT MORE THAN SEX,
BECAUSE I WANT TO KNOW YOU
AND YOU TO KNOW ME,
LIKE NORMAL PEOPLE.
♪
(clears throat)
FOR INSTANCE, ME.
I'M FROM AKRON.
I'M AN ONLY CHILD.
I WAS ADOPTED,
AND I NEVER CARED.
I NEVER SOUGHT OUT
MY BIRTH PARENTS
BECAUSE MY PARENTS WERE GREAT,
ARE GREAT.
AND, UH, I SPENT SUMMERS
WORKING AT A CAMP IN INDIANA,
WHICH IS WHEN I REALIZED
THAT I LOVED CHILDREN
AND, UH, DECIDED I WANTED
TO BE A PEDIATRICIAN.
MY FAVORITE COLOR
IS CHARTREUSE
BECAUSE I LIKE
THE WAY IT SOUNDS
COMING OUT OF MY MOUTH--
CHARTREUSE.
♪
EUSE.
CHARTREUSE.
♪
THAT IS A GOOD WORD.
OKAY, NOW IT'S YOUR TURN.
(clears throat)
♪
WELL... UM...
I'M FROM
MONROEVILLE, ALABAMA...
(chuckles)
HOME OF HARPER LEE,
WHO WROTE--
"TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD."
RIGHT.
♪
WHICH IS MY FAVORITE BOOK.
YES, I READ.
(laughs)
♪
HEY.
I'M GLAD YOU CALLED.
YEAH.
(clears throat)
♪
(laughs)
ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOU CAN COUNT ON.
INTRODUCING AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
WITH MORE SPEED OPTIONS,
RELIABILITY
AND Wi-Fi HOT SPOTS THAN EVER.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW TO GET
U-verse HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
IT'S ALL THE SPEED YOU NEED
ALL AT A GREAT PRICE.
OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network
GIVES YOU MORE
OF WHAT YOU ENJOY ONLINE.
AND WITH AT&T,
OUR WIRELESS GATEWAY
TURNS YOUR HOME
INTO A PRIVATE Wi-Fi HOT SPOT
THAT CONNECTS
YOUR Wi-Fi DEVICES
AND CAN EVEN SAVE ON YOUR
SMART PHONE DATA USAGE AT HOME.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW
TO GET AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT INCLUDES ACCESS ON-THE-GO
TO OUR ENTIRE NATIONAL
Wi-Fi HOT SPOT NETWORK,
WITH OVER 30,000 HOT SPOTS.
AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET.
NOW ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOUR WHOLE HOUSE
CAN COUNT ON.
♪
Captioned by
Closed Captioning Services, Inc.
THIS IS "JEOPARDY!"
PLEASE WELCOME
TODAY'S CONTESTANTS--
A ST COUNSEL
FROM PROVO, UTAH...
A STAY-AT-HOME MOM
AND FREELANCE DESIGNER
FROM AART-UP TEXAS...
AND OUR RETURNING CHAMPION--
A LAW STUDENT ORIGINALLY
FROM LONG BEACH, CALIFORNIA...
WHOSE 4-DAY CASH WINNINGS
TOTAL...
AND NOW HERE IS
THE HOST OF "JEOPARDY!"--