CLASSROOM 5 YEARS OLD SITTING
THERE, JUST BEGINNING THEIR DAY,
HOPING TO GET THROUGH TO
CHRISTMAS, AND IT WOULD
CERTAINLY HELP EXPLAIN WHY WE
SAW WHAT WE BELIEVE TO BE
PERHAPS ONE OF THE MOST
EMOTIONAL MOMENTS FROM OUR
PRESIDENT AS HE TRIED TO CONSOLE
A NATION.
HERE HE IS.
>> THIS EVENING MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER,
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM, AND WE'LL REMIND EACH
OTHER HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE
ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
IN THE HARD DAYS TO COME THAT
COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT OUR
BEST AS AMERICANS, AND I WILL DO
EVERYTHING IN MY POWER AS
PRESIDENT TO HELP.
BECAUSE WHILE NOTHING CAN FILL
THE SPACE OF A LOST CHILD OR
LOVED ONE, ALL OF US CAN EXTEND
A HAND TO THOSE IN NEED, TO
REMIND THEM THAT WE ARE THERE
FOR THEM, THAT WE ARE PRAYING
FOR THEM, THAT THE LOVE THEY
FELT FOR THOSE THEY LOST ENDURES
NOT JUST IN THEIR MEMORIES, BUT
ALSO IN OURS.
MAY GOD BLESS THE MEMORY OF THE
VICTIMS, AND IN THE WORDS OF
SCRIPTURE, HEAL THE BROKEN
HEARTED, AND BIND UP THEIR
WOUNDS.
>> THE PRESIDENT SPEAKING AT THE
WHITE HOUSE JUST A SHORT TIME
AGO, ABOUT 45 MINUTES AGO.
IT'S NOW JUST A COUPLE OF
MINUTES PAST 4:00 EASTERN TIME.
WE PLAN TO TAKE YOU THROUGH THE
NEXT HOUR HERE ON ABC NEWS.
MANY OF YOU WILL THEN JOIN YOUR
LOCAL NEWS DURING THIS HORRIFIC,
WHAT'S BECOME A NATIONAL TRAGEDY
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, OF
COURSE AT THAT SCHOOL.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
BEGAN UNFOLDING SHORTLY AFTER
9:30 THIS MORNING.
27 PEOPLE ARE DEAD.
THE CONNECTICUT POLICE HELPED
DESCRIBE THE SCENE INSIDE THE
SCHOOL.
THE SHOOTER IS BELIEVED THE
SUSPECT'S MOTHER WAS THAT
KINDERGARTEN TEACHER, THAT THAT
WAS ONE OF TWO ROOMS, PRESUMABLY
TWO CLASSROOMS THAT HER
KINDERGARTEN CLASS WAS ONE OF
THEM.
SHE DIDN'T SURVIVE IT.
NOR DID MANY OF THE STUDENTS
INSIDE THAT CLASSROOM.
YOU CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE HORROR
HE WAS DESCRIBED AS WEARING A
VEST THAT HE HAD WALKED IN WITH
AT LEAST FOUR WEAPONS.
THERE WAS ONE MOTHER WHO SAID,
YOU KNOW, HE WAS MASKED ALTO WE
WILL NOT KNOW THAT UNTIL, OF
COURSE, THE HOURS THAT FOLLOW
HERE WHEN WE GET A SLIGHTLY
BETTER DESCRIPTION.
THOUGH IT'S ALREADY HORRIFIC
ENOUGH.
THAT HE SKOOD AT THE DOORWAY AND
WE DON'T KNOW IF HE ACTUALLY
ENTERED THE CLASSROOM.
BUT HERE ARE THE NUMBERS AS THEY
WERE LAID OUT JUST MOMENTS AGO
BY CONNECTICUT AUTHORITIES, THAT
THERE WERE 18 CHILDREN WHO DIED
AT THE SCENE.
18 UNFATHOMABLE, TWO CHILDREN
WERE THEN RUSHED TO AREA
HOSPITALS.
THEY'D BEEN SHOT, AS WELL, AND
THEN DIED AT AREA HOSPITALS.
SO THAT BRINGS YOU TO 20
CHILDREN WHO WERE KILLED TODAY
AT THAT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
CONNECTICUT.
SIX ADULTS ALSO KILLED AT THE
SCENE.
THAT BRINGS YOU TO 26.
AND WE'VE BEEN HEARING THAT
NUMBER AT LEAST 27 ALL DAY.
THAT'S WHERE WE GET TO THE
ADDITIONAL ADULT AT ANOTHER
SCENE THERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
THEY WOULDN'T TELL US WHAT THE
SCENE IS, OR PERHAPS THE
RELATIONSHIP WITH THAT
ADDITIONAL ADULT.
SO AT LEAST 27 PEOPLE DEAD, AND
THEN YOU ADD THE GUNMAN, AND
WHAT'S NOT CLEAR, AUTHORITIES
MAKING IT CLEAR TO ALL OF US IN
THAT PRESS CONFERENCE JUST
MOMENTS AGO, THEY DON'T KNOW
WHETHER OR NOT AT THIS POINT HE
TOOK HIS OWN LIFE OR WHETHER
AUTHORITIES HAD ALREADY ARRIVED
AT THE SCENE.
AND AS WE LEARN MORE ABOUT THIS
PARTICULAR SUSPECT YOU HEARD JEN
ASHTON SAY HERE A MOMENT AGO ON
THE DESK THAT THIS IS MENTAL
ILLNESS.
AND THERE'S A LOT OF TALK ABOUT
GUN CONTROL IN THIS COUNTRY BUT
THERE WILL BE A LOT OF TALK
ABOUT MENTAL ILLNESS.
HOW WE REACH OUT TO PEOPLE WHO
NEED HELP EARLIER, MUCH EARLIER
THAN SOMETHING LIKE THIS CAN
THEN UNFOLD.
AND I WANTED TO BRING IN BRAD
GARRETT, AN FBI PROFILER.
HE'S AN ABC NEWS ANALYST AND WE
TURN TO BRAD IN TIMES LIKE THESE
TO TRY TO WRAP OUR HEADS AROUND
WHY SOMEONE COULD BE CAPABLE OF
THIS AND HOW WE WOULDN'T SEE IT
EARLIER TO TRY TO HELP PREVENT
IT.
BUT BRAD, YOU KNOW, HOW EARLIER
BRETT, HOW DOES A 24-YEAR-OLD
WALK INTO HIS OWN MOTHER'S
CLASSROOM, IF THAT IS INDEED THE
CASE, WITH CHILDREN BEGINNING
THEIR SCHOOL DAY,
KINDERGARTENERS AND PERFORM SUCH
A HEINOUS ACT?
>> WELL, DAVID, THIS IS PROBABLY
BUILT UP OVER A NUMBER OF YEARS,
I WOULD GUESS.
AND WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE PROFILE
OF MASS SHOOTERS, IT'S LIKE
THEIR LIFE NEVER WENT TOGETHER.
THAT THEY HAD PROBLEMS WHEN THEY
WERE A CHILD.
THEY HAD PROBLEMS IN
RELATIONSHIP, WHETHER THEY BE
FEMALE, A WIFE, A PARENT.
AND THESE THINGS TEND TO BUILD.
NOW, A LOT OF THE TIMES THEY
CAUSE THE PROBLEM.
BUT THEY PERCEIVE IT AS IT'S OUR
FAULT THAT THEY ARE FAILING AT
THINGS THAT THEY ARE DOING.
SO AS THEY REACH, UNFORTUNATELY,
THEIR LATE TEENS OR EARLY 20s,
THERE IS THIS PERIOD WHERE THEY
BELIEVE THAT THEY HAVE TO
EMPOWER THEMSELVES AND AS ADD AS
THIS SOUNDS, THEY THINK THEY
HAVE THE RIGHT TO GO OUT AND
DESTROY EVERYTHING THEY BELIEVE
HAS WRONGED THEM.
AND I THINK THE REASON HE WENT
TO THE SCHOOL, OBVIOUSLY, TO
SHOOT, PERHAPS, MOM, BUT TO ALL
OF HER KIDS, IS THAT THOSE KIDS
ARE ASSOCIATED WITH HER.
AND I'M GOING TO BET THAT THE
OTHER SCENE IS A RELATIVE, O
BROTHER, A FATHER, SOMEBODY ELSE
THAT HE BELIEVED HE NEEDED TO
WIPE OFF THE EARTH BECAUSE THEY
HAD WRONGED HIM.
>> CHILLING WHEN YOU PUT IT THAT
WAY.
AND YOU'RE THE PROFILER.
YOU KNOW, I HATE TO TYPECAST,
BUT YOU LOOK BACK AT THESE
SHOOTINGS, AURORA, I WAS THERE
EARLIER THIS YEAR, IN COLORADO,
FOR THAT.
VIRGINIA TECH.
COLUMBINE.
AND YOU SEE THIS PATTERN OF
YOUNG, WHITE MALES AND PERHAPS
YOU CAN SHED A LITTLE LIGHT ON
WHY THAT BUILDS INTO THIS
PROFILE.
>> WELL, THE MALE PART I
UNDERSTAND, AND I THINK THE AGE
RANGE WE JUST TALKED ABOUT, 18
TO EARLY 20s, SOMETIMES UP TO
30, SEEMS TO BE WHERE IT FALLS.
BUT IT -- I ALSO THINK, DAVID,
THIS HAS SOMETHING TO DO WITH
HOW MALES IN GENERAL DEAL WITH
STRESS, FAILURE, ANGER, AND
RAGE.
WHERE FEMALES TEND TO
INTERNALIZE IT, MALES
EXTERNALIZE IT.
AND IF YOU COMBINE THAT WITH HOW
MALES TYPICALLY ARE SOCIALIZED
TO BE MORE AGGRESSIVE, THAT IT
MAKES IT EASIER, I SUPPOSE, FOR
A MALE TO GO AND COMMIT SUCH A
HORRENDOUS ACT, AND WE LOOK
HISTORICALLY ABOUT HOW PEOPLE
KILL EACH OTHER.
MALES TEND TO DO IT MUCH MORE
VIOLENT FASHION AND,
UNFORTUNATELY, IN A MASS FASHION
LIKE WE HAVE TODAY.
>> AND THE EXTRAORDINARY THING
IS, IS THAT THIS PARTICULAR
FAMILY IS DEALING WITH HORRIFIC
LOSS, TOO.
AND WE OFTEN FIND THAT IN THESE
CASES.
YOU KNOW, THE MOTHER IS DEAD.
THE KINDERGARTEN TEACHER.
WE DON'T KNOW WHO THIS SECOND
ADULT IS AT THIS SECOND SCENE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
BUT AS IS SO OFTEN THE CASE, THE
FAMILIES SAY AFTERWARDS THAT
THEY, TOO, FEEL AND PRAY FOR THE
VICTIMS OF THESE TRAGEDIES, BUT
WHEN WE GO BACK AND LOOK, JEN
ASHTON, PART OF OUR MEDICAL UNIT
HERE ON THE DESK, DR. ASHTON,
WHEN YOU LOOK BACK, THERE ARE
OFTEN WARNING SIGNS ALONG THE
WAY AND NOBODY'S SAYING, WHY
DIDN'T YOU DO THIS, WHY DIDN'T
YOU DO THAT?
WE HAVE TO AS A NATION LOOK FOR
THESE WARNING SIGNS.
>> THEY'RE WARNING SIGNS, DAVID,
THAT ARE ONLY CLEAR IN
HINDSIGHT, OF COURSE.
WHEN YOU LOOK, AGAIN, AT THE
PROFILE OF AN ACUTE PSYCHOTIC
BREAK, BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT THIS
IS, WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS, WE'RE TALKING HERE BY
DEFINITION OF A SITUATION OR
STATE KNOWN AS ACUTE PSYCHOSIS
WHICH MEANS THERE'S AN
IMPAIRMENT OF REALITY AND
JUDGMENT.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT PEOPLE WHO
SUFFER ACUTE PSYCHOSIS,
TYPICALLY YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
PEOPLE WHO MAY HAVE PARANOID
SCHIZOPHRENIA WHO MAY HAVE AN
EXTREME OR MANIC FORM OF BIPOLAR
DISORDER, AND POSSIBLY AS WE
JUST HEARD, YOU KNOW, A HISTORY
OF EITHER PSYCHOLOGICAL OR
PHYSICAL TRAUMA OR ABUSE IN THE
PAST.
AS TO WHETHER OR NOT THOSE
WARNING SIGNS, AS WE'RE GOING TO
BE TALKING SO MUCH ABOUT, IN THE
UPCOMING DAYS, HAD BEEN
APPARENT, AGAIN, MAYBE IN
HINDSIGHT, YES, BUT LOOKING
FORWARD, A LOT OF PEOPLE CAN
HAVE THEIR MOMENTS WHERE THEY
BEHAVE ERRATICALLY.
IT'S ONLY WHEN YOU PUT THOSE AS
A SUM TOTAL AND THEN MAKE A
WHOLE TIMELINE OF OVER A COURSE
OF SOMEONE'S LIFE THEN DO YOU
START TO CONNECT THE PIECES.
IN TIMES, YES, THERE CAN BE
GLARING WARNING SIGNS.
PEOPLE WHO WITHDRAW FROM THEIR
JOB, WITHDRAW FROM THEIR FAMILY,
WHO HAVE A HISTORY OF ABUSING
ANIMALS, WHO HAVE A HISTORY OF
VIOLENCE OR VIOLENT THOUGHTS, OR
HEARING VOICES.
BUT SOMETIMES THOSE THINGS ARE
NOT APPARENT.
>> SO MANY OF THESE ISSUES CAME
UP IN THE AURORA, COLORADO,
SHOOTING.
THE BATMAN MOVIE, OF COURSE, AND
WE THEN SAW THE SUSPECT IN COURT
WITH THE HAIR THAT SORT OF FIRE
ENGINE RED/ORANGE.
AND THERE WERE SIGNS IN THAT
CASE, TOO, AS THAT CONTINUES TO
UNFOLD.
>> RIGHT.
AND, YOU KNOW, IT'S IMPORTANT
FOR PEOPLE TO UNDERSTAND WHEN
YOU TALK ABOUT THIS CONDITION OF
ACUTE PSYCHOSIS THAT A CRIME, A
HEINOUS ACT LIKE THIS CAN BE
PREMEDITATED.
AND CAN BE METHODICALLY EXECUTED
IN SOMEONE WHO IS ACUTELY
PSYCHOTIC.
THAT'S WHERE THE MENTAL ILLNESS
COMES IN.
>> WE'LL BE TALKING ABOUT THAT
IN THE DAYS TO COME.
OF COURSE, THERE'S ALWAYS THAT
DEBATE ABOUT GIVING A SUSPECT IN
ANY OF THESE CASES ANY MORE
ATTENTION THAN THEY DESERVE.
BUT WE OBVIOUSLY DO IT TO TRY TO
PREVENT IT FROM HAPPENING AGAIN.
I WANT TO TURN TO YOUR TEAMMATE,
DR. BESSER WHO'S AT THE SCENE
NOW.
THE MOST IMPORTANT PEOPLE TO
FOCUS ON, TONIGHT, OF COURSE,
AND THIS AFTERNOON, AND INTO THE
WEEKEND, ARE THOSE CHILDREN WHO
WERE SHUTTLED OUT OF THAT SCHOOL
TODAY AND WHAT TO SAY TO THEM.
RICH, YOU'RE A DAD, TOO.
THE QUESTION FOR YOU TONIGHT,
IS, WHAT WILL YOU SAY TO YOUR
OWN CHILDREN?
>> YOU KNOW, THAT'S A TOUGH ONE,
DAVID.
AND, YOU KNOW, EVERYONE KNOWS
THEIR OWN CHILD BEST.
SO YOU REALLY WANT TO DEAL WITH
THEM BASED ON THEIR AGE, AND
THEIR OWN PERSONALITY.
VERY YOUNG CHILDREN, CHILDREN
WHO ARE IN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL OR
YOUNGER, IF IT'S POSSIBLE TO
SHIELD THEM FROM THIS SO THEY
DON'T EVEN KNOW ABOUT IT, THAT'S
THE BEST APPROACH.
IF THEY'RE A LITTLE OLDER THAN
THAT, IF THEY'RE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL UP TO MIDDLE SCHOOL, YOU
WANT THEM TO BE ABLE TO TALK TO
YOU ABOUT WHAT THEY'RE FEELING.
YOU WANT TO BE ABLE TO TALK TO
THEM IN CLEAR LANGUAGE ABOUT
WHAT YOU'RE FEELING.
BUT OVERALL, YOU WANT TO GIVE
THEM THAT SENSE THAT THEY ARE
SAFE, THAT THIS WAS A BAD MAN
WHO DID THIS, THIS WAS SOMEONE
WHO WASN'T WELL AND HE'S NOT
AROUND ANYMORE.
THE POLICE DID THEIR JOB.
THAT WILL GIVE THEM THAT FEELING
OF SECURITY.
HUGS, PHYSICAL CONTACT, CAN BE
VERY, VERY IMPORTANT TO
COMMUNICATING THAT SENSE OF
WELLBEING.
WHEN YOU'RE LOOKING AT OLDER
KIDS, I HAVE TEENAGERS, MY KIDS,
THEY WANT TO TALK ABOUT THIS.
WHY DID THIS HAPPEN?
HOW COULD IT HAVE BEEN
PREVENTED?
WHAT CAN THEY DO IN THEIR LIVES
RIGHT NOW TO TAKE CHARGE TO MAKE
SURE THAT THESE THINGS DON'T
KEEP HAPPENING SO OFTEN?
AND SO UNDERSTANDING YOUR CHILD,
LETTING THEM TALK, LETTING THEM
KNOW THAT YOU'RE FEELING BAD
ABOUT THIS, THAT YOU'RE FEELING
SAD, THAT YOU'RE ANGRY, THOSE
THINGS ARE ALL VERY IMPORTANT TO
DO DURING THIS PHASE.
>> RICH, THANKS SO MUCH.
I KNOW YOU'RE THERE ON THE
SCENE.
HAVE YOU HAD A CHANCE TO TALK
WITH ANY OF THESE FAMILIES, TO
HEAR HOW THIS COMMUNITY IS
DEALING WITH THIS?
WE KNOW IT INITIALLY, YOU KNOW,
BEGAN AT THAT 9:30 CALL THAT
WENT INTO AUTHORITIES AND THEN
THAT SORT OF -- THAT
TECHNOLOGICAL SIDE OF THE TIMES
THAT TEXT ALERT THAT WENT OUT
SAYING TO PICK UP YOUR CHILDREN
AT THAT FIREHOUSE, WHICH WAS
JUST AROUND THE CORNER FROM THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
AND, YOU KNOW, IN THE BEGINNING,
WHAT WAS EARLY REPORTED WAS THAT
PARENTS DIDN'T ACTUALLY KNOW
WHICH SCHOOL THEY WERE TALKING
ABOUT.
YOU CAN ONLY IMAGINE THE FEAR
THAT STRIKES IN ANY PARENT.
I'M CURIOUS IF YOU'VE BEEN ABLE
TO TALK TO ANY MEMBERS OF THAT
COMMUNITY.
THEY'VE BEEN DESCRIBED AS CLOSE
KNIT AND THEY LIKELY ALL KNOW
EACH OTHER AND ARE PULLING
TOGETHER ALREADY.
BUT WHAT HAVE YOU SEEN?
>> YOU KNOW, I HAVEN'T HAD A
CHANCE TO TALK TO ANYONE YET,
DAVID.
THE POLICE HAVE BARRICADED OFF
THAT AREA.
THERE ARE LONG LINES OF PEOPLE
TRYING TO GET CLOSE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY OF THEM
ARE FAMILY AND HOW MANY OF THEM
ARE MEDIA.
BUT THESE ARE THE SORT OF E
EVENTS THAT DO PULL COMMUNITIES
CLOSER TOGETHER.
THIS IS A TIME WHEN YOU NEED TO
REACH OUT TO YOUR FRIENDS, TO
YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD, TO YOUR
NEIGHBORS, AND TO THOSE PEOPLE
WHO MAY BE ALONE AND MAKE SURE
THAT THEY ARE WELL -- THEY'RE
BEING WELL CARED FOR AND THAT
THEY HAVE SOMEONE WHO IS GIVING
THEM THE EMOTIONAL SUPPORT THAT
YOU ARE GIVING YOUR OWN FAMILY.
>> AND, RICH, FOR THE STUDENTS
THERE AT SANDY HOOK, I MEAN,
THIS IS A K-4 SCHOOL.
IT'S AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE KNOW TWO OF THE ROOMS
TARGETED.
ONE OF THEM WAS A KINDERGARTEN
CLASS.
IN CASES THEY JUST SHUT TOWN THE
SCHOOL FOR A COUPLE WEEKS.
WE DON'T KNOW IF THEY'LL HAVE
CLASS NOW THROUGH WHAT WAS GOING
TO BE THEIR CHRISTMAS HOLIDAY
AND THEIR NEW YEAR'S HOLIDAY IN
JUST A COUPLE OF WEEKS' TIME.
MOW DO YOU CONVINCE STUDENTS AT
THIS SCHOOL, STUDENTS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY, BUT IN PARTICULAR AT
THIS SCHOOL THAT WHEN THEY GO
BACK THAT THEIR CLASSROOM, THAT
THEIR HALLWAYS ARE SAFE?
>> YOU KNOW, THAT'S A GREAT
QUESTION.
AND I THINK THEY'RE GOING IT
LOOK FOR SOME EXPERT OPINION
ABOUT WHEN TO LET CHILDREN BACK
INTO THIS SCHOOL.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT COUNTRIES THAT
FACE A LOT OF TERRORISM, ONE OF
THE THINGS THAT THEY TRY AND DO
RIGHT AWAY IS TO NORMALIZE THE
SITUATION.
AND REMOVE ANY SIGN OF THE EVENT
THAT TOOK PLACE.
YOU KNOW, WE HAVEN'T BEEN INSIDE
THIS SCHOOL.
THERE HASN'T BEEN A LOT OF
INFORMATION ABOUT THAT.
BUT THE MORE THEY CAN DO TO MAKE
THAT AREA LOOK NORMAL SO THAT
WHEN KIDS EVENTUALLY GO BACK
INTO THAT SCHOOL, IT LOOKS LIKE
THEY REMEMBERED IT AS A SAFE
PLACE, THAT WILL BE VERY
IMPORTANT IN TERMS OF HEALING.
>> RICH BESSER THERE ON SCENE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
DR. RICHARD BESSER.
WE'LL BE CHECKING IN WITH YOU
THROUGHOUT OUR COVERAGE.
VIEWERS JOINING US, 15 MINUTES
PAST 4:00 EASTERN TIME, MY
FRIEND, COLLEAGUE, DIANE SAWYER
WILL BE ANCHOR FROM THE SCENE, A
ONE HOUR EDITION OF "WORLD
NEWS."
SHE'S BEEN ON THE SCENE MUCH OF
THE DAY AND TALKED WITH PARENTS
EARLIER WHO DESCRIBED A CHAOTIC
SCENE WHEN THEY GOT THERE.
SOME OF THE TEACHERS, VERY
CALMLY TELLING CHILDREN TO COVER
THEIR EYES AS THEY WERE WALKING
OUT.
IN FACT, ONE OF THE IMAGES THAT
STRUCK ME WAS THE FATHER WHO
HELD HIS OWN HAND, HIS OWN ARM
OVER HIS SON'S EYE, DOING THE
SHIELDING FOR HIM.
ON YOUR SCREEN, JUST A QUICK
LOOK AT OUR PROGRAMS.
WE'LL BE COVERING THIS OBVIOUSLY
THROUGHOUT THE EVENING.
"WORLD NEWS" OF COURSE WITH
DIANE.
"2020."
"NIGHTLINE" TONIGHT.
THROUGHOUT THE NIGHT.
"GMA" THROUGH THE MORNING.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE YOU THROUGH
THE AFTERNOON.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO LEAVE YOU.
FOR THOSE OF YOU WHO HAVE TO
LEAVE THE TV, ABCNEWS.COM, FIND
THE LATEST DEVELOPMENTS.
I WANT TO BRING YOU UP TO SPEED
ON WHAT WE'VE LEARNED.
THE PORTRAIT OF THE SCHOOL IS
THE CLEAREST WE'VE HAD YET SINCE
THIS TRAGEDY BEGAN UNFOLDING
THIS MORNING.
AS WE LOOK BACK TO IMAGES OF
THAT SCENE, HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW.
WE KNOW 18 CHILDREN DIED INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL.
THERE WERE TWO ROOMS, IT'S
BELIEVED, THE SUSPECT ACTUALLY
TARGETED.
ONE OF THEM WAS A KINDERGARTEN
CLASS WHERE HIS MOTHER WAS THE
TEACHER.
TWO OF THE CHILDREN WHO HAD BEEN
SHOT THEY HOPED TO BE ABLE TO
SAVE.
WE SAW THE IMAGES OF THE
AMBULANCES GOING TO THE SCHOOL.
THEY RUSHED THE TWO CHILDREN TO
AN AREA HOSPITAL AND THEY, TOO,
DIED AT THE HOSPITAL.
WE ARE TOLD.
YOU CAN SEE THE ANGUISH ON THESE
FACES HERE.
AS WE GO DOWN THE LIST AND THE
NUMBERS HERE.
6 ADULTS WERE ALSO KILLED AT THE
SCENE.
SO IT'S 18 CHILDREN, 6 ADULTS.
TWO ADDITIONAL CHILDREN AT THE
LOCAL HOSPITAL.
AND THEN WHAT WE DON'T KNOW, AND
WE'RE WAITING FOR MORE REPORTING
FROM OUR JUSTICE TEAM, LED BY
PIERRE THOMAS, IS THE ADDITIONAL
SCENE WHERE WE BELIEVE FROM
LIEUTENANT PAUL VANCE OF
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE THAT
THERE IS ONE MORE SCENE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, WHERE
AUTHORITIES CONTINUE TO
INVESTIGATE THAT THERE'S AN
ADDITIONAL ADULT WHO HAS DIED AT
THAT SCENE, BUT THEY WERE VERY
RELUCTANT TO OFFER ANY MORE
DETAILS BECAUSE OF HOW EARLY WE
ARE IN THE INVESTIGATION.
THIS LITTLE BOY HERE, AND THE
MOTHER, THE ANGUISH AND ONE OF
THE THINGS THAT WE'VE TALKED
ABOUT HERE, JEN, IS THAT THE
CHILDREN, THEMSELVES, WALKING
SINGLE FILE OUT OF THAT SCHOOL,
ONE OF THE VERY EARLY REPORTS AS
WE WERE SITTING HERE ON THE DESK
WAS FROM SOMEONE ON THE SCENE
WHO SAID THEY COULD HEAR THE
CRIES, A LITTLE BIT OF
WHIMPERING, BUT THERE WAS NO
SCREAMING.
THE CHILDREN DID EXACTLY WHAT
THEY WERE TOLD.
THAT THE REAL EMOTION CAME FROM
THE ADULTS AND THE TEENAGERS AT
THE MIDDLE SCHOOL, THE HIGH
SCHOOL WHO WERE WORRIED ABOUT
THEIR OWN YOUNGER SIBLINGS AT
THE SCHOOL.
THEY HAD A BETTER GRASP OF THE
HORROR THAT WAS UNFOLDING.
YOU CAN SEE IN THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN THE REACTIONS.
>> WHAT REALLY STRIKES ME,
DAVID, WE SEE THOSE IMAGES WHICH
ARE SO DISTRESSING.
YOU KNOW, THE PARENTS AS
STRESSED AND UPSET AND CONCERNED
AS THEY ALL CERTAINLY APPEAR TO
BE, THEY'RE DOING THEIR JOBS AND
THEIR JOBS IS TO TRY AND FIND
THEIR CHILDREN AND TO TRY AND
PROTECT THEIR CHILDREN AND TO
TRY TO REMOVE THEIR CHILDREN
FROM THAT SCENE.
THAT'S WHAT THE TEACHERS DID.
THAT'S WHAT THE FACULTIES' TASK
IS.
TO SOME EXTENT, THAT'S WHAT THE
FIRST RESPONDERS TRIED TO DO
AFTER THE SCENE WAS AS SECURED
AS POSSIBLE.
BUT MAKE NO MISTAKE ABOUT IT,
DAVID, JUST AS WE'LL SEE THIS
FROM THE CHILDREN, WE'LL ALSO
EXPECT AND SEE FROM THE ADULTS,
FROM THE PARENTS WHO WERE AT THE
SCENE, EVEN FROM THE FIRST
RESPONDERS, ONCE THEY'RE ALONE
AND KNOW THEIR CHILDREN ARE
SAFE, THIS WILL TAKE ITS TOLL ON
THEM.
THERE'S NO QUESTION.
I MEAN, IT'S IMPOSSIBLE NOT TO.
>> ONCE IT SETTLES IN, YOU HAVE
TO HAND IT TO THE BRAVERY OF
THESE TEACHERS WHO KEPT THOSE
KIDS FOCUSED ON THE SOLE
PURPOSE, THE SOLE TASK AT HAND
WHICH WAS TO GET OUT OF THAT
SCHOOL AND GET TO THE FIREHOUSE
RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER.
I WANTED TO PLAY FOR YOU A
MOTHER AND A DAUGHTER WHO DAN
HARRIS SPOKE TO A SHORT TIME
AGO.
SHE WAS ONE OF THE LITTLE GIRLS
IN THE SCHOOL WHO GOT OUT AND
HER BRAVERY WAS REALLY
SOMETHING.
SHE TALKED ABOUT THE EMOTION AND
QUITE FRANKLY ABOUT HOW SHE FELT
ON THE INSIDE.
HERE'S DAN'S MOMENT WITH THAT
MOTHER AND DAUGHTER.
>> Reporter: YOU WERE IN THERE,
ALEXIS?
>> YES.
>> Reporter: WHAT HAPPENED?
>> NOTHING REALLY MUCH.
JUST, WE HEARD, LIKE, AN
AMBULANCE COME AND POLICE
OFFICER COME.
EVERYBODY WAS SCARED CRYING.
I FELT A LITTLE SICK.
I FELT LIKE I WAS GOING TO THROW
UP.
TO MY TEACHER, TOO.
>> Reporter: HOW DID YOU GET OUT
OF THERE?
>> WE HAD TO GO THROUGH THE
BUILDING AND THEN WE HAD TO JUST
GO TO THE FIREHOUSE.
>> Reporter: AND DID YOU KNOW
WHAT WAS HAPPENING AT THE TIME?
>> NO.
UNTIL OUR NEXT DOOR NEIGHBOR
MRS. WALKER, ONE OF OUR FRIENDS
FROM -- AND THEN SHE SAID THAT
IF THERE'S A LOCKDOWN, JUST YOU
HAVE TO BE CALM AND THEN JUST
HER CLASS CAME INTO OUR ROOM AND
THEN WE JUST --
>> Reporter: WERE KIDS CRYING
AND SCREAMING?
>> YEAH.
KIDS WERE CRYING.
NOT REALLY SCREAMING BUT THEY
FELT -- THEY'RE ALL HUDDLING
TOGETHER AND THEY GOT, THEY FELT
SO SICK.
>> Reporter: AND HOW OLD ARE
YOU?
8.
>> Reporter: YOU'RE 8 YEARS OLD.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME AGAIN?
>> Reporter: ALEXIS.
>> WHAT'S YOUR LAST NAME?
>> WASIK.
>> Reporter: HOW DO YOU SPELL
THAT?
>> W-A-S-I-K.
>> Reporter: HOW DID YOU FIND
OUT ABOUT THIS?
>> THEY HAVE AN ALERT SYSTEM
THROUGH THE SCHOOL.
THEY SENT A MESSAGE SAYING -- I
DON'T REMEMBER THE MESSAGE.
SOMETHING ABOUT LOCKDOWN.
AND SO WE'RE JUST -- I FIGURED
IT WAS THE HIGH SCHOOL.
LITTLE DID I KNOW THAT IT WAS
ACTUALLY HERE.
SO I ACTUALLY CALLED MY HUSBAND
AND SAID, CAN YOU GO FIND OUT
WHAT ACTUALLY -- WHAT ARE THEY
TALKING ABOUT?
HE GOES, GET IN THE CAR AND
DRIVE, GO GET HER, I'LL MEET YOU
AT THE SCHOOL.
HE GOT HERE.
I GOT HERE.
HE WAS ACTUALLY -- HE HAD HER IN
HIS ARMS AND, YOU KNOW, CRYING,
AND SO SHE'S JUST -- SHE GOES,
MAMA, I'M OKAY, I'M HERE.
BUT IT JUST DOESN'T EVEN SEEM
REAL.
I MEAN, I STILL, LIKE, REALLY?
I MEAN, HERE IN NEWTOWN?
IN THIS SMALL TOWN?
YOU KNOW, YOU READ ABOUT THIS
EVERYWHERE ELSE, BUT HERE.
AND IT'S JUST -- IT'S HEART
WRENCHING FOR THE CHILDREN AND
FOR THE PARENTS AND GRANDPARENTS
AND EVERYBODY.
JUST, I JUST CAN'T -- I CAN'T
FATHOM.
IT JUST DOESN'T EVEN SEEM REAL.
IT'S LIKE SHOULD I BE PINCHED TO
SEE IF IT REALLY IS REAL?
JUST, IT'S JUST HEART WRENCHING.
>> Reporter: FEELS LIKE A DREAM
AND A BAD DREAM.
>> IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
IT FEELS LIKE A NIGHTMARE.
YOU JUST NEVER IN A MILLION, IN
A MILLION YEARS WOULD YOU EVER
THINK, YOU KNOW, YOU DROP YOUR
CHILD OFF AT SCHOOL, HUGS AND
KISSES, HAVE A GOOD DAY, I'LL
SEE YOU LATER.
AND SEE YOU AT THE END OF THE
DAY.
AND YOU NEVER KNOW.
YOU KNOW?
ARE YOU STILL GOING TO HAVE --
YOU KNOW, IN 20 MINUTES FROM
NOW, WHAT'S GOING TO HAPPEN?
AND YOU COUNT YOUR BLESSINGS
EVERY DAY FOR WHAT YOU HAVE.
>> Reporter: ALEXIS, I'M REALLY
GLAD YOU'RE OKAY.
REALLY GLAD YOU'RE OKAY.
YOU'RE PRETTY TOUGH.
>> WE ARE, TOO.
>> Reporter: THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
I'M SORRY TO --
>> VERY TOUGH.
THAT MOTHER SAYING COUNTING YOUR
BLESSINGS AND WE'LL ALL BE DOING
THAT ACROSS THIS COUNTRY AND
HUGGING OUR CHILDREN TONIGHT.
WHEN THEY GET HOME FROM SCHOOL.
AS THIS HAS BECOME A NATIONAL
TRAGEDY.
THERE ARE IMAGES ALREADY FROM
THE WHITE HOUSE TONIGHT.
THEY HAVE SAID THAT FLAGS WILL
BE LOWERED TO HALF-STAFF AT
GOVERNMENT BUILDINGS ACROSS THIS
COUNTRY, AT FEDERAL BUILDINGS.
WE SAW VERY EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA ABOUT AN HOUR AGO.
THE MOST EMOTIONAL, QUITE
FRANKLY, THAT WE'VE SEEN HIM AS
PRESIDENT.
AND NOT SURPRISINGLY GIVEN HOW
OFTEN HE'S TALKED ABOUT HIS ROLE
AS A DAD, BEING EQUALLY AS
IMPORTANT, IF NOT MORE THAN HIS
ROLE AS THE PRESIDENT.
AND YOU SEE THE FLAG THERE
FLYING AT HALF-STAFF.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A TOUGH
STORY TO GET THROUGH OVER THE
NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS.
WE'RE GOING TO SWING THROUGH ALL
OF OUR REPORTERS WORKING THIS
AND LET'S BEGIN WITH DAN HARRIS
AT THE SCENE.
DAN, THERE WOULD SEEM TO BE A
COUPLE OF OUTSTANDING ISSUES WE
DON'T KNOW THE ANSWERS TO YET.
AND FORGIVE ME FOR PUT YOU ON
THE SPOT.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW, BUT IT'S
UNCLEAR WHEN THE GUNMAN WAS IN
THE BUILDING WHETHER OR NOT
AUTHORITIES ACTUALLY GOT TO HIM
OR WHETHER HE TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT THE SECOND
SCENE THERE IN NEWTOWN, THE
CONNECTICUT STATE POLICE TALKING
ABOUT THERE BEING A SECOND SCENE
WITH ANOTHER ADULT?
BUT WE'RE RELUCTANT TO ADD
ANYTHING MORE.
I'M WONDERING IF YOU'VE HEARD
ANYTHING THERE ON THE GROUND.
>> Reporter: I THINK YOU'VE PUT
YOUR FINGER ON THE TWO HUGE
OUTSTANDING QUESTIONS.
I WOULD ADD A THIRD WHICH IS
WHAT WAS THE MOTIVE OF THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER?
WHY WOULD HE DO THIS?
IT MAY, AS OFTEN IS THE CASE IN
THESE STORY THAT YOU AND I HAVE
COVERED SO FREQUENTLY, DAVID, IN
THE LAST COUPLE YEARS, THE
MOTIVE IS OFTEN DEEPLY
UNSATISFYING AND ILLOGICAL BUT
WE STILL DON'T KNOW THAT.
AS TO THE QUESTIONS YOU RAISED,
WAS HE KILLED BY POLICE OFFICERS
OR WAS HE, DID HE DO THE DEED
HIMSELF?
WE SHOULD KNOW MORE SOON ON THAT
WHEN POLICE HOLD A NEWS
CONFERENCE.
DAY WERE, AS YOU SAID, RELUCTANT
TO SAY, WE JUST DON'T KNOW AT
THIS POINT.
WE DO KNOW THAT THERE WAS AN
ENORMOUS RESPONSE HERE.
HERE IN THIS WOODSY LITTLE
NEIGHBORHOOD CALLED SANDY HOOK
WHICH IS PART OF NEWTOWN.
SO NAMED FOR A SORT OF BEND IN
THE RIVER THAT RUNS THROUGH THIS
NEIGHBORHOOD.
A SANDY BEND IN THE RIVER.
IN THIS NEIGHBORHOOD, WE'VE HAD
THIS STARK JUXTAPOSITION TODAY
OF HAVING ALL OF THESE TACTICAL
TEAM OFFICER, PEOPLE IN FULL,
FULL ARMOR, WITH THEIR LONG GUNS
DRAWN.
THEY RESPONDED IN A MASSIVE WAY
WHEN THE REPORTS CAME IN OF THIS
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
SO IT'S UNCLEAR WHETHER THEY
TOOK THE SHOOTER'S LIFE OR
WHETHER HE, AS I SAID, DID THE
DEED, HIMSELF.
THE OTHER QUESTION, OF COURSE,
THERE IS A SECOND CRIME SCENE
HERE TONIGHT.
THERE IS ANOTHER BODY PRESENT AT
ANOTHER LOCATION.
WE BELIEVE, AS YOU SAID, AN
ADULT.
POLICE STILL WORKING THAT SCENE.
WE HOPE TO HAVE ANSWERS ON BOTH
OF THOSE FRONTS IN THE NOT TOO
DISTANT FUTURE WHEN THE POLICE
HOLD ANOTHER BRIEFING.
>> I CAN SEE THE EMERGENCY
TRUCKS BEHIND YOU.
YOU'VE BEEN THERE ON THE SCENES
REALLY FOR HOURS SINCE THIS
MORNING WHEN THE FIRST CALL CAME
INTO THE NEWSROOM.
ONE OF THE STRIKING THINGS THAT
WE LEARN FROM THIS PRESS
CONFERENCE A SHORT TIME AGO IS
THAT FIRST OF ALL WE BELIEVE
ONLY THREE PEOPLE WERE TAKEN TO
AREA HOSPITALS.
AND NOW WE'VE LEARNED THAT TWO
OF THEM WERE CHILDREN WHO DID
NOT SURVIVE.
SO ONE OF THE REALLY STARK
THINGS ABOUT THIS PARTICULAR
SCHOOL SHOOTING IS THE FACT THAT
SO FEW PEOPLE HAD A CHANCE TO
GET OUT OF THAT SCHOOL.
SO FEW STUDENTS AND TEACHERS WHO
WERE TARGETED EVEN HAD A CHANCE,
WERE CARRIED OUT BY THOSE
AMBULANCES.
>> Reporter: RIGHT.
RIGHT.
AND, YOU KNOW, ONE OF THE SAD
THINGS THAT WE'VE SEEN HERE
TODAY, AMONG MANY, MANY SAD
THINGS, AND YOU AND I HAVE
DISCUSSED THIS, DAVID, IS TO SEE
AMBULANCES LEAVING THE SCENE
HERE DRIVING SLOWLY, THEIR
LIGHTS NOT FLASHING.
THEY WOULD MUCH RATHER, ONE HAS
TO IMAGINE, HAVE IN THEIR CARGO
LOAD PATIENTS WHO NEED TO BE
TREATED.
THE FACT OF THE MATTER HERE IS
THIS SHOOTER WAS ALL TOO
SUCCESSFUL AND HE WAS ABLE TO
TAKE OUT A LOT OF VERY YOUNG,
YOUNG PEOPLE AS THE PRESIDENT
CALLED THEM, BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN,
AND IT'S AN INCREDIBLY SAD FACT.
ONLY THREE PEOPLE TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITAL.
WE KNOW TWO OF THEM CHILDREN.
BOTH OF THEM, UNFORTUNATELY,
DECEASED.
YOU MENTIONED THIS PLACE WHERE
I'M STANDING.
THIS IS THE LOCAL FIREHOUSE.
IT'S JUST UP THE STREET JUST A
LITTLE BIT FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THIS IS KIND OF THE EMOTIONAL
EPICENTER OF THIS STORY BECAUSE
THIS IS WHERE PARENTS WERE TOLD
TO COME TO PICK UP THEIR
CHILDREN.
SO ALL DAY LONG, WE'VE BEEN
WATCHING THESE ASTONISHINGLY
EMOTIONAL REUNIONS.
YOU SAW THE PARENT AND CHILD
ALEXIS AND HER MOM SPEAKING
EARLIER ABOUT WHAT IT WAS LIKE
TO FINALLY BE REUNITED AFTER
THIS SCARE.
WHAT WE'VE ALSO SEEN ARE THE
PARENTS WHO ARE NOT GOING TO BE
REUNITED.
20 PARENTS, 20 FAMILIES,
SHATTERED BY WHAT HAPPENED AT
THE LITTLE SCHOOL RIGHT DOWN
THIS LITTLE ROAD HERE TODAY AND
THIS LITTLE TOWN IS NOW, AS YOU
POINTED OUT, DAVID, IN THE
HISTORY BOOKS FOR ALL THE WRONG
REASONS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
DAN HARRIS.
WITH US ALL DAY LONG.
WE'LL SEE YOU AGAIN SHORTLY.
DAN, OUR THANKS TO YOU.
I WANT TO BRING IN PIERRE
THOMAS, SENIOR JUSTICE
CORRESPONDENT TONIGHT.
WE'LL TAKE YOU THROUGH EACH OF
THE POINTS HERE.
FIRST OF ALL, PIERRE, FOR THOSE
WATCHING AND JUST TUNING IN,
WHAT DO WE KNOW TONIGHT ABOUT
THE SUSPECT?
>> AGAIN, LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS WERE INITIALLY TOLD
THAT THE SUSPECT WAS IDENTIFIED
AS A RYAN LANZA.
THERE'S NOW SOME INFORMATION
THAT IT'S, IN FACT HIS BROTHER
ADAM LANZA.
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS ARE
TRYING TO GET DEFINITIVE CLARITY
ON THAT.
AS SOON AS WE KNOW THAT IS
DEFINITIVELY, ONE BROTHER OR THE
OTHER, WE'LL GET THAT
INFORMATION OUT.
AGAIN, THE INFORMATION IS THAT
THE SHOOTER IS DEAD AT THE
SCENE.
AS WE'VE REPORTED ALL AFTERNOON.
THE SUSPECT'S MOTHER, WE DO KNOW
THAT, WHO WAS AN EMPLOYEE AT THE
SCHOOL, WAS ALSO AMONG THOSE
KILLED ALONG WITH THOSE
CHILDREN.
AND THE LAW ENFORCEMENT
OFFICIALS NOW ARE NOW TRYING TO
SORT THROUGH PERSON'S BACKGROUND
TRYING TO GET SOME SENSE OF WHAT
THE MOTIVE MAY HAVE BEEN FOR
THIS TRAGIC SHOOTING.
>> SO THE QUESTION AT THIS HOUR
IS WHICH OF THESE TWO NAMES HAS
BEEN ATTACHED TO THE SUSPECT BY
AUTHORITIES.
THERE'S SOME QUESTION OF WHETHER
IT'S ADAM LANZA OR RYAN LANZA.
THEY'RE BOTH BROTHERS.
AS THEY SORT THROUGH THAT,
PIERRE, THE RELATIONSHIP WITH
THE WOMAN TARGETED, THE TEACHER
TARGETED IN THE SCHOOL, WOULD BE
THE SAME REGARDLESS OF WHICH
NAME IS ACTUALLY FINALLY SETTLED
UPON BY AUTHORITIES.
IF THIS WAS -- THE MOTHER,
CORRECT?
>> THAT IS CORRECT.
AS ONE SOURCE SAID, LOOK, YOU
HAVE A DEAD SUSPECT AT THE
SCENE, AGAIN, THE INITIAL
INFORMATION PROVIDED BY LOCAL
AUTHORITIES, THE FEDERAL
OFFICIALS HAVE BEEN WORKING OFF
THAT INFORMATION.
BUT THEY ARE NOW BECOMING
INCREASINGLY CERTAIN THAT IT'S
PROBABLY GOING TO BE ADAM LANZA,
BUT, AGAIN, WE'LL KNOW MORE
SHORTLY.
>> BUT THIS WOULD BE A SON GOING
INTO A SCHOOL WHERE HIS MOTHER
WAS A TEACHER, AND IT WOULD
APPEAR TARGETING HER
KINDERGARTEN CLASS.
>> WELL, THAT IS THE INFORMATION
THAT THE PEOPLE WHO WERE AT THE
SCHOOL WERE -- THE TARGET WAS AT
THE SCHOOL, AGAIN, THE THOUGHT,
THE EARLY THOUGHT IS THAT THE
MOTHER LIKELY WAS THE INITIAL
TARGET.
>> WRAP YOUR HEAD AROUND THE
NUMBERS, PIERRE, AS THEY'VE
UNCOVERED THIS AFTERNOON.
YOU'VE COVERED A NUMBER OF
TRAGEDIES FOR US, PARTICULARLY
SCHOOL SHOOTINGS AROUND THE
COUNTRY.
THIS ONE, AS WE LOOK AT THE
NUMBERS.
18 CHILDREN.
TWO ADDITIONAL CHILDREN AT THE
HOSPITALS.
THIS WILL GO DOWN AS THE
DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTING AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN THIS
COUNTRY.
>> AWFUL, AWFUL SITUATION, AS A
FATHER OF A 10-YEAR-OLD, I OFTEN
GO TO HIS SCHOOL AND I RING THE
BUZZER AND THEY LET ME WALK INTO
THE SCHOOL.
THIS IS THE KIND OF SITUATION
WHERE NO PARENT COULD EVEN
FATHOM OF SOMETHING LIKE THIS
HAPPENING.
AGAIN, AS WE TALKED TO MANY OF
THE LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS
TODAY, WHO WERE TRYING TO GET
THE INFORMATION, TRYING TO
ASSESS WHAT WAS GOING ON, YOU
COULD HEAR THE SADNESS IN THEIR
VOICES AS WELL, DAVID.
>> PIERRE, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU BEEN WORKING YOUR SOURCES
THROUGHOUT THE DAY HERE ON
WHAT'S BEEN A VERY DIFFICULT
STORY.
IF I COULD, I WOULD LOVE TO TAKE
OUR VIEWERS BACK TO THAT IMAGE.
THE FLAG ABOVE THE WHITE HOUSE
TONIGHT.
BECAUSE THIS HAS BECOME A
NATIONAL TRAGEDY.
IN TIMES OF TRAGEDY, THIS
COUNTRY DOES COME TOGETHER AND
LEADING THAT EFFORT WAS THE
PRESIDENT THIS AFTERNOON WHO
SAID BEFORE THE COUNTRY THAT HE
ADDRESSES THIS, REACTS TO IT
INITIALLY, AS A PARENT, NOT A
PRESIDENT.
FLAGS ARE NOW AT HALF-STAFF, AND
INSIDE THAT WHITE HOUSE TONIGHT,
HE DESCRIBED A SCENE THAT WILL
UNFOLD.
HE AND HIS WIFE, MICHELLE, HE
SAID, WILL HUG THEIR DAUGHTERS
WHEN THEY GET HOME FROM SCHOOL
JUST AS EVERY PARENT ACROSS THIS
COUNTRY, AND JAKE, HE WASN'T
OVERTLY POLITICAL, BUT HE DID --
HE DID OFFER A LITTLE BIT OF
INSIGHT INTO WHERE HE'S THINKING
THAT THIS CONVERSATION ABOUT HOW
TO PREVENT THIS HAS GOT TO MOVE
FORWARD IN SOME SORT OF
CONSTRUCTIVE FASHION.
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT,
DAVID.
CONSIDERING HOW MUCH PRESIDENT
OBAMA HAS AVOIDED TALKING OR
ACTING FOR GUN CONTROL, HE
ORIGINALLY WHEN HIS POLITICAL
CAREER BEGAN AS A STATE SENATOR,
WAS VERY ACTIVE IN GUN CONTROL.
AND EVEN SOMEWHAT AS A U.S.
SENATOR, BUT AS A PRESIDENTIAL
CANDIDATE, HE HAS NOT TALKED
MUCH ABOUT IT.
CERTAINLY AS A PRESIDENT, HAS
NOT DONE MUCH ABOUT IT.
HE ALLUDED TO IT TODAY, TALKING
ABOUT HOW WE NEEDED TO COME
TOGETHER AS A SOCIETY TO PREVENT
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS FROM
HAPPENING AGAIN.
NO MATTER WHAT THE POLITICS ARE.
THAT WOULD SEEM TO ME, BASED ON
COVERING HIM FOR R THE LAST FIVE
OR SIX YEARS, TO BE AT LEAST A
NOD TOWARD GUN CONTROL, WHETHER
IT IS HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINE
CLIPS, OR KEEPING GUNS OUT OF
THE HANDS OF PEOPLE WITH A
HISTORY OF MENTAL AND EMOTIONAL
PROBLEMS.
I CAN'T TELL YOU.
BUT IT WAS AT LEAST AN ALLUSION
TO IT WHICH IS MORE THAN WE'VE
HEARD FROM HIM IN THE PAST.
BUT BEYOND THE POLITICS OF IT,
DAVID, OF COURSE, THERE WAS THE
RAW EMOTION OF IT.
I'VE COVERED PRESIDENT OBAMA, AS
I SAID, FOR MORE THAN HALF A
DECADE.
HE IS NOT KNOWN AS A
PARTICULARLY DEMONSTRATIVE OR
OVERLY HISTRIONIC PERSON WHEN IT
COMES TO HIS EMOTIONS.
HE WAS TEARFUL TODAY IN A WAY
THAT I HAVE NOT SEEN HIM EXCEPT
FOR A COUPLE TIMES, THE DEATH OF
HIS GRANDMOTHER WHO HELPED RAISE
HIM SHORTLY BEFORE THE ELECTION
IN 2008 WOULD BE ONE OF THOSE
TIMES.
BUT HE'S NOT SOMEBODY WHO IS
EMOTIONAL, BUT HE REALLY HAD TO
COLLECT HIMSELF A FEW TIMES
DURING HIS REMARKS, NOT JUST
WITH WIPING TEARS FROM HIS EYES
BUT TAKING A MOMENT, SO AS TO
SEEMINGLY TO GIRD HIMSELF
EMOTIONALLY TO PREVENT HIMSELF
FROM HAVING TO BREAK DOWN.
HE DID REACT, AS HE SAID HE DID
INITIALLY AS A FATHER, AS
SOMEBODY WHO IS FEELING
DEMONSTRABLE GRIEF ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED TODAY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
OF COURSE, WE ALL KNOW HIS
DAUGHTER, SASHA AND MALIA, WHO
ARE NOW 11 AND 14 YEARS OLD, HE
SAID HE AND THE FIRST LADY
TONIGHT WOULD DO WHAT SO MANY
PARENTS WILL DO ACROSS THIS
COUNTRY, HOLD HIS DAUGHTER, HOLD
THEIR DAUGHTERS A LITTLE BIT
TIGHTER TONIGHT.
AND, OF COURSE, HE NOTED ALL
THOSE FAMILIES IN CONNECTICUT
THAT WILL NOT BE ABLE TO DO THE
SAME, DAVID.
>> WE WERE LOOKING AT IMAGES AS
YOU WERE DESCRIBING THE
PRESIDENT WIPING AWAY THOSE
TEARS ALONG WITH YOUR
DESCRIPTION OF HIM THERE IN THE
BRIEFING ROOM.
AND YOU AND I JUST COVERED THIS
BRUISING CAMPAIGN, BUT ONE THING
HIS CHALLENGER, GOVERNOR ROMNEY
SAID THROUGH THE CAMPAIGN, WHEN
ASKED WHAT DO YOU RESPECT THE
PRESIDENT FOR?
AND HE OFTEN SAID, HIS ROLE AS A
FATHER.
THAT HE'S A DEDICATED FAMILY
MAN.
AND THAT MOMENT OF EMOTION THERE
AT THE WHITE HOUSE TODAY WILL
LIKELY BE WELCOMED BY PARENTS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY BUT IN
PARTICULAR IN THAT ONE
COMMUNITY, JAKE.
>> Reporter: INDEED.
AND, IN FACT, ONE THING THAT IS
NOT AS INTERESTING AND NOT AS
IMPORTANT, BUT CERTAINLY I TOOK
NOTE OF AS WELL, WHILE THE
PRESIDENT WAS SPEAKING TO THE
SIDE, WERE THAT HIS PRESS
SECRETARY AND ONE OF HIS DEPUTY
CHIEFS OF STAFF, AS IS NORMAL,
BUT IN THIS INSTANCE, THEY WERE
HOLDING HANDS.
AND WIPING AWAY TEARS
THEMSELVES.
THIS IS THE KIND OF THING
BECAUSE THE PRESIDENT, WHOMEVER
HE IS, IS THE COMMANDER IN
CHIEF, THE CARETAKER OF THE
NATION, RESPONSIBLE FOR KEEPING
PEOPLE IN THIS COUNTRY SAFE.
THAT IS THE NUMBER ONE
RESPONSIBILITY OF THE PRESIDENT.
EVENTS LIKE THIS, ALTHOUGH THEY
CAN'T BE COMPARED TO HOW HARD
IT'S HITTING PEOPLE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THEY DO HIT RATHER
HARD HERE.
BECAUSE PEOPLE HERE FEEL
RESPONSIBLE FOR THE WELLBEING OF
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
ESPECIALLY CHILDREN.
AND SO IT IS VERY SAD HERE
TODAY, DAVID.
>> ALL RIGHT.
SENIOR WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT, JAKE TAPPER THERE
AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
WHERE HE'S BEEN ALL DAY
FOLLOWING THE PRESIDENT AND HIS
BRIEFINGS.
JAKE, THANK YOU.
WE'LL TALK TO YOU AGAIN SOON.
IN THE MEANTIME, I WANT TO BRING
IN MY FRIEND CHRIS CUOMO, OF
"2020" IN SHADY BROOK,
CONNECTICUT.
THE COMMUNITY SURROUNDING THAT
SCHOOL.
CHRIS, YOU SAID YOU WERE INSIDE
ONE OF THESE HOMES AS THIS
PLAYED OUT TONIGHT.
THE UNCERTAINTY AND FINDING OUT
THE ANSWERS.
DO YOU KNOW ANYTHING MORE ABOUT
THE TEXT MESSAGES THAT WENT OUT,
THAT IMMEDIATE ALERT THAT SENT A
SHOCKWAVE THROUGH THIS ENTIRE
COMMUNITY?
PARENTS DIDN'T KNOW AT FIRST
REALLY WHICH SCHOOL, CERTAINLY
DIDN'T KNOW WHETHER OR NOT THEY
WOULD FIND THEIR CHILDREN WHEN
THEY GOT TO THAT FIREHOUSE.
>> THAT'S EXACTLY RIGHT, DAVID.
THE FIRST WORD THAT THESE
PARENTS HEARD WAS "LOCKDOWN."
AND IMAGINE THAT.
YOU'VE GOT A KID IN A K-4 AND
YOU'RE HEARING THE WORDS
"LOCKDOWN."
THEN THE PHONE TREE STARTS.
AND THAT IT'S A SHOOTER AND THAT
THERE ARE INJURIES AND THEN
EVERYBODY IN THIS SMALL
COMMUNITY RUSHES THIS PLACE, THE
PLACE HAS BEEN CHOKED WITH
TRAFFIC ALL DAY.
AND THEY COULDN'T GET WITHIN A
QUARTER MILE OF THE SCHOOL, SO
THEN THEY RUN UP TO THE SCHOOL.
POLICE ARE HECTIC AND HURRIED AT
THE SAME TIME.
THERE'S RUMOR OF A SECOND
SHOOTER.
THESE PARENTS ARE DESPERATE FOR
THEIR KIDS.
THEY WIND UP COMING TO A
FIREHOUSE.
HOLDING UP SIGNS.
DESPERATELY SEARCHING AROUND.
ALL THESE KIDS ALL LOOK THE SAME
WITHIN THAT AGE RANGE.
OVER TIME THEY START CONNECTING
WITH A FACE, THEY SEE A
TEACHER'S AIDE, SEE A TEACHER,
SEE THEIR OWN KID.
LIVES FROM FROM THE DARKEST OF
MOMENTS INTO THE MOST GUILTY OF
FEELING GOOD IN A SITUATION
BECAUSE YOU HAVE YOUR KID.
I SAT WITH THESE MOTHERS AND
FATHERS TODAY WHO DIDN'T KNOW
WHERE THEIR KID WAS AND DIDN'T
KNOW WHICH WAY IT WAS GOING TO
GO.
THERE WERE OTHER PARENTS WHO
LOST THEIR KIDS TODAY.
AND THEN THEY WOUND UP HAVING
THEIRS COME HOME.
AND THEY'RE COMING TOGETHER IN
THEIR HOMES, THEY'RE COMING
TOGETHER IN EACH OTHER'S ARMS IN
WHAT IS UNFIXABLE.
IN TERMS OF THE PAIN AND THE
SENSELESSNESS.
WE'VE HEARD IT ALL BEFORE, BUT
FOR THESE FAMILIES, IT'S ALL NEW
AND THEY'RE ALL TRYING TO HANDLE
WHAT TO TELL THEIR KIDS.
IT'S ONE OF THE COMPLICATING
FACTORS OF THIS STORY FOR THE
VICTIMS AND EVEN FOR EVERYONE
INVOLVED.
WHAT DO YOU TELL THE KIDS WHO
ARE AT THE CENTER OF IT WHO ARE
TOO YOUNG TO UNDERSTAND WHAT
HAPPENED?
YOU DON'T WANT THEM TO KNOW
THESE TYPES OF THINGS.
THAT'S HOW YOUNG THOSE KIDS
WERE, DAVID.
THAT'S WHAT THE FAMILIES ARE
STRUGGLING WITH TONIGHT.
>> YOU KNOW THE CALENDAR, IT'S
DECEMBER 14th.
THE COUNTDOWN IS ON TO
CHRISTMAS.
AND YOU'RE A DAD, YOURSELF.
YOU KNOW THEY HAVE AN INTERNAL
CLOCK.
THEY WAKE UP EVERY MORNING
KNOWING HOW MANY DAYS UNTIL
SANTA COMES.
>> YOU KNOW, THESE PARENTS, I
WATCHED THEM.
YOU WATCH THEM, YOU KNOW, THEY
SHATTER A LITTLE BIT LISTENING
TO THEIR LITTLE GIRL.
SHE'S GOT NEW TEETH IN THE FRONT
OF HER MOUTH.
SHE'S TALKING ABOUT AN AMERICAN
GIRL DOLL.
AND THAT'S WHAT WAS ON HER MIND
THIS MORNING.
IT'S WHAT SHOULD HAVE BEEN ON
HER MIND THIS MORNING.
THE NEXT THING SHE HEARS ARE
LOUD BANGS.
WE KNOW WHAT THEY WERE.
SHE DIDN'T.
AND THE TEACHER KEEPING THEIR
POISE IN THE WORST OF MOMENTS.
AND SHE COULD KEEP FOCUSED ON
CHRISTMAS.
SHE'S TOLD TO CLOSE HER EYES
TIGHTLY AND SHE DOES BECAUSE
SHE'S SO YOUNG.
SHE DOESN'T EVEN KNOW WHAT SHE
MOVES PAST.
WHAT'S INSIDE THAT SCHOOL RIGHT
NOW.
WHICH FAMILIES ARE NEVER GOING
TO RECOVER FROM.
AND THIS BEING AT CHRISTMAS IS A
MIXED SITUATION, BECAUSE AT
ONCE, IT MAKES IS SO MUCH WORSE
BECAUSE YOU WERE SO CLOSE TO
SOMETHING THAT WAS GOING TO MAKE
PEOPLE HAPPY.
YET, MORE FAMILIES HERE THAN NOT
WHO GOT CHRISTMAS EARLY TODAY.
THE NUMBERS ARE STAGGERING.
NO ONE COULD TAKE IT AWAY.
WE DON'T KNOW HOW MANY KIDS ARE
LEFT INSIDE THAT SCHOOL YET.
BUT THESE FAMILIES, A LOT OF
THEM GOT CHRISTMAS EARLY, DAVID,
BECAUSE THEY HAVE A GIFT THAT
FOR MOMENTS TODAY THEY DID NOT
KNOW THAT THEY WERE GOING TO
HAVE.
THAT IS A PAIN FOR THE PARENTS.
>> YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY RIGHT,
CHRIS.
FOR THE CHILDREN, SANTA WILL BE
PLAYING A MORE OUTSIZED ROLE
THIS YEAR, FROM AN ESCAPE OF
WHAT IT IS THEY JUST SURVIVED.
I WANT TO CHECK BACK IN WITH
PIERRE THOMAS.
OBVIOUSLY HE'S BEEN TRYING TO
SORT THROUGH THIS DEVELOPING
INVESTIGATION.
THERE HAD BEEN SOME QUESTION
ABOUT WHICH OF THE TWO SONS
MIGHT HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN
TARGETING THEIR MOTHER.
ACCORDING TO AUTHORITIES.
PIERRE, ARE WE ANY CLOSER?
>> Reporter: YES, WE HAVE AT
LEAST TWO SOURCES NOW WHO HAVE
GONE BACK AND DOUBLE CHECKED THE
INFORMATION.
THE INITIAL INFORMATION WAS
PROVIDED, WAS RYAN LANZA.
THEY'RE NOW SAYING THEY'RE
PRETTY MUCH CERTAIN, CERTAIN
THAT IT'S GOING TO TURN OUT TO
BE ADAM LANZA WHO WAS 20 YEARS
OLD.
THE YOUNGER BROTHER.
WHO THEY BELIEVE TO BE THE
PERSON WHO WENT INTO THE SCHOOL
AND DID THE SHOOTING.
>> AND THERE'S SOME REPORTING,
PIERRE, THAT THE OTHER BROTHER
IS BEING QUESTIONED A THIS
POINT.
WHAT CAN YOU ADD TO THAT?
>> I DON'T HAVE ANY CLARITY ON
THAT YET, BUT ANY PERSON WHO'S
ASSOCIATED WITH THE BELIEVED
SHOOTER IS A PERSON THAT WILL BE
TALKED TO BY LAW ENFORCEMENT.
>> AND, OF COURSE, THE BIG
QUESTION, AT THIS HOUR, AMONG
MANY, IS THE SECOND SCENE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, PIERRE,
AND IS THERE ANY MORE GUIDANCE
ON WHAT THEY'RE SEARCHING FOR
AND WHO THE PERSON IS WHO'S
DECEASED AT THAT LOCATION?
>> AGAIN, ALL WE KNOW SO FAR,
IT'S ANOTHER PERSON WHO'S DEAD.
SOMEHOW ASSOCIATED WITH THE
YOUNG MAN WHO IS BELIEVED TO
HAVE DONE THE SHOOTING.
AGAIN, NO DIRECT CONFIRMATION
EXACTLY WHO THAT IS YET.
>> PIERRE, WE'LL CHECK BACK IN
WITH YOU SHORTLY.
I WANT TO CHECK IN WITH YOUR
COLLEAGUE, JIM, WHO IS UP FROM
WASHINGTON, AND IN THE REGION
COVERING THE STORY.
AND, JIM HAS BEEN LOOKING INTO
THE FAMILY DYNAMIC, TOO.
AND I KNOW SO LITTLE IS KNOWN AT
THIS POINT, BUT JIM, CAN YOU
SHED ANY LIGHT ON THE FAMILY
THAT WE'RE TALKING ABOUT HERE,
THE LANZA FAMILY, THE MOTHER WHO
IS THE KINDER GARDEN TEACHER,
AND, OF COURSE, TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHICH OF THE CHILDREN
INVESTIGATORS ARE ZEROING IN ON.
>> LOOK, DAVID, JUST FOLLOWING
UP ON WHAT PIERRE JUST REPORTED,
IF INDEED THE SHOOTER TURNS OUT
TO BE ADAM, I JUST SPOKE WITH A
LOCAL REALTOR HERE NAMED BARBARA
FRY WHO IS A NEIGHBOR OF THAT
FAMILY.
HER SON WENT TO SCHOOL AT THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WITH ADAM.
SHE DESCRIBED TO ME THAT ADAM,
IN FACT, WAS A BIT OF A TROUBLED
CHILD.
THAT SHE DESCRIBES THE MOTHER AS
SAYING THAT -- DESCRIBES THE
MOTHER SAYING HE HAD ASPERGER'S
AND ALSO SUFFERED FROM OCD.
SHE QUOTES THE MOTHER AS SAYING
THAT.
SHE ALSO SAYS THE MOTHER, SHE
KNEW THE MOTHER BRIEFLY AND THAT
THE MOTHER WAS A DIGNIFIED
WOMAN, IS WHAT SHE SAID, BUT
THAT SHE WAS A VERY STRICT
PARENT.
AND THAT SOMETIMES HER SON,
ADAM, WOULD REBEL AT THAT AS HER
CHILDREN GREW UP WITH ADAM.
SO THAT'S THE BEGINNING OF A
PORTRAIT WE'RE GETTING OF THE
FAMILY WE'RE GETTING FROM HERE,
IF IT IS ADAM, HE MAY HAVE HAD
SOME KIND OF TROUBLE, SOME KIND
OF LEARNING DISABILITY, OCD OR
ASPERGER'S OF SOME KIND.
THAT'S WHAT WE'RE GETTING FROM
PEOPLE HERE.
WE'VE ALSO BEEN REPORTING ON THE
SCHOOL, ITSELF, DAVID.
I'LL JUST TELL YOU THAT THIS IS
A VERY SPECIAL SCHOOL, AND I
MEAN THAT IN THE TERMS OF
HONORED AND, AN HONORED SCHOOL,
A SCHOOL WHERE PEOPLE, IN FACT,
MOVE TO NEWTOWN SO THEY COULD GO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN GO TO THIS
SCHOOL.
IN FACT, PARENTS OFTEN HAD
LONGER COMMUTES BUT THEY WANTED
TO LIVE HERE BECAUSE THE SCHOOL
WAS SO GOOD AND THE TEACHERS
WERE SO -- HAD SUCH A GREAT
REPUTATION.
>> AND, JIM, WE REPORTED THIS
EARLIER, STICK WITH US HERE,
BECAUSE THIS SCHOOL SEEMED TO BE
DOING EVERYTHING RIGHT WHEN IT
COMES TO PROTECTING YOUR
CHILDREN.
WHEN YOU TRAVEL TO THESE SCHOOLS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY TO DO STORIES
OR IF YOU'RE A PARENT OR UNCLE
AND GOING TO PICK UP THE
CHILDREN FROM SCHOOL, OFTEN
THERE ARE THESE PROCEDURES IN
PLACE, NOT METAL DETECTERS,
ALTHOUGH THERE ARE SOME OF THOSE
AT SCHOOLS IN THIS COUNTRY.
MORE OFTEN IT'S THE CASE THAT
YOU WALK IN, THERE'S SOME SORT
OF CAMERA INVOLVED AND A SIGN-IN
DESK IN THE OFFICE AND THAT'S
EXACTLY WHAT THEY HAD DONE JUST
THIS YEAR IS TO ADD SOME SORT OF
VISUAL MONITORING SYSTEM.
YOU GET THROUGH THAT, HAVE TO GO
TO THE OFFICE, SHOW I.D.
THEY EVEN SENT OUT A LETTER
SAYING IT MIGHT BE A BIT OF A
HASSLE, BUT PLEASE UNDERSTAND US
THAT WE HAVE TO DO THIS IN
ASKING FOR I.D.
CERTAINLY WE NOW KNOW HOW
IMPORTANT THAT IS.
BUT AS YOU POINT OUT, THIS WOULD
SEEM TO BE A SCHOOL THAT WAS
TRYING TO DO JUST ABOUT
EVERYTHING IT COULD FOR THE
WELLBEING, THE WELFARE OF ITS
LITTLE CHILDREN.
>> YES.
I JUST SPOKE WITH A FORMER
STUDENT WHO'S NOW IN COLLEGE WHO
WENT TO SANDY HOOK, AND SHE SAID
THAT WHEN SHE WAS IN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THERE, THEY EVEN HAD
DRILLS BACK THEN.
AND THAT THE PARENTS, THE
TEACHERS WOULD TELL THE CHILDREN
THAT WE'RE HAVING A DRILL NOW,
AND THEY WOULD HAVE TO GO TO THE
CORNERS OF THE CLASSROOM AND
THEY WOULD HAVE TO BE QUIET AND
WAIT FOR FURTHER INSTRUCTION AND
THEY WERE TOLD IN ADVANCE HOW TO
HANDLE THIS.
AND THAT'S, IN FACT, A YOUNG
STUDENT TOLD ME THAT WHEN SHE
HEARD TODAY ABOUT THESE STORIES
OF THESE LITTLE KIDS RUNNING
INTO CLOSETS AND HIDING IN
CLOSETS AND HIDING FROM A
GUNMAN, THAT, IN FACT, IT SENT
CHILLS UP HER SPINE BECAUSE SHE
REMEMBERED THOSE DRILLS AND WHAT
THESE KIDS WERE GOING THROUGH.
>> YEAH.
>> SO IT IS A VERY DIFFICULT
TIME FOR EVERYBODY IN THIS
COMMUNITY.
BECAUSE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IS SORT OF THE JEWEL OF
THIS COMMUNITY AND SOMETHING
THAT THE SCHOOL HAD HAD A
REPUTATION FOR SOMETHING TOTALLY
DIFFERENT.
>> LET'S JUST SAY IT'S STILL A
JEWEL TONIGHT BECAUSE, JIM, AS
YOU KNOW, ON THIS END OF
REPORTING THE STORY, WE'VE BEEN
WATCHING THE IMAGES OF THESE
DEDICATED TEACHERS,
EXTRAORDINARY BRAVERY AS THEY
TOOK THOSE CHILDREN OUT OF THE
SCHOOL TODAY.
WE CAN SEE SOME OF THE CLERGY,
THIS NUN HERE IN THIS IMAGE
ARRIVING AT THE SCENE.
AS WE CONTINUE TO LOOK AT IMAGES
JUST COMING INTO US NOW, I WANT
TO BRING JEN ASHTON, A DOCTOR
WITH OUR MEDICAL TEAM, IN ON THE
CONVERSATION.
YOU WERE NODDING YOUR HEAD AS
JIM TALKED ABOUT, REALLY A WAY
OF LIFE IN SCHOOLS IN AMERICA
RIGHT NOW.
THESE DRILLS THAT STUDENTS GO
THROUGH.
EVEN AT THE VERY YOUNGEST OF
AGES WHICH MIGHT EXPLAIN WHY
THEY WERE SO CALM AND FOLLOWED
EVERYTHING RIGHT DOWN TO A "T"
IN GETTING OUT OF THAT SCHOOL
TODAY.
>> YEAH.
I THINK THIS IS A REALITY OF THE
TIMES IN WHICH WE LIVE, DAVID.
MY OWN CHILDREN HAVE LOCKDOWN
DRILLS REGULARLY AT THEIR SCHOOL
AND THEY EXPLAIN THEM AND
DESCRIBE THEM TO ME IN EXPLICIT
DETAIL.
YOU KNOW, THEY ARE TOLD THAT
THEY HAVE 60 SECONDS TO GET INTO
THE CLOSEST BUILDING, THE
TEACHERS LOCK THE DOORS.
THEY ARE THEN INSTRUCTED TO GO
INTO CLASSROOMS WHERE THEY ARE
TOLD TO GET UNDER DESKS, IN THE
CORNER OF THE ROOM.
THE SHADES ARE PULLED.
THE CLASSROOM DOORS ARE LOCKED.
I MEAN, THESE THINGS ARE REALLY
ROUTINE NOW MANY MANY, MANY
SCHOOLS.
SO I THINK THAT EVEN AT THESE
YOUNG AGES IN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS, YES, THESE DRILLS WERE
PRACTICED AS ANY DISASTER DRILL
IS PRACTICED.
UNFORTUNATELY, YOU NEVER WANT TO
NEED TO USE THOSE SKILLS, BUT
THEY ARE UNFORTUNATELY ROUTINE
NOW IN MANY, MANY SCHOOLS.
MY CHILDREN'S INCLUDED.
>> THEY WERE EMPLOYED TODAY, AND
I WANT TO KEEP WITH THESE
PICTURES HERE NOW IF WE COULD.
BUT, JEN, I WAS STRUCK BY THE
CHILDREN INSIDE THAT FIRST GRADE
CLASSROOM.
THE TEACHER WHO SAID SHE HAD
THEM HIDING IN THE BATHROOM IN
THE CLASSROOM.
AND ONE OF THE FIRST INSTINCTS,
THESE ARE FIRST GRADERS, WAS TO
ASK, HOW ARE THE OTHER KIDS OUT
THERE?
IS THERE ANYONE ELSE OUT THERE
WE CAN GET INTO THE BATHROOM?
>> WHEN YOU SEE A DISASTER LIKE
THIS, DAVID, YOU SEE REFLEX
BEHAVIOR, INSTINCTIVE BEHAVIOR
AND REACTION BECOME AUTOMATIC.
>> BUT AT 6 YEARS OLD.
>> INSTINCT AND REACTIONS OF
THOSE 6-YEAR-OLDS, INSTINCTS AND
REACTIONS OF ANY ADULT THERE.
IF YOU HAVE EVER BEEN AROUND A
CHILD, WHETHER YOU'RE A PARENT
OR NOT, YOU KNOW THAT YOUR
INSTINCTIVE HUMAN REACTION IS TO
PROTECT THAT CHILD.
THAT'S WHAT THESE TEACHERS DID.
AND THE CHILDREN, YOU KNOW, YES,
THEY'RE BRAVE, YES, THEY'RE
SELFLESS, BUT THEIR INSTINCTS
KICK IN AND WE SEE THAT ACROSS
THE BOARD WITH THIS TYPE OF
TRAGEDY HERE.
>> WE'RE LOOKING AT PICTURES
NOW, PARENTS, OR PERHAPS
GRANDPARENTS PICKING UP THEIR
CHILDREN TODAY.
THE AMBULANCES THAT ARRIVED WITH
THEIR LIGHTS GOING AND THEN AS
DAN HARRIS REPORTED EARLIER,
PARKED THERE.
THE LIGHTS TURNING OFF.
THAT WAS ONE OF THE THINGS I
HEARD FROM ONE DOCTOR TODAY WHO
SAID WHAT THEY WERE EXPECTING
WAS TO DEAL WITH AN INFLUX OF
PATIENTS WHO HAD BEEN CARRIED IN
FROM THE HOSPITAL.
INSTEAD WHAT THEY GOT WAS A
SITUATION VERY MUCH LIKE WHAT WE
SAW ON 9/11, WAS THAT EMERGENCY
ROOMS WERE READY AND NO ONE
CAME.
>> RIGHT.
LET ME TAKE YOU INSIDE THE
HOSPITAL, DAVID, TO THESE CLOSE
HOSPITALS.
THESE TRAUMA CENTERS.
TO WHAT THEY WOULD HAVE BEEN
DOING IN PREPARATION FOR THIS
TYPE OF MASS CASUALTY TRAUMA
SITUATION.
THEY IMMEDIATELY STOP ALL
ELECTIVE SURGERY, THEY WILL
CLEAR OUT THE TRAUMA BAYS IN THE
EMERGENCY ROOM.
THEY NOTIFY THE BLOOD BANK.
THEY MAKE SURE THEY HAVE MASSIVE
READY AMOUNTS OF BLOOD
TRANSFUSIONS AVAILABLE FOR THE
INCOMING PATIENTS.
AND THEY DESIGNATE SOMETIMES
BETWEEN 10 AND 20 MEDICAL
PERSONNEL PER PATIENT AND
UNFORTUNATELY AT THIS TIME, THEY
GOT VERY, VERY FEW,
UNFORTUNATELY, THAT WERE AROUND.
BUT, YOU KNOW, THIS TYPE OF
DISASTER DRILL, TRAUMA DRILL,
ROUTINE AT ANY LEVEL 1 TRAUMA
CENTER.
>> WE WANT TO BRING IN BRAD
GARRETT, WHO'S AN FBI PROFILER,
FORMALLY WITH THE FBI AND WORKS
WITH US HERE AT ABC NEWS.
BRAD, AS WE LOOK AT THIS AND WE
TRY TO LEARN MORE ABOUT WHICH OF
THESE TWO BROTHERS IT WAS, WHAT
DOESN'T CHANGE IS THE
RELATIONSHIP THAT THIS WAS --
THIS WAS SON AND THIS WAS
MOTHER.
SHE WAS A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER.
AND FOR SOME REASON THE SUSPECT
APPEARED AT HER DOORWAY TODAY
AND THAT'S GOING TO BE A HUGE
PART OF THIS AS WE MOVE FORWARD.
>> I THINK ONE OF THE MORE
INTERESTING REPORTINGS IS THAT
IF WE HAVE THE RIGHT SON, HE HAD
SOME LEARNING DISABILITIES.
SO YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT A CHILD
EXCLUDING WHAT HAPPENED TODAY
GROWING UP MORE FRUSTRATED, MANY
TIMES FEELING MORE ALIENATED
BECAUSE THEY HAVE DIFFICULTIES
DEVELOPING RELATIONSHIPS.
AND SO TO GO BACK TO WHAT WE
BRIEFLY TALKED ABOUT EARLIER,
THIS SORT OF GOES UP AND IT
ESCALATES AS THEY GET OLDER,
THEY GET MORE ANGRY.
AND SO RESULT, I THINK HE JUST
COULDN'T TAKE IT ANY MORE AND HE
WANTED TO EMPOWER HIMSELF.
AND UNFORTUNATELY HE CHOSE A
HORRIBLE WAY TO DO IT.
>> IT ALMOST SOUNDS -- SOME ARE
TALKING ABOUT THIS NOTION OF
SOME SORT OF A SUICIDE MISSION,
IF YOU HAVE A SUSPECT.
WE CLEARLY DON'T KNOW WHETHER OR
NOT HE TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
IF THAT'S THE CASE IN GOING TO
TWO DIFFERENT LOCATIONS, THE
MOTHER NOW DEAD.
THE TEACHER.
AND 18 CHILDREN IN THAT SCHOOL
IN TWO SEPARATE ROOMS, MANY OF
THE CHILDREN IN HER OWN
CLASSROOM AND THEN THE TWO
CHILDREN WHO DIED AT THE
HOSPITAL LATER.
THIS IS SOMEONE WHO LOOKED INTO
THAT CLASSROOM AND SAW
5-YEAR-OLDS SITTING THERE AND
STILL WAS ABLE TO, CAPABLE
OBVIOUS PULLING THIS OFF WHICH
IS JUST IMPOSSIBLE TO
COMPREHEND.
>> BUT THEY WEREN'T 5-YEAR-OLDS
TO HIM.
THEY WERE JUST OBJECTS.
THEY WERE SOMETHING THAT WAS
CONNECTED TO HIS MOTHER.
YOU HAVE TO WIPE AWAY ANY
EMPATHY, ANY BELIEF OR FEELING
THAT HE HAS ABOUT ANYONE ELSE
EXCEPT HIMSELF.
THIS IS ALL ABOUT ME.
THESE MASS SHOOTERS COULD CARE
LESS ABOUT THE REST OF US.
THAT THEY ARE GOING TO GET --
THEY'RE GOING TO SEEK REVENGE
AND IF THE PERSON THAT WRONGED
THEM IS TOUCHING OTHER PEOPLE,
THEY'RE GOING TO GET RID OF
THEM.
SO IF IT ENDS UP BEING THAT THE
SHOOTER, MR. LANZA, SHOT
HIMSELF, DOESN'T SURPRISE ME.
I TELL YOU WHY.
THEN HE'S ACTUALLY CONTROLLING
THE ULTIMATE END TO HIS LIFE.
THAT HE TOOK HIS LIFE BEFORE HE
ALLOWED LAW ENFORCEMENT TO TAKE
IT.
SO, LIKE, YOU'RE NOT GOING TO
TALK TO ME, I'M GOING TO TAKE
THIS WITH ME.
SO WE HAVE SEEN THAT ACROSS THE
BOARD IN THESE SHOOTINGS.
>> BRAD, STAY WITH US HERE.
YOU'VE BEEN SO HELPFUL
THROUGHOUT THE DAY.
IT'S STILL HARD FOR ANYONE TO
ACCEPT THAT SOMEONE COULDN'T
HAVE EMPATHY FOR CHILDREN
SITTING IN A SCHOOL CLASSROOM.
BUT THAT'S THE MENTAL HEALTH
COMPONENT OF THIS.
AND WHY WE NEED TO REPORT THAT
IN THE COMING DAYS, TOO SO WE
CAN TRY TO SEE THESE WARNING
SIGNS BEFORE SOMETHING LIKE THIS
CAN DEVELOP.
BUT WE'VE LEARNED THAT THERE'S
GOING TO BE A PRAYER VIGIL AT
THE NEWTOWN UNITED METHODIST
CHURCH.
THAT'S THIS EVENING WE BELIEVE.
THEY SECURED A LOCATION THERE
FOR PEOPLE TO COME AND PRAY
TOGETHER.
THIS IS GOING TO BE A COMMUNITY
THAT, AS JIM POINTED OUT, HAD
LONG COME TOGETHER.
THIS WAS A SCHOOL THAT PRIDED
ITSELF ON ITS AWARDS AND WHAT IT
WAS ABLE TO DO FOR ITS CHILDREN,
EDUCATIONALLY.
WE'VE LEARNED ABOUT THE
ADDITIONAL STRATEGIES FOR
KEEPING THEIR CHILDREN SAFE,
EMPLOYED JUST THIS YEAR.
AND TONIGHT, IT'S NOW A
COMMUNITY THAT WILL HUG LIKE THE
HUG YOU SAW THERE JUST NOW ON
THE SCREEN AND COME TOGETHER AT
THIS VIGIL.
THE INVESTIGATION AND THE
PRODUCERS WILL LET ME KNOW WHEN
I HAVE PIERRE THOMAS BACK ON THE
LINE, CONTINUES TONIGHT, AND FOR
THOSE OF YOU JOINING US, LOOKING
FOR YOUR LOCAL NEWS A SHORT TIME
FROM NOW, IN MUCH OF THIS
COUNTRY, WE WANTED TO BRING YOU
UP TO SPEED.
THERE ARE TWO LOCATIONS TONIGHT
WHERE INVESTIGATORS ARE.
THE SCHOOL AND THE SECOND
LOCATION.
IS THAT NOT CORRECT, PIERRE?
>> THAT IS CORRECT.
AND, AGAIN, WE ARE GETTING
ADDITIONAL CONFIRMATION THAT
ADAM LANZA, AGE 20, IS THOUGHT
TO BE THE SHOOTER AS WE JUST
REPORTED A FEW MOMENTS AGO.
OUR LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS
ARE NOW DISSECTING HIS LIFE,
TRYING TO FIGURE OUT WHAT THE
MOTIVE MAY HAVE BEEN.
THEY BELIEVE THAT HE WENT TO THE
SCHOOL IN PART, THE EARLY THEORY
IS, TO KILL HIS MOTHER WHO
WORKED AT THE SCHOOL.
LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS ARE
NOW, WE'RE ALSO BEING TOLD BY A
NUMBER OF SOURCES, SPEAKING WITH
AND INTERVIEWING HIS BROTHER,
RYAN, WHO'S AGE 24.
>> DO WE HAVE ANY IDEA, PIERRE,
ABOUT WHAT HE HAD ON HIS PERSON?
HE'S BEEN DESCRIBED AS WEARING A
VEST CARRYING FOUR WEAPONS, I
BELIEVE, YOU REPORTED EARLIER
TODAY, AND THERE WAS ONE MOTHER
WHO TOLD US EARLIER IN OUR
REPORTING AND TALKING WITH DIANE
SAYING THERE WAS WORD OF A MASK.
YOU WOULD KNOW BETTER THAN ANY
OF US.
CAN YOU DESCRIBE WHAT WE KNOW HE
HAD ON WHEN HE ENTERED THAT
SCHOOL?
>> WHAT WE KNOW OFFICIALLY WE'RE
TOLD AT LEAST TWO HANDGUNS WERE
RECOVERED NEAR THE SHOOTER'S
BODY.
THAT THEY ALSO FOUND SHELL
CASINGS WHICH APPEAR TO BE FROM
A .223 ASSAULT-STYLE RIFLE.
WE DON'T HAVE CONFIRMATION ON IT
YET AS TO WHETHER THAT RIFLE HAS
BEEN RECOVERED.
SO LAW ENFORCEMENT, AGAIN, IS
METICULOUSLY GOING THROUGH THAT
CRIME SCENE TRYING TO GATHER ALL
THE EVIDENCE THEY CAN AS WELL AS
TRYING TO RECONSTRUCT THIS MAN'S
FINAL FEW DAYS.
>> IN THE FOLLOW-UP OF THE
INVESTIGATIONS, THESE ARE THE
KIND OF QUESTIONS THAT GET
CLEARED UP WITH TIME.
THERE WAS SOME INITIAL REPORTING
PERHAPS ONE OF THEM LIVED IN NEW
JERSEY, ONE OF THE SONS, BUT IT
WOULD SEEM THAT THE FAMILY LIVED
IN NEWTOWN, IS THAT CORRECT?
>> WELL, DAVID, YOU KNOW, IN
THESE SITUATIONS, HAVING COVERED
THEM A NUMBER OF TIMES, THERE'S
SO MUCH INFORMATION THAT POLICE
ARE TRYING TO GET.
SOME OF THE EYEWITNESSS TEND TO
HAVE WRONG INFORMATION.
THEY GET INITIAL INFORMATION
FROM THE CRIME SCENE, FROM THE
PERSON'S BODY SOMETIME.
THAT INFORMATION IS SOMETIMES
CONFUSING.
SO, AGAIN, RIGHT NOW, THEY'RE
SIMPLY TRYING TO ASSESS THE
DAMAGE.
THEY NOW KNOW THE NUMBER OF
DEAD.
THEY'VE REMOVED ALL THE PEOPLE
FROM THE SCENE WHO WERE INJURED.
NOW THE DIFFICULT WORK OF WHY?
WHY DID THIS HAPPEN?
IS BEGINNING TO TAKE PLACE.
>> PIERRE, DO WE HAVE ANY UPDATE
ON THE TIMELINE FOR THE PARENTS
WHO ARE STILL WAITING FOR
CONFIRMATION?
HOURS HAVE GONE BY AND MANY KNOW
THE INEVITABLE, BUT DO WE KNOW
HOW THIS WILL PLAY OUT?
THE MOST DIFFICULT PART OF THIS
DAY?
>> WE KNOW THE GOVERNOR, AS YOU
REPORTED EARLIER, SPOKE TO SOME
OF THE PARENTS.
AGAIN, WE DON'T KNOW THE
SPECIFIC DETAILS ABOUT WHAT WAS
SAID ABOUT EACH CHILD WHICH IS
THE MOST DIFFICULT PART.
>> PIERRE, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOUR HARD WORK IN OUR WASHINGTON
BUREAU TODAY.
SO HERE'S WHAT WE KNOW.
REPORTING IN JUST NOW, PIERRE
THOMAS, THE SUSPECT IS BELIEVED
AT THIS HOUR TO BE ADAM LANZA.
HE'S 20 YEARS OLD.
ONE OF THE VICTIMS, HIS MOTHER,
A KINDERGARTEN TEACHER, AND MANY
OF THE CHILDREN INSIDE HER
CLASSROOM.
IN FACT, WE DON'T KNOW IF ANY OF
THE CHILDREN SURVIVED IN THAT
KINDERGARTEN CLASS.
AND SO THE NUMBERS ARE AS
FOLLOW.
18 CHILDREN IN THE SCHOOL.
TWO CHILDREN HAVE BEEN SHOT.
THEY RUSHED THEM TO THE
HOSPITAL.
THAT WAS THE DANBURY HOSPITAL
WHERE THEY HAD SET UP A TRIAGE
AND THE TWO CHILDREN DID NOT
SURVIVE THERE.
SO 20 CHILDREN IN ALL, 6 ADULTS.
WE BELIEVE THAT SOME OF THOSE
ADULTS WERE IN FACT TEACHERS.
OBVIOUSLY THE KINDERGARTEN
TEACHER, THE MOTHER.
WHAT'S NOT KNOWN AT THIS HOUR IS
THAT SECOND LOCATION IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THE ADDITIONAL
ADULT THAT'S ALSO DECEASED.
WE DON'T KNOW THE RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN THEM, BUT WE DO KNOW
THAT THE SUSPECT, AGAIN, AT THIS
HOUR, IS ADAM LANZA, 20 YEARS
OLD AND IT'S HIS BROTHER, RYAN,
WHO MIGHT BE AT THIS HOUR BEING
QUESTIONED.
THAT'S WHAT WE DO NOT KNOW AT
THIS POINT.
WE CERTAINLY DO NOT KNOW WHO
THAT OTHER PERSON IS IN THAT
HOUSE WE TALKED TO.
ONE OF THE THINGS WE DID TALK
ABOUT HERE WITH THE MEDICAL TEAM
IS THE REACTION FROM THE
CHILDREN INSIDE THAT SCHOOL, HOW
CALM THEY WERE, HOW TERRIFIED
THEY WERE BUT HOW CALM THEY WERE
IN GETTING OUT OF THAT SCHOOL.
THEN THE REACTION FROM OLDER
SIBLINGS THAT WERE AT THE MIDDLE
SCHOOL, AT THE HIGH SCHOOL AND
SO WORRIED ABOUT WHETHER OR NOT
THEIR YOUNGER SIBLINGS HAD
SURVIVED.
THERE WAS A 17-YEAR-OLD EARLIER
TODAY, HE TALKED WITH OUR
AFFILIATE WTNH AND IT WAS A
MOMENT THAT I THOUGHT WAS QUITE
POWERFUL ABOUT THE WORRY ONE
SIBLING HAS FOR ANOTHER,
PARTICULARLY WHEN YOU'RE A
TEENAGER AND YOU KNOW THE
BREADTH OF WHAT'S GOING ON.
TAKE A LOOK.
>> Reporter: WHAT DID YOUR
SISTER TELL YOU?
I SAW HER WITH YOU EARLIER.
SHE WON'T EVEN LOOK ANYWHERE
NEAR THE CAMERA.
SHE SEEMS PRETTY HORRIFIED.
WAS SHE ABLE TO EXPLAIN TO YOU
WHAT SHE WITNESSED?
>> WELL, I MEAN, AGAIN, SHE'S
VERY TRAUMATIZED.
WHEN SHE WALKED OUT OF THE
SCHOOL, SHE WAS CRYING.
ALL THE STUDENTS WERE HOLDING
HANDS.
THE TEACHERS WERE TRAUMATIZED.
BUT, YOU KNOW, BASED ON WHAT SHE
SAID WAS, AT ABOUT, LIKE, EARLY
IN THE MORNING, THERE WAS -- SHE
HEARD, LIKE, THE INTERCOM CAME
ON THE SCHOOL AND SHE HEARD A
SCREAM AND SHE HEARD A GUNSHOT
OR TWO GUNSHOTS.
AND THEN THE SCHOOL WENT INTO
LOCKDOWN.
AND WHEN THEY HID IN THE CLOSET.
SHE WAS IN ART CLASS AND THEY
HAD TO HIDE IN THE CLOSET.
THEY WERE QUIET.
THE CHILDREN OBVIOUSLY WERE VERY
SHAKEN.
THEY WERE CRYING IN THE CLOSET.
AND THE CLOSET OF THE ART ROOM.
AND EVENTUALLY, YOU KNOW, THEY
WERE LEAVING AND WHEN THEY WERE
LEAVING, THE POLICE MADE THEM
HOLD HANDS AND THE POLICE TOLD
THEM TO CLOSE THEIR EYES.
>> THE 17-YEAR-OLD WHO TALKED
ABOUT HIS REACTION WHEN HE FOUND
OUT HIS YOUNGER SISTER IN THE
FOURTH GRADE, HIS LITTLE SISTER,
WAS OKAY.
WE WANT TO TAKE YOU BACK TO
IMAGES THAT ARE JUST COMING IN
NOW AS THE SCENE CONTINUES TO
UNFOLD.
AS WE LOOK AT THEM, I WANTED TO
BRING IN JEN ASHTON FROM OUR
MEDICAL TEAM.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT A
17-YEAR-OLD BOY, THIS IS A
TEENAGER.
WE KNOW WHAT YOUNGER SIBLINGS
ARE LIKE, IN THE MAKEUP OF A
HOUSEHOLD.
BOY, DO YOU SEE THE TRUE COLORS
OF A LOVE BETWEEN TWO SIBLINGS
WHEN SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPENS
AND HOW WORRIED AND DEVASTATED
HE WAS AT THE NOTION, THE
THOUGHT HE MIGHT NOT SEE HER.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AND I THINK A LOT OF THAT HAS TO
DO WITH WHAT WE KNOW AS WE GET
OLDER.
WE CAN THEORIZE OR GUESS AND
IMAGINE WHAT THAT 5-YEAR-OLD OR
6-YEAR-OLD OR 7-YEAR-OLD HAS
JUST SEEN, HEARD, FELT.
AND THAT IN AND OF ITSELF IS
MIND-BOGGLING FOR AN ADULT OR
LATE ADOLESCENT.
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT THOSE
CHILDREN, WE USED TO REMEMBER
DEVELOPMENTALLY THEY'RE AT A
STAGE RIGHT NOW WHERE THEY'RE
VERY VULNERABLE.
>> THANK YOU, JEN.
WE WANT TO GO BACK TO
CONNECTICUT NOW.
>> I TOLD YOU THE NUMBER OF
DECEASED IN THE BUILDING AT THE
HOSPITAL, AND AT THE SECONDARY
CRIME SCENE.
IT'S OUR POLICY AND PROTOCOL
THAT WE HAVE TO ESTABLISH
POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION OF THOSE
VICTIMS.
THAT IS A TIME CONSUMING
PROCESS.
THAT'S SOMETHING THAT'S GOING TO
TAKE A GREAT DEAL OF TIME.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER HAS ALREADY
ARRIVED ON THE SCENE.
HE'S GOING TO WORK VERY CLOSELY
WITH US TO EXPEDITE THAT, GET
THAT DONE AS EFFICIENTLY AS
POSSIBLE.
AS I TOLD YOU, THE FAMILIES HAVE
BEEN ASSIGNED A TROOPER, AN
OFFICER, AS A LINE OF
COMMUNICATION.
BUT THAT WAS DONE SPECIFICALLY
TO ENSURE THE FAMILIES THAT THEY
HAVE CONSTANT COMMUNICATION WITH
THIS ONGOING INVESTIGATION AND
THEY WON'T HAVE TO SIT AND WATCH
TELEVISION NEWS OR ANYTHING
ELSE.
THEY WILL BE THE FIRST TO KNOW
ANY OF THE PROGRESS THAT'S MADE
AS THIS INVESTIGATION CONTINUES
ON.
AS I STATED EARLIER, THE ASSETS
THAT WERE UTILIZED INITIALLY
WERE CERTAINLY WHEN THE CALL
CAME IN, NEWTOWN POLICE
DEPARTMENT IMMEDIATELY RESPONDED
AND IMMEDIATELY CALLED FOR HELP.
SURROUNDING LOCAL AGENCIES SENT
OFFICERS AND THE CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE SENT ALL OFF DUTY
AND ON-DUTY TROOPERS TO RESPOND
SO THEY COULD IMMEDIATELY GAIN
ACCESS TO THAT BUILDING AND
BEGIN THAT SEARCH PROCESS THAT I
ALLUDED TO BEFORE.
WE HAD THE STATE POLICE TEAM, WE
HAD K-9 TEAMS OUT HERE.
WE CERTAINLY HAD TROOPER 1 IN
THE AIR.
IT WAS PROBABLY TO KEEP SOME OF
YOUR HELICOPTERS AWAY, QUITE
FRANKLY.
BUT WE HAD EVERY POSSIBLE ASSET.
CAME OUT TO THIS SCENE THE
MINUTE THAT THIS ALARM CAME IN
OR THIS CALL CAME IN AND IT WAS
CERTAINLY TO DO EVERYTHING WE
COULD TO PROTECT CERTAINLY LIFE
AND PROPERTY.
THE COMMUNITY HAS BEEN
OUTSTANDING IN SUPPORTING THIS
EFFORT.
AS YOU CAN SEE, YOU'VE TAKEN
OVER THEIR PARK AND THEY'RE
SHOWING UP.
THEY'RE OFFERING CONDOLENCES.
THEY'RE DOING EVERYTHING THEY
POSSIBLY CAN TO SUPPORT THE
VICTIMS, THE VICTIMS' FAMILIES
OF THIS HORRIFIC TRAGEDY.
THE FBI CRISIS MANAGEMENT TEAM
HAS OFFERED TO RESPOND, GOING TO
RESPOND HERE TOMORROW TO ASSIST
IN CRISIS MANAGEMENT, TO ASSIST
NOT ONLY WITH THE FAMILIES AND
THE FAMILY MEMBERS, BUT WITH ALL
THE FIRST RESPONDERS, THE
POLICE, FIRE, EMS, ALL WORKING
AT WHAT I DESCRIBE BEFORE AS A
VERY HORRIFIC AND DIFFICULT
SCENE.
CERTAINLY LOCAL MENTAL HEALTH
CRISIS INTERVENTION TEAMS HAD
BEEN ON SCENE AND HAVE BEEN HERE
ALL OF TODAY WORKING AND
ASSISTING AND HELPING.
I JUST WANT TO MAKE IT VERY
CLEAR THAT THERE WERE 18
CHILDREN WHO WERE PRONOUNCED
DEAD AT THE SCENE.
THERE WERE TWO CHILDREN
TRANSPORTED TO AREA HOSPITAL
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE HOSPITAL.
THERE WERE SIX ADULTS THAT WERE
PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE SCENE.
AND OBVIOUSLY THE SHOOTER WAS
ALSO PRONOUNCED DEAD AT THE
SCENE.
I DON'T HAVE MUCH MORE DETAIL
ABOUT THAT SECONDARY SCENE, BUT
THERE IS A RELATED SCENE THAT WE
DISCOVERED AS WE WERE CONTINUING
THE CRIMINAL INVESTIGATION AND
SPECIFICALLY INVESTIGATING THE
SHOOTER.
AND YOU PROBABLY SAW AND SOMEONE
ASKED ME ON THE WAY IN HERE
ABOUT THE BOMB SQUAD AND, YES,
WE BROUGHT ALL OUR ASSETS IN IN
CASE THEY WERE NEEDED AND WHEN
WE WENT OUT WITH NEWTOWN
OFFICERS TO SEARCH OR TO EXECUTE
SEARCH WARRANTS, OR TO EXAMINE
OTHER POSSIBLE SECONDARY SCENES,
WE TOOK ALL THOSE ASSETS WITH US
TO MAKE SURE THEY WERE RIGHT
THERE IMMEDIATELY SO WE COULD
REACT IF IT WAS NECESSARY.
THAT'S ABOUT ALL I HAVE AS FAR
AS THE DETAILS ARE CONCERNED.
I WANT TO GIVE YOU ONE MORE
BRIEFING, PROBABLY JUST BEFORE
6:00 WE'LL TRY TO GET BACK UP
HERE FOR ONE MORE BRIEFING.
I'LL TAKE A COUPLE BRIEF
QUESTIONS BUT I MUST, AGAIN,
TELL YOU THERE ARE CERTAIN
THINGS WE CANNOT DISCUSS AT THIS
TIME.
I'LL TAKE IT RIGHT HERE.
[ INAUDIBLE QUESTION ]
>> THAT WAS ONE PERSON WHO WAS
INJURED WHO SUFFERED AN SWRUR
AND DID SURVIVE, YES.
I'M SORRY, I CAN'T CONFIRM.
I KNOW ABOUT THE SECONDARY
SCENE.
I DON'T HAVE TIME TO GET INTO
DETAIL ABOUT THAT.
I'LL TRY TO THAT FOR 6:00.
>> THE SHOOTER'S IDENTITY, ADAM
LANZA --
>> NOT GOING TO CONFIRM THE
IDENTITY OF THE SHOOTER.
WE'RE NOT PREPARED TO DO THAT.
WE HAVE A TENTATIVE
IDENTIFICATION.
WE'RE WORKING WITH THAT.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO CONFIRM THE
IDENTITY AND PUT THAT OUT THERE.
WE WILL, WE WILL IDENTIFY THE
SHOOTER AT AN APPROPRIATE TIME
FOR OUR INVESTIGATE PURPOSES
IT'S NOT APPROPRIATE TO DO THAT
RIGHT NOW.
>> WHAT HAPPENED IN HOBOKEN NEW
JERSEY, THE INVESTIGATION THERE?