>>> SENSELESS, UNTHINKABLE,
INCONCEIVABLE.
THERE ARE NO SHORTAGE OF WORDS
TO DESCRIBE THE TRAGEDY THAT
STRUCK AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
RIGHT HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT TODAY.
BUT WE'VE HEARD ONE WORD
REPEATED OVER AND OVER AGAIN --
WHY.
ABC'S CHIEF INVESTIGATIVE
REPORTER BRIAN ROSS HAS SPENT
THE DAY UNCOVERING DETAILS ABOUT
THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER.
BRIAN?
>> CYNTHIA, HE WAS ARMED TO THE
TEETH WITH LEGALLY PURCHASED
GUNS AND WENT FROM OBSCURITY TO
INFAMY.
UNTIL TODAY, ADAM LANZA WAS
KNOWN MOSTLY IN HIS NEIGHBORHOOD
AS SOMEONE WHO DID NOT PLAY WELL
WITH OTHERS.
ADAM LANZA WAS A CHILD OF AN
AFFLUENT CONNECTICUT TOWN AND
THE CHILD OF DIVORCE.
A FAMILY FRIEND, BARBARA FREY,
TOLD ABC'S JIM AVILA THAT THE
SON WAS TROUBLED AND THE MOTHER
WAS DEMANDING OF HIM.
>> HE WAS NOT CONNECTED WITH THE
OTHER KIDS.
MY SON PLAYED WITH HIM WHEN THEY
WERE YOUNG.
AND IN HER HOME, I KNOW SHE WAS
VERY PARTICULAR.
I JUST THINK SHE MAYBE HAD TOO
HIGH OF STANDARDS OR SOMETHING.
OR FOCUSED ONLY TOO MUCH FOR
WHATEVER REASON.
>> SO WAS THERE CONFLICT?
WAS THERE SOME KIND OF TENSION
BETWEEN THE TWO OF THEM?
PARENT AND CHILD?
>> NOT THAT I KNOW OF, BUT I
THINK THE FACT THAT THE PARENTS
WERE DIVORCED MUST HAVE
CONTRIBUTED TO IT.
>> Reporter: TONIGHT, ADAM'S
BROTHER RYAN AND HIS FATHER
PETER, A GE TAX LAWYER, WERE
QUESTIONED BY THE FBI AND POLICE
IN NEW JERSEY.
LOOKING FOR CLUES AS TO WHAT LED
THE YOUNGEST MEMBER OF THE
FAMILY TO KILL.
SOMEONE BELIEVED TO BE RYAN
LANZA LEFT THE STATION TONIGHT
WITHOUT COMMENT.
>> I THINK THE MOST IMPORTANT
THING TO POINT OUT WITH THIS
KIND OF AN INDIVIDUAL IS THAT HE
DID NOT SNAP JUST THIS MORNING
AND DECIDE TO ACT OUT VIOLENTLY.
THESE CRIMES INVOLVE PLANNING
AND THOUGHTFULNESS AND
STRATEGIZING IN ORDER TO PUT THE
PLAN TOGETHER.
SO WHAT MAY APPEAR TO BE SNAP
BEHAVIOR IS NOT THAT AT ALL.
>> Reporter: AFTER FIRST KILLING
HIS MOTHER AT THE FAMILY HOME,
AUTHORITIES SAY THE YOUNG MAN
HEADED TO THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, WEARING A
BULLETPROOF VEST.
AUTHORITIES SAY HE WAS ARMED
WITH A SEMIAUTOMATIC ASSAULT
RIFLE AND TWO HIGH-POWERED
PISTOLS LIKE THESE.
POLICE SAY BOTH HIS MOTHER AND
HIS FATHER LEGALLY OWNED A
NUMBER OF GUNS OF THE SAME KIND.
A RELATIVE SAID ADAM WAS
OBVIOUSLY NOT WELL.
>> WE'LL GO BACKWARDS AS FAR AS
WE HAVE TO GO IN THIS
INVESTIGATION, AND HOPEFULLY
WE'LL STUMBLE ON ANSWERS.
>> Reporter: BUT WHAT EVEN THE
CRIME PROFILERS ARE HAVING A
HARD TIME TRYING TO FIGURE OUT
IS WHY THE ATTACK ON THE
CHILDREN.
MOST OF THEM KILLED ON THE SPOT,
ACCORDING TO AUTHORITIES.
THE ONLY THEORY IS BASED ON
REPORTS THAT HIS MOTHER,
DIVORCED THREE YEARS AGO AND
UNEMPLOYED, MAY HAVE WORKED AS A
TEACHERS' AIDE AT THE SCHOOL.
>> THE CHILDREN DIDN'T HARM HIM,
BUT THEY WERE ASSOCIATED WITH
HIS MOTHER AND HIS MOTHER MAY BE
THE REAL FOCUS ALL OF THIS.
THE ANGER AND RAGE AND
RESENTMENT HAS BUILT UP IN HIM
OVER A NUMBER OF YEARS, AND HE
DECIDED, I'VE BEEN POWERLESS ALL
THIS TIME, AND NOW I'M GOING TO
EMPOWER MYSELF.
>> Reporter: BUT SO FAR, IT IS
ONLY A THEORY, FOLLOWING A DAY
OF CONFUSION AND MISINFORMATION
ABOUT THE TRAGEDY.
STARTING WHEN STATE AND FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES FIRST IDENTIFIED THE
SHOOTER AS ADAM'S OLDER BROTHER
RYAN, NOW A NEW YORK ACCOUNTANT.
THAT LED TO RYAN POSTING
MESSAGES ON HIS FACEBOOK PAGE.
"IT WASN'T ME.
I WAS AT WORK.
IT WASN'T ME."
BUT WHEN RYAN ARRIVED AT HIS
HOME IN HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY,
POLICE TOOK HIM INTO CUSTODY FOR
QUESTIONING.
AUTHORITIES WANT TO KNOW IF RYAN
OR ANYBODY ELSE IN THE FAMILY
HAD ANY IDEA ADAM WAS
THREATENING TO BECOME VIOLENT.
>> TYPICALLY, I'VE HEARD PEOPLE
SAY, YES, HE SAID THAT, BUT I
DIDN'T TAKE HIM SERIOUSLY.
YES, HE SAID THAT, I THOUGHT HE
WAS JOKING.
I COULDN'T BELIEVE THAT ANYONE
WOULD DO THAT.
I JUST IGNORED HIM.
>> Reporter: IT'S NOT KNOWN IF
ADAM LANZA MADE ANY SUCH
THREATS.
IN THE END, HE APPARENTLY KILLED
HIMSELF AT THE SCHOOL AFTER
KILLING SO MANY OTHERS.
WHAT CRIME PROFILERS SAY IS THE
EXPECTED OUTCOME IN CASES LIKE
THIS ONE.
>> EVERY ONE OF THEM EITHER --
THEY KNOW WHEN THEY GO THAT
THEY'RE GOING TO DIE AT THE
SCENE, EITHER BY THE HANDS OF
THE POLICE OR THEY KILL
THEMSELVES.
>> POLICE KNOW IN HORRIFYING
DETAIL WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL, BUT THEY DON'T YET HAVE
ANY IDEA WHAT HAPPENED INSIDE
THE DAMAGED MIND AND BROKEN SOUL
OF ADAM LANZA, CYNTHIA.
>> THANKS, BRIAN.
>>> JUST AHEAD, THE QUESTION OF
MILLIONS OF AMERICAN FAMILIES
ARE STRUGGLING WITH TONIGHT.
WHAT SHOULD YOU TELL YOUR
CHILDREN ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY?
I HAVE OBLIGATIONS. CUTE
OBLIGATIONS, BUT OBLIGATIONS.
I NEED TO RETHINK THE
CORE OF MY PORTFOLIO.
WHAT I REALLY NEED IS SLEEP.
INTRODUCING THE ISHARES CORE,
BUILDING BLOCKS FOR THE
HEART OF YOUR PORTFOLIO.
FIND OUT WHY 9 OUT OF 10
LARGE PROFESSIONAL INVESTORS
CHOOSE ISHARES FOR THEIR ETFS.
ISHARES BY BLACKROCK.
CALL 1-800-ISHARES FOR A
PROSPECTUS WHICH INCLUDES
INVESTMENT OBJECTIVES,
RISKS, CHARGES AND EXPENSES.
READ AND CONSIDER
IT CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
RISK INCLUDES POSSIBLE
LOSS OF PRINCIPAL.
>>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, CALLER
INDICATING THAT SHE THINKS
SOMEONE'S SHOOTING IN THE
BUILDING.
>> I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING
TO DIE.
>> WE ALL HURRIED INTO MY
TEACHER'S OFFICE.
IT WAS SCARY.
WE HAD TO HIDE THERE.
>> THOSE WHO DIED TODAY WERE
CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
>> WE'RE CONFIDENT THAT WE HAVE
THE SHOOTER IN THIS INCIDENT.
>> MY HEART GOES OUT TO ANYONE
WHO KNEW THEM AND WAS PART OF
THEIR LIVES.
I JUST CAN'T IMAGINE.
>> AND WELCOME BACK TO A SPECIAL
ONE-HOUR EDITION OF "NIGHTLINE."
I'M CYNTHIA McFADDEN REPORTING
FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, NEAR
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, THE SITE OF AN
UNTHINKABLE TRAGEDY THAT PLAYED
OUT THIS MORNING.
AT LEAST 20 YOUNG CHILDREN AND
SIX ADULTS SHOT AND KILLED HERE
IN LESS THAN 30 MINUTES WHEN A
20-YEAR-OLD GUNMAN WENT ON A
RAMPAGE.
TONIGHT WE KNOW THAT SO MANY
PEOPLE ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE
FACING A DIFFICULT CHALLENGE.
HOW TO EXPLAIN SOMETHING SO
HORRIBLE TO THE CHILDREN IN
THEIR LIVES.
ABC'S JUJU CHANG SPENT THE DAY
CONSULTING WITH THE EXPERTS.
>> I WAS IN SHOCK.
>> IT WAS TERRIFYING.
I'M STILL TERRIFIED.
I'M STILL IN SHOCK.
>> Reporter: WHEN ADULTS ARE
LEFT SPEECHLESS BY TRAUMATIC
EVENTS, IT'S HARD TO IMAGINE
WHAT'S GOING ON IN THE MIND OF A
CHILD.
>> WE ARE CONTINUING OUR
BREAKING NEWS COVERAGE.
>> Reporter: ADULTS OFTEN GORGE
ON MEDIA IMAGES, TRYING TO GLEAN
FACTS, GAIN PERSPECTIVE.
>> WHAT WAS THE MOTIVE OF THE
ALLEGED SHOOTER, WHY WOULD HE DO
THIS?
>> Reporter: TO MAKE SENSE OUT
OF A SENSELESS EVENT.
BUT FOR CHILDREN, IT CAN HAVE
THE OPPOSITE EFFECT.
TODAY, PSYCHOLOGISTS AND
PEDIATRICIANS ARE STRONGLY
URGING PARENTS TO SHIELD THEIR
SCHOOL-AGED CHILDREN FROM TOO
MUCH EXPOSURE TO THE NEWS.
>> FOR REALLY YOUNG CHILDREN,
THEY CAN BE CONFUSED AND THINK
THAT THIS IS HAPPENING OVER AND
OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
THEY DON'T NECESSARILY KNOW THAT
IT'S ON LOOP.
FOR OLDER KIDS OR KIDS WHO ARE
IN, LIKE, AROUND 8, 9, 10, THEY
MIGHT SORT OF JUST BE INUNDATED
WITH ANXIETY AND PEOPLE'S FEAR
AND PEOPLE'S STRESS.
IT CAN OVERWHELM THEIR CAPACITY
TO COPE.
>> Reporter: ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
IS SUPPOSED TO BE A SAFE,
INNOCENT PLACE.
BUT TODAY'S SHOOTING SHATTERS
THAT NOTION FOR PARENTS.
IF YOUR CHILDREN ARE OLD ENOUGH
TO ASK QUESTIONS, INSTEAD OF
TALKING TO THE KIDS, TRY JUST
LISTENING.
>> START BY ASKING THEM WHAT DO
YOU KNOW, HOW ARE YOU FEELING?
ASK OPEN-ENDED QUESTIONS SO THAT
YOU CAN START FROM THERE.
A LOT OF TIMES WE THINK THEY
WANT TO KNOW LOTS AND LOTS OF
INFORMATION THAT ADULTS WANT TO
KNOW, BUT CHILDREN DON'T
NECESSARILY HAVE THE SAME
QUESTIONS OR HAVE THE SAME
NEEDS.
>> Reporter: WHEN THEY DO ASK
QUESTIONS, DON'T HIDE FROM THEIR
CONCERNS, BUT TRY NOT TO
OVER-ANSWER EITHER.
THAT CAN JUST HEIGHTEN THEIR
ANXIETY?
>> OR CONFUSE THEM.
IT CAN MAKE THEM MORE ANXIOUS.
IT COULD PLANT SEEDS, MAYBE
IDEAS THAT HADN'T OCCURRED TO
THEM.
>> Reporter: WHILE WE DON'T WANT
TO HIDE OUR EMOTIONS, TRY NOT BE
OVERLY EMOTIONAL I'DER IN FRONT
OF THE KIDS.
KIDS GET THEIR CUES FROM
GROWN-UPS.
>> WE LOOK TO GROWN-UPS, IT'S
CALLED SOCIAL REFERENCING, IT'S
WHAT KIDS DO.
SO WE'RE ALL SORT OF BEING
WATCHED AND KIDS ARE LOOKING TO
US TO LET THEM KNOW HOW SHOULD
WE BE REACTING TO THIS?
>> Reporter: AND SO IF PARENTS
ARE OVERREACTING?
>> UNDERSTANDABLE, BUT TRY TO
SHARE YOUR SADNESS AND YOUR
ANXIETY AND YOUR FEAR AND YOUR
ANGER WITH OTHER ADULTS AND
SHIELD CHILDREN FROM THOSE
CONVERSATIONS.
>> Reporter: MENTAL HEALTH
EXPERTS TOLD US THEY'VE LEARNED
A LOT FROM THE EXPERIENCE OF
9/11.
>> A NUMBER OF CHILDREN WERE
TRAUMATIZED WHO HAD NO DIRECT
CONTACT WITH 9/11.
BUT RATHER, WATCHED THE MEDIA
EXTENSIVELY, AND FOR THOSE
CHILDREN, A TERM WAS COINED
CALLED SECONDARY TERRORISM.
>> Reporter: FOR PARENTS, IT'S A
DELICATE BALANCING ACT,
CALIBRATED TO EACH CHILD'S
PERSONALITY.
IS MY KID ANXIOUS?
IS SHE FEARFUL?
>> RIGHT NOW, YOU'RE GOING TO
SEE A LOT OF ANGER.
YOU'RE GOING SEE A LOT OF
SADNESS.
A LOT OF TEARS.
BUT OVER TIME, WATCH FOR THESE
KINDS OF THINGS.
WATCH FOR CHILDREN WHO ARE
HAVING TROUBLE SLEEPING OR
EATING.
KIDS WHO CAN'T FOCUS, THEY CAN'T
GO TO SCHOOL, THEY CAN'T RESUME
THEIR NORMAL ACTIVITIES.
OR CHILDREN WHO ARE JUST
OBSESSED WITH WORRYING.
ALL THEY CAN THINK ABOUT AND
TALK ABOUT IS THIS EVENT.
THOSE KIDS, YOU'LL WANT TO GET
THEM SOME SPECIAL HELP.
>> Reporter: REASSURE THEM THAT
THEY'RE SAFE.
THE IMAGES CAN BE HAUNTING.
EXPLAIN IN CONCRETE TERMS THAT
THE POLICE AND TEACHERS ARE
WORKING TO KEEP SCHOOLS SAFE AND
EXPLAIN THAT THIS IS A VERY,
VERY RARE EVENT.
PARENTS ARE ABLE TO PUT IT INTO
PERSPECTIVE.
THEY KNOW THE ODDS ARE
INCREDIBLY LONG THAT THEIR
CHILD'S SCHOOL IS GOING TO HAVE
THIS KIND OF INCIDENT, AND YET
KIDS MIGHT NOT KNOW THAT.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
WE DEVELOP THINKING ERRORS LIKE
THAT SOMETIMES AFTER A TRAUMA,
AND KIDS ARE ESPECIALLY PRONE TO
IT.
THEY'RE ESPECIALLY PRONE TO WHAT
WE CALL MAGICAL THINKING OR
ASSOCIATIVE LOGIC, SO IF IT
HAPPENED IN A KINDERGARTEN
CLASSROOM, IT WILL HAPPEN IN
ANOTHER KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM.
>> Reporter: YOU HAVE TO CORRECT
THEIR MAGICAL THINKING.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
>> Reporter: THE PROFESSIONALS
WE SPOKE WITH SAID THAT THE BEST
COMFORT MAY NOT BE VERBAL.
>> THERE'S A SUPERB BODY OF
RESEARCH FROM ANIMAL RESEARCH TO
HUMAN RESEARCH, RESEARCH WITH
PREMATURE BABIES, AND WHAT THIS
ALL COMES TO IS THAT THE TOUCH,
THE COMFORTING HAS STRONG
BIOLOGICAL EFFECTS AND SO IT'S
NOT JUST A CLICHE OF PARENTHOOD.
IT'S WISDOM THROUGH THE AGES
THAT HAS NOW SCIENCE BEHIND IT.
>> Reporter: AN IDEA ENDORSED BY
PRESIDENT OBAMA EARLIER TODAY.
>> THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER.
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM.
>> Reporter: SO WHEN WORDS FAIL
US, NEVER UNDERESTIMATE THE
POWER OF AN EMBRACE.
EVERY PARENT KNOWS THAT SCHOOL
CAN BE A SOURCE OF ANXIETY TOO
FOR YOUNG KIDS, REGARDLESS.
I SPENT THE DAY INTERVIEWING
THOSE TRAUMA EXPERTS AND CHILD
PSYCHOLOGISTS AND THEY ALL SAY
THE SAME THING.
KIDS DEPEND ON PARENTS TO FEEL
SAFE.
SO WHILE IT MAY NOT BE
APPROPRIATE TO HOLD A SCHOOL
ASSEMBLY, WHICH MIGHT INCREASE
FEARS, SCHOOLS ARE A SOURCE OF
COMMUNITY AND PARENTS SHOULD
CHECK IN WITH THEIR TEACHERS AND
ADMINISTRATORS TO SEE HOW THEIR
KIDS ARE RESPONDING.
BUT AS A SAD FOOTNOTE, CYNTHIA,
THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL PRINCIPAL
WAS AMONG THOSE KILLED TODAY AND
THAT COMMUNITY WILL NEED A LOT
OF SUPPORT MOVING AHEAD.
>> OUR THANKS TO YOU, JUJU
CHANG.
>>> EARLIER TODAY, WE SAW A
DEEPLY TOUCHED PRESIDENT OBAMA,
THE FATHER OF TWO, CHOKED UP
WHILE ADDRESSING THE NATION
ABOUT THE TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK.
ABC'S JAKE TAPPER HAS BEEN
FOLLOWING THE PRESIDENT
THROUGHOUT THE DAY AND HE BRINGS
US THE LATEST.
>> Reporter: THE DAY BEGAN
QUIETLY.
NORMALLY, AS DAYS LIKE THIS
ALWAYS SEEM TO DO.
THERE WAS NOT MUCH ON THE
PRESIDENT'S SCHEDULE TODAY.
A BILL SIGNING.
A MEETING WITH U.S. AMBASSADOR
TO THE UNITED NATIONS SUSAN RICE
FOLLOWING HER HEADLINE-GRABBING
NEWS.
THERE WAS A HOLIDAY PARTY.
BUT A MADMAN WOULD MAKE TODAY
ONE OF THE WORST DAYS OF THE
OBAMA PRESIDENCY.
THE PRESIDENT PARTICIPATED IN
THAT BILL SIGNING AROUND 12:30,
BUT BY THE TIME THE PRESS
SECRETARY CAME OUT FOR THE DAILY
BRIEFING A FEW MINUTES LATER,
THE NEWS.
THAT HORRIFYING NEWS ABOUT THE
REALITY OF THE SHOOTING.
CLEARLY WAS KNOWN.
>> AT APPROXIMATELY 10:30 THIS
MORNING --
>> Reporter: THE PRESS SECRETARY
WAS RELUCTANT TO SHARE ANY
INFORMATION UNTIL IT WAS
DEFINITIVE.
>> YOU SEEM SHAKEN.
A LOT OF US FEEL SHAKEN.
>> I CAN TELL YOU THAT AS A
FATHER, INCIDENTS LIKE THESE
WEIGH HEAVILY ON HIM.
>> Reporter: SHORTLY AFTER 2:00
P.M. EASTERN, FLAGS WERE LOWERED
TO HALF STAFF AT THE WHITE HOUSE
AND AT GOVERNMENT BUILDINGS AND
MILITARY INSTALLATIONS AND
VESSELS THROUGHOUT THE WORLD.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
>> Reporter: SHORTLY AFTER 3:00
P.M., PRESIDENT OBAMA REACTED.
NOT AS A PRESIDENT, BUT AS A
PARENT.
>> I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
>> Reporter: IT WAS AN EMOTIONAL
SIDE OF THE PRESIDENT, RARELY
SEEN IN PUBLIC.
HE REPEATEDLY WIPED AWAY TEARS
AND PAUSED TO COMPOSE HIMSELF.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> Reporter: TODAY THE PRESIDENT
SUGGESTED HE MIGHT TAKE SOME
ACTION.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS, REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
>> Reporter: IT WAS UNCLEAR WHAT
MEANINGFUL ACTION THE PRESIDENT
INTENDED, WHETHER GUN CONTROL OR
SOMETHING TO DO WITH THE
MENTALLY ILL OR SOMETHING ELSE.
THE ONLY ACTION WE KNEW FOR SURE
HE WOULD TAKE WAS THIS ONE.
>> THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER,
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
>> Reporter: THE PRESIDENT LATER
TODAY VISITED WITH HIS FAMILY
AND APPEARED AT A HOLIDAY
RECEPTION.
WE HAD A TOUGH DAY TODAY, HE
TOLD THE CROWD.
WE DID.
AND THERE ARE SOME PEOPLE WHO
WILL NOW HAVE NOTHING BUT TOUGH
DAYS FOR THE REST OF THEIR
LIVES.
THIS IS JAKE TAPPER FOR
"NIGHTLINE" AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
>> OUR THANKS TO YOU, JAKE.
>>> JUST AHEAD, WHAT WE'VE
LEARNED TODAY ABOUT THIS
EXTRAORDINARY COMMUNITY AS WE
BRING YOU INCREDIBLE IMAGES OF
THE TOWN BANDING TOGETHER IN THE
FACE OF TRAGEDY.
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>>> TODAY'S TRAGEDY MAY HAVE
CATAPULTED SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
INTO THE NATIONAL SPOTLIGHT, BUT
THE SCHOOL SYSTEM HERE HAS LONG
BEEN RENOWNED FOR ITS
EXCELLENCE.
SO MUCH SO THAT PARENTS GO TO
GREAT LENGTHS TO HAVE THEIR KIDS
ATTEND SCHOOL IN THIS AREA.
ABC'S JIM AVILA BRINGS US A LOOK
INSIDE SOME VERY SPECIAL
CLASSROOMS.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY HAS ALWAYS BEEN
WELL-KNOWN HERE IN CENTRAL
CONNECTICUT.
NOT FOR TRAGEDY, BUT AS A WARM,
CREATIVE SANCTUARY FOR CHILDREN
AGED 5 TO 10 YEARS OLD.
WITH A STERLING REPUTATION FOR
ACADEMICS, SMALL CLASSES OF 20,
KNOWN FOR ITS CARING TEACHERS
AND SCORING A PERFECT 10 FROM
GREATSCHOOLS.ORG.
IN THE TOP 3% OF ALL THE STATE'S
ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS, A MAGNET FOR
CIVIC PRIDE AND GROWTH.
>> PEOPLE COME TO NEWTOWN FOR
THE SCHOOLS.
THE HUSBANDS WILL SACRIFICE THE
COMMUTE JUST TO COME TO NEWTOWN.
>> Reporter: THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, WHO DIED IN THE
ATTACK, KEPT A TWITTER ACCOUNT
PROUDLY DOCUMENTING THE SCHOOL
EASILY ACHIEVEMENTS.
JUST TWO DAYS BEFORE THE GUNFIRE
SHE WROTE, SANDY HOOK STUDENTS
ENJOY THE REHEARSAL FOR OUR
FOURTH GRADE WINTER CONCERT.
ON DECEMBER 10th, KINDERS WRITE
LISTS, SELECT GROCERY ITEMS.
PAY THE CASHIER AT THEIR NEW
CLASSROOM SUPERMARKET CENTER.
AND IN OCTOBER, THIS TWEET
EMPHASIZING SECURITY, SAFETY
FIRST AT SANDY HOOK.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY FOR OUR
ANNUAL EVACUATION DRILL.
MESSAGES FROM A PRINCIPAL WHO
LOVED HER STUDENTS, WELCOMING
INCOMING KINDERGARTENERS WITH
THIS SWEET MESSAGE THIS FALL.
>> WE HAVE TO SAY THE TEACHERS
ARE PRETTY MUCH WHERE IT'S AT.
THEY LOVE THE KIDS.
THEY LOVE TO TEACH.
THE KIDS GET A LOT OUT OF IT.
>> Reporter: CAITLIN SPENT SIX
YEARS AT SANDY HOOK.
SHE'S 21 NOW AND STILL REMEMBERS
THE WARNLGT
THE WARMTH SHE FELT AT HER FIRST
SCHOOL.
>> IT'S VERY CLOSE-KNIT.
IT'S A SMALL SCHOOL, BUT I
JUST -- I DON'T KNOW.
IT WAS JUST REALLY IMPORTANT TO
ME.
REALLY IMPORTANT TO MY
DEVELOPMENT.
>> Reporter: KAITLIN WATCHED THE
TRAGEDY UNFOLD ON TELEVISION
THIS MORNING.
HEARD LITTLE CHILDREN ATTENDING
THE SAME CLASSES SHE REMEMBERS
SO FONDLY, TELL OF HIDING IN
CLASSROOM CLOSETS AND CORRIDORS.
>> WHEN I WAS LISTENING TO THE
NEWS, I KNOW THE LAYOUT OF THE
SCHOOL.
SO I CAN IMAGINE WHAT WAS GOING
ON, THE CHAOS.
SO THIS WAS REALLY CLOSE TO
HOME.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK IS
INDEED QUAINT, IDYLLIC, EVEN.
QUINTESSENTIAL NEW ENGLAND.
BUT HERE, TOO, SCHOOLS HAVE
STEPPED UP SECURITY.
JUST THIS YEAR, SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL PUT INTO PLACE
A SECURITY PLAN, MAKING IT
MANDATORY FOR VISITORS TO RING A
DOORBELL, AND ONLY BE LET IN IF
THE STAFF RECOGNIZED THEM
THROUGH THE VIDEO MONITOR.
AND IF STAFF DIDN'T RECOGNIZE
THE VISITOR, HE OR SHE NEEDED TO
PRESENT A PICTURE I.D., SIGN IN,
AND ONLY THEN WOULD BE LET INTO
THE SCHOOL.
EVEN WHEN KAITLIN WENT TO SANDY
HOOK, THERE WERE EMERGENCY
DRILLS, LESSONS THAT MAY HAVE
SAVED SOME OF THE CHILDREN
TODAY.
>> EXACTLY WHAT THE KIDS WERE
SAYING ON THE NEWS, GO INTO THE
CORNER OF THE ROOM, THE TEACHER
WOULD LOCK THE DOOR AND TURN OUT
THE LIGHTS, BE QUIET, WHICH IS
REALLY HARD FOR KIDS.
ESPECIALLY WHEN THEY THINK IT'S
NOT REAL.
BUT I THINK MOST OF THEM KNEW
THAT SOMETHING WAS REALLY
SERIOUS THIS TIME.
>> Reporter: FOR "NIGHTLINE,"
JIM AVILA, IN SANDY HOOK,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THANKS, JIM.
>>> EARLIER TONIGHT, I WAS ABLE
TO SEE SOME OF THE REMARKABLE
STRENGTH OF THIS SMALL COMMUNITY
FIRSTHAND, WHEN I ATTENDED A
CROWDED VIGIL RIGHT DOWN THE
STREET AT SAINT ROSE CHURCH
WHERE I FOUND SCENES OF LOVE AND
RESILIENCE IN THE FACE OF THE
MOST INCOMPREHENSIBLE TRAGEDY.
WHERE DO YOU PUT A PAIN THIS
DEEP?
FOR HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE IN THIS
TINY, TIGHT-KNIT COMMUNITY, THE
PLACE WAS SAINT ROSE CATHOLIC
CHURCH.
IT WAS PART VIGIL.
♪
PART WAKE.
PART GROUP HUG.
THEY CAME TO PRAY, YES, BUT ALSO
JUST TO BE NEXT TO EACH OTHER.
AND WHILE HUNDREDS OF THEM
CROWDED INSIDE THE CHURCH, EVEN
MORE PILED OUTSIDE.
♪ AMAZING GRACE
LIGHTING CANDLES AND PRAYING
SILENTLY.
THIS PARISH ALONE LOST SIX OF
ITS YOUNGEST MEMBERS TODAY.
THE PRIEST HERE, MONSIGNOR
ROBERT WEISS, SPENT MOST OF THE
DAY THE A THE FIREHOUSE NEXT TO
THE SCHOOL COUNSELING THEIR
GRIEVING PARENTS.
>> THE PARENTS, I HAVE TO SAY,
THE LOVE IN THE ROOM -- AS
BROKEN AS THEY ARE -- IS JUST
PHENOMENAL.
>> Reporter: IN FACT, HE TOLD US
TONIGHT MANY OF THE PARENTS PLAN
TO REMAIN AT THE FIREHOUSE
OVERNIGHT, UNABLE TO BEAR THE
THOUGHT OF LEAVING WHILE
CHILDREN'S BODIES REMAIN INSIDE
THE SCHOOL.
>> I THINK THE REALITY HAS
SUDDENLY HIT THAT THESE 20
CHILDREN ARE WITH THE LORD NOW
AND THEY'VE BEEN TAKEN FROM THEM
TOO YOUNG AND TOO INNOCENT.
AND THAT WE JUST TOLD A LITTLE
BOY ABOUT HIS SISTER NOW.
IT'S JUST HARD.
WHO AM I GOING TO PLAY WITH, HE
SAID.
>> THE STATE'S GOVERNOR DAN
MALLOY WAS HERE, TOO.
>> IN THE COMES DAYS AND THE
COMING WEEKS, I WILL PRAY THAT
YOU ALL EMBRACE ONE ANOTHER.
THAT YOU LIFT ONE ANOTHER UP,
THAT YOU UNDERSTAND THE
DIFFICULTIES THAT YOU
COLLECTIVELY WILL UNDERGO.
>> AND OUTSIDE THE CHURCH, THEY
WERE EMBRACING, SHARING COMFORT
AND SOMETIMES HORROR.
>> I'M SO SORRY.
OH, GOD.
>> Reporter: RAY WORKED AT A
BEFORE AND AFTER SCHOOL PROGRAM
IN SANDY HOOK, ELEMENTARY, AND
SAYS HE LEFT JUST FIVE MINUTES
BEFORE THE SHOOTING HAPPENED.
>> I WISH I HAD STAYED FIVE MORE
MINUTES TO STAND IN FRONT OF THE
SON OF A BITCH.
>> Reporter: AMONG THE FACES IN
THE CROWD HERE, THIS YOUNG MAN,
WHO SAYS HE WENT TO HIGH SCHOOL
WITH THE SHOOTER.
>> HE ALWAYS SEEMED LIKE THE
QUIET TYPE.
I TRIED TO MAKE A CONNECTION
WITH HIM A COUPLE TIMES BUT
NOTHING REALLY EVER WORKED OUT.
>> HAIL MARY, FULL OF GRACE.
THE LORD IS WITH THEE.
>> Reporter: BUT FOR THE MOST
PART, PEOPLE HERE WERE NOT
TALKING ABOUT THE SHOOTER BUT
ABOUT THE CHILDREN AND THE
OTHERS WHO LOST THEIR LIVES SO
HORRIFICALLY.
>> I FEEL PARENTS WHO HAVE
PROBABLY CHRISTMAS PRESENTS AT
HOME FOR THEIR BABIES AND JUST
KIDS WHO ARE NOT COMING HOME.
THEY LEFT TODAY THIS MORNING AND
THEY'RE NOT COMING HOME.
IT BREAKS YOUR HEART.
♪ ROUND YON VIRGIN MOTHER AND
CHILD ♪
>> THAT SOUND OF CHRISTMAS JUST
DAYS AWAY, ALMOST UNBEARABLE
TONIGHT.
>> THERE'S 20 BRIGHTER STARS IN
THE HEAVEN THAN EVERY NIGHT IN
NEWTOWN.
THESE 20 CHILDREN WERE JUST
BEAUTIFUL, BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN.
>> SADLY, THIS IS JUST THE FIRST
CHAPTER IN THIS TRAGEDY.
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA" WILL BE
HERE IN THE MORNING AS THE STORY
DEVELOPS OVERNIGHT.
GOOD NIGHT, AMERICA.
>>> UP NEXT ON JIMMY KIMMEL
LIVE.
>> HEY, AN APP THAT CAN HELP YOU
LOSE YOUR JOB.
IT'S CALLED FACEBOOK.
>> MEL BROOKS.
>> HOW DID YOU GET INTO SHOW
BUSINESS IN THE FIRST PLACE?
>> NONE OF YOUR BUSINESS.
>> ABC NEWS JAKE TAPPER, MUSIC
FROM JASON ALDEEN, AND "THIS
WEEK IN UNNECESSARY CENSORSHIP."
>> WOW, THIS WORLD IS SERIO
>>> HI.
JIMMY KIMMEL HERE LETTING YOU
KNOW THAT SUBWAY IS READY TO
CATER YOUR NEXT EVENT.
WITH SANDWICH PLATTERS LIKE THE
FLAVOR CRATER, OR THE FRESH FIT.
I THINK NOW WOULD BE THE PERFECT
TIME FOR ME TO GIVE YOU YOUR
GIFT.
>> OKAY, JIMMY.
>> AND HERE IT IS.
THAT'S THE SUBWAY THREE-FOOT
GIANT SUB.
>> WOW.
A THREE-FOOT GIANT SUB FROM
SUBWAY?
MY FAVORITE.
THANK YOU, JIMMY.
YOU ARE SO VERY, VERY, VERY
GENEROUS.
>> WELL, YOU DESERVE IT, BUDDY.
>> I GOT A PRESENT FOR YOU, TOO.
>> YOU DO?
>> YEAH.
>> Jimmy: WOW.
>> Jimmy: THANK YOU.
>> PUT IT DOWN A LITTLE BIT.
>> Jimmy: SO YOU CAN READ THE
TELEPROMPTER?
>> EXACTLY.
THAT IS THE SUBWAY SIX-FOOT
GIANT SUB.
>> Jimmy: WELL, THANK YOU,
GUILLERMO.
>> IT'S BIGGER THAN THE ONE YOU
GAVE ME.
>> Jimmy: I SEE THAT.
>> IT'S THREE FOOT BIGGER.
>> Jimmy: YES, I CAN SEE.
>> IT'S TWICE AS BIG.
>> Jimmy: I GET IT.
YOU GOT ME A BETTER GIFT THAN I
GOT YOU.
I'M EMBARRASSED AND I'M SORRY.
>> DON'T FEEL BAD, JIMMY.
CHRISTMAS IS ABOUT FRIENDSHIP.
>> Jimmy: THANK YOU FOR SAYING
THAT, PAL.
I FEEL THE SAME WAY.
MERRY CHRISTMAS, GUILLERMO.
>> MERRY CHRISTMAS, YOU CHEAP
SON OF A BITCH.
>> SUBWAY CATERS.
GIVE THEM WHAT THEY LOVE.
VISIT SUBWAYCATERING.COM TO
ORDER.
>> Dicky: "JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE"
BACK IN TWO MINUTES WITH MEL
BROOKS, JAKE TAPPER AND MUSIC
FROM JASON ALDEAN.
We need to leave our contract
plan for Net10 Wireless.
Doug's family doesn't have that.
You could have any of these
top smartphones
at half the cost of our plan.
You aren't bad parents.
You just fell in with the wrong
wireless plan.
Welcome to the next generation
of family plans.
Visit Net10Wireless.com.
♪
>> Dicky: FROM HOLLYWOOD, IT'S
"JIMMY KIMMEL LIVE!"
TONIGHT --
MEL BROOKS.
FROM ABC NEWS, JAKE TAPPER.
AND MUSIC FROM JASON ALDEAN.
WITH CLETO AND THE CLETONES.
AND NOW, LIKE IT OR NOT, HERE'S
JIMMY KIMMEL!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: HOLA.
THANK YOU, CLETO.
HI, EVERYONE, I'M JIMMY, I'M THE
HOST OF THE SHOW.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
WELCOME TO MY APARTMENT COMPLEX.
THANK YOU.
MY PLEASURE TO HAVE YOU HERE.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
SHOULDN'T YOU BE AT WORK RIGHT
NOW?
BY THE WAY, IF YOU ARE LOOKING
FOR A JOB, FACEBOOK JUST
LAUNCHED A NEW APP.
THEY TEAMED UP WITH THE
DEPARTMENT OF LABOR TO CREATE
WHAT THEY CALL THE SOCIAL JOBS
APP.
YOU CAN BROWSE THROUGH 2 MILLION
JOB LISTINGS.
YOU KNOW IT'S BAD WHEN EVEN
FACEBOOK THINKS IT'S TIME FOR
YOU TO GET A JOB.
FACEBOOK ALSO HAS AN APP THAT
CAN HELP YOU LOSE YOUR JOB.
IT'S CALLED FACEBOOK.
TRY IT.
[ APPLAUSE ]
THIS SATURDAY -- ON SATURDAY, WE
ARE CELEBRATING THE THIRD ANNUAL
NATIONAL UNFRIEND DAY OR NUD,
FOR SHORT.
THIS IS A HOLIDAY I STARTED TWO
YEARS AGO.
THE IDEA IS TO ENCOURAGE PEOPLE
TO GO THROUGH THEIR LIST OF
FACEBOOK FRIENDS AND UNFRIEND
ANYONE THAT IS NOT ACTUALLY A
FRIEND.
IT'S ALL PART OF YOUR HISTORY
MONTH HERE AT THE SHOW AND
ANYONE WHO FALLS INTO THE NOT A
FRIEND CATEGORY, I WOULD LIKE
YOU TO CUT THEM LOOSE ON
SATURDAY.
BECAUSE WHO HAS TIME TO KEEP UP
WITH ALL THE PETS, THE KIDS, THE
LUNCH.
I USED TO WANT TO KNOW WHAT MY
FRIENDS WERE HAVING FOR LUNCH
EVERY DAY, BUT THEN I TURNED 6
YEARS OLD AND NOW I DON'T
ANYMORE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
I -- THANK YOU.
[ APPLAUSE ]
I DREAM OF A BETTER WORLD, A
WORLD IN WHICH I DON'T KNOW THAT
THE GUY I SAT NEXT TO IN
WOODSHOP IS NOW TRAINING FOR A
HALF MARATHON AND SATURDAY, THAT
DREAM WILL BECOME A REALITY.
AND YES, MAYBE SOME PEOPLE'S
FEELINGS WILL GET HURT, BUT
TRUST ME.
AFTER YOU UNFRIEND, YOU WILL
FEEL AS CLEAN AND HAPPY AS A
LADY IN A SHAMPOO COMMERCIAL.
IT WILL BE A WONDERFUL THING.
TO FULLY PARTICIPATE IN NATIONAL
UNFRIEND DAY THIS YEAR, I'D LIKE
YOU TO GO TO OUR FACEBOOK PAGE,
FACEBOOK.COM/JIMMYKIMMELLIVE.
WE WILL PROVIDE YOU WITH A BADGE
YOU CAN AD TO YOUR PROFILE
PICTURE.
FOR INSTANCE, IF THIS IS YOUR
PICTURE, OF GUILLERMO 30 YEARS
AGO, YOU JUST CLICK ON IT AND
THIS LOGO WILL BE ADDED TO YOUR
PICTURE.
IT SAYS I NUD'D.
IF YOU TELL EVERYONE, MAYBE THEY
MAYBE TAKE -- MAYBE THEY WON'T
TAKE IT SO PERSONALLY.
EARLIER THIS WEEK, I ASKED OUR
VIEWERS TO TELL US WHO THEY'LL
BE UNFRIENDING AND WHY.
A LOT OF PEOPLE TOOK TIME TO
UPLOAD VIDEOS TO YOUTUBE WITH
THE TITLE, HEY JIMMY KIMMEL,
MEET MY BEST UNFRIEND.
THIS IS THE PERSON THAT THEY
WERE MOST LOOKING FORWARD TO
UNFRIENDING ON SATURDAY.
WE GOT SOME GOOD RESPONSES,
WHICH I PRESENT TO YOU NOW.
>> HEY, JIMMY KIMMEL, THIS IS MY
BEST UNFRIEND.
I JUST WANT TO MOVE TO
PITTSBURGH!
FINALLY ARRIVED IN PITTSBURGH!
I'M IN FREAKING PITTSBURGH AND
IT'S SO BEAUTIFUL.
OFF TO PITTSBURGH!
ALMOST.
HERE'S THE WEATHER IN
PITTSBURGH!
THIS IS ME SAD BECAUSE I'M NOT
IN PITTSBURGH ANYMORE.
CAN I JUST GO BACK TO PITTSBURGH
NOW?
UNFRIEND!
>> I AM UNFRIENDING EVERYONE
WHOSE FACEBOOK PROFILE SAYS THAT
THEY ATTEND HOGWARTS.
>> THIS IS MY BEST UNFRIEND.
AS YOU CAN SEE, HE HAS A PROFILE
PICTURE WHICH IS A CAR.
AND THERE HE IS FLEXING HIS
GUNS.
>> FOR NATIONAL UNFRIEND DAY, WE
DECIDED TO UNFRIEND RICO.
>> SHE WENT TO MY HIGH SCHOOL IN
2007 BUT SHE WAS AN EXCHANGE
STUDENT AND WE NEVER SPOKE.
IN CASE YOU ARE WONDERING WHAT
SHE'S UP TO TODAY --
[ SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE ]
GOOD-BYE.
UNFRIENDED.
>> I WOULD LIKE TO TELL YOU WHO
I'M GOING TO UNFRIEND.
HEY!
GUYS.
GUYS, CAN YOU KEEP IT DOWN?
UM -- I -- SORRY ABOUT THAT.
UM -- YOU KNOW WHAT, MAYBE,
JIMMY, I'M JUST GOING TO
UNFRIEND MY ROOMMATES.
>> UNFRIEND THIS TOOL BAG I WENT
TO HIGH SCHOOL WITH.
HE POSTS A NEW STATUS EVERY HOUR
ABOUT WHAT HE'S DOING AND NOBODY
CARES.
NOBODY CARES THAT YOU MET MARK
WAHLBERG, OKAY?
I'M SURPRISED HE DIDN'T PUNCH
YOU IN A FACE BECAUSE YOU'RE SO
ANNOYING.
>> I WANT TO PRODUCE YOU TO MY
BEST UNFRIEND.
THIS GUY DEREK IS AN AVID
EXHIBITIONIST.
WE USED TO BE FRIENDS, HE WAS A
NORMAL DUDE.
NOW WHEN I CHECK MY MESSAGES,
THIS IS WHAT I HAVE TO LOOK AT.
I'M SORRY, MAN.
BUT IT'S TIME.
BAM.
UNFRIENDED.
>> Jimmy: ALL VERY DESERVING OF
UNFRIENDING.
REMEMBER, THIS SATURDAY,
NOVEMBER 17th, THE THIRD ANNUAL
NATIONAL UNFRIEND DAY.
IF YOU ARE NOT APART OF THE
SOLUTION --
>> HEY, HOLD ON A SECOND.
WHAT'S THIS ALL ABOUT?
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S FRED WILLARD, EVERYONE.
>> THANK YOU, THANK YOU.
WAIT A MINUTE.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THANK YOU.
I DIDN'T COME FOR THE APPLAUSE,
BUT IT'S VERY NICE.
JIMMY, I'M SERIOUS.
WHAT'S GOING ON HERE?
I MEAN, I THOUGHT WE WERE
FRIENDS.
>> Jimmy: WE ARE FRIENDS.
>> WHAT'S ALL THIS WITH NATIONAL
UNFRED DAY.
>> Jimmy: NO, NO.
>> LET ME GET THIS OFF MY CHEST.
EVERYTHING IS FUN FOR A LAUGH,
JIMMY, BUT THERE ARE MILLIONS OF
PEOPLE NAMED FRED OUT THERE AND
I HAPPEN TO BE ONE OF THEM.
AND DID YOU EVER STOP FOR TWO
SECONDS AND THINK ABOUT MY
FEELINGS.
EVIDENTLY NOT, BECAUSE YOU ARE
TELLING PEOPLE TO UNFRED.
WHICH, I MEAN, WHAT IF I STARTED
A HOLIDAY AND TOLD PEOPLE TO
UNJIMMY?
HOW WOULD THAT MAKE YOU FEEL?
>> Jimmy: WELL, FRED, IT'S --
>> DON'T CALL ME FRED.
YOU CAN CALL ME MR. WILLARD
UNTIL YOU DECIDE TO BANISH THAT
FOR HEAVEN'S SAKE.
>> Jimmy: IT'S NOT --
>> YOU KNOW, I'VE HAD ENOUGH OF
THIS.
YOU DON'T CARE ABOUT ANYONE
OTHER THAN YOURSELF.
>> Jimmy: THAT IS JUST NOT TRUE.
>> MAYBE YOU ARE UNFAMILIAR WITH
THE MANY CONTRIBUTIONS PEOPLE
NAMED FRED HAVE MADE TO THE
WORLD.
>> Jimmy: I THINK AM I FAMILIAR.
>> ROLL TAPE.
>> Jimmy: THERE'S TAPE?
>> HI, I'M FRED WILLARD.
SOME VERY IGNORE RAT PEOPLE OUT
THERE SEEM TO UNAWARE THE
IMPORTANT ROLES FREDS HAVE
PLAYED THROUGHOUT HISTORY.
FROM THE BRILLIANT MILITARY
STRATEGIST FRED THE GREAT.
AND PIONEERING CIVIL RIGHTS
LEADER FRED DOUGLAS.
THE INCOMPARABLE OF FRED CHOPIN
AND FRED MERCURY.
THE DANCING OF FRED ASTAIRE.
AND LET'S SEE, FRED ROGERS.
FRED FLINTSTONE, FRED KRUEGER.
AND I'M SURE THERE'S MORE I
CAN'T THINK OF RIGHT NOW.
SO, THE NEXT TIME SOMETIME TELLS
YOU TO UNFRED, MAYBE YOU SHOULD
STOP AND THINK ABOUT WHERE WE'D
BE WITHOUT FRED.
AND THEN TELL JIMMY KIMMEL TO
STUFF IT.
THIS HAS BEEN A SPECIAL MESSAGE
FROM THE AMERICAN FRED CROSS.
FRED!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WHAT DO YOU HAVE TO SAY FOR
YOURSELF NOW?
>> Jimmy: IT'S UNFRIEND.
>> WHAT?
>> Jimmy: IT'S UNFRIEND, LIKE
NATIONAL UNFRIEND DAY, IT'S --
>> UNFRIEND?
>> Jimmy: YEAH, LIKE ON
FACEBOOK.
>> OH.
>> Jimmy: TO GET BACK TO
UNFRIEND PEOPLE THAT THEY
AREN'T --
>> I FEEL A BIT FOOLISH.
>> Jimmy: THIS IS THE THIRD YEAR
WE'VE DONE THIS.
>> IT SOUNDS LIKE A VERY GOOD
IDEA.
>> Jimmy: THANK YOU, YEAH.
NOTHING TO DO WITH FRED AT ALL.
>> OH, THAT'S A RELIEF.
THANKS, JIMMY.
>> Jimmy: WELL, THANK YOU.
>> DO YOU MIND IF I HANG OUT IN
THE GREEN ROOM?
THEY HAVE GREAT MEAT BALLS BACK
THERE.
>> Jimmy: ENJOY.
STAY AS LONG AS YOU LIKE.
>> I DIDN'T WANT TO DO THIS.
I FEEL MUCH BETTER ABOUT THIS.
>> Jimmy: UN -- AH -- I HAD NO
IDEA THAT WAS GOING TO HAPPEN.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IN BUSINESS NEWS, HOSTESS, THE
COMPANY THAT MAKES TWINKIES,
WONDER BREAD, THAT SORT OF
THING, IS IN BIG FINANCIAL
TROUBLE RIGHT NOW.
HOSTESS FILED CHAPTER 11 BACK IN
JANUARY AND AFTER THEY WENT
BANKRUPT, THE COURT ALLOWED THEM
TO CUT THE PAY OF 18,000
EMPLOYEES.
LAST WEEK, THE EMPLOYEES WENT ON
STRIKE.
HOSTESS ANNOUNCED IF THE
EMPLOYEES DIDN'T RETURN TO WORK
BY 5:00 P.M. TODAY, THEY WOULD
SHUT HOSTESS DOWN AND LIQUIDATE
THEIR ASSETS.
THEY DIDN'T COME BACK.
THERE'S A BIG ANNOUNCEMENT
TOMORROW AND IF THEY DO WHAT
THEY SAID THEY WOULD, HOSTESS
COULD BE A THING OF THE PAST
WHICH IS KIND OF SAD, REALLY.
I HOPE THE TWINKIE COWBOY
DOESN'T HAVE TO GO BACK TO
TURNING TRICKS.
THAT WOULD BE -- I DON'T
UNDERSTAND HOW THIS IS POSSIBLE.
THIS COUNTRY HAS NEVER BEEN
FATTER.
HOW ARE THE PEOPLE WHO MAKE
ZINGERS AND SNOWBALLS LOSING
MONEY?
[ LAUGHTER ]
COLORADO AND WASHINGTON JUST
LEGALIZED MARIJUANA.
IF YOU CAN'T FIGURE OUT A WAY TO
MAKE MONEY OFF OF THAT --
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
I GOT TO TELL YOU SOMETHING,
HOSTESS.
MAYBE YOU SHOULDN'T BE IN THE
SNACK CAKE INDUSTRY.
I GUESS I'LL JUST HAVE TO TAKE
MY BUSINESS TO LITTLE DEBBIE.
THIS IS GOOD.
THIS IS VIDEO FROM A BASKETBALL
GAME IN BELGIUM.
I CAN SENSE YOUR EXCITEMENT
ALREADY, BUT -- HERE WE GO.
YOU SEE, THIS GUY SHOOTS A FREE
THROW.
AND HE MISSES, PLAYER FROM THE
OTHER TEAM GRABS THE REBOUND AND
INSTEAD OF GOING THE OTHER WAY,
HE TRIES TO SCORE -- WE'VE SEEN
THIS BEFORE BUT NEVER THIS MANY
TIMES.
I DON'T KNOW IF THOSE ARE
BELGIAN RULES BASKETBALL OR -- I
DON'T KNOW.
ALL I KNOW IS I WOULD LIKE TO
SEE HIM IN A CLIPPERS UNIFORM
IMMEDIATELY.
[ APPLAUSE ]
AND ONE MORE THING.
IT IS THURSDAY NIGHT, IT IS THE
END OF OUR BROADCAST WEEK.
IT'S TIME FOR OUR WEEKLY TRIBUTE
TO THE FCC WHERE WE BLEEP AND
BLUR THINGS WHETHER THEY NEED IT
OR NOT.
IT IS "THIS WEEK IN UNNECESSARY
CENSORSHIP."
ENJOY.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> THANKSGIVING JUST EIGHT DAYS
AWAY, THE ANIMAL WELFARE GROUP
MERCY FOR ANIMALS IS ACCUSING
BUTTER BALL OF [ BLEEP ] ITS
TURKEYS.
>> TONIGHT'S LEAD, PREPARE TO
[ BLEEP ].
>> LET'S COME TOGETHER.
ONCE MORE THIS HOLIDAY SEASON
AND [ BLEEP ] SMALL ON NOVEMBER
24th.
>> GENERAL PETRAEUS HAD AN
EXTRAORDINARY CAREER.
HE [ BLEEP ] THIS [ BLEEP ] WITH
GREAT DISTINCTION.
>> WOW.
THIS WORLD IS SERIOUSLY
[ BLEEP ] UP.
>> THE THEME FOR THIS WEEK IS
[ BLEEP ] AND [ BLEEP ].
DON'T COME ANY BIGGER THAN THESE
FOUR.
PLEASE WELCOME THE X FACTOR
JUDGES!
>> CAN I [ BLEEP ] ONE OF THE
SEA LIONS.
>> DO YOU WANT TO DO THAT?
>> I WANT TO.
>> THE LAYOFFS WOULD MEAN TAKING
OFFICERS OFF THE STREET TO
HANDLE [ BLEEP ] JOBS.
>> YOU BE [ BLEEP ] OR DO THE
[ BLEEP ]?
>> I'D RATHER BE THE ONE DOING
THE [ BLEEP ].
>> YOU THINK YOU KNOW EVERYTHING
ABOUT ME, DON'T YOU?
>> I [ BLEEP ] YOUR BOTTOM, I
BLOODY WELL OUGHT TO, SIR.
>> SOMEBODY CALLED THE POLICE
BECAUSE YOU WERE [ BLEEP ].
>> NOT [ BLEEP ].
>> I DIDN'T SAY YOU WERE
[ BLEEP ].
>> WELL, YOU SAY [ BLEEP ].
IT MADE YOU SOUND LIKE --
>> DID HE CAUSE ANY DAMAGE
INSIDE WHEN HE WAS [ BLEEP ].
>> NO, HE DID NOT.
>> YES, HE DID.
>> Jimmy: TONIGHT ON THE SHOW,
FROM ABC NEWS, JAKE TAPPER IS
HERE.
WE HAVE MUSIC FROM JASON ALDEAN.
AND WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH THE
GREAT MEL BROOKS, SO STICK
AROUND.
BUT THAT DOESN'T HAPPEN MUCH
ANYMORE.
THE CREATIVE PROCESS
NEVER STOPS.
AND SONGWRITING IS SO HARD,
BUT I LOVE IT.
THESE DAYS, I GUESS I JUST
DON'T WANT TO MISS A THING.
[ laughs ]
I MISS YOU GUYS.
THAT'S ME.
AND THIS IS MY WINDOWS PHONE.
[ Male Announcer ]
NEW WINDOWS PHONE.
REINVENTED AROUND YOU.
♪
THE BLITZ.
THE DUNK.
NOTHING GOES BETTER
WITH FOOTBALL
THAN GOLDEN, CRISPY
Chicken McNuggets
FROM McDonald's,
DUNKED IN SPICY BUFFALO
AND CREAMY RANCH.
MORE GOOD TIMES TO LOVE.
IT'S THE BOURBON LOST
TO EVAPORATION AS IT AGES.
BUT THIS STORY HAS TWO SIDES.
THIS IS THE DEVIL'S CUT:
A MORE INTENSE BOURBON
TRAPPED IN THE BARREL WOOD...
THAT WE FOUND A WAY TO UNLOCK.
THE RESULT IS A SMOOTH,
SLIGHTLY SINISTER, BOURBON...
...AND IT AIN'T FOR CHOIR BOYS.
JIM BEAM DEVIL'S CUT.
THIS YEAR GIVE 'EM
AN APPLEBEE'S GIFT CARD.
BUY 50 BUCKS
IN APPLEBEE'S GIFT CARDS,
AND YOU GET
A 10 DOLLAR BONUS CARD FREE.
A REAL BRIGHT IDEA.
A REAL BONUS.
ONLY AT APPLEBEE'S RESTAURANTS
OR APPLEBEES.COM.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
MY SON LOVES THE APPS
AND MOVIES.
BUT MY DAUGHTER?
VAMPIRE BOOKS.
SHARING...
WHOOH FORGET IT!
WITH OUR WALMART
CREDIT CARD --
SPECIAL FINANCING,
WE CAN GET TWO.
THE KIDS ARE HAPPY.
MY SHOPPING'S DONE.
OUR BUDGET -- UNDER CONTROL.
NOW, LET'S GO.
I KNEW THAT.
RIGHT.
UMPH, I LOVE THAT WOMAN.
[ Male Announcer ]
GET THE SEASONS HOTTEST BRANDS,
LIKE NOOK HD AND HD+.
MAKE AN ELECTRONICS PURCHASE
OF $299 OR MORE
ON YOUR WALMART CREDIT CARD
AND GET NO INTEREST IF PAID
IN FULL WITHIN 12 MONTHS.
AMERICA'S GIFT HEADQUARTERS.
WALMART.
>> Jimmy: TONIGHT ON THE
PROGRAM, HE IS THE SENIOR WHITE
HOUSE CORRESPONDENT FOR ABC NEWS
AND AUTHOR OF THIS VERY BIG NEWS
BOOK, IT'S CALLED "THE OUTPOST."
JAKE TAPPER IS HERE.
I'VE BEEN READING THIS.
IT'S ACTUALLY GREAT.
AND JAKE, BY THE WAY, IS ALSO
THE GUY WHO, ON ELECTION NIGHT,
FAMOUSLY TAUGHT US THIS.
>> I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE THAT
EVERYBODY'S CLEAR ON THE FACT
THAT BARACK OBAMA'S NOT WHITE.
>> Jimmy: THAT'S THE FIRST I WAS
HEARING OF IT.
AND THEN, A MULTIPLE PLATINUM
SELLING COUNTRY ARTIST, JASON
ALDEAN, FROM THE BUD LIGHT
OUTDOOR STAGE.
JASON WILL BE PERFORMING ON THE
AMERICAN MUSIC AWARDS, THIS
SUNDAY NIGHT HERE ON ABC, SO,
WATCH HIM THERE.
WE'VE GOT A VERY GOOD LINEUP
NEXT WEEK.
TIM ALLEN BEEN HERE, ERIC
STONESTREET, L.A. REID, SIMON
COWELL, DEMI LOVATO AND MUSIC
FROM AMY MANN AND JAMES MERCER
AND FLO RIDA WILL BE HERE, TOO,
SO PLEASE WATCH IT.
IF IT WEREN'T FOR OUR FIRST
GUEST TONIGHT, THE WORLD MIGHT
NEVER HAVE DISCOVERED HOW A VERY
FUNNY NAZIS HUNCHBACKS CAN BE.
HE HOLDS THE BRAIN BEHIND
CLASSICS LIKE "THE PRODUCERS," A
MONDAY MORE GREAT FILMS.
A NEW BOX SET CELEBRATING HIS 65
YEARS IN ENTERTAINMENT, "THE
INCREDIBLE MEL BROOKS: AN
IRRESISTIBLE COLLECTION OF
UNHINGED COMEDY," IS OUT NOW.
PLEASE WELCOME MEL BROOKS.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: HOW ARE YOU?
>> IT'S ALMOST A PLEASURE TO BE
HERE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S VERY NICE.
VERY -- VERY, VERY NICE.
WASHED, CLEAN PEOPLE.
>> Jimmy: THEY HOSE THEM DOWN
BEFORE THEY COME IN.
>> LOVELY.
AND THE UNFRIEND THING ALMOST
WORKED.
>> Jimmy: ALMOST WORKED.
THIS CLOSE.
YOU'RE SAYING LONGER, SHOULD BE
LONGER?
WELL, THANK YOU.
I HAVE TO SAY -- IT IS -- IT'S
OKAY.
IT'S A GOOD PREMISE, YOU KNOW.
WHEN YOU SAID -- WE DIDN'T SAY
FRED, WE SAID FRIEND.
NOW -- I DON'T -- I WROTE THE
SHOW OF SHOWS FOR TEN YEARS.
[ APPLAUSE ]
AND -- AND I HAPPEN TO BE FREE
NOW, SO --
[ LAUGHTER ]
SO --
>> Jimmy: NOW YOU TELL ME.
WHERE WERE YOU THIS AFTERNOON.
>> GET A PREMISE LIKE THAT,
WE'LL TALK --
>> Jimmy: I'LL RUN IT BY YOU.
>> I CAN HELP.
>> Jimmy: YOU HAVE TO UNDERSTAND
THOUGH, HE'S CONFUSED BECAUSE
IT'S FRIEND AND HE THOUGHT IT
WAS FRED.
>> THEY GOT IT.
>> Jimmy: OH, OKAY.
MAKE SURE WE --
>> LET ME -- I -- THERE'S A
LITTLE HOLE IN THE DOOR WHERE
YOU CAN SEE THE AUDIENCE AND THE
MIDDLE OF IT, THERE WAS A LOT OF
THEM, THERE'S A WHOLE ROW OVER
THERE THAT WAS --
[ SNORING SOUND ]
BUT IT'S OKAY.
YOU'VE GOT TO TRY.
YOU'RE ON EVERY NIGHT.
>> Jimmy: AND IT'S IMPORTANT.
>> IT'S HARD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
>> Jimmy: IT'S IMPORTANT TO
REST, TOO.
IT'S SO IMPORTANT.
>> YES, YES.
IT'S HARD.
>> Jimmy: WELL, THANK YOU FOR
COMING.
WE'RE RIGHT -- YOU PUT THIS
TOGETHER, BUT WE'RE RIGHT ACROSS
THE STREET FROM THE CHINESE
THEATER, WHICH, THE CLIMAX OF
"BLAZING SADDLES" OCCURRED,
WHICH IS -- DOES THAT GIVE YOU
ANY FEELINGS OF --
>> WE SHOT HARVEY IN THE BALLS.
I KNOW, IT HAPPENED.
>> Jimmy: SOMEONE HAD TO.
>> RIGHT.
SOMEONE HAD TO.
>> Jimmy: ONE OF THE WRITERS OF
"BLAZING SADDLES," I LEARNED
FROM WATCHING THIS GREAT DVD
COLLECTION IS --
>> THANK YOU.
>> WAS RICHARD PRYOR, WHICH
SURPRISED ME, BECAUSE I DON'T
KNOW WHY I DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
HOW DID THAT HAPPEN?
>> HE WAS A BUDDY OF MINE.
HE WAS WORKING AT THE VANGUARD.
WE KIND OF HUNG OUT TOGETHER IN
THE VILLAGE.
AND WHEN WE GOT THE IDEA TO DO
"BLAZING SADDLES," IT'S ABOUT A
BLACK SHERIFF AND WE USED THE
N-WORD A LOT.
AND --
[ LAUGHTER ]
SO I CALLED RICHARD, I SAID,
RICHARD, I, YOU KNOW, I NEED YOU
TO BLESS THE N-WORD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
I, YOU KNOW, I'M CLOSE.
YOU KNOW, I'M A DRUMMER.
>> Jimmy: YEAH.
NICE.
THIS IS NOT DRUMS, THOUGH, THIS
IS A DESK, MEL.
>> YOU KNOW, THE TRUTH IS, IT'S
NOT REALLY A DESK.
>> Jimmy: NOT REALLY A DESK.
>> CARDBOARD.
IT'S MOSTLY CARDBOARD.
A DESK IS WOOD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
AND THIS LOOKS LIKE WOOD BUT IT
REALLY ISN'T WOOD.
>> Jimmy: IT'S A VINYL STICKER
WE PUT ON THE TOP.
>> IT'S ALL RIGHT.
SHOW BUSINESS.
>> Jimmy: THAT MOVIE, I THINK --
YOU KNOW, BECAUSE I SHOW MY
KIDS, JUST AS MY PARENTS, LIKE,
MY, "YOUNG FRANKENSTEIN," WE
WATCH THAT MOVIE MORE THAN ANY
MOVIE AS A FAMILY IN MY HOUSE.
WE PROBABLY WATCHED IT 80 TIMES,
I THINK.
>> THIS IS A DEPRIVED FAMILY.
>> Jimmy: NO, IT IS -- THAT
MOVIE IS BULLET PROOF.
IT IS FUNNY FROM BEGINNING TO
END AND IT DOESN'T MATTER WHAT
YEAR IT IS, I MEAN, I THINK
SOMETIMES YOU LOOK BACK AT
MOVIES AND PEOPLE, YOU KNOW, GO
FURTHER AND THEY DO THINGS THAT
ARE EVEN MORE EXTREME, BUT A
MOVIE LIKE "BLAZING SADDLES,"
THIS IS A MOVIE THAT EVEN -- I
THINK IT'S TOO POLITICALLY
INCORRECT TO BE MADE TODAY.
>> IT COULDN'T BE MADE TODAY.
COULD NOT.
THEY WOULDN'T LET YOU.
YOU KNOW, WHEN WE HAD A PREVIEW
AT THE EMBASSY, THERE WAS A GUY
RUNNING THE STUDIO.
THERE WERE TWO GUYS, ONE GUY,
HIS NAME WAS, A LOVELY GUY, HIS
NAME WAS JOHN CALLIE, HE WAS IN
CHARGE OF MAKING THE MOVIES.
AND THEN THERE WAS A GUY, TED
ASHLEY, WHO WAS IN CHARGE OF
WARNER BROTHERS.
AND HE WAS GOING WITH A GIRL,
HIS FIANCE, AND WE HAD THIS KIND
OF THIS PREVIEW, PEOPLE LAUGHED,
THEY ENJOYED.
I HE SHOVES ME INTO THE
MANAGER'S OFFICE, TERRIBLE
OFFICE, AND, ANYWAY, HE SAYS, HE
SAYS, OKAY, HERE'S A LEGAL PAD,
HERE'S A PENCIL.
TAKE THESE NOTES.
I SAID, YES, SIR.
HE RAN WARNER BROTHERS.
YES, SIR, WHATEVER YOU SAY.
HE SAYS, N-WORD, OUT.
IT'S OUT.
WE DON'T SAY IT.
HE SAID, NO PUNCHING A HORSE.
NO PUNCHING A HORSE.
AROUND THE CAMPFIRE, CUT OUT
THE FARTING.
OUT.
YOU CAN'T PUNCH AN OLD LADY.
THE BLACK SHERIFF -- OUT, OUT.
SO, OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
I -- I SAID YES, SIR, IT'S GONE.
IT NEVER HAPPENED.
COME BACK TOMORROW, IT'S ALL OUT
OF THE MOVIE.
HE LEAVES.
I CRUNCH IT UP AND I GO ALL THE
WAY ACROSS THE ROOM AND PUT IT
IN THE WASTEBASKET.
AND JOHN CALLIE SAYS GOOD
FILING.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> Jimmy: THANK GOD.
YOU WERE ABLE TO LEAVE IT IN.
>> NO, I HAD FINAL CUT SO I
SAID, YOU KNOW, WHAT DO I CARE?
YOU HAVE PROBLEMS, YOU KNOW.
>> Jimmy: YOU'RE ONE OF FEW
PEOPLE THAT HAVE WON THE EMMY,
GRAMMY, OSCAR AND TONY AWARD.
THAT'S A LOT OF HARDWARE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
THERE'S MORE?
>> AND NEXT THURSDAY, A WEEK
FROM TODAY, YOU WILL SEE THEM
ALL ON EBAY.
>> Jimmy: IS THAT RIGHT?
YOU'RE SELLING EVERYTHING?
>> I THINK THINGS ARE GOING AS
WELL AS YOU COULD.
>> Jimmy: WHAT DO YOU THINK YOU
COULD GET FOR ONE OF THOSE?
>> $100.
>> Jimmy: THAT'S JUST
UNBELIEVABLE.
DOES THAT MAKE AN IMPRESSION ON
YOU?
I KNOW YOU ARE GETTING AN HONOR
FROM THE AMERICAN FILM
INSTITUTE.
>> THAT'S IMPORTANT BECAUSE I
SPENT MY LIFE IN, YOU KNOW,
MAKING MOVIES AND TO BE
ALONGSIDE CAPPRA AND FORD AND
HITCHCOCK, THAT'S A REAL HONOR.
>> Jimmy: THAT MEANS SOMETHING
TO YOU.
[ APPLAUSE ]
HOW DID YOU -- HOW DID YOU GET
INTO SHOW BUSINESS IN THE FIRST
PLACE?
>> WHAT DID YOU SAY?
>> Jimmy: HOW DID YOU GET INTO
SHOW BUSINESS IN THE FIRST
PLACE?
>> WELL, THAT'S REALLY NONE OF
YOUR BUSINESS, JIMMY.
>> Jimmy: TELL THEM AND I'LL
LISTEN IN.
>> ALL RIGHT.
YOU KNOW --
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU MEET PEOPLE, YOU KNOW?
YOU KNOW, THE BAND, I LOVE THE
BAND, THE BAND -- I WAS IN THE
MOUNTAINS, GOOD EVENING LADIES
AND JEWS --
>> Jimmy: IN THE CATSKILLS?
>> YEAH, THE CATSKILLS.
THIS IS ALL TRUE.
I WOULD SAY GOOD EVENING, LADIES
AND GENTLEMEN, MAN OF A HOUSE
FACES.
ONE.
TWO.
THREE.
THE JEWS WAITED FOR 1,000 FACES.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THE BAND --
>> Jimmy: THEY WANTED THEM ALL?
>> THE BAND ALWAYS LAUGHED.
BY THE SIXTH FACE, THE BAND GOT
IT, YOU KNOW.
THE BAND IS NOT THAT SMART.
>> Jimmy: THEY WERE WITH ME ON
THE FRIEND THING, TOO.
>> I HEARD THEM ON THE FRED
THING.
[ SNORING ]
>> Jimmy: WHEN WE COME BACK,
WE'RE GOING TO LOOK AT SOMETHING
FROM THIS GREAT COLLECTION, "THE
INCREDIBLE MEL BROOKS: AN
IRRESISTIBLE COLLECTION OF
UNHINGED COMEDY."
MEL BROOKS IS HERE.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] EVERY TIME
YOU SAY NO TO A CIGARETTE
YOU CELEBRATE A LITTLE WIN.
NICORETTE GUM HELPS CALM
YOUR CRAVINGS
AND MAKES YOU LESS IRRITABLE.
QUIT ONE CIGARETTE AT A TIME.
THAT THERE'S THE GUY WHO GETS
HIS SALSA FROM NEW YORK CITY.
NEW YORK CITY?!
[ Male Announcer ] ONLY PACE
HAS THAT BIG, BOLD KICK.
ANYTHING ELSE JUST AIN'T RIGHT.
PACE. GRAB THE SOUTHWEST
BY THE BOTTLE.
AND THIS IS
THE NOKIA LUMIA 920 FROM AT&T.
IT'S GOT LIVE TILES
SO ALL MY STUFF'S
ALWAYS RIGHT THERE IN REAL-TIME.
IT'S LIKE
THE ULTIMATE PERSONAL ASSISTANT.
BUT I'M ME,
AND ME NEEDS HANDLERS.
SO I HIRED TODD
TO HANDLE IT FOR ME.
TODD, GIMME THAT HOLLYWOOD NEWS!
WHAT'S HAPPENING ON TWITTER?
YOU'RE TRENDING!
YES!
YOU CAN'T HAVE A TODD,
BUT YOU CAN HAVE YOUR
OWN PERSONAL ASSISTANT.
I GUESS
YOU COULD CALL IT TODD.
[ Male Announcer ] THE NEW
NOKIA LUMIA 920 WITH LIVE TILES
THAT DELIVER WHAT YOU WANT
IN REAL TIME.
ONLY FROM AT&T.
RETHINK POSSIBLE.
THAT DELIVER WHAT YOU WANT
IN REAL TIME.
This season, give Craftsman
tools and give the gifts that
keep on giving.
CRAFTSMAN. GUYS'
FAVORITES GUARANTEED.
FIND IT AT SEARS.
>> Jimmy: WE HAVE MEL BROOKS
SITTING IN WITH THE CLETONES.