THIS COST A DOLLAR A
BAG, COMPARED TO THIS.
SURPRISING TIPS TO
EATING ON A BUDGET.
PLUS CREATING THE
PERFECT GIFT BASKETS.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO KEEP THINGS UP
RIGHT IN OTHER WAYS.
AND DON'TS.
DO NOT PLACE
CHOCOLATE ITEMS AND
CANDLES TOGETHER.
LIVE WELL FOR LESS WITH
DEALS STARTS RIGHT NOW.
♪
HIGH STYLE TABLE SCAPES
WITHOUT THE EXPENSIVE
PRICE TAG AND YOU WON'T
BELIEVE WHAT WE USED
TO DECORATE IT WITH.
THIS IS WHAT YOU
DO FOR A LIVING.
YES.
BUT WE KIND OF CHALLENGE
YOU AT DEALS A LITTLE BIT.
YOU DO, YOU REALLY DO.
WE KNOW YOU KEEP BUDGETS
FOR THE PEOPLE YOU DESIGN
FOR BUT THEIR BUDGET MIGHT
BE A LITTLE BIGGER
THAN SOME OF OURS.
THAT'S PRETTY TRUE.
I WORK WITH
SIZABLE BUDGETS.
ANYWHERE FROM SEVEN
THOUSAND TO TEN
THOUSAND AS A BASE.
AND GO FROM THERE.
HOLY MOLY YEAH I
DEFIANTLY DON'T HAVE
A BUDGET LIKE THAT.
BUT DESIGNER DWIGHT
TELLS ME WE CAN PULL
OF A SIMILAR LOOK
FOR A FRACTION OF THE COST.
YOU NEVER HAVE TO SACRIFICE
HIGH STYLE AND SOPHISTICATION
FOR AFFORDABILITY.
AND USING THING
YOU HAVE ON HAND AND
A LITTLE PLANNING YOU CAN
ABSOLUTELY RECREATE THIS
FOR ALL YOUR DINNER GUEST.
THE FIRST PLACE TO SAVE
TONS THAT TABLE CLOTH.
IT'S ACTUALLY A BED SHEET.
AND I TELL PEOPLE IF YOU
DON'T HAVE FINE IMPORTED
LINENS ITS NO BIG DEAL.
YOU CAN TAKE A BED SHEET,
AND I'VE USED IT MANY
TIMES, AND NO ONE EVER KNOWS.
THIS IS KEY.
IF YOU'RE WORKING WITH A
BED SHEET THAT HAS A LOW
THREAD COUNT BY LAYING
FELT ON THE TABLE FIRST IT
WILL IMPROVE THE WAY THE SHEET
DRAPES AND HANGS ON THE TABLE.
WHERE DO YOU GET FELT?
ANY FABRIC STORE
WILL HAVE IT.
THIS RAN ME MAYBE FOUR OR
THREE DOLLARS A YARD, AND WE'RE
WORKING WITH THREE YARDS HERE.
HE DRESSES THE BED
SHEET WITH THE OVERLAY.
WHAT IS THIS?
ITS ALMOST LIKE A CORSET.
THAT'S INTERESTING YOU
PICKED UP ON THAT.
THAT'S THE INSPIRATION
BEHIND THIS OVERLAY.
I LIKE USING VELUM
BECAUSE THE TRANSPARENCY
THAT IT HAS.
BUT IF YOU DON'T HAVE THAT
OR WANT TO BUY IT YOU CAN
ACHIEVE THE LOOK WITH
PLAIN OLD PRINTER PAPER.
YOU'VE GOT TO START
WITH A TEMPLATE FIRST.
THIS IS WHAT I MADE
FOR THIS TABLE.
THIS IS PRETTY EXTENSIVE.
I DO HAVE AN ARCHITECTURAL
BACKGROUND THAT MIGHT BE WHY IT
LOOKS MORE TECHNICAL THAN IT IS.
YOU DECIDE HOW MANY
PANELS YOU WANT THE
OVERLAY TO HAVE.
THEN YOUR IN WORK ON EACH SIDE,
THAT TELLS ME WHAT SIZE EACH
VELUM PANEL NEEDS TO BE.
PUNCH WHOLES IN TO LACE
THE RIBBON THROUGH, ITS
IMPORTANT YOU START WITH
THE CORNERS BECAUSE
IT LACES TOGETHER.
AND ONCE YOU GET THAT DONE
YOU DECIDE HOW FAR YOU WANT
THE WHOLE TO BE SPACED APART.
I USUALLY DO ABOUT
TWO INCHES TWO AND
A HALF INCHES APART.
ONCE YOU GET THE HOLES
IN YOU STRING THE RIBBON.
ACTUALLY WE SHOULD
HAVE GONE UNDER.
BECAUSE YOU WANT THE
XS TO STAY ON TOP.
THIS IS WHY I'M HERE.
SO I CAN MAKE
ALL THE MISTAKES AND
YOU DON'T MAKE THEM.
THEN WE LACE UNDER.
OH.
DWIGHT ADVICES DO
NOT DO THIS THE SAME
DAY AS THE PARTY.
I DON'T WANT TO RECEIVE
ANY EMAILS SAYING WAIT A
MINUTE THIS IS NOT, YOU
MADE IT LOOK A LOT EASIER.
DEPENDING ON THE SIZE OF
YOUR TABLE IT CAN TAKE A
COUPLE DAYS TO DO.
THESE GLASSES.
THESE ARE JUST JUICE
GLASSES THAT I HAD AROUND
THE HOUSE AND I TOOK THEM
AND I'M GOING TO USE THEM
AS RISERS, AND I FILLED THEM
FIRST WITH DRIED SPLIT PEAS.
HOW COOL.
KIND OF COOL YEAH.
HE USES RECYCLED GLASS
FROM AN OLD PIECE OF
FURNITURE AS A RISER IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE TABLE.
SMELLS GREAT DOESN'T IT.
AND FILLED THEM
WITH COFFEE BEANS.
AND LOOK AT THIS, HE
ADDS A BRANCH AS PART
OF THE CENTERPIECE.
HE GAVE IT A GOOD CLEANING
WITH BLEACH AND WATER YOU
WOULDN'T WANT UNINVITED
GUEST SHOWING
UP AT THE PARTY.
WHEN ITS DRIED WE ADD SOME
GOLD WIRE BEADS AND MOSS
AROUND IT TO DRESS IT UP A BIT.
BUT ITS JUST THAT SIMPLE.
ITS ALL ABOUT USING
WHAT YOU HAVE AT HAND.
THIS IS JUST AS YOU CAN
SEE A CABBAGE HEAD, I WILL
TURN ANYTHING INTO A VASE.
YOU KNOW.
SO I CARVED IT OUT AND BY
TAKING LIKE FOAM OASIS
THAT'S BEEN SOAKED IN WATER
WE CAN INSERT IT IN THERE.
NOW CARVING IT OUT, IS
IT AS SIMPLE AS TAKING
A KNIFE ON THE INSIDE.
ITS LIKE A PUMPKIN.
IF YOU TAKE IT AND SPRAY
IT WITH WATER AND PUT IT
IN A PLASTIC BAG
AND IN YOUR CRISPER FOR A COUPLE
DAYS IT WILL HARDEN AND
STAY THIS WAY THAT'S HOW
ITS ABLE TO SIT OUT ON THE
TABLE DURING THE DINNER
PARTY AND NOT WILT.
THAT'S THE KEY
RIGHT THERE.
THAT'S THE KEY.
I KNEW THERE HAD
TO BE SOMETHING.
OKAY COOL.
INEXPENSIVE
SUPERMARKET ROSES.
THESE ARE SPRAY ROSES,
I TAKE THEM AND START
INSERTING THEM INTO OUR OASIS.
WE ADD GOURDS,
MOSS AND PLACEMATS.
IT WAS A LONG TWIG RUNNER
THAT I TOOK AND JUST CUT UP
INTO PARTS AND MADE
OUR PLACEMATS WITH WHITE CHINA
IS ABSOLUTELY THE BEST WAY
TO STRETCH A DOLLAR.
YOU CAN USE THIS OVER
AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
ENDLESS THEMES,
COLOR COMBINATIONS.
THERE IS ONLY ONE PLACE
SETTING IN THIS DESIGN AND
ONE IN THAT BUT IF YOU SEE
IF YOU PUT THEM TOGETHER.
YEAH THEY COMPLIMENT
EACH OTHER.
I'M ALL ABOUT MIXING AND
MATCHING SO BELIEVE IT OR
NOT FOR 18 DOLLARS WE HAVE
A PLACE SETTING
FOR 6 PEOPLE.
I LOVE IT.
AND LOOK AT THESE
CUTE NAME HOLDERS.
SOME GHOST PUMPKINS, AND VELUM
AND I WROTE NAMES ON IT AND
USE THIS TO SECURE IT ON HERE.
AND THERE IS ONE FOR ME.
ABSENTLY A PLACE
HERE FOR YOU KAT.
PUT ONE CENTER
ON EACH DISH.
A FEW FLAMELESS CANDLES TO SET
THE MOOD AND CONTINUES WITH
THE MOOD OF MIXING AND MATCHING.
AND NAPKIN RINGS.
GORGEOUS.
VERY HIGH END AND
SHEIK AREN'T THEY.
WELL I MADE THOSE.
I MADE THOSE.
YOU CAN TAKE ANY TYPE OF
INNER TUBE YOU MIGHT HAVE
FROM ALUMINUM FOIL, GLAD WRAP.
I'M GOING TO USE LIKE A
TUBE FROM PAPER TOWELS.
WE MEASURE AN INCH AND A
HALF ON THE TUBE AND CUT
IT OUT WITH AN EXACTO KNIFE.
THIS IS RIBBON FROM THE
HOLIDAYS AND I LOVE IT
BECAUSE ITS BURLAP.
THEN WE MAKE SMALL CUTS
ON EACH END.
FOLD THE FABRIC
INSIDE AND GLUE.
ONCE I'VE DONE THAT I THEN
TAKE GOLD WIRE AND SIMPLY
WRAPPED IT AROUND, TWISTED IT,
CREATED MY OWN DESIGN.
NO RHYME OR REASON TO IT.
AND TO EMBELLISH IT
EVEN MORE A HAZEL NUT.
THEN ANOTHER WIRE
AROUND THAT AND
GLUED IT TOGETHER.
BEAUTIFUL.
LOOK AT THIS
GORGEOUS TABLE.
WE'RE KEEPING IT
IN THE 250 RANGE.
NO, NO, NO, LOWER,
I CREATED THIS ON
A 50 DOLLAR BUDGET.
UNBELIEVABLE.
AND CAN YOU IMAGINE
THE CONVERSATION ABOUT
THIS UNIQUE TABLE.
SO BE THE TALK OF THE TOWN
WITH DWIGHT'S DESIGN.
JUST GO TO LIVEWELLNETWORK.COM
AND CLICK ON DEALS
FOR ALL THE DETAILS.
STILL AHEAD A STEP BY
STEP GUIDE FOR DESIGNING
YOUR OWN UNIQUE
BUT PROFESSIONAL
LOOKING GIFT BASKET.
BUT NEXT OUR BOOTS ARE MADE FOR
WALKING BUT IF YOURS SEEM TO BE
ON THEIR LAST LEG, WE CAN HELP.
THIS IS THE BEST
ECONOMICAL PRODUCT.
OUR DIY BOOT MAKEOVERS
WHEN DEALS RETURNS.
THESE LEATHER SHOES LOOK
BRAND NEW BUT THEY'RE NOT.
EVERY SO OFTEN DOCTOR OKESY
STRETCHES HIS DOLLAR BY GETTING
HIS SHOES RENEWED AT THE SHOE
HOSPITAL, BUT THEY SAY YOU CAN
SAVE EVEN MORE MONEY BY DOING
SOME OF THE WORK YOURSELF.
THIS IS THE BEST
ECONOMICAL PRODUCT.
FOR SUEDE AND FABRIC BOOTS
LIKE UGGS TRY THE SUEDE
CLEANER FOR 7.95,
IT WILL NOT ONLY CLEAN AND
CONDITION BUT ALSO
SOFTEN YOUR SUEDE.
BUT IF YOU WANT TO DO IT
YOURSELF AND KIND OF KEEP
YOUR SUEDE'S LOOKING GOOD
THEN THIS PRODUCT
IS REALLY GOOD.
WE DECIDED TO
GIVE IT A TRY.
THESE UGGS AS YOU
CAN SEE ARE BADLY
STAINED AND DIRTY.
USING THE SUEDE CLEANER
AND FOLLOWING THE
DIRECTION WE LIBERALLY
SPRAY OUR CLEANER AND
SCRUB AWAY ESPECIALLY
WHERE THE STAINS ARE SET IN.
AFTER SEVERAL MINUTES AND
A SORE ARM WE ARE ABLE TO
LIFT THE STAINS TAKE A LOOK
AT THE STAINS
BEFORE AND NOW AFTER A
CLEANER FRESHER BOOT.
NEXT UP A PAIR
OF COWBOY BOOTS.
KELLY SAYS THIS LEATHER
ONLY CLEANER WHICH COST
20 BUCKS IS ANOTHER DIY PRODUCT
TO MAINTAIN YOUR SHOES.
YOU WANT TO PUT THE CONDITIONING
BACK INTO IT TO KEEP THEM
MOIST AND PROTECTED.
WE GENTLY CLEAN OUR
BOOTS AND TAKE A LOOK AT
THE BOOTS BEFORE AND NOW AFTER.
COMPLETELY CONDITIONED.
AND FINALLY OUR FASHION
BOOTS, YOU CAN SEE THEY'RE
A LITTLE SCUFFED, WHETHER
THEY'RE OLD OR BRAND NEW
KELLY SAYS PROTECT YOUR
INVESTMENT WITH
AN ALL STAIN PROTECTOR AND WATER
PROTECTOR FOR 7.95 A QUICK
ONCE OVER WITH
THE LEATHER ONLY PRODUCT AND
THEY LOOK RENEWED.
NOW IF YOU'RE HARD ON SHOES LIKE
I AM YOU MIGHT BE FORCED TO VIST
THE SHOE DOCTOR.
KELLY SAYS IT IS
POSSIBLE TO MAKE THE
OLD LOOK NEW AGAIN.
TAKE THESE UGG
BOOTS FOR EXAMPLE.
KELLY SAYS THIS
IS A TYPICAL WEAR AND
TARE AND DISCOLORING.
WERE GOING TO CLEAN IT
WELL, ADD PIGMENT TO BLEND
EVERYTHING BACK IN, AND
THEN ALWAYS ADD A WATER
PROFFER TO YOUR UGG BOOTS.
TAKE A LOOK NOW.
THE PRICE 25.99 TO REVIVE.
A RETAIL PRICE TO REPAIR.
195 BUCKS.
I WOULD SAY THAT'S
QUITE A DEAL.
THESE BOOTS WERE
ALMOST THROWN OUT.
THEY'RE WORN OUT, BEAT
UP AND ALMOST HAVE
HOLES IN THE SOLES.
BUT THE OWNER REFUSED TO
GIVE THEM UP BECAUSE SHE
PAID SO MUCH FOR THEM.
WE'RE GOING TO PUT NEW
LEATHER SOLES ON THESE,
RE-PEG THE SHANK FORM, PUT
NEW HEELS AND ADD A
CONDITIONER AND
SANTICOSHER CREAM TO THIS BOOK
AND ITS GOING
TO LOOK FANTASTIC.
TAKE A LOOK NOW.
FOR 59.95 THESE BOOKS LOOK
BRAND NEW WITHOUT
SACRIFICING THE CHARACTER.
KELLY ADMITS HE WASN'T
SURE IF THIS BOOT
COULD BE SALVAGED.
THE SUEDE HAS BEEN
ALMOST WORN OFF AND
THE BOOT IS TORN.
THEY'VE REALLY WORN INTO
THIS BOOT, PROBABLY WORN
DOWN SO MUCH TO WHERE
THEY'RE WALKING ON
THE HEEL COUNTERS.
NOW TAKE A LOOK
AFTER THE REPAIRS.
THE EXPERTS WERE
ABLE TO SAVE THEM.
REMEMBER WHAT THEY LOOKED
LIKE BEFORE TOTALLY
TRANSFORMED FOR JUST 25 DOLLARS.
TO SEE THIS STORY AGAIN
GO TO LIVEWELLNETWORK.COM
AND CLICK ON DEALS.
UP NEXT EVERYTHING YOU
NEED TO KNOW TO CREATE
BEAUTIFUL PROFESSIONAL
LOOKING GIFT BASKETS
FOR ANY OCCASION
WHEN DEALS RETURNS.
GIFT BASKETS REALLY ARE
THE BEST GIFT OR THE MOST
PREFERRED GIFT TO GIVE A PERSON
BECAUSE YOU CAN
REALLY PUT YOUR ARTISTRY
INTO CREATING SOMETHING
THAT WILL BE REMEMBERED FOREVER.
AND SHIRLEY GEORGE
IS AN EXPERT.
SHE'S ACTUALLY A
BASKETOLOGIST.
MAKING GIFT BASKETS IS
VERY EASY, ITS NOT A
DIFFICULT PROCESS BECAUSE
YOU ARE GOING TO FIND ITEMS
THAT ARE GOING TO PUT
A BIG SMILE ON A PERSONS FACE.
AUTHOR OF THE GIFT BASKET DESIGN
BOOK WE CAUGHT UP WITH HER AT TE
ACCESSORY PLACE
FOR A LESSON.
ANY TYPE OF OPEN CONTAINER
CAN BE A BASKET.
YOU'RE GOING TO FIND
BASKETS PERHAPS IN YOUR
HOME THAT YOU MAY NOT HAVE
A PURPOSE FOR
ANYMORE AND YOU JUST
WANT TO REPURPOSE IT.
THE FIRST THING YOU DO
AFTER YOU PICK YOUR BASKET
OR YOUR CONTAINER IS TO
GET SOME GROCERY
STORE BAGS.
THOSE JUST REGULAR BROWN
GROCERY STORE BAGS.
YOU'RE GOING TO OPEN THE
BAG, RIGHT AT THAT SPLIT.
AND OPEN IT UP SO THAT ITS
NICE AND FLAT AND THEN CRUSH IT,
SO THAT ITS NICE AND FIRM.
AND THAT FIRMNESS IS
GOING TO HELP YOU TO KEEP
ALL OF THE GIFTS AND FOOD
STABILIZED INSIDE THE
BASKET OR CONTAINER
SO NOTHING FALLS.
ONCE YOU HAVE PAPER
BAGS INSIDE TO
STABILIZE ANYTHING.
THE NEXT STEP
IS SHRED ON TOP.
THAT WILL HIDE GROCERY
STORE BAGS ON THE
BOTTOM OF THE BASKET.
THEN ADD THE GOODIES.
SHIRLEY HAS A TIP TO
KEEP EVERYTHING UPRIGHT.
OTHER THAN USING THE PAPER
WHICH IS THE BASE FOR
MAKING YOUR GIFT BASKET
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
KEEP ITEM UPRIGHT IN OTHER
WAYS, YOU CAN USE SKEWERS,
YES I'M TALKING
ABOUT THE BBQ SKEWERS
WE USE EVERY SUMMER.
YOU WILL BREAK THE SKEWERS
INTO THREE INCH PIECES,
AND THEN ATTACH THE
SKEWERS ON THE BACK
OF CERTAIN ITEMS.
YOU JUST ATTACH THE
SKEWER WITH TAPE.
YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE TO
USE SCISSORS TO JUST PUNCH
A WHOLE IN THE PAPER AND
BRING THE SKEWER DOWN
INTO THE PAPER UNTIL ALL
THE ITEMS STAY UPRIGHT.
THAT'S BECAUSE A HEAVY
ITEM LIKE A BOTTLE OF
CIDER OR SOMETHING ELSE
THAT'S HEAVY NEEDS THE
STABILIZATION OF A SKEWER
BUT THE ITEMS AROUND IT,
MAYBE CHIPS, MAYBE DIP,
THAT'S GOING TO BE THE
LIGHT, AND THAT'S GOING TO
ACTUALLY JUST SIT ON THE SIDE OF
THE HEAVY ITEM SO THAT THOSE
ITEMS STAY UPRIGHT AS WELL.
FILL THE BASKET WITH GOODIES YOU
KNOW THE RECIPIENT WILL LOVE IS
THE BEST PART AND THE MOST FUNT
THINK ABOUT THE PERSON RECEIVING
THE GIFT BECAUSE YOU WANT TO
AMAZE AND DAZZLE THEM.
ALSO THINK ABOUT THE
ENHANCEMENTS THAT YOU ADD.
AFTER YOU PUT YOUR GIFT
BASKET TOGETHER AND ITS
LOOKING BOUNTIFUL AND DAZZLING,
NOW YOU'RE
GOING TO CLOSE IT.
SO I'M GOING TO NEED THE
TAPE, THE SCISSORS, AND
THE CELLOPHANE AND THE BOW.
YOU'RE GOING TO USE THE
MOST POPULAR ITEM TO CLOSE
A BASKET AND THAT IS CELLOPHANE.
CELLOPHANE CAN BE PURCHASED
AT MANY, MANY CRAFT STORES,
YOU WILL TAKE THE CELLOPHANE,
UNWRAP IT, AND PLACE IT
UNDERNEATH THE GIFT BASKET AND
BRING THE CELLOPHANE UP
IN FRONT AND
IN BACK OF THE BASKET.
CLOSE THE CELLOPHANE AND
THEN CLOSE FROM BACK TO
FRONT AND FRONT TO BACK.
THAT IS IT FOR CLOSING.
ON THE SIDE.
TAPE DOWN THE BACK ENDS OF
THE CELLOPHANE SO THEY'RE NOT
IN THE WAY OF THE APPEARANCE,
THEN USE A TWIST TIE
TO SECURE THE CELLOPHANE
AT THE TOP.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
NOW ITS TIME FOR THE BOW.
YOU PROBABLY HAVE BOWS IN
YOUR HOME ALREADY, SO EVEN
THOUGH YOU HAVE THE OPTION
OF PICKING A BOW OR TWO UP
FROM A CRAFT STORE, FIRST
JUST LIKE WITH THE BASKET
AND THE ITEMS YOU'RE GOING
TO PUT IN THE GIFT BASKET
LOOK AROUND YOUR HOME.
YOU PUT THE BOW ON, AND PUT
THE TWIST TIE BECAUSE YOU NEED
THE TIE FOR YOUR NEXT BASKET.
NOW YOU CROWN THAT BASKET
WITH THAT BEAUTIFUL BOW
THAT COMES FROM YOUR HEART
AND YOUR HOUSE
AT THE SAME TIME.
AND THAT IS YOUR
TOTAL GIFT BASKET.
FROM WHAT WE CALL THE
BASKET TO THE BOW.
NOW THERE ARE SOME DOS
AND DON'TS WHEN IT COMES
TO MAKING A GIFT BASKET.
ONE IS TO MAKE SURE THAT
YOU DO NOT PLACE CHOCOLATE
ITEMS AND FRAGRANT CANDLES
OR FRAGRANT SOAPS TOGETHER.
YOU WANT THE PERSON WHOSE
RECEIVING THE BASKET TO GET
EVERYTHING AND TO ENJOY
EVERYTHING IN THE BASKET.
MAKE SURE YOU KNOW OF ANY
ALLERGIC REACTION TO ANY NUT
ITEMS, AND PASTA ITEMS,
ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
ANOTHER THING ABOUT GIFT
BASKETS THAT IS A DON'T IS
CUTTING YOUR CELLOPHANE
A LITTLE TOO SHORT.
A LOT OF TIMES WHEN YOU'RE
NOT SURE HOW TALL A PIECE
OF CELLOPHANE SHOULD BE
OR HOW BIG YOU SHOULD CUT
YOUR CELLOPHANE SOMETIMES
YOU DON'T HAVE A BIG ENOUGH FAN
ON THE GIFT BASKET
AND IT COULD BE STUBBY
RIGHT AT THE TOP,
SO MAKE SURE YOUR CUT
IT AS TALL AS POSSIBLE.
FIND ALL OF SHIRLEY'S TIPS ON
LIVEWELLNETWORK.COM AND
SEARCH GIFT BASKETS.
UP NEXT WHERE CAN YOU FIND
HEALTHY FOOD THAT COSTS
LESS AND LAST LONGER THAN
MOST FRESH OFFERINGS THIS
DIETITIANS SECRETS WILL
LEAVE YOU PLEASANTLY SURPRISED.
BECAUSE THE FROZEN
VEGETABLES ARE PICKED
AT THE PEAK OF.
THAT'S NEXT ON DEALS.
THERE ARE SO MANY MISCONCEPTIONS
ABOUT WHAT'S CONSIDERED HEALTHY
AND WHAT'S NOT.
AND WHILE MANY OF YOU
MIGHT SHY FROM CANNED OR
FROZEN FOODS, IT ACTUALLY
MIGHT BE A GOOD OPTION
IF YOU'RE TRYING
TO SAVE SOME MONEY.
WHEN IT COMES TO STRETCHING
A MEAL, CYNTHIA WILLIAMS
IS PINCHING PENNIES,
BUT WILLIAMS IS
NOT CHOOSING JUNK FOOD,
SHE WANTS TO FEED HER FAMILY
HEALTHY MEALS, THAT'S WHY
SHE HAS CANNED AND FROZEN
VEGETABLES IN HER CART.
A MOVE THAT DIETICIAN
PENNY WILSON SAYS IS SMART.
YOU CAN SAVE MONEY AND EAT
WELL AT THE SAME TIME.
TIP NUMBER ONE.
TO SAVE ON FOOD, CHOOSE
FROZEN OVER FRESH, ITS
USUALLY CHEAPER.
BECAUSE THE FROZEN VEGETABLES
ARE PICKED AT THE PEAK OF
RIPENESS AND FROZEN RIGHT THEN.
TAKE FOR EXAMPLE BROCCOLI,
WE FOUND IT FOR 2.18 FRESH,
BUT IN THE FROZEN FOOD SECTION
BROCCOLI CUTS COST $1 A BAG
FOR ABOUT THE SAME SIZE
AS THE FRESH BUNCH.
AND YOU DON'T HAVE
TO WORRY ABOUT
THEM GOING BAD.
TIP NUMBER TWO GO
FOR CANNED VEGGIES.
WE GREW UP ON CANNED
VEGETABLES, THAT'S ALL
WE HAD IN MY HOUSE.
WILSON SAYS WHILE FRESH
PRODUCE IS ALWAYS A GREAT OPTION
SHE SAYS CANNED VEGETABLES
ARE A GOOD SUBSTITUTE.
JUST READ THE LABELS.
STILL 10% ONE THING YOU WANT TO
LOOK FOR IS IF YOU CAN GET
THE ONES WITH NO ADDED SALT.
BECAUSE THEY DO TEND
TO ADD SALT INTO
CANNED VEGETABLES.
TIP NUMBER THREE BEANS
ARE A SUPER FOOD.
A LOT OF PEOPLE DON'T
REALIZE BEANS ARE A GOOD
SOURCE OF PROTEIN AND FIBER.
SHE SAYS CANNED BEANS ARE
A GREAT OPTION BUT TO SAVE EVEN
MORE PICK UP SOME DRIED BEANS.
YEAH, YOU'RE GOING TO GET
MORE OVERALL WITH THAT.
TIP NUMBER FOUR BUY YOUR
GRAINS FROM THE BULK FOOD
CONTAINERS LIKE OATS OR
BROWN RICE, WILSON SAYS
YOU WILL SAVE A BUNDLE,
FOR EXAMPLE WE PICKED UP
A POUND OF STEEL CUT OATS OF
1.29 VS 4.69 FOR A POUND AND
A HALF WE FOUND ON THE SHELF.
FINALLY PICK SUPER FOODS
THAT ARE JAMMED PACKED WITH
VITAMINS AND BUDGET-FRIENDLY
THESE INCLUDE SWEET POTATOES,
APPLES AND KALE.
FOR TIPS ON THESE GO TO
OUR WEBSITE
LIVEWELLNETWORK.COM AND
CLICK ON DEALS.
THAT WILL DO IT FOR
THIS ADDITION OF DEALS.
WHAT'S YOUR DEAL?
WE ALWAYS WANT TO HEAR
YOUR MONEY SAVING IDEAS
AND TALK TO US ANYTIME ONLINE.
UNTIL NEXT TIME
I'M KAT COSLEY
THANKS SO MUCH FOR JOINING US.
IT'S AN ISLAND PARADISE WHERE
CRYSTAL CLEAR WATERS, WHITE SAND
BEACHES AND SPECTACULAR SUNSETS
COMBINE TO MAKE THIS
ONE OF THE TOP VACATION
DESTINATIONS IN THE WORLD.
WOW, THIS IS AMAZING.
SEE HOW A LITTLE TWIST ON THE
WAY YOU TRAVEL CAN TURN ALL
THIS INTO YOUR OWN TROPICAL
PLAYGROUND.
THIS IS SO COOL.
GET READY TO SET SAIL ON
THE BRITISH VIRGIN ISLANDS,
COMING UP NEXT ON MOTION.
♪