ESS
OF FINDING OUT, SHALL WE?
THE JEOPARDY! ROUND
COMES FIRST, AS ALWAYS.
IT CONTAINS ONE DAILY DOUBLE
AND'LL FIND IT
IN ONE OF THESE CATEGORIES...
WELL GIVE YOU THE YEAR.
YOU IDENTIFY THE POPE.
JASON, START.
CLASSIC NOVELS FOR $200.
WHAT IS "A ROOM WITH A VIEW"?
NO. KAREN OR DOUG?
(imitates Dracula)
BIG BAT. "DRACULA."
I AM DRACULA. YOU ARE NOT.
(normal voice) JASON.
UH, CLASSIC NOVELS FOR $400.
WHAT IS "WAR AND PEACE"?
CLASSIC NOVELS FOR $600.
WHAT IS "BLACK BEAUTY"?
CLASSIC NOVELS FOR $800.
WHAT ARE PIONEERS?
CLASSIC NOVELS, $1,000.
WHAT IS "SENSE AND SENSIBILITY"?
BROADWAY MUSICAL SETTINGS, $200.
WHAT IS "THE KING AND I"?
UH, BROADWAY FOR $400.
WHAT IS "MEMPHIS"?
BROADWAY MUSICALS, $600.
WHAT IS RIVER CITY?
COLORS FOR $200.
WHAT IS YELLOW?
COLORS FOR $400.
WHAT IS EMERALD?
COLORS, $600.
WHAT IS GRAY?
WHAT IS "MAMMA MIA!"?
BROADWAY FOR $1,000.
WHAT IS BALTIMORE?
COLORS FOR $800.
WHAT IR?
NOPE. KAREN.
WHAT IS PURPLE?
COLORS FOR $1,000.
AND YOU HAVE JUST TAKEN
THE LEAD AWAY FROM JASON.
A LOT OF POSSIBILITIES
FOR YOU HERE.
I'LL BET $1,800.
$1,800. THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
THAT'LL TAKE YOU UP TO $5,000.
HERE IS THE CLUE...
KAREN?
WHAT IS CRIMSON?
NO. WHAT IS CARDINAL?
OH.
CARDINAL.
ALL RIGHT, THAT'S TOO BAD.
LET'S TAREAK
AND WE'LL RELAX
FOR A FEW MOMENTS
WHILE WE PAUSE
FOR THESE MESSAGES.
KE A B DOUG DAVIES IS
AND WE'LL RELAX
AN INVESTMENT CONSULTANT
FROM MONROVIA, CALIFORNIA,
WH WALKED
IN THE ROSE PARADE IN PASADENA
WHEN YOU WERE IN SCHOOL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WERE YOU IN A MARCHING BAND?
MY HIGH SCHOOL BAND WAS
A MULTIPLE STATE CHAMPION
AND ALWAYS INVITED TO PERFORM
IN THE ROSE PARADE.
AND I WAS FRONT AND CENTER
AND RIGHT BEHIND
A QUITE CONSIDERABLE LINE
OF, UH, CLYDESDALES
FOR THE ENTIRE 5 MILES AND--
AND HOW DID THAT WORK OUT
FOR YOU?
WELL, I STARTED
WITH WHITE SHOES
AND I WOUND UP WITH SOMETHING
ELSE. (speaks indistinctly)
THE SHOVELERS DIDN'T GET IN
QUICKLY ENOUGH BEHIND
THE HORSES. ALL RIGHT.
KAREN HEDLUND, A NURSING TUTOR
FROM BROOKLYN, NEW YORK,
WHOSE FAMILY HAS LIVED IN
THE SAME HOUSE IN BROOKLYN...
FOR 75 YEARS, ALEX.
WOW.
IN, UM, 1934,
WE WERE DISPLACED
FROM OUR PREVIOUS HOME
TO MAKE WAY
FOR A STATE COURTHOUSE
AND WE USED THE MONEY TO BUY
A LOVELY LITTLE ROOMING HOUSE,
UH, JUST AROUND THE CORNER
TWO YEARS LATER,
AND WERE STILL THERE TODAY.
STILL THERE AND NO DANGER
OF BEING DISPLACED AGAIN
BY DEVELOPMENT
AND STUFF LIKE THAT?
NO. WE'RE A LANDMARK NOW,
SO WE'RE THERE TO STAY.
OKAY. GOOD FOR YOU.
JASON KELLER IS OUR CHAMPION,
AND HE IS NOT ONLY
A GOOD "JEOPARDY!" PLAYER,
HE'S ALSO AN EXCELLENT
SCRABBLE PLAYER, I UNDERSTAND.
NOW WHEN I PLAY SCRABBLE,
I'M HAPPY IF I GET
A WORD LIKE "TIME,"
BUT, UH,
YOU ARE AMONG THE WHAT?
UH, I AM AMONG
THE TOP 100-RANKED PLAYERS
IN NORTH AMERICA
ACCORDING TO THE NORTH AMERICAN
SCRABBLE PLAYERS ASSOCIATION.
AND WHAT'S THE HIGHEST SCORE
YOU'VE EVER GOTTEN ON ONE WORD?
ON ONE WORD--ACTUALLY,
DURING A FACEBOOK GAME,
I PLAYED "SELTZERS"
FOR, UH, 284 POINTS.
GET OUT.
(laughs)
OH, GEE WHIZ.
200--OVER 200 POINTS
ON ONE WORD?
YEAH.
I DON'T GET THAT IN THREE GAMES.
LET'S GO BACK TO WORK HERE.
KAREN, YOU MAKE A SEN,
PLEASE.
PROJECT RUNAWAY FOR $200.
WHAT IS MARYLAND?
NO. KAREN.
WHAT IS VIRGINIA?
HE KINDA NARROWED IT DOWN
FOR YOU, DIDN'T HE?
ANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT, GO AGAIN, KAREN.
PROJECT RUNAWAY FOR $400.
WHAT IS THE SUMMER OLYMPICS?
RUNAWAY FOR $600.
WHAT IS RUSSIA?
RUNAWAY, $800.
WHAT IS THE BBC?
BRITISH BROADCASTING
COION.
WORD ORIGINS FOR $200.
WHAT IS SASSY?
WORD ORIGINS FOR $400.
WHAT IS THE BALLOT?
WORD ORIGINS FOR $600.
WHAT IS BODACIOUS?
WORD ORIGINS FOR $800.
WHAT IS A HANSOM CAB?
WORD ORIGINS FOR $1,000.
(beep)
AND THAT WOULD BE FOOLSCAP.
YOU'RE TOO YOUNG TO HAVE DEALT
WITH THOSE, UH, SHEETS OF PAPER
IN SCHOOL. KAREN, GO AGAIN.
PROJECT RUNAWAY FOR $1,000.
WHO IS ROBERT F. KENNEDY?
ROBERT F. KENNEDY WHO WAS
ASSASSINATED THERE, YES.
PAPAL PEOPLE FOR $200.
ALL RIGHT...
WHO IS BENEDICT?
PAPAL PEOPLE FOR $400.
WE DIDN'T CATCH YOU.
PAPAL PEOPLE FOR $600.
WHAT IS JOHN PAUL?
PAPAL PEOPLE FOR $800.
WHAT IS JOHN?
AND NOW THE LAST ONE...
WHO IS PAUL?
GOOD.
THAT TAKES YOU UP TO $2,800.
YOU TRAIL KAREN,
AND BOTH OF YOU TRAIL JASON.
BUT, DOUG, YOU'RE GETTING
TO GO FIRST
IN DOUBLE JEOPARDY!
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED IN PART BY...
ALL RIGHT, DOUG, IT'S TIME
FOR THE DOUBLE JEOPARDY! ROUND,
AND HERE ARE THE CATEGORIES.
YOU GET TO PICK FIRST
OM THESE...
"LIST" IN QUOTATION MARKS...
START US.
HOW ABOUT MAKING A "LIST"
FOR $400?
WHAT IS ENLIST?
UM, YULE TUBE FOR $400.
WHAT IS "SHREK THE HALLS"?
MAKING A "LIST" FOR $800.
WHAT IS NOVELIST?
MAKING A "LIST," $1,200.
WHAT IS SOMNAMBULIST?
UM, "LIST" FOR $1,600.
OOH!
AND IT'S YOURS,
AND YOU HAVE THE LEAD
WITH $7,800.
I'LL WAGER $1,600, PLEASE.
OKAY. HERE'S THE CLUE...
WHAT IS HOLISTIC?
HOLISTIC. YOU ARE CORRECT.
YOU ADD TO YOUR LEAD.
"LIST" FOR $2,000.
WHAT IS CA-LLISTO?
CALLISTO.
HAVE A WONDERFUL WEDDING
FOR $400.
WHAT IS MAID OF HONOR?
UH, WONDERFUL WEDDING, $800.
WHAT IS A RING BEARER?
WEDDING FOR $1,200.
WHO IS QUEEN VICTORIA?
HAVE A WONDERFUL WEDDING,
$1,600.
WHAT IS A GARTER?
WEDDING, $2,000.
WHAT IS
"A MIDSUMMER NIGHT'S DREAM"?
CHECKING IT TWICE FOR $400.
WHAT IS A BIGAMOUS?
CHECKING IT FOR $800.
WELL, TWO GOOD THINGS
HAVE JUST HAPP
YOU HAVE FOUND THE DAILY DOUBLE
AND YOU HAVE PREVENTED
OUR CHAMPION FROM FINDING IT.
SO WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO
WITH YOUR $5,800?
ENED.
AND YOU HAVE PREVENTED
OU(exhales deeply) LET'S GO...
$2,500.
OKAY. HERE IS THE CLUE...
WHAT IS THE SIXTH AMENDMENT?
OH, NO.
IT'S THE FIFTH AMENDMENT.
FIFTH AMENDMENT
OR DOUBLE JEOPARDY.
SO YOU DROP TO $3,300.
GO AGAIN.
PLENTY OF TIME LEFT.
YULE TUBE FOR $800.
WHAT IS "MADAGASCAR"?
UH, CHECKING IT TWICE
FOR $1,200.
WHAT IS "RECOUNT"?
CHECKING IT TWICE FOR $1,600.
WHAT'S AN F-STOP?
CHECKING IT TWICE FOR $2,000.
WHO IS MAGELLAN?
YES FOR $2,000.
UH, YULE TUBE, $1,200.
YOU'RE GONNA LOVE IT--OLIVE.
"OLIVE, THE OTHER REINDEER."
(Karen) OH.
DOUG, BACK TO YOU.
UH, YULE TUBE, $
WHAT ARE TOYS?
YULE TUBE FOR $2,000.
WHAT IS JULY?
THAT'S A GOOD MONTH,
AND IT EARNS YOU $2,000.
TOUCHED BY AN ANGEL, $400.
WHO IS JOSEPH SMITH?
UH, TOUCHED BY AN ANGEL, $800.
WHO IS JOHN THE BAPTIST?
UH, TOUCHED BY AN ANGEL. $1,200.
WHAT IS ON HIGH?
ZOOM IN FOR A CLOSE-UP FOR $400.
TO START OFF,
YOU'RE GETTING AN AERIAL VIEW
OF THIS STATE.
WHAT IS MASSACHUSETTS?
ZOOM IN, $800.
FIRST THERE WAS
ONE BIG COUNTY,
THEN NORFOLK SPLIT OFF IN 1793,
LEAVING THIS COUNTY.
(beep)
NOT NORFOLK, BUT SUFFOLK.
NORTH AND SOUTH.
DOUG, GO AGAIN.
ZOOM IN, $1,200.
THIS RIVER WINDS
THROUGH THE COUNTY
UNTIL IT REACHES BOSTON HARBOR.
WHAT IS THE CHARLES RIVER?
ZOOM IN, $1,600.
JUST SOUTH OF THE RIVER
AND WEST OF BOSTON COMMON IS
THE AREA CALLED THIS GARDEN,
FOR ALL PEOPLE TO ENJOY.
WHAT IS THE COMMON GARDEN?
NO. KAREN.
WHAT IS BOSTON COMMONS?
NO.
JASON.
INUTE TO GO.
WITH LESS THAN A MINUTE TO GO.
ZOOM IN FOR $2,000.
IN THE GARDEN IS
THIS AMERICAN--
BUT NOT MASSACHUSETTS-BORN--
HERO ON HORSEBACK,
READY FOR HIS CLOSE-UP.
WHO IS REVERE?
NO.
THAT WOULD BE OUR FIRST
PRESIDENT GEORGE WASHINGTON.
$1,600, PLEASE.
THAT WOULD BE OUR FIRST
PRESIDENT GEORGE WASHINGTON.
WHO IS SWEDENBORG?
NOW THE LAST CLUE...
WHO IS KING PHILIP?
$22,600 YOUR TOTAL.
YOU'VE MADE THIS A RUNAWAY
AS WE COME TO FINAL JEOPARDY!
AND HERE IS THE CATEGORY--
POETS.
MAKE YOUR WAGERS, PLAYERS.
AND WE'LL COME BACK IMENT.
GO TO WALGREENS.COM.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR PHOTO,
CREATE ANY NUMBER OF GIFTS
AND PICK THEM UP
THE SAME DAY.
RIGHT HERE.
AT THE CORNER
OF HAPPY AND HEALTHY.
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
R ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
AND EDDY SAID THE TOYS
NIMIGHT NOT BE READY!MASA BAYE
EDDY?
THE ELF!
♪
[ Radio Announcer ]
TODAY'S FORECAST:
IT'S SNOWING SNOWBALLS
SNOW BRICKS OUT THERE...
SEVEN MORE DAYS
AND IT'S SNOWING SNOW BRICKS!
OH, WELL, BE CAREFUL!
[ Radio Announcer ]
ONLY TWO DAYS TO GO,
AND SEVERAL OF THE ELVES
AND  TOSSED AROUND
WHEN THEY TRIED TO WRAP A PONY.
[ Female Announcer ] THE
Keepsake Countdown ORNAMENT.
BUILD ANTICIPATION EVERY DAY
TILL CHRISTMAS.
ELVES TRIED TO WRA!
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
P        BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
GO TO WALGREENS.COM.
JUST UPLOAD YOUR PHOTO,
CREATE ANY NUMBER OF GIFTS
RIGHT HERE.
AT THE CORNER
OF HAPPY AND HEALTHY.
OUR CATEGORY FOR FINAL JEOPARDY!
TODAY IS POETS,
AND THIS IS THE CLUE.
TAKE A LOOK...
30 SECONDS. GOOD LUCK, PLAYERS.
♪
KAREN, WE COME TO YOU FIRST.
YOU WERE IN THIRD PLACE,
$6,100 GOING INTO FINAL.
YOU WROTE DOWN...
NO. SORRY.
ILL COST YOU HOW MUCH?
NOTHING. YOU REMAIN AT $6,100.
OVER TO DOUG.
$7,600 GOING INTO FINAL.
HIS RESPONSE...
PABLO NERUDA IS RIGHT.
YOUR WAGER?
THAT BUMPS YOU UP A BIT
TO $12,201.
JASON WROTE DOWN HISNSE
BEFORE THE MUSIC STARTED,
SO I BET HE GOT IT RIGHT.
HE DID INDEED.
AND HIS WAGER?
A $25,000 PA RESPO
AND WE ADD THAT
TO HIS PREVIOUS TOTAL.
HE NOW HAS $69,800
FOR THREE DAYS' WORK
AND HE GETS TO PLAY AGAIN
TOMORROW RIGHT HERE.
SEE YOU THEN.
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
ANNOUNCER: TODAY ON KATIE --
KATIE: PLEASE WELCOME HUGH
JACKMAN.
[APPLAUSE]
>> THIS IS A HIGHLIGHT OF MY
TRIP.
IT IS GOING TO BE AN EIGHT-HOUR
SHOW.
ANNOUNCER: NEED WE SAY MORE?
KATIE: YOU CAN DO THAT IF YOU
NEED TO.
>>