GRIEVING, OTHERS IN RELIEF AND
JOY.
AND ABC NEWS'S DAN HARRIS SPENT
THE DAY WITH SURVIVORS.
>> DIANE, WE SPENT ALL DAY HERE
AT WHAT WAS IN MANY WAYS, THE
EMOTIONAL EPICENTER OF THIS
STORY.
THE VOLUNTEER FIREHOUSE RIGHT
DOWN THE STREET FROM THE SCHOOL
WHERE WE WATCHED MANY FAMILIES
HOLDING TEARFUL REUNIONS WITH
THEIR CHILDREN AND ALSO FAMILIES
WHO WEREN'T SO LUCKY.
ALL DAY LONG HERE AT THE
FIREHOUSE WHERE THE STUDENTS
WERE KEPT SAFE AFTER THE
SHOOTING, AN URGENT PARADE OF
PARENTS COMING TO PICK UP THEIR
CHILDREN.
THIS IS 8-YEAR-OLD ALEXIS WASIK
AND HER MOTHER.
>> YOU WERE IN THERE?
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WE HEARD LIKE AN AMBULANCE
AND A POLICE OFFICER COME AND
EVERYBODY WAS A LITTLE SCARED,
CRYING AND I FELT ACTUALLY A
LITTLE SICK.
THOUGHT I WAS GOING TO THROW UP.
>> WERE KIDS CRYING AND
SCREAMING?
>> YES.
KIDS WERE CRYING, NOT REALLY
SCREAMING, BUT THEY WERE ALL
HUDDLING TOGETHER AND FELT SO
SICK.
>> Reporter: HER MOM SAID WHEN
SHE ARRIVED AT THE FIREHOUSE,
ALEXIS WAS WITH HER FATHER.
>> HE HAD HER IN HIS ARMS AND
WERE CRYING AND SHE JUST GOES,
MOMMA, I'M OKAY, I'M HERE.
>> Reporter: ANOTHER MOM WHOSE
KIDS GO TO A NEARBY SCHOOL TOLD
US SHE WAS PUTTING OFF PICKING
THEM UP BECAUSE SHE DIDN'T WANT
TO TELL THEM ABOUT THE HORROR
HERE.
>> THIS IS THE LAST FEW HOURS OF
THEIR LIFE THAT THEY'RE GOING TO
BE A KID.
>> Reporter: WE DON'T KNOW MUCH
ABOUT THE VICTIMS YET.
THERE ARE THE REPORTS ABOUT THE
PRINCIPAL, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG,
BEING AMONG THOSE WHO WERE SHOT.
>> YOU CAN TELL SHE LOVED HER
JOB, SHE LOVED THE KIDS.
SANDY HOOK WAS A SAFE SCHOOL.
>> JUST MONDAY SHE TWEETED THIS
UPBEAT MESSAGE ABOUT
KINDERGARTNERS MAKING THEIR OWN
SHOPPING LIST AND PAYING THE
CASHIER AT A LOCAL SUPERMARKET.
ONLY THREE VICTIMS WERE BROUGHT
TO THE LOCAL HOSPITAL.
TWO OF THEM DIED.
>> A NUMBER OF US IMAGINED WHAT
IT MUST HAVE FELT LIKE ON 9/11
WHEN THERE WERE PEOPLE BRACING
FOR SCORES OF INJURED AND THEY
DIDN'T ARRIVE.
>> ALL DAY LONG THE SIGHT OF
AMBULANCES DRIVING SLOWLY,
LIGHTS NOT FLASHING.
SO FEW WOUNDED TO TRY TO SAVE.
EVEN MORE SAD, THE KNOWLEDGE
THAT SO MANY FAMILIES WHO SHOWED
UP TO PICK UP THEIR CHILDREN
COULD NOT BE RE-UNITED.
A FACT THAT IS NOT LOST ON
ALEXIS'S MOTHER.
>> YOU COUNT YOUR BLESSINGS
EVERY DAY.
>> Reporter: I'M REALLY GLAD
YOU'RE OKAY, ALEXIS.
YOU'RE PRETTY TOUGH.
ADDING TO THE SHOCK, THIS PLACE
IS SUCH AN UNLIKELY VENUE FOR
VIOLENCE, A CLASSIC, SMALL,
SLEEPY SOUTHERN NEW ENGLAND
TOWN, WHERE TONIGHT THEY'RE
FOLLOWING ANOTHER PART OF THE
ALL-TOO-FAMILIAR SCRIPT AFTER
THESE MASS SHOOTINGS, THEY'RE
COMING TOGETHER TO HOLD
CANDLELIGHT VIGILS.
DIANE?
>> ALL RIGHT, DAN, THANK YOU SO
MUCH.
>>> AND ALL DAY LONG, OF COURSE,
WE'VE BEEN TRYING TO FIND OUT
MORE ABOUT THE 20-YEAR-OLD
SUSPECT IN THIS SHOOTING AND
RIGHT NOW ABC'S CHIEF
INVESTIGATIVE CORRESPONDENT
BRIAN ROSS IS BACK WITH WHAT HE
KNOWS AT THIS HOUR.
>> Reporter: AS YOU AND DAN
REPORTED, THIS ALL TOOK PLACE IN
THE SMALL TOWN OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, A PLACE WHERE
EVERYTHING IS NEARBY.
THE SPREE ENDED AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, BUT BEGAN AT
THE LANZA FAMILY HOME.
AUTHORITIES IDENTIFIED THE
SHOOTER AS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA, SEEN HERE IN A PICTURE
TAKEN SEVEN YEARS AGO AND
PROVIDED TO ABC NEWS BY A FAMILY
FRIEND WHO TOLD US ADAM WAS
OBVIOUSLY NOT WELL.
SOMETHING WE ALSO HEARD FROM A
NEWTOWN REAL ESTATE AGENT,
BARBARA FREY, A FAMILY FRIEND.
>> HE WAS NOT CONNECTED WITH THE
OTHER KIDS.
MY SON PLAYED WITH HIM WHEN THEY
WERE YOUNG.
AND IN HER HOME, I KNOW SHE WAS
VERY PARTICULAR.
I JUST THINK SHE MAYBE HAD TOO
HIGH A STANDARD OR SOMETHING, OR
FOCUSED TOO MUCH, FOR WHATEVER
REASON.
>> SO WAS THERE CONFLICT OR
TENSION BETWEEN THE TWO OF THEM?
>> THE PARENT AND CHILD?
>> YES.
>> NOT THAT I KNOW OF, BUT THE
FACT THAT THE PARENTS WERE
DIVORCED MUST HAVE CONTRIBUTED.
>> THE MOTHER WAS THE FIRST TO
DIE ACCORDING TO POLICE.
ADAM'S FATHER AND BROTHER ARE
BEING QUESTIONED BY AUTHORITIES
IN NEW JERSEY, WHERE THEY LIVE.
DIANE?
>> BRIAN ROSS REPORTING AND ONCE
AGAIN, WE WANT TO GIVE YOU THE
LATEST NOW ON THOSE WHO WERE
INJURED.
THE VICTIMS WHO ARE RECOVERING
TONIGHT IN THE HOSPITAL.
FOR THAT WE GO TO AMY ROBACH WHO
HAS BEEN FOLLOWING THEIR
STORIES.
AMY?
>> GOOD EVENING TO YOU.
THIS HAS BEEN THE MOST TRAUMATIC
EVENT ANYONE AT THIS HOSPITAL
HAS EVER EXPERIENCED, THAT'S
WHAT I HEARD FROM A PHYSICIAN
HERE WHO ALSO IS THE PRESIDENT
AND CEO OF DANBURY HOSPITAL.
HE TALKED ABOUT THE MOMENT HE
RECEIVED THE PHONE CALL
EXPECTING TWO DOZEN VICTIMS
WHO WILL COME HERE REQUIRING
IMMEDIATE MEDICAL CARE.
HE AMASSED 80 DOCTORS AND
NURSES, THE FINEST SURGEONS
AVAILABLE TO BE PREPARED FOR
ANYTHING AND EVERYTHING, AND
THEY ONLY RECEIVED THREE INJURED
VICTIMS AT THIS POINT.
THEY SAID ABOUT TEN MINUTES
LATER, THAT'S WHEN THEY REALIZED
THAT NO MORE WERE COMING.
IT'S IMPORTANT TO NOTE, HE SAID,
THIS OBVIOUSLY AFFECTED EVERYONE
WHO WAS IN THIS HOSPITAL AT THE
TIME.
ALL THE POLICE OFFICERS, THE
FIREFIGHTERS, THE CHILDREN
AND TEACHERS INSIDE THE SCHOOL,
THE PARENTS, THERE IS NO ONE IN
THIS COMMUNITY WHO WASN'T
AFFECTED.
THIS MEANS THIS IS GOING TO BE A
COMMUNITY THAT WILL REQUIRE
MEDICAL, EMOTIONAL CARE FOR
YEARS TO COME.
THEY HAVE SET UP SERVICES THAT
PEOPLE CAN ACCESS 24 HOURS A
DAY, SEVEN DAYS A WEEK.
THEY ACTUALLY HAVE MOBILE LABS
SPREAD OUT THROUGHOUT THE
COMMUNITY TO HELP ANYONE WHO
FEELS A MOMENT OF CRISIS BECAUSE
THIS IS SOMETHING THEY WILL DEAL
WITH, THEY'RE BRINGING IT HOME
TO THEIR FAMILY.
HE TOLD ME IT WAS THE SINGLE
MOST TRAUMATIC EVENT HE'S EVER
EXPERIENCED OR CONSIDERED IN HIS
PROFESSIONAL OR PERSONAL LIFE.
THOSE ARE FAIRLY WEIGHTY WORDS
FROM AN EMERGENCY ROOM DOCTOR
WHO YOU WOULD THINK HAD PRETTY
MUCH SEEN IT ALL.
HE AND I DON'T THINK ANYONE IN
THE COMMUNITY HAD EVER PREPARED
TO SEE ANYTHING LIKE WHAT THEY
SAW TODAY.
>> THANK YOU, AMY.
NOW I WANT TO BRING BACK "20/20"
ANCHOR CHRIS CUOMO, BECAUSE YOU
TALKED TO PARENTS WHO HAD TO
WAIT TO SEE IF THEIR CHILDREN
SURVIVED.
>> IMAGINE THE FIRST WORD THEY
GOT WAS THE SCHOOL WAS ON
LOCKDOWN.
THEY THOUGHT THEIR KIDS WERE
MAKING GINGERBREAD HOUSES TODAY
AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
THAT WAS THE PLAN.
THEY RUSHED THERE, THERE'S
CHAOS, TO BE IMAGINED IN THESE
SITUATIONS, BUT TO NOT KNOW FOR
SO LONG.
NOT BECAUSE OF DISARRAY, JUST
BECAUSE OF THE SITUATION.
INSIDE ARE THE CHILDREN LIVING
THROUGH THIS EVENT.
THOSE WHO SURVIVED, THEIR
PARENTS HOPE SOMEDAY THEY'LL BE
ABLE TO FORGET.
WE SPOKE TO ONE LITTLE GIRL AND
HER MOTHER WHO ARE VERY HAPPY TO
HAVE EACH OTHER TONIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU REMEMBER?
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> WE GOT TO SCHOOL.
DID EVERYTHING WE NEEDED TO.
WE HEARD ALL THIS RACKET IN OUR
CLASSROOM.
WE WERE LIKE ALL SCARED.
THEN WE HEARD THEM SAY, GO INTO
YOUR CUBBY.
>> EVERYBODY WENT TO THEIR
CUBBY?
>> YES.
>> DID YOU HEAR ANY MORE BAD
NOISES?
>> YES.
>> Reporter: WHILE THAT WAS
GOING ON, YOUR TEACHER WAS
READING YOU BOOKS AND KEEPING
YOU CALM?
>> YES.
>> YOU HAVE A GOOD TEACHER,
DON'T YOU?
>> YES.
>> YOU LOVE YOUR TEACHER.
DID SHE SEEM NERVOUS?
>> NO.
>> SHE JUST KEPT HER CALM AND
TOLD YOU A STORY.
>> YES.
>> DO YOU REMEMBER WHICH ONE?
>> SHE READ US THE NUTCRACKER
AND ANOTHER BOOK THAT WAS ABOUT
CHRISTMAS.
>> Reporter: I LOVE THE
NUTCRACKER.
DO YOU LOVE IT?
>> YES.
>> Reporter: I'M AFRAID OF THE
MOUSE KING.
A LITTLE SCARY, LET'S
BE HONEST, IT'S NOT JUST ME.
SO YOU'RE IN THERE, HOW DO YOU
LEAVE THE CLASSROOM?
>> WE GOT IN A LINE AND WE HAD
TO CLOSE OUR EYES.
>> Reporter: YOU HAD TO CLOSE
YOUR EYES?
>> YES.
>> WHEN YOU OPENED THEM, WHERE
WERE YOU?
>> WE WERE WALKING DOWN TO THE
FIRE STATION.
>> Reporter: WHAT HAPPENED THERE
TODAY HAPPENED AND IT'S OVER,
OKAY?
AND YOU HAVE TO BE HAPPY THAT
YOU'RE OKAY.
ARE YOU OKAY?
I DIDN'T EVEN CHECK YOU OUT, ARE
YOU ALL RIGHT?
>> YES.
>> WHAT HAPPENED HERE IN THE
FRONT?
DID YOU HAVE TEETH THERE THIS
MORNING WHEN YOU WENT THERE?
>> NO.
>> Reporter: GOOD.
YOU'RE AWARE YOU'RE MISSING
THOSE TEETH?
>> YES.
>> Reporter: YOU GOT A CHRISTMAS
LIST MADE, SENT TO SANTA?
>> YEAH.
>> HOW LONG IS THE LIST?
>> TWO PIECES OF PAPER.
>> Reporter: IT WAS A LONG LIST.
SHE'S IN BETTER SHAPE WITH SANTA
AFTER WHAT SHE LIVED THROUGH
TODAY.
BUT THE BIGGEST GIFT WITH THESE
FAMILIES, THESE TEACHERS, FIRST
RESPONDERS TODAY, THE CALM IN
THE FACE OF A SITUATION LIKE
THIS, LEADING THESE KIDS OUT,
MAKING SURE THEY HAD THEIR EYES
CLOSED BUT THOSE TEACHERSED THAT
THEIR EYES WIDE OPEN AND THEY
GOT THE KIDS TO SAFETY AS MANY
AS THEY COULD.
>> THEY KNEW THAT WAS THE MAIN
THING THEY HAD TO DO AND THEY
CALLED ON ALL THEIR COURAGE AND
THEIR TRAINING.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WE DO LOVE HER SMILE.
>>> NOW WE WANT TO TURN BACK TO
WASHINGTON WHERE PRESIDENT OBAMA
DID SPEAK TODAY ABOUT THE
TRAGEDY IN HIS EMOTIONAL PRESS
CONFERENCE, TALKING AS COMMANDER
IN CHIEF AND AS FATHER OF TWO
YOUNG DAUGHTERS.
HERE ABC'S CHIEF WHITE HOUSE
CORRESPONDENT JAKE TAPPER NOW.
>> Reporter: AS FLAGS WERE
LOWERED TO HALF-STAFF AT THE
WHITE HOUSE THIS AFTERNOON.
>> OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
>> Reporter: PRESIDENT OBAMA
REACTED NOT AS A PRESIDENT, BUT
AS A PARENT.
>> I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
>> Reporter: IT WAS AN EMOTIONAL
SIDE OF THE PRESIDENT RARELY
SEEN IN PUBLIC.
HE REPEATEDLY WIPED AWAY TEARS
AND PAUSED TO COMPOSE HIMSELF.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN,
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM -- BIRTHDAYS,
GRADUATIONS, WEDDINGS, KIDS OF
THEIR OWN.
>> Reporter: IT WAS ALMOST TWO
YEARS AGO THE PRESIDENT WAS
CALLED TO BE CONSOLER IN CHIEF
AFTER A DIFFERENT ACT OF GUN
VIOLENCE IN TUCSON WHERE
CONGRESSWOMAN GABBY GIFFORDS WAS
SHOT AND SIX OTHERS WERE KILLED.
>> WE MOURN WITH YOU FOR THE
FALLEN.
WE JOIN YOU IN YOUR GRIEF.
>> Reporter: TODAY THE PRESIDENT
RECITED A GRIM LIST OF OTHER
PLACES NOW KNOWN FOR HORRIFIC
GUN VIOLENCE ON HIS WATCH.
A SHOPPING MALL IN OREGON, A
SIKH TEMPLE IN WISCONSIN, A
MOVIE THEATER IN COLORADO.
TODAY THE PRESIDENT SUGGESTED HE
MIGHT TAKE SOME ACTION.
>> WE'RE GOING TO HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER TO TAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE TRAGEDIES
LIKE THIS REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITICS.
>> THE ONLY ACTION WE KNOW FOR
SURE HE WOULD TAKE IS THIS ONE.
>> THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY PARENT
IN AMERICA WILL DO, WHICH IS HUG
OUR CHILDREN A LITTLE TIGHTER,
AND WE'LL TELL THEM THAT WE LOVE
THEM.
AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER HOW
DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE ANOTHER.
>> Reporter: EARLIER TONIGHT,
THE PRESIDENT WAS SCHEDULED TO
SPEND TIME WITH THE FIRST LADY
AND FIRST DAUGHTERS, WE'RE
PRESUMING THAT HUG TOOK PLACE.
HOUSE SPEAKER JOHN BOEHNER
ANNOUNCED THAT HE WOULD FOREGO
THE TRADITIONAL WEEKLY
REPUBLICAN ADDRESS SO THE
PRESIDENT COULD SPEAK FOR THE
ENTIRE NATION AT THIS TIME OF
MOURNING.
>> ALL RIGHT, JAKE, REPORTING IN
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
>>> STILL AHEAD HERE ON "WORLD
NEWS," MORE FROM THE TRAGEDY OF
THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
WE ASKED THE EXPERTS, THE FBI
PROFILERS, ABOUT THE MEN BEHIND
THESE GUN ASSAULTS.
AND WE'LL TELL YOU WHAT THEY
TOLD US TODAY.
>>> TODAY'S TRAGEDY COMES ON THE
HEELS OF THAT OTHER SEARING MASS
SHOOTING 72 HOURS AGO IN THE
MALL FILLED WITH HOLIDAY
SHOPPERS OUTSIDE PORTLAND.
THIS SINGULAR TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, JOINING THE RANKS OF
THE OTHER DARK DAYS --
COLUMBINE, TUCSON, AURORA.
ABC'S SENIOR JUSTICE
CORRESPONDENT
PIERRE THOMAS NOW TELLS US WHAT
THE EXPERTS SAY THEY SEE WHEN
THEY LOOK AT THE MEN BEHIND
THESE MASSACRES.
>> Reporter: THE VIRGINIA TECH
MASSACRE, 32 DEAD.
A SHOOTING SPREE IN TUCSON,
ARIZONA -- SIX DEAD.
12 KILLED AT A COLORADO MOVIE
THEATER.
MASS MURDER CONDUCTED BY LONE
GUNMEN.
BUT WHO ARE THESE MEN?
AND WHAT MOTIVATES THEM?
>> WE'RE TALKING ABOUT ATTACKS
THAT ARE CARRIED OUT LARGELY BY
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT NECESSARILY
PSYCHOPATHIC, NOT SOCIOPATHIC,
BUT FOLKS WHO ARE RELATIVELY
NORMAL, BUT AT A POINT OF
ABSOLUTE DESPERATION.
>> Reporter: ACCORDING TO ONE
ESTIMATE, THIS YEAR ALONE,
THERE HAVE BEEN 15 MASS
SHOOTINGS WITH AT LEAST
84 PEOPLE KILLED BEFORE TODAY.
IN THE 61 MASS MURDERS CARRIED
OUT SINCE 1982, ALL BUT ONE OF
THE 43 SHOOTERS WERE MALE.
MOST WERE WHITE AND THE AVERAGE
AGE OF THE PRIMARY SHOOTER WAS
35.
NEARLY HALF OF THE MASS MURDERS
HAVE INVOLVED SCHOOL OR
WORKPLACE SHOOTINGS.
BUT IN RECENT YEARS, SHOPPING
MALLS, RESTAURANTS, AND HOUSES
OF WORSHIP HAVE ALSO COME UNDER
FIRE.
>> MASS SHOOTERS TEND TO LOOK
FOR SOFT TARGETS BECAUSE THEY'RE
EASY.
THEY WANT TO BE ABLE TO WALK
INTO A SITUATION WHERE PEOPLE
ARE NOT ARMED, THEY HAVE NO IDEA
WHAT'S ABOUT TO HAPPEN TO THEM.
YOU CAN GET THE JUMP ON THEM.
>> Reporter: IN MANY CASES, THE
SHOOTER TARGETS SPECIFIC PEOPLE
FOR SPECIFIC REASONS.
>> SOMETIMES THEY WANT FAME AND
NOTORIETY.
SOMETIMES THEY SEE IT AS A WAY
TO SOLVE A PROBLEM OR GET BACK
AT SOMEONE, SOME FORM OF
REVENGE.
>> Reporter: AND OFTEN, AS WE
HAVE SEEN AT VIRGINIA TECH,
TUCSON, AND COLORADO -- THE
SHOOTERS HAVE SERIOUS MENTAL
HEALTH ISSUES.
>> USUALLY THE ATTACKERS WILL
TELL OTHER PEOPLE BEFOREHAND
WHAT THEY'RE THINKING ABOUT AND
PLANNING TO DO.
>> Reporter: THEY OFTEN EXHIBIT
WARNING SIGNS.
SOME OF THE INDICATORS ARE
BLATANT.
OTHER SIGNS ARE MORE SUBTLE AND
ONLY BECOME CLEAR IN HINDSIGHT.
DIANE, THERE ARE AN ESTIMATED
200 MILLION-PLUS GUNS ALREADY IN
CIRCULATION IN THE U.S.
THE FACT IS DISTURBED PEOPLE ARE
GOING TO GET THEM.
ONE SOURCE PREDICTED TONIGHT
WE'RE GOING TO SEE THIS SAD
SITUATION UNFOLD AGAIN.
IT MAY BE DAYS, IT MAY BE WEEKS
OR MONTHS, BUT HE SAID, IT WILL
HAPPEN AGAIN.
>> THANK YOU, SO MUCH PIERRE
THOMAS.
>>> WHEN WE COME BACK, THIS
REMARKABLE SCHOOL STRUCK BY
TRAGEDY, CONSIDERED ONE OF THE
TOP IN THE NATION.
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'LL TELL
YOU WHY SO MANY PEOPLE SAY, THIS
SCHOOL IS SPECIAL.
NEXT.
♪
>>> WE HAVE BEEN TELLING YOU ALL
DAY ABOUT THE TRAGEDY AT THE
SCHOOL IN CONNECTICUT, SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY, CONSIDERED BY
SO MANY PEOPLE AN EXTRAORDINARY
SCHOOL.
PARENTS HOPING THEIR CHILDREN
CAN ATTEND.
ABC'S SENIOR NATIONAL
CORRESPONDENT JIM AVILA TELLS
THE REST OF US WHAT MAKES THOSE
CLASSROOMS SO SPECIAL.
>> SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY, WITH
SMALL CLASS SIZES AND REPUTATION
AS ONE OF CONNECTICUT'S TOP
SCHOOLS, SCORED A PERFECT 10 BY
GREATSCHOOLS.ORG IS THE JEWEL OF
THIS PICTURESQUE NEW ENGLAND
TOWN, A MAGNET FOR YOUNG
FAMILIES WHO ENDURE LONG DRIVES
TO HARTFORD OR NEW HAVEN SO
THEIR KIDS COULD BE EDUCATED
HERE.
>> HUSBANDS WILL SACRIFICE THE
COMMUTE TO COME TO NEWTOWN IF
IT'S A LITTLE FARTHER THAN
ANYWHERE ELSE.
>> Reporter: 21-YEAR-OLD CAITLIN
TEFFT WENT TO SANDY HOOK AS A
SMALL GIRL.
>> IT'S A SMALL SCHOOL, BUT I
JUST, I DON'T KNOW, IT WAS JUST
REALLY IMPORTANT TO ME AND
REALLY IMPORTANT IN MY
DEVELOPMENT.
>> Reporter: AND WHILE THE TOWN
IS IDYLLIC AND THE SCHOOL A WARM
EMBRACE, TO THE KINDERGARTNERS
THROUGH FOURTH GRADERS WHO
ATTEND HERE, SHE REMEMBERS HOW
PREPARED THEY WERE FOR A TRAGEDY
LIKE TODAY, DRILLING IN THE VERY
CLASSROOMS SO TERRORIZED THIS
MORNING.
>> THE TEACHER WOULD LOCK THE
DOOR, SHUT OFF THE LIGHTS AND
YOU HAD TO BE QUIET.
WHICH IS HARD FOR KIDS,
ESPECIALLY WHEN THEY THINK IT'S
NOT REAL.
BUT I THINK SOME KNEW IT WAS
REALLY SERIOUS THIS TIME.
>> Reporter: THE PAIN IN THIS
TOWN MAGNIFIED BY THE FACT THAT
ITS PRIDE AND JOY,
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY NOW
ENDURES A NEW LEGACY SO
DIFFERENT FROM THE OLD.
TO HAVE THIS HAPPEN IN YOUR
COMMUNITY, IT'S PAINFUL?
>> IT'S EXTREMELY PAINFUL.
WE'RE ALL IN SHOCK.
PEOPLE ARE COMING TO THE CHURCH
TO WALK IN AND PRAY AND THEY
HAVE BLANK FACES.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY IS MORE THAN JUST A
PLACE PARENTS SENT THEIR
CHILDREN FOR A GOOD EDUCATION.
IT IS THE CENTER OF THE
COMMUNITY, A PRIDE AND JOY AND
SOMETHING THAT NOW HAS BEEN
DAMAGED FOREVER.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, JIM.
WHEN WE COME BACK, CHRIS CUOMO
AND I WILL HAVE CLOSING
THOUGHTS.
JIM.
WHEN WE COME, CHRIS CUOMO AND I
WILL HAVE CLOSING THOUGHTS.
>>> YOU ARE LOOKING AT A LIVE
SHOT, ONE OF THE CHURCHES
REMAINING OPEN ALL NIGHT TONIGHT
FOR ANYONE TO COME AND PRAY.
AND JOINING ME HERE NOW IS
"20/20" ANCHOR CHRIS CUOMO, A
CLOSING THOUGHT ON WHAT YOU'VE
SEEN TODAY.
>> THEY'RE GOING TO NEED EACH
OTHER.
PRAYER IS JUST THE BEGINNING FOR
THEM.
THIS WASN'T SUPPOSED TO HAPPEN
IN A PLACE LIKE THIS.
YET THE STRENGTH OF THIS
COMMUNITY IS HELPING THEM GET
THROUGH IT, THE TEACHERS, WHAT
THEY DID, THE FAMILIES COMING
TOGETHER TODAY, WHAT MAKES THIS
COMMUNITY UNIQUE IS WHAT WILL
HELP THEM GET THROUGH IT.
>> WE'LL BE HEARING SO MANY
STORIES OF THAT KIND OF COURAGE,
AS WE KNOW.
I NOTICED TODAY THAT MAYA
ANGELOU, THE POET, SENT OUT WORD
TO EVERYONE.
"EACH CHILD WHO WAS SLAUGHTERED
BELONGS TO EACH OF US, OUR
COUNTRY IS GRIEVING TONIGHT."
>>> WE THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
CHRIS AND I WILL BE BACK FOR A
SPECIAL EDITION OF "20/20" AT
10:00 P.M. EASTERN TIME.
UNTIL THEN, WE SAY GOODNIGHT AND
LEAVE YOU WITH THESE IMAGES OF
THIS DAY.
♪
>>> AUTHORITIES NOW BELIEVE
THE GUNMAN'S FIRST TARGET WAS
HIS MOTHER.
THE PEOPLE OF THE SMALL TOWN
OF CONNECTICUT PACKED A LOCAL
CHURCH AFTER ONE OF THE MOST
SENSELESS TRAGEDY THAT'S EVER
OCCURRED.
>> TONIGHT THERE IS A VOID IN
MORE THAN TWO DOZEN HOMES
AFTER THE WORST ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL SHOOTING IN U.S.
HISTORY.
THANKS FOR JOINING US.
I'M AMA DAETZ.
>> I'M DAN ASHLEY.
AUTHORITIES BELIEVE THE TARGET
WAS HIS MOTHER, A KIND GARDEN
TEACHER SHOT AND KILLED IN HER
HOME IN CONNECTICUT, ALSO THE
REGISTERED OWNER OF THREE
D4)QphONS HE USED AT THE SCHOOL.
>> THE GUNMAN HAS BEEN
IDENTIFIED AS 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA, PICTURED HERE AS A
TEENAGER.
HE HAS NO CRIMINAL HISTORY,
ONCE A STUDENT AT THE SCHOOL
AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENT THE TRI
IN CUT.
>> THIS IS VIDEO OF[sUws HIS OLR
BROTHER, RYAN.
HE WAS DETAINED FOR
QUESTIONING IN NEW JERSEY
TODAY BUT OFFICIALS SAY HE HAD
NOT HAD CONTACT WITH HIS
BROTHER SEVERAL SKBREERS WAS
NOT INVOLVED IN THIS SHOOTING.
INVESTIGATORS SAY HE'S
COOPERATING FULLY.
>> IN THE COUNTING THE GUNMEN,
26 VICTIMS LOST THEIR LIVES
TODAY, 18 CHILDREN DIED AT THE
SCENE, TWO OTHERS LATER IN THE
HOSPITAL.
THE PRINCIPAL AND PSYCHOLOGIST
ARE AMONG THE SIX ADULT WHO'S
ARE KILLED BEFORE LANZA SHOT
AND KILLED HIMSELF.
>> IN WASHINGTON FLAG AT THE
U.S. CAPITOL LOWER TO HALF
STAFF TODAY, WAS THE WHEN THE
PRESIDENT WENT ON NATIONAL
TELEVISION TO OFFER
CONDOLENCES.
>> I KNOW THERE IS NOT A
PARENT WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME GRIEF THAT I DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
AGES OF FIVE AND 10 YEARS OLD.
>> THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
KIDS ARE GONE.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS, MEN AND WOMEN
DEVOTING THEIR LIVES TO
HELPING OUR CHILDREN FULFILL
THEIR DREAMS.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY.
>> THERE ARE PLENTY OF PEOPLE
WHO SHARE PRESIDENT'S
EMOTIONS.
THIS VIGIL ORGANIZED OUTSIDE
OF THE WHITE HOUSE CALLING FOR
STRICTER GUN CONTROL LAWS AND
AN END TO GUN VIOLENCE.
>> ABC 7 NEWS CHECKED SCHOOL
DISTRICTS AND POLICE
DEPARTMENT AS CROSS THE BAY
AREA TODAY TO FIND OUT HOW
MANY ARE STEPPING UP SECURITY.
WE FOUND THAT POLICE IN
OAKLAND WHO ARE SIGNED TO HALF
A DOZEN SCHOOLS WERE PREPARED
TO RESPOND TO ANY SCHOOL IN
THE DISTRICT ON REQUEST.
AND OFFICERS PAID VISITS TO
EVERY SCHOOL IN BURLINGAME
JUST TO MAKE SURE EVERYTHING
WAS OKAY TODAY.
ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER VIC LEE
AND LAURA ANTHONY ARE COVERING
LOCAL SCHOOLS FOR US TONIGHT
WHAT. CAN YOU TELL US ABOUT
SCHOOL SECURITY?
>> WELL, DAN, SINCE YOU
MENTIONED POLICE, I CAN TELL
YOU THEY'VE BEEN IN THE
PROCESS OF DISTRIBUTING POLICE
RADIOS TO SCHOOLS.
SO THAT TEACHERS CAN CALL THEM
DIRECTLY INSTEAD OF USING 911.
I CAN ALSO TELL YOU THAT ALL
OF THE SCHOOL ZREKTS BY WE
CONTACTED TODAY SAY THEY DO
HAVE SECURITY MEASURES IN
PLACE AND THAT THEY DRILL
REGULARLY, ALL OF THIS IS
AFTER COLUMBINE.S5[4x
SINCE THE COLUMBINE MASSACRE,
SCHOOLS HAVE BEEN HOLDING
DRILL WAS POLICE, SIMULATING
SHOOTINGS.
ALL WITH A GOAL OF PREPARING
TEACHERS, STAFF AND STUDENTS
FOR THE UNTHINKABLE.
IT'S TAUGHT SCHOOLS TO TOUGHEN
THEIR SECURITY.
SAN FRANCISCO SCHOOL CHIEF
SAYS EVERY CAMPUS NOW HZ A
SAFETY PLAN AND A CRISIS MAN
YULE.
>> IT HAS SCENARIOS FROM YOU
KNOW, INTRUDERS TO GAS LEAKS
TO ELECTRICAL LEAKS TO
EVACUATIONS AND SCHOOLS
PRACTICE THE SAFETY PLANS
REGULARLY.
>> HE AND OTHER SCHOOL
OFFICIALS WE SPOKE WITH WON'T
SHARE ALL OF THE SECURITY
PROTOCOL WITH US BUZZ THEY
DON'T WANT POTENTIAL INTRUDERS
TO KNOW ABOUT THEM.
BUT MOST SCHOOLS HAVE ONE
COMMON POLICY.
>> WE HAVE A SINGLE POINT OF
ENTRANCE TO SCHOOLS WE
ENCOURAGE SCHOOLS TO FOLLOW
THAT PROTOCOL SO VISITORS ARE
CHECKING IN IN ONE PLACE IN
THE SCHOOL.
>> THIS DISTRICT HELD FOUR
YEARS AGO.
IT INVOLVED POLICE, FIRE,
EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES THE
PUBLIC SCHOOLS AND PUBLIC
WORKS.
NOW, THEY HOLD TWO DRILLS PER
YEAR.
THE PRINCIPAL SAYS THEY'RE
MORE AWARE OF SECURITY HOLD
AUTOS WE'RE RECOGNIZING WE
HAVE ACCESS NOINTS OUR
SCHOOLS.
BUT WE HAVE TRIED TO ICE YOT
YOEL YAIT THOSE SO WE'RE AWARE
OF WHERE PEOPLE CAN GAIN
ACCESS TO CAMPUS.
>> IN COLUMBINE, OFFICERS
WAITED FOR S.W.A.T. TEAMS TO
ASSEMBLE BEFORE GOING IN.
THAT HAPPENED, THE SHOOTER
KEPT FIRING, KILLING MORE
STUDENTS, NOW, POLICE CHANGED
TACTIC AUTOS IF THERE IS A
VIOLENT INCIDENT ONGOING,
ACTIVE SHOOTER WE TAKE
IMMEDIATE ACTION.
WE KNOW THAT LIVES ARE AT
STAKE F THERE IS AN IMMEDIACY,
OUR OFFICERS ARE TOLD TO
GATHER AND ENGAGE.
>> BUT IN TERMS OF WHAT
SCHOOLS CAN DO TO PREVENT
WE CONTACTED ECHOED WHAT THE
SUPERINTENDENT SAID.
>> I WILL TELL YOU THE SINGLE
GREATEST SECURITY SYSTEM YOU
CAN HAVE IN PLACE IS THE WELL
INFORMED, ENABLED STUDENT BODY
THAT IS HAS GOING TO NOTICE
SOMETHING TO TELL AN ADULT.
>> WELL, AS THE SUPERINTENDENT
SAID, IF SOMEONE IS REALLY
INTENSE, REALLY MOTIVATED TO
CAUSE HARM, CHANCES ARE YEEL
FIND A WAY TO DO IT A WARENESS
IS THE FRONT LINE.
POLICE WILL TELL YOU THAT
THAT.
IS WHAT STUDENTS ARE TOLD
DURING THESE DRILLS.
>> A BETTER WAS SENT TO
PARENTS IN THE OAKLAND SCHOOL
DISTRICT TODAY WEX FOUND ONE
DISTRICT PLNING AHEAD JUST IN
CASE.
ABC 7 NEWS LAURA ANTHONY IS
WLIF THAT PART OF THE STORY.
LAURA?
>> YES.
NEAR UNION CITY, THE SCHOOL
DISTRICT HAS BEEN PLANNING
IT'S FIRST ACTIVEL(PYKçó r# SHOR
DRILL HERE SOMETIME.
BUT NOW, IN LIGHT OF EVENTS
THEY'LL HAVE TO COME UP WITH
WAYS TO CONDUCT SUCH A DRILL,
EXPLINING TO IT KIDS IN A WAY
THAT DOESN'T TRAUMATIZE
STUDENTS.
>> I FOUND OUT ON SOCIAL
NETWORK AUTOS MANY STUDENTS IN
THE BAY AREA LEARNED ABOUT THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING ON
FACEBOOK.
>> IT IS JUST WRONG.
LIKE... THEY'RE NOT ADULTS
YET.
THEY'RE KILLING LITTLE KIDS.
>> LEO WAS WAITING TO PICK UP
HIS GRANDDAUGHTER.
>> DO YOU THINK KIDS SHOULD
HAVE TO WORY ABOUT GOING TO
SCHOOL?
>> NATURALLY.
EVERYBODY HAS TO WORRY.
IT'S TERRIBLE.
>> NEW HAVEN DISTRICT
PSYCHOLOGIST SPENT MOST OF HER
DAY TALKING WITH TEACHERS AND
STAFF ABOUT HOW TO SPOT SIGNS
OF DISSTAY WITH US STRES IN
KIDS, HOW TO RESPOND WHEN THEY
COME BACK NEXT WEEK, INFORMED.
>> LET THEM KNOW EVERY ONCE IN
A WHILE THIS DOES HAPPEN.
IT RARELY HAPPENS AND THAT
THERE ARE ADULTS THERE THAT
THEY CAN GO TO WHEN THEY'RE
FEELING AFRAYED.
>> IN OAKLAND, THE DISTRICT
SENT HOME A LETTER TO PARENTS
ABOUT HOW TO REASSURE KIDS
THAT SCHOOL IS STILL A SAFE
PLACE.
>> PART OF THAT IS GIVING THEM
THE INFORMATION WITHOUT DRAMA
TIESING.
AND AT THE SAME TIME, AS YOU
PRESENT THE INFORMATION
IMPRESS UPON THEM THEY THEY
HAVE MANY PEOPLE LOOKING OUT
FOR THEM.
>> IN UNION CITY, THE DISTRICT
HAD A FIRST ACTIVE SHOOTER
DRILL SET FOR NEXT MARCH.
NOW, IT'S TIMELY.
DIRECT OFFICIALS ARE ALSO
AWARE THE IMAGE NAIRY SCENARIO
COULD BE TRAUMATIZING TO
STUDENTS GIVEN WHAT HAPPENED
IN CONNECTICUT.
>> HOW DO YOU HAVE AN ACTIVE
SHOOTER DRILL AND NOT ALARM
STUDENTS?
>> EXACTLY.
RIGHT.
AND WITH YOUNGER CHILDREN,
IT'S A -- IT'S A FIRE DRILL
LIKE EARTHQUAKE DRILL LIKE
MANEUVER.
WHERE YOU REASSURING THE
CHILDREN Z YOU'RE MOVING
CHILDREN AROUND.
AND ADULTS NEED TO KNOW WHAT
IS GOING ON.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
CHILDREN, LITTLE ONES DON'T
NEED TO KNOW WHAT IS GOING ON.
>> AND AGAIN, THAT IS COMING
UP NEAR UNION CITY N A FEW
MONTHS IN THE MEANTIME,
OAKLAND SENT OUT A LETTER,
OTHER DISTRICTS THROUGHOUT THE
BAY AREA SENT EITHER LETTERS
HOME WITH STUDENTS TODAY, OR
SENT E MAILS HOME TO PARENTS
ABOUT HOW TO TALK TO THEIR
KIDS AND HEAR IN -- HERE IN
UNION CITY ON MONDAY, THERE
WILL BE MORE COUNSELORS
AVAILABLE TO KIDS BECAUSE
ADMINISTRATOR KNOWS THAT IF
THEY DIDN'T KNOW ABOUT IT
TODAY, MANY MORE STUDENTS WILL
KNOW ABOUT EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED ON MONDAY.
IN UNIONIN CITY, ABC 7 NEWS.
>> LET'S EXPLORE THIS QUESTION
OF TALKING TO KIDS A LITTLE
MORE.
THIS MASS SHOOTING IS
EMOTIONAL FOR PARENTS.
AND YOU'RE PROBABLY WONDERING
HOW DO YOU TALK TO YOUR
CHILDREN?
THE DEAN OF THE SCHOOL OFóY[!
EDUCATION AND COUNSELING
PSYCHOLOGY TELLS US THAT YOU
FIRST NEED TO CONFRONT YOUR
OWN FEELINGS WHETHER THOSE
INCLUDE FEAR, ANGER OR
ANXIETY.
THEN, SPEAK TO YOUR CHILD
CALMLY AND HERE IS THE KEY.
LISTEN.
THE TAME TO DO THAT IS NOW
BEFORE THEY SEE IT SOMEWHERE
ELSE.
>> I WILL TALK TODAY, I DON'T
THINK IT'S WORTH WAITING UNTIL
THE END OF THE WEEKEND OR A
RIGHT MOMENT.
THE MOMENT IS NOW.
THE KIDS ARE EXPERIENCING
THCHT THEY HAVE TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT DOES THIS MEAN?
WHEN A SCHOOL HAS THIS KIND OF
TRAGEDY?
>> GOOD ADVICE AND HE SAYS YOU
SHOULD REASSURE KIDS THAT THEY
ARE SAFE IN SCHOOL BEFORE THEY
GO BACK TO CLASS ON MONDAY
BECAUSE THEY WILL BE VERY
WORRIED ABOUT THEIR SAFETY.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
DEVELOPMENTS CONTINUE TO
UNFOLD, YOU CAN RECEIVE URGENT
UPDATES DOWN LOADING FREE ABC
7 NEWS SNART PHONE APP.
>> WE'RE UPDATING THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY AS WELL.
FOLLOW US ON ABC 7 NEWS BAY
AREA.
>> THAT IS RIGHT.
AND STILL TO COME, YOU CAN
EXPRESS YOUR CONDWRONLSS.
WE WANT TO LET YOU KNOW ABOUT
THAT TO THOSE TOUCHED BY THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
WE INVITE TO YOU SHARE YOUR
THOUGHTS.
>> YOU CAN ALSO POST THIS
BADGE TO+l9Ny YOUR FACE BOOK WA,
SHOWING SUPPORT FOR EVERYONE
STRUGGLING TONIGHT WITH
UNBELIEVABLE SORRY.
-- SORROW.
>> 2020 WILL BE DEVOTED TO THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY TONIGHT AT
10:00 HERE ON ABC 7.
>> AND WE'LL BRING YOU AN
EARLY EDITION OF GOOD MORNING
AMERICA WEEKEND TOMORROW AT
4:00 A.M.
OUR COVERAGE CONTINUES IN JUST
A MOMENT WITH MORE NEWS AND A
LOOK AT
>>> WE HAVE BREAKING NEWS NOW
IN THE SOUTH BAY.
SKY 7 HD IS LIVE ABOVE THE
GREAT MALL IN MILPITAS.
PART OF THE MALL HAS BEEN SHUT
DOWN BECAUSE OF WHAT A KHOL'S
EMPLOYEE SAW IN THE MEN'S
ROOM.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT IT RIGHT
THERE.
>> RIGHT.
NOW, SEVERAL STORES AND
RESTAURANTS ARE CLOSED HERE AT
THE GREAT MALL.
MILPITAS POLICE HAVE CORDONED
OFF KHOLS AND STORES AND
RESTAURANTS NEXT TO THE
DEPARTMENT STORE.
NOW, TAKE A LOOK FROM SKY 7.
THIS STARTED THIS AFTERNOON.
MILPITAS POLICE WERE CONTACTED
BY EMPLOYEES IN THE STORE,
THEY TOLD POLICE SOMEONE HAD
WRITTEN A MESSAGE THAT SAID
THAT THERE WAS A BOMB IN THE
STORE.
NOW, POLICE EVACUATED THE
STORE, OFFICERS THEN DID A
WALK THROUGH AFTER EMPTYING
NOT FIND ITEMS.
THE BUREAU OF ALCOHOL, TOBACCO
AND FIREARMS BROUGHT IN
BOMB-SNIFFING DOGS.
THE ANIMALS ARE APPARENTLY
STILL INSIDE OF THE STORE.
WE HAVE NOT BEEN ABLE TO SPEAK
TO POLICE AT THIS POINT.
POLICE HAVE SENT OUT AN ALERT
ASKING PEOPLE TO STAY AWAY
FROM THE AREA, WHICH INCLUDES
KHOL'S AND OUTBACK RESTAURANT
SITTING NEXT DOOR TO THE
DEPARTMENT STORE.
NOW BACK HERE LIVER, PEOPLE
HAVE A -- POLICE ANNOUNCED
THEY EXPECT TO REOPEN AT 8:00
THIS EVENING AFTER CONCLUDING
THEIR INVESTIGATION.
THEY SAY THE INVESTIGATION
WILL BE DONE BY 8:00 AND
THEY'RE ASKING FOR ANYONE WITH
INFORMATION TO GIVE THEM A
WALL.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WE'LL KEEP YOU UPDATED THERE.
NOW LATEST ON TRAGIC BREAKING
NEWS FROM SAN MATEO COUNTY.
POLICE SAY THE DRIVER OF A CAR
THAT HIT AND KILLED THREE
PEOPLE WILL BE CHARGED WITH
VEHICULAR MANSLAUGHTER.
SKY 7 HD WAS OVER THE SCENE OF
THE DENT&óiL ON INTERSTATE 280.
ACCORDING TO THE CHP, VICTIMS
WERE CHANGING A TIRE IN THE
CENTER DIVE YI.D A BACK
VOLKSWAGON SWERVED.
SOP LEVER SEVERAL LANES OF
NORTHBOUND I 80 ARE STILL
CLOSED.
THIS IS AN AWFUL, AWFUL SCENE.
>> IT IS.
NOW, TIME FOR A CHECK ON
SKBERJ HOW IT'S SHAPING UP FOR
THE WEEKEND.
>> YES.
SANDHYA PATEL IS IN TONIGHT.
>> I HAVE A LITTLE BIT OF
EVERYTHING FOR EVERYONE.
SO, THE LATEST COMPUTER MODEL
RUNS ARE CHANGING THE TIMING
OF THE RAIN, AND WHEN IT WILL
BE MOVING OUT OF HERE, LET ME
SHOW YOU A LIVE PICTURE FIRST.
PULLING OUT FROM OUR EASTmy'B BY
HILLS CAMERA, IT'S SPARKLING.
WE DO HAVE A FEW CLOUDS OUT
THERE AND STILL, AS WE CHECK
OUT LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD RIGHT
NOW, SOME LIGHT RETURNS DOWN
TOWARDS THE SOUTH BAY.
MOST SYSTEMS HAVE BEEN COMING
IN FROM NORTH.
WE HAVE OUR OWN RADAR KEEPING
YOU AHEAD OF THE STORM.
OUR DOPPLER COMBINED WITH
NATIONAL WEATHER SERVICE
KEEPING UP TO DATE ON STORMS
COMING IN.
OURS PICKS IT UP.
IT'S FARTHER WEST.
STORMS COMING IN FROM THE
NORTH.
RIGHT NOW, YOU CAN SEE VERY
LIGHT RETURNS.
LIGHT RAINFALL NOW.
IT'S ALL WINDING DOWN.
ANOTHER SYSTEM COMING IN OVER
THE WEEKEND.
TEMPERATURES NOW WE HAVE 41 IN
NAPA.
AND CURRENTLY DROPPING TO 46
DEGREES IN HALF MOON BAY.
HERE ARE THE HIGHLIGHTS.
IT'S GOING TO BE CHILLY
OVERNIGHT.
COLD, WET TOMORROW, AND A
CHANCE OF SHOWERS NORTH BAY
NOW ON SUNDAY.
IF YOU HAVE HOLIDAY SHOPPING
STILL TO DO, IT'S LOOKING GOOD
FOR SND.
HERE IS A SYSTEM THAT PRODUCED
LIGHT RAIN TODAY.
IT'S MOVING DOWN SOUTH.
WE HAVE ANOTHER WEAK SYSTEM
THAT IS COMING IN OVER THE
WEEKEND.
TOMORROW MORNING MAKE SURE YOU
BUNDLE UP.
8:00, CLOUD COVER.
IT'S GOING TO BE COLD.
NOW, AS YOU LOOK AT NOON TIME,
WE START TO SEE RAIN, IT WILL
CONTINUE TO SPREAD.
LIGHT TO MODERATE RAIN EVENT
FOR SATURDAY.
WE CONFINE IT FOR SUNDAY TO
THE NORTH.
NORTH BAY HAS THE BEST CHANCE.
REST OF THE BAY AREA LOOKING
FINE F DO YOU HAVE PLANS LATER
INTO THE AFTERNOON IT WILL BE
CHILLY TOMORROW MORNING
CHILLY.
TEMPERATURES DIPPING DOWN
CLOSE TO FREEZING.
MID-30s, 34 IN LIVERMORE,
THOSE WILL BE COLDEST SPOTS.
HIGHS TOMORROW, MID-40s AROUND
CLEAR LAKE, YOU'LL SEE SNOW.
LIGHT RAIN, UPPER 50s TO
LOW -- LOW 50s.
ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST SUNDAY,
CHANCE OF SHOWERS.
ANOTHER SYSTEM BRINGS US RAIN.
LOOK AT THE ACCU-WEATHER
FORECAST.
WEDNESDAY, THURSDAY LOOKING
DRY.
NEXT CHANCE OF RAIN FRIDAY
NIGHT.
>> THANK YOU.
>> STAY WITH US.
WE CONTINUE TO MONITOR
DEVELOPMENTS IN CONNECTICUT.
THE SCENE IS THAT SCHOOL
TRAGEDY TODAY.
>> BE STHOUR FOLLOW US ON
TWITTER ON ABC 7 NEWS BAY AREA
>>> 373 YEARS IS THE SENTENCE
HANDED DOWN FOR A FORMER SAN
FRANCISCO SCHOOLS WORKER WHO
TERRORIZED THE MISSION
DISTRICT LAST YEAR.
BESIDES THE SENTENCE, HE WAS
ALSO ORDERED TO PAY 250,000S
NDZ RESTITUTION TO THE THREE
WOMEN HE RAPED.
THE JUDGE HEARD FROM TWO
VICTIMS BEFORE ANNOUNCING THE
SENTENCE.
THEY BOTH DESCRIBED THE
VIOLENT ATTACK AND HOW THE
RAPE HAS AFFECTED THEIR LIVES
SINCE.
DOZER'S FAMILY STORMED OUT OF
THE COURTROOM AFTER THE
SENTENCE WAS READ.
>> SAN FRANCISCO FIRE
DEPARTMENT IN THE MIDDLE OF A
HIRING SPREE.
48 RECRUITS TOOK THE OATH THIS
MORNING.
THE CHIEF THEN PINNED BADGES
ON THE FIREFIGHTERS.
THE CLASS IS THE BIGGEST IN
THE DEPARTMENT HISTORY.
Ñ ABOUT
1500 FIREFIGHTERS.
THE FIRE DEPARTMENT HAS
ANOTHER ACADEMY SET FOR NEXT
YEAR, AND MAY SCHEDULE A
SECOND ONE IN A FEW MONTHS
JUST TO TRY TO REAP KEEP UP
WITH RETIREMENT AUTOS
CONGRATULATIONS AUTOS YES.
>> THE WARRIORS ARE ON AND
HAVE BEEN ON QUITE A ROLL.
>> THEY HAVE.
LARRY BEIL IS HERE.
TELLING US IF THEY CONTINUE.
>> THEY WERE.
>> OH, MAN.
>> SORRY.
LAST TEAM TO BEAT THE WARRIORS
WAS THE TEAM THEY FACED
TONIGHT TRYING TO STAY
UN
>> NO PLACE IS SAFE.
FEAR, TERROR, THE YOUNGEST OF
VICTIMS.
A MANMAN OPENS FIRE IN A SCHOOL,
KILLING 27.
WHY?
TONIGHT, DIANE
>>> GOOD EVENING SPORTS, IS A
)-z,
FIVE WIN STZ MOST OF THE
WARRIORS HAD SINCE 1962.
UNFORTUNATELY THEY'RE KIND OF
ASLEEP FOR THE GAME.
ORLANDO BLOCKED 10 SHOTS IN
THE FIRST HALF.
WARRIORS SHOOTING JUST 29%,
DOWN 16 AT THE HALF.
MAGIC SEVEN AND 13.
2 AND 0 AGAINST WARRIORS.
THERE IS OR LANDO, UP 17.
DAVID LEE BRINGING IT.
24 POINTS.
HIS SIXTH STRAIGHT DOUBLE,
DOUBLE.
WARRIORS DROP FIRST GAME ON
THE TRIP 99-85 WILL END THE
ROAD TRIP TOMORROW IN ATLANTA.
THE DELASALLE HIGH SCHOOL BE
FOOTBALL TEAM LOOKS TO WIN
TOMORROW AGAINST CORONA FROM
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
HE'S TALKING ABOUT RETIREMENT
EITHER AFTER THE GAME OR NEXT
SEASON.
IT'S THE ONE AND ONLY JOB HE'S
WANTED.
>> NO. I WANTED TO BE A HIGH
SCHOOLTEACHER.
I WANTED TO BE AT THIS SCHOOL.
SO THAT IS WHEN I WAS 24 YEARS
OLD.
THAT NEVER CHANGED.
IT BEEN VERY REWARDING AND A
GOOD CAREER.
VERY NO REGRETS WHATSOEVER.
>> PEOPLE FOCUSING ON THE 49er
QUARTERBACK SITUATION THEY
FORGOT ABOUT FRANK GORE.
LAST WEEK, GORE TIDE ROGER
CRAIG AND JOE PERRY FOR
FRANCHISE RECORD WITH 50
RUSHING TOUCHDOWNS.
GORE HAS BEEN BANGED UP DURING
THE SEASON, BUT IS READY FOR
THE PATRIOTS ON SUNDAY.
HE BLOCKS OUT THE PAIN.
>> STH IS THE LOVE OF THE GAME,
YOU KNOW?
HOW MUCH HE LOVES FOOTBALL.
HOW MUCH HE LIKES PRACTICING
AND PLAYING THIS GAME.
THAT HAS QUITE THE BIG PART IN
MAKING HIM SUCH A SURE GUY
WEEK AFTER WEEK.2úC
>> THAT HE S THIS SPORTS
REPORT BROUGHT TO YOU BY
MERCEDES-BENZ.
>> THAT IS A LOT OF TOUCHES.
HE GETS A LOT OF PLAY.
>> HE IS A WORK HORSE.
HE RUNS LOW TO THE GROUND HARD
TO TACKLE.
>> THIS IS JUST A POUNDING
PUNCH.
>> BIGGER GUY.
>> TRUE.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
>> IN RESPONSE TO OVERWHELMING
CRITICISM, UNIVERSITY OF
CALIFORNIA SYSTEM DECIDED TO
NIX PLANS TO USE A COLORFUL
NEW LOGO.
IT CAME UNDER FIRE FROM
STUDENTS AND ALUMNI CALLING IT
BLAND.
MOAT WANT THEM TO GO BACK TO
THE CLASSIC LOGO, USED FOR 144
YEARS.
>> ABC 7 NEWS WILL BRING YOU
CONTINUING COVERAGE TONIGHT
WITH THE LATEST FROM
CONNECTICUT.
>> HUNDREDS HOLDING VIGILS IN
CHURCHES IN CONNECTICUT AND
ACROSS THE NATION.
THE MESSAGE BEING DELIVERED
THERE, AND HERE IN THE BAY
AREA.
>> IT'S BEEN A HORRIFYING DAY
THERE AND AROUND THE COUNTRY
THAT.
IS COMING UP AT 9:00.
AND THEN ABC 7 NEWS AT 11:00.
WE APPRECIATE YOUR BEING WITH
US TONIGHT.
>> FROM THE ENTIRE TEAM HERE,
GOOD NIGHT.
THIS IS "JEOPARDY!"
HERE ARE TODAY'S CONTESTANTS --
A GRADUATE STUDENT
AND RESEARCH ASSISTANT
ORIGINALLY
FROM PLYMOUTH, WISCONSIN...
AN ASSOCIATE EDITOR
OF TEXTBOOKS
FROM ORLANDO, FLORIDA...
AND OUR RETURNING CHAMPION,
A COMPUTER-CHIP DESIGNER
FROM BERLIN, MASSACHUSETTS...
AND NOW HERE IS
THE HOST OF "JEOPARDY!" --
ALEX TREBEK!
THANK YOU, JOHNNY.
WAITING TO COME OUT HERE,
THAT WHENEVER WE INTRODUCE
ALISTAIR,
HE'S VERY BRIGHT,
BUT HE ALWAYS SEEMS SO SURPRISE.
HE'S WON TWO SHOWS
AND BEEN VERY POWERFUL
IN ALL KINDS OF AREAS
OF KNOWLEDGE.
SO, CARLY AND MATT, YOU HA
YOUR WORK CUT OUT FOR YOU.
YOU KNOW THAT.
GOOD LUCK.
HERE WE GO.
JEOPARDY! ROUND.
AND THE CATEGORIES.
WHAT GOES WITH THAT?