>> OH, WELL, YOU'VE GOT ME,
SO THAT'S OKAY.
>> [laughs]
SO YOU REALLY KNOW EVERY WINNER?
>> OH, WELL, SINCE YOU'VE BEEN
AROUND, THERE WAS FIRST
KEVIN SMITH, AND THEN THERE WAS
NANCY CHRISTY, AND THEN EVEN THE
HALF MILLION DOLLAR WINNERS,
THE VERY NEXT CONTESTANT,
YOU HAD ARMAND KACHIGIAN.
THE NEXT SEASON,
YOU HAD JEFF GROSS.
TWO SEASONS LATER, YOU HAD
OGI OGAS, AND THEN TWO SEASONS
LATER, YOU HAD LYN PAYNE.
THEY'RE ALL REALLY GREAT.
>> YOU ARE A TRUE FAN.
>> OH, I LOVE THE GAME.
>> I GOT IT.
>> IT'S THE BEST GAME.
>> OH, THANK YOU.
AND YOUR MOM IS HERE, TRISH.
DOES HE REALLY LOVE THE GAME?
IS HE TRULY THIS BIG A FAN?
>> YES.
THIS IS SO, SO TRUE.
HE LIVES, EATS, BREATHES IT.
HE TALKS ABOUT IT.
HE TELLS ME ABOUT EVERY EPISODE.
HE'LL CALL ME AND TELL ME WHAT
HAPPENED ON THE EPISODE THATDAY.
HE NEVER MISSES IT.
HE LOVES IT.
>> AND WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT
THAT?
>> HE LOVES GAMES
AND GAME SHOWS,
AND THIS IS A DREAM COME TRUE
FOR HIM.
I'M JUST EXCITED HE'S HERE.
>> I'M EXCITED HE'S HERE TOO.
SHAWN, IT IS A DREAM COME TRUE
FOR YOU.
>> OH, THIS IS.
>> THIS IS YOUR AUDIENCE TODAY.
>> OH, YEAH.
[cheers and applause]
>> ALL RIGHT, SHAWN, IT IS ALL
ABOUT YOU.
AND THERE'S SOMEBODY AT HOME
RIGHT NOW PAYING CLOSE
ATTENTION.
SO LET'S SEE THE MONEY IN YOUR
ROUND 1.
OKAY, COMPUTER, PLEASE RANDOMIZE
THE DOLLAR AMOUNTS.
NOW HERE ARE THE CATEGORIES TO
YOUR QUESTIONS.
LET'S RANDOMIZE THOSE
CATEGORIES.
AND NOW THAT EVERYTHING IS ALL
SHUFFLED, ARE YOU READY?
>> OH, I'M READY.
>> AUDIENCE, ARE YOU READY?
[cheers and applause]
THEN LET'S PLAY MILLIONAIRE.
GOOD LUCK, SHAWN.
GROWING UP TO FOUR INCHES LONG,
THE LEOPARD SLUG GETS ITS NAME
DUE TO WHAT CHARACTERISTIC?
>> "C," IT HAS SPOTS.
>> FINAL?
>> YES, FINAL ANSWER.
>> GOOD START, SHAWN.
ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
LET'S START BUILDING THAT BANK
OF YOURS, OKAY?
WE'RE GONNA START YOU WITH
$2,000.
VERY NICE.
13 AWAY FROM THE MILLION.
>> WE'RE GOING THERE.
>> "MEAL BREAK" IS YOUR NEXT
CATEGORY.
WHICH OF THE FOLLOWING IS
A BREAKFAST CEREAL AND NOT
A SUBATOMIC PARTICLE?
>> I DON'T KNOW THE BREAKFAST
CEREAL.
FORTUNATELY, I'M PRETTY GOOD
WITH SUBATOMIC PARTICLES.
NO NEUTRINO, NO QUARK.
GLUON, GLUON, GLUON, THAT'S
JUMPING OUT AT ME AS BEING LIKE
A SUBATOMIC PARTICLE.
QUISP?
THAT SOUNDS LIKE SOMEONE--
SOMEONE IN A THINK TANK WENT,
"WHAT ARE WE GONNA NAME THIS
CEREAL?"
WELL, MY HEART'S BEATING A MILE
A MINUTE, BUT I THINK I'M GONNA
GO WITH "D," QUISP
AS A BREAKFAST CEREAL,
NOT A SUBATOMIC PARTICLE.
"D," QUISP.
>> FINAL?
>> FINAL ANSWER.
>> AFTER ALL THIS TIME WANTING
TO BE ON, YOU GOT IT RIGHT.
>> OH, THANK GOD.
>> IT'S MADE BY QUAKER OATS.
IT IS QUISP.
>> YES!
WHOO!
[cheers and applause]
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> OH, GOODNESS.
>> OH, IS IT--HAS--HAS IT
HIT YOU THAT YOU'RE HERE?
>> A LITTLE BIT.
>> YEAH.
$27,000.
12 AWAY FROM THE MILLION.
>> OH.
>> ON THE 2012 TV SERIES
ELEMENTARY, LUCY LIU PLAYS AN
UPDATED VERSION OF WHAT
FICTIONAL CHARACTER WHO IS
TYPICALLY PORTRAYED AS A MAN?
>> I HAVEN'T SEEN IT, BUT IT'S
GOT TO BE "B," 'CAUSE IT'S ABOUT
SHERLOCK HOLMES.
SO I'M GONNA GO WITH "B,"
DR. WATSON.
>> FINAL?
>> FINAL ANSWER.
>> YES, IT IS DR. WATSON.
SHOW US THE MONEY, PLEASE,
COMPUTER.
$100.
>> $100'S GOOD.
>> $27,100.
NOW JUST 11 AWAY FROM
$1 MILLION, SHAWN.
>> 3 DOWN, 11 TO GO.
>> "GETTING OLDER."
>> JOINING THE COMPANY OF THE
LEANING TOWER OF PISA, WHAT
OTHER ITALIAN LANDMARK IS NOW
TILTING WITH A DIP OF 16 INCHES
ON ITS SOUTH SIDE?
>> COLOSSEUM, THAT SEEMS LIKE AN
ODD THING TO ACTUALLY MEASURE,
BECAUSE, I MEAN, IT'S SO WIDE.
TREVI FOUNTAIN, MAYBE.
BUT--OH.
I DIDN'T WANT TO DO THIS.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO
JUMP THE QUESTION, I THINK.
>> OKAY, NO PROBLEM.
QUESTION'S OUT OF PLAY.
YOU DON'T KNOW THE ANSWER,
SO THAT'S FAIR ENOUGH.
LET'S SEE THE ANSWER.
IT WAS THE ROMAN COLOSSEUM.
AND YOU WERE NOT LEANING THAT
WAY.
>> THAT WAS THE LAST ONE
I WOULD'VE GUESSED.
>> GOOD, I'M GLAD YOU JUMPED.
LET'S SEE WHAT YOU JUMPED OVER.
HOPEFULLY NOT A LOT.
$1,000, THAT'S NOT TOO BAD IN
THE SCHEME OF THINGS AT ALL.
BY JUMPING THE QUESTION,
NOW 10 AWAY FROM THE MILLION.
STILL A LOT OF GOOD MONEY TO BE
HAD.
DONNA SUMMER ONCE QUIPPED,
"IT'S NICE TO BE THE QUEEN OF
SOMETHING," WHEN ASKED ABOUT
BEING DUBBED WHAT?
>> OH, A MUSIC QUESTION.
>> DONNA SUMMER.
DO YOU KNOW DONNA SUMMER?
>> NO.
[audience groans]
>> WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
HE WAS BUSY WATCHING
MILLIONAIRE, SO LEAVE HIM
ALONE.
>> EXACTLY.
>> IT GOT HIM HERE.
>> YOU SHOULD'VE ASKED
A QUESTION ABOUT DONNA SUMMER
TWO YEARS AGO.
I WOULD KNOW IT THEN.
WELL, CLEARLY THE AUDIENCE IS
NOT HAPPY WITH ME, SO LET'S ASK
THEM.
>> OKAY.
YEAH, WE'LL PUT THE AUDIENCE ON
THE SPOT.
OKAY, AUDIENCE, SHAWN NEEDS YOUR
HELP.
ON YOUR KEYPADS, VOTE NOW.
[percussive music]
♪
OKAY.
90% BELIEVE IT IS THE QUEEN OF
DISCO.
>> I GUESS I HAVE TO GO WITH
THAT.
"A," QUEEN OF DISCO,
FINAL ANSWER.
>> YEAH, AND YOU'D LOVE HER.
SHE'S GREAT.
SHE'S A REALLY PHENOMENAL
ARTIST.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT HOW MUCH
MONEY IS BEHIND THIS QUESTION.
$3,000.
$30,100.
WE'RE GONNA TAKE A BREAK.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
MILLIONAIRE RIGHT AFTER THIS.
This holiday when Kmart
Shop Your Way members
check out, they
can win...
... a trip to
Universal Orlando Resort,
during our 30 Days of
Surprise Sweepstakes.
You could have a despicably
good time.
Fly with Harry.
Or win lots of other
great prizes.
For more chances to win visit
Shop Your Way .com
Only at Kmart.
♪
I MUST HAVE
THE WRONG HOUSE.
SISTER?
WE MISSED YOU.
THEY WAITED UP ALL NIGHT
FOR YOU, YOU KNOW.
IT'S A LONG WAY
FROM WEST AFRICA.
AHH...COFFEE.
[ inhales deeply ]
♪
HE'S HERE.
I BROUGHT YOU SOMETHING.
[ chuckles ]
REALLY?
♪
[ chuckles ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU'RE MY PRESENT
THIS YEAR.
♪ THE BEST PART OF WAKIN' UP
♪ IS FOLGERS IN YOUR CUP
>> AND WE ARE BACK WITH
SHAWN SUTHERLAND, WHO SAYS HE IS
MILLIONAIRE'S BIGGEST FAN,
WATCHES RELIGIOUSLY.
IT'S PAYING OFF IN THE FACT THAT
YOU HAVE $30,100.
THAT'S NOW SHAWN'S BANK INSTEAD
7OF SOMEONE ELSE'S BANK.
>> LOVE SEEING THAT.
>> I DON'T BLAME YOU.
9 AWAY FROM THE MILLION,
5 AWAY FROM ROUND 2.
AT THAT POINT, YOU GET TO KEEP
ALL THE MONEY IN YOUR BANK.
AND YOU SAID TO ME IN THE BREAK
THAT THERE IS NO WAY YOU'RE JUST
GONNA WALK AWAY.
>> NOT A CHANCE.
WELL, YOU HAD OGI OGAS
AND LYN PAYNE.
THEY WOULD'VE GOTTEN THEIRS
RIGHT.
WE NEED ANOTHER WINNER.
WE ARE GONNA HAVE TO GO ALL THE
WAY IF WE'RE GONNA WIN
THE MILLION.
>> OKAY.
[cheers and applause]
>> ALL RIGHT, I LIKE YOUR
ATTITUDE.
WE'LL SEE IF THAT PLAYS OUT.
ARE YOU READY?
>> OH, I'M READY.
>> THEN LET'S PLAY.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
IF YOU'RE A NINE TO FIVER,
YOU MIGHT DREAD WHAT MONTH, FED?
AS IT HAS NO FEDERAL HOLIDAYS?
>> PRESIDENT'S DAY, ISN'T THAT
IN FEBRUARY?
JUNE, I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S
A FEDERAL HOLIDAY, BUT IT'S GOT
FLAG DAY, MY BIRTHDAY.
YEAH, IT'S A GREAT DAY,
BEST DAY, JUNE 14TH.
>> IT'S MY WEDDING DAY.
>> OH, WELL, HAPPY FUTURE
ANNIVERSARY, I GUESS.
>> YEAH, AND HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> I CAN'T GET THE QUESTION
WRONG.
I WOULDN'T BE ABLE TO DEAL WITH
THAT.
SO I'M--I'M GONNA JUMP THE
QUESTION.
>> NO PROBLEM.
>> QUESTION IS OUT OF PLAY.
>> PLEASE DON'T TELL ME IT WAS
GONNA BE MAY.
>> LET'S SEE THE CORRECT ANSWER.
IT WAS GOING TO BE JUNE.
MAY HAS MEMORIAL DAY IN IT.
>> MEMORIAL DAY.
>> SO GLAD YOU JUMPED IT.
LET'S SEE WHAT YOU JUMPED OVER.
OW.
OKAY.
>> BUT I'M NOT WALKING AWAY
ANYWAY.
>> EXACTLY.
BY JUMPING THAT QUESTION--YOU
DIDN'T KNOW IT--YOU'RE STILL IN
THE GAME, WHICH IS THE IMPORTANT
PART.
8 AWAY FROM $1 MILLION.
"HAIRY HISTORY."
REPORTEDLY SEEN AS A
"POTENT SYMBOL OF VIRILITY,"
THE BRITISH ARMY FORBADE ITS
RANKS FROM SHAVING ANY HAIR FROM
WHERE UNTIL 1916?
>> IT'S GOT TO BE EITHER "A"
OR "C."
YOU ALWAYS TALK ABOUT, "OH,
IT'LL PUT HAIR ON YOUR CHEST,"
AND I THINK THAT PHRASE ACTUALLY
COMES FROM GREAT BRITAIN, BUT I
DON'T KNOW IF I'M JUST TALKING
MYSELF OUT OF IT.
IT'S GOT TO BE THE FACE OR THE
CHEST.
I'M GONNA HAVE TO GO WITH MY
FIRST INSTINCT.
I MEAN, WE ALWAYS TELL MATH
STUDENTS ON A MATH TEST, "DON'T
CHANGE YOUR ANSWER UNTIL YOU
KNOW IT'S WRONG."
SO I MIGHT BE GOING HOME RIGHT
NOW, BUT I'M GOING TO RISK IT.
THOUGHT IT WAS THE FACE, 'CAUSE
YOU SEE--YOU CAN SEE THE FACES
OF THE PEOPLE WHO ARE SHOOTING
AT YOU IF THEY'RE CLOSE ENOUGH.
[laughter]
IN WHICH CASE, THAT'S KIND OF
BAD NEWS, BUT NONETHELESS, I'M
GONNA GO WITH "A," UPPER LIP.
PRAYING IT'S RIGHT.
>> FINAL ANSWER?
>> FINAL ANSWER.
>> IT'S UPPER LIP.
YOU GOT IT RIGHT.
[cheers and applause]
>> THIS IS STRESSFUL.
>> YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, SHAWN, LET'S SEE THE
MONEY BEHIND THIS QUESTION.
YOU WORKED SO HARD AT IT.
YOU GOT YOUR $15,000.
$45,100.
IT WAS WORTH ALL THAT STRESS.
YEAH, IT WAS.
>> ALL RIGHT, JUST THREE
QUESTIONS LEFT IN ROUND 1.
"NOT SO FAST."
SOME SCIENTISTS BELIEVE THE
APPENDIX MAY HAVE AN IMPORTANT
FUNCTION WITHIN WHICH
BODILY SYSTEM?
>> I THOUGHT IT HAD TO DO--
I THOUGHT THERE WAS SOME
DISCUSSION A COUPLE YEARS BACK.
THEY THOUGHT IT USED TO WORK
WITH THE GALLBLADDER AND THE
LIVER, LIKE, FILTERING
SOMETHING.
RESPIRATORY, THAT DOESN'T FIT IN
ANYWHERE, NOT EXACTLY A LOT
OF NERVES IN THERE.
FILTERING WOULD FIT IN
WITH IMMUNITY.
AND IT'S NOT REALLY PART OF
A BLOOD VESSEL OR HEART.
ALL RIGHT, I'M STILL GONNA GO
FOR IT, BUT I THINK MY BEST
CHANCE IS ON "B," IMMUNE.
>> FINAL?
>> THAT'S MY FINAL ANSWER.
>> YOUR BEST CHANCE IS RIGHT.
YOU GOT IT.
[cheers and applause]
LET'S PUT SOME MORE MONEY IN
THAT BANK, SHAWN.
$5,000.
$50,100.
SHAWN'S ON A ROLL.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
RIGHT AFTER THIS.
>> AND WELCOME BACK.
WE'RE HERE WITH
SHAWN SUTHERLAND.
HIS BANK STANDS AT $50,100.
A GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT.
ASSISTANT TEACHING MATH, SO YOU
KNOW A LOT ABOUT NUMBERS,IS GAM.
A LOT ABOUT THIS GAME.
I WAS TEASING YOU ABOUT YOUR
OBSESSION HERE, BUT ALL TEASING
ASIDE, I THINK IT'S GREAT THAT
YOU'RE A BIG FAN OF THE SHOW,
AND I'M SO GLAD THAT YOU'VE HAD
THE CHANCE TO BE HERE AND MAKE
THIS KIND OF MONEY.
>> DREAM COME TRUE.
WELL, I HOPE TO PURSUE THE DREAM
A LITTLE BIT FURTHER.
YOU'VE STILL GOT TWO TO GO IN
ROUND 1.
GET THESE TWO RIGHT, AND YOU'LL
LOOK AT THAT $100,000 QUESTION.
OUT OF LIFELINES.
YOU READY TO KEEP PLAYING?
>> OH, I'M READY.
>> THEN LET'S PLAY.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
ACROSS THE STREET FROM THE ALAMO
IS A HOTEL NAMED WHAT?
>> I'M LOOKING AT "A," "B,"
AND "D," THINKING THOSE DON'T
SOUND RIGHT.
BUT, YOU KNOW, YOU'VE GOT
DAVY CROCKETT.
THAT'S KIND OF THAT REGION.
I DON'T HAVE A BETTER ANSWER,
AND I AM GOING FOR IT,
SO "C," CROCKETT HOTEL,
FINAL ANSWER.
>> ABSOLUTELY RIGHT.
IS IT $7,000 OR $500?
LET'S CHECK IT OUT HERE.
THAT'S $500.
$50,600.
ONE QUESTION LEFT IN ROUND 1,
WORTH W THAT IT IS
WORTH $7,000.
>> I'LL FEEL MUCH BETTER AFTER
THIS ONE.
>> WHICH OF THE FOLLOWING
"VILLES" IS NOT THE NAME OF A
POPULAR SOCIAL NETWORKING GAME
FOUND ON FACEBOOK?
>> FARMVILLE IS HER GREATEST
OBSESSION, I THINK.
I RECENTLY DEFRIENDED A BUNCH OF
PEOPLE FOR SENDING ME REQUESTS.
I WAS TIRED OF THEM.
BUT I GOT TONS OF THEM FOR
FARMVILLE AND CITYVILLE.
NONE FOR CASTLEVILLE OR
VEGASVILLE, SO...
IT'S GONNA BE "A" OR "D."
I'VE GOT A 50/50 SHOT THERE.
>> YOU COULD WALK WITH $25,300.
>> NOT GONNA HAPPEN.
[applause]
>> SO LET'S SEE.
OKAY, IF--IF I WERE GOING TO
CREATE A NEW FACEBOOK GAME,
YOU GOT FARMVILLE, CITYVILLE.
AND THEY DO ALL THE DIFFERENT
FARMS.
I'VE SEEN HER PLAY WAY TOO MUCH
FARMVILLE.
THEY'VE GOT DIFFERENT THEMES OF
ONE.
BUT THEN YOU'VE GOT ALL THE
POPULAR, LIKE, DEFEND YOUR
CASTLE, CASTLE TOWER DEFENSE
THINGS ON THE INTERNET.
THAT SEEMS LIKE IT WOULD BE
A GOOD TIE-IN.
VEGAS, IT SEEMS LIKE THAT'S KIND
OF SPECIFIC.
IT WOULD BE HARD TO, LIKE,
CREATE A WHOLE LOT OF DIFFERENT
IMAGINARY THINGS LIKE A--
A RAINBOW BURPING UNICORN FOR
FARMVILLE.
THEY HAVE WEIRD THINGS ON THERE,
IT'S--
>> SO WHAT IS IT GONNA BE?
>> SO, I'M--IT'S GONNA HAVE TO
BE WHAT I'M GONNA SAY.
"D," VEGASVILLE.
>> FINAL ANSWER?
>> YES.
>> NO.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA WALK AWAY.
IT IS VEGASVILLE.
[cheers and applause]
>> HIGH FIVE.
>> WELL, SHAWN.
SOME MIGHT THINK THAT YOU'RE
ABSOLUTELY CRAZY.
NOW, I CERTAINLY WASN'T SURE YOU
WERE GONNA DO IT AT ALL,
AND I THOUGHT, YOU'RE CRAZY TO
RISK THAT KIND OF MONEY.
>> I JUST WON $25,000.
>> YES, YOU DID.
YOU'VE GOT $57,600.
GOOD FOR YOU FOR GOING FOR IT.
YOU'RE NOW IN ROUND 2, SHAWN.
YOUR NEXT QUESTION WILL BE
FOR $100,000.
IT IS TIME TO PLAY CLASSIC
MILLIONAIRE.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
ALL RIGHT, SHAWN.
HERE'S THE THING.
YOU'RE FOUR QUESTIONS AWAY FROM
THE MILLION DOLLARS.
YOU HAVE $57,600 IN YOUR BANK
RIGHT NOW.
IT'S YOUR MONEY, OKAY?
>> $25,000, ALL RIGHT.
>> $57,600.
>> $25,000.
>> YOU--
I'M NOT GONNA CONVINCE YOU,
AM I?
>> NO.
>> OKAY, HERE'S YOUR QUESTION
FOR $100,000.
>> THE PRESSURE'S ACTUALLY
OFF NOW.
I GOT $25,000.
>> IF YOU HATE SHAKESPEARE,
YOU'D MOST LIKELY APPRECIATE
WHAT PLAY, WHICH AT AROUND
1,800 LINES IS HIS SHORTEST?
>> OKAY, SO MY INITIAL INSTINCT
OF KING LEAR, NOT RIGHT.
HE HAD SO MANY OF THE--ABOUT
RICHARD III, RICHARD II, ALL OF
THE DIFFERENT KINGS.
KING JOHN'S JUMPING OUT AT ME,
BUT THEN COMEDY OF ERRORS,
I SEEM TO REMEMBER THERE BEING
SOME PLAY I WAS PROBABLY DRAGGED
TO AS AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL--
ABOUT THAT.
WELL, WE'LL GO WITH THE ONE THAT
KIND OF DESCRIBES ME, "B."
[laughter]
OH, COME ON, YOU KNOW IT'S TRUE.
>> [laughs]
>> SO I HOPE IT'S NOT MY LAST
ONE, BUT FOR NOW,
"B," FINAL ANSWER.
>> YOU HAVE $100,000.
[cheers and applause]
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK WITH MORE
MILLIONAIRE.
SHAWN WILL LOOK AT THAT QUESTION
FOR $250,000.
[laughs]
>> HERE IS YOUR QUESTION OF THE
DAY.
IN THE SONG THE LADY
THE LADY HATES CALIFORNIA FOR
WHICH OF THESE REASONS?
STAY TUNED FOR THE ANSWER.
>> THE ANSWER TO THAT QUESTION
WAS, IT'S COLD AND IT'S DAMP.
AND WELCOME BACK TO MILLIONAIRE.
I GOT TO TELL YOU,
SHAWN SUTHERLAND, WHEN YOU SAID
YOU WERE NOT GONNA WALK AWAY,
I THOUGHT YOU WERE CRAZY.
BUT YOU SAID IT'S NOT ABOUT
THE MONEY HERE.
IT'S THE EXPERIENCE FOR YOU.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>> THAT LAST QUESTION WHEN IT
CAME UP, COMEDY OF ERRORS,
THAT'S WHY YOU PICKED IT,
BECAUSE YOU SAID "WELL, I'M
A COMEDY OF ERRORS,
SO I'LL GO FOR THAT," HAD NO
IDEA.
>> GOD'S SMILING DOWN ON ME.
I GUESS I HAVE TO GO FOR THE
NEXT THREE TOO.
>> $100,000, SHAWN.
>> $25,000.
>> OKAY, $25,000.
$100,000.
>> $25,000.
>> THAT'S WHERE WE'RE GOING.
>> $250,000 QUESTION.
>> OH, WE'RE GOING TO
$1 MILLION.
>> OKAY, I BELIEVE YOU.
I'M A CONVERT HERE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
>> ARE YOU READY?
>> I'M READY.
>> THEN LET'S PLAY.
[dramatic musical flourish]
♪
FOR $250,000, AS A CHILD, WHICH
CAST MEMBER OF FRIENDS HAD
ARTWORK EXHIBITED AT NEW YORK'S
METROPOLITAN MUSEUM OF ART?
>> SINCE IT CAME UP, I WENT,
"PHOEBE."
I DON'T--I DON'T KNOW IF FOR
SURE THAT'S RIGHT, BUT THAT WAS
PLAYED BY LISA KUDROW, RIGHT?
UH...
WELL, THINKING ABOUT THIS
FURTHER IS NOT GOING TO HELP.
I TOLD YOU I'M GOING FOR IT.
THAT'S NOT CHANGING NOW.
SO I HOPE I'M HERE FOR TWO MORE
QUESTIONS, BUT IF NOT,T.
IT'S BEEN GREAT.
IT'S EVERYTHING I'VE WANTED,
EXCEPT THE MILLION DOLLARS
SO FAR.
BUT, YEAH, I THINK I'M GONNA GO
WITH "C," LISA KUDROW.
>> FINAL ANSWER?
>> FINAL ANSWER.
>> IT'S JENNIFER ANISTON.
BUT YOU DON'T CARE, 'CAUSE YOU
JUST WANTED THE $25,000.
>> I GOT $25,000.
>> YOU GOT $25,000, SHAWN.
GREAT PLAYING.
CONGRATULATIONS.
[horn blares]
WHAT A WAY TO END THE GAME.
REALLY, SERIOUSLY.
THAT SOUND MEANS OUR TIME IS UP
FOR TODAY, BUT, SHAWN, YOU'RE
WALKING AWAY WITH $25,000,
A DREAM COME TRUE FOR YOU.
UNTIL NEXT TIME, FOLKS,
FROM NEW YORK, EVERYBODY,
BYE BYE.LET'S GIVE YOUR MOM A H.
I know how tempting those
newfangled cleaners are,
but we both know that won't end
well.
Stick with what you know ladies,
Pine Sol.
It's got everything you need,
and nothing you don't.
And when I get a cold I take
Coricidin HBP.
The number one pharmacist
recommended cold brand
designed for people with high
blood pressure.
Coricidin HBP.
>> CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED BY:
[ fishing rod casting line,
marching band playing ]
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
>>> GOOD MORNING, I'M
METEOROLOGIST MIKE NICCO.
WE'RE ON STORM WATCH.
GOOD NEWS, STEADIER RAIN JUST
ABOUT OVER FOR MOST OF US.
LIGHT RAIN IN THE EAST BAY HILLS
COMING DOWN INTO THE SANTA CLARA
VALLEY.
SANTA CLARA RIGHT NOW, LAWRENCE
EXPRESSWAY, OVER TO SAN JOSE,
KING ROAD WHERE WE'RE SEEING
SOME OF STEADIER RAIN.
AS WE GO FORWARD, WE'RE SEEING
BREAKS IN THE CLOUDS AND SOME
SUNSHINE AND SHOWERS UP TO THE
NORTH.
STEADY RAIN AS WE HEAD THROUGH
THE AFTERNOON IS ENDING AND
ISOLATED SHOWER, BIG STORMS
COMING UP ON THURSDAY AND
FRIDAY.
SPENCER AND SANDY WILL HAVE THAT
FOR YOU.
STAY TUNEDKx;ñ;ñ;ñ;ñ;ñ$x
>>> THE DEVASTATING EVENTS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT HAS TOUCHED
US AT "THE CHEW."
>> AMONG THE LOSS IS A MEMBER OF
OUR CHEW FAMILY.
>> OUR HEARTS AND PRAYERS GO OUT
TO ALL OF THE FAMILIES AFFECT TD
BY THIS HEARTBREAKING TRAGEDY.
>> WE OFFER THAT WE CAN OFFER
COMFORT BY BRINGING LOVED ONES
AROUND THE FAMILY TABLE TO HELP
EACH OTHER THROUGH THE DIFFICULT
DAYS AHEAD.
>> Announcer: TODAY ON
"THE CHEW" --
WE'RE DREAMING OF A SWEET
CHRISTMAS.
>> WE'RE LOOKING AT THE NOUGAT
FUSING WITH THE CARAMEL.
>> Announcer: AND CARLA'S GOING