SOCIETY BECAUSE, FRANKLY, WE'RE
AFRAID TO TALK ABOUT IT.
>> TONIGHT, AS AMERICA JOINS A
CONVERSATION ABOUT GUN VIOLENCE
IN THIS COUNTRY, ALL OF ABC NEWS
JOINS THE SEARCH FOR SOLUTIONS.
A WAY FORWARD, TOGETHER, AS
"WORLD NEWS" BEGINS.
>>> AND GOOD EVENING, ON THIS
MONDAY NIGHT.
AND AS WE BEGIN A NEW WEEK ALL
ACROSS THE COUNTRY, PARENTS AND
CHILDREN RETURN TO THEIR
SCHOOLS, THINKING OF THOSE 26
FAMILIES FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
LAST NIGHT, THE PRESIDENT
ASSURED THEM HE WILL TAKE
ACTION, SAYING THEY ARE NOT
ALONE.
AND, AS WE SAID, THIS WEEK HERE
AT ABC NEWS, WE WILL JOIN THE
SEARCH FOR ANSWERS ABOUT GUN
VIOLENCE IN AMERICA.
BUT WE DO BEGIN THIS EVENING IN
A COMMUNITY THAT IS SHATTERED
BUT HOLDING ON, AND ABC'S DAN
HARRIS, WHO HAS BEEN THERE FROM
THE START, WATCHED AS THE
FUNERALS BEGAN TODAY.
DAN?
>> Reporter: DIANE, GOOD
EVENING.
THIS GROWING CARPET OF CARDS AND
FLOWERS AND TEDDY BEARS BEHIND
ME IS A SYMBOL OF A COMMUNITY
THAT IS HOPING, IN THE WORDS OF
ONE OF THE SIGNS HERE, THAT LOVE
WILL GET THEM THROUGH THIS.
FIRST, THOUGH, THEY NEED TO GET
THROUGH THE FUNERALS, WHICH
BEGAN TODAY.
TODAY, IN NEWTOWN, A FUNERAL FOR
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER, WHO WAS
EULOGIZED AS A BOY WHO LIKED
ANIMALS, VIDEO GAMES AND MEXICAN
FOOD.
HE USED TO TELL PEOPLE HE WORKED
IN A TACO FACTORY.
AT HIS FUNERAL, AN ONLOOKER
COLLAPSED AS THE PROCESSION
PASSED.
INSIDE, HIS MOTHER SHARED
STORIES THAT HAD EVERYONE IN
TEARS.
>> WHEN SHE TOLD HIM, I LOVE
YOU, HIS ANSWER WAS, NOT AS MUCH
AS I LOVE YOU.
>> Reporter: A FEW MILES AWAY,
ANOTHER FUNERAL.
JACK PINTO, ALSO 6, A HUGE
SPORTS FAN, WHOSE FAVORITE NEW
YORK GIANTS PLAYER, VICTOR CRUZ,
WORE HIS NAME ON HIS CLEATS
DURING SUNDAY'S GAME.
>> I WAS HONORED, MAN.
IT WAS -- I COULDN'T EXPRESS TO
THEM HOW GREAT THAT MADE ME
FEEL.
>> Reporter: JACK'S FRIENDS FROM
THE WRESTLING TEAM SHOWED UP IN
THEIR LITTLE UNIFORMS.
IN A NEWS CONFERENCE TODAY, THE
NORMALLY STOIC STATE TROOPER
WHO HAS BEEN BRIEFING REPORTERS,
CHOKED UP WHEN ASKING FOR PROOI
SI FOR THE FAMILIES.
>> AT THIS TIME I CAN TAKE A
COUPLE OF QUESTIONS.
>> Reporter: HE ALSO REVEALED
THAT THERE WERE ACTUALLY TWO
ADULT SURVIVORS ON FRIDAY'S
RAMPAGE, NOT ONE.
BOTH FEMALE EMPLOYEES WITH
GUNSHOT WOUNDS.
>> INVESTIGATORS WILL SPEAK WITH
THEM WHEN IT'S MEDICALLY
APPROPRIATE, AND CERTAINLY THEY
WILL SHED A GREAT DEAL OF LIGHT
ON THE FACTS AND CIRCUMSTANCES
OF THIS TRAGIC INVESTIGATION.
>> Reporter: WITH THE SCHOOL
ITSELF REMAINING A CRIME SCENE,
PERHAPS FOR MONTHS, POLICE SAID
TODAY, 75 TO 100 VOLUNTEERS ARE
NOW FIXING UP AN UNUSED MIDDLE
SCHOOL IN THE NEXT TOWN OVER.
>> WE WANT TO HAVE THEM COME IN
AND FEEL THAT THEY ARE SAFE AND
SECURE.
>> Reporter: THE NATIONAL
OUTPOURING IS BEING FELT KEENLY
HERE, FROM THE PRESIDENT,
VISITING WITH FAMILIES SUNDAY
NIGHT --
>> I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR
YOU TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE IN YOUR GRIEF.
>> Reporter: TO THE LOCAL
FLORIST, WHERE THEY ARE
OVERWHELMED WITH PEOPLE FROM ALL
OVER THE COUNTRY CALLING TO
ORDER FLOWERS.
BACK NOW AT THE MAKESHIFT
MEMORIAL, WHERE A MARCHING BAND
IS PLAYING, SCHOOL OFFICIALS
HAVEN'T ANNOUNCED YET WHEN
CLASSES WILL START UP AGAIN FOR
THE STUDENTS FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY.
THE REST OF THE SCHOOLS HERE IN
NEWTOWN WILL REOPEN TOMORROW,
WHICH COULD BE A TRICKY CONCEPT
FOR SOME PARENTS, WHO MAY NOT
WANT TO LET THEIR KIDS OUT OF
THEIR SIGHT.
DIANE?
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH, DAN.
AND ALL ACROSS THIS COUNTRY, IN
OTHER STATES AND OTHER
COMMUNITIES, AS WE SAID, IT WAS
AN ANXIOUS MONDAY, ABOUT
SOMETHING EVERYONE HAS TAKEN FOR
GRANTED.
MILLIONS OF CHILDREN RETURNING
TO CLASSROOMS AND SOME SCHOOLS
CALLED IN MORE SECURITY.
THERE WERE EVEN FALSE ALARMS
AROUND THE COUNTRY, AND HERE'S
ABC'S AMY ROBACH WITH THAT.
AMY?
>> Reporter: THAT'S RIGHT,
DIANE.
AND GOOD EVENING TO YOU.
WHAT HAPPENED HERE IN NEWTOWN
HAS BROUGHT SWEEPING CHANGES TO
SCHOOLS ACROSS THIS COUNTRY ON
THIS VERY FIRST DAY BACK TO
CLASS SINCE THIS HORRIFIC
TRAGEDY UNFOLDED HERE.
PARENTS AROUND THE NATION
DROPPED THEIR CHILDREN OFF AT
SCHOOL THIS MORNING.
MANY HOLDING ON A LITTLE MORE
TIGHTLY.
>> SEE YOU, OKAY?
HAVE A GOOD DAY.
>> Reporter: A DAY OF JITTERS.
SCHOOLS FROM NEW YORK TO
TENNESSEE TO TEXAS ALL WENT ON
ALERT AFTER FEAR IGNITED SEVERAL
FALSE ALARMS.
SOME BOMB THREATS, OTHERS AS
MINOR AS AN UMBRELLA MISTAKEN
FOR A GUN.
>> TURN AROUND.
IT'S CLOSED.
>> Reporter: AN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN RICHFIELD,
CONNECTICUT, JUST 20 MILES FROM
NEWTOWN, WENT INTO LOCKDOWN
TODAY, AFTER SOMEONE REPORTED A
SUSPICIOUS PERSON.
SECURITY ON THE MINDS OF
PRINCIPALS THROUGHOUT THE
COUNTRY TODAY.
IT WAS A PRIORITY OF SANDY
HOOK'S OWN PRINCIPAL, DAWN
HOCHSPRUNG, KILLED IN THE MASS
SHOOTING.
WE SPOKE WITH HER BEST FRIEND
AND COUSIN.
SAFETY WAS IMPORTANT TO HER.
SHE WAS HOLDING EXERCISES AND
MAKING SURE PEOPLE KNEW HOW TO
GET OUT AND TO GET OUT SAFELY.
>> SAFETY WAS HER NUMBER ONE
PRIORITY.
SHE WANTED SCHOOL TO BE A SAFE
HAVEN, A PLACE WHERE STUDENTS
COULD COME AND JUST FEEL
COMFORTABLE, LIKE IT WAS THEIR
SECOND HOME.
>> Reporter: TODAY, FROM COAST
TO COAST, PRINCIPALS WERE
RE-EVALUATING SECURITY AND
TAKING EXTRA MEASURES TO PROTECT
THEIR STUDENTS.
IN PITTSBURGH, SECURITY GUARDS
NOW HAVE GUNS.
IN THIS CALIFORNIA SCHOOL, THE
DAY STARTED WITH A MOCK LOCKDOWN
DRILL.
>> PLEASE STAY IN LOCKDOWN MODE
UNTIL YOU HEAR AN ALL CLEAR
ANNOUNCEMENT.
>> Reporter: THE OTHER CHALLENGE
FOR TEACHERS AND PRINCIPALS
TODAY, WHAT TO SAY TO THEIR
STUDENTS.
>> WE TELL THEM THAT SOMEBODY
WAS A VERY SICK PERSON, MADE
SOME VERY POOR CHOICES AND THAT
IS RARE.
THAT NORMALLY, USUALLY, SCHOOLS
ARE SAFE PLACES.
>> Reporter: AND IN GEORGIA,
PARENTS LEFT NOTHING TO CHANCE,
WALKING THEIR KIDS ALL THE WAY
INTO SCHOOL, HAND IN HAND.
AND WHILE SOME PARENTS DID KEEP
THEIR CHILDREN OUT OF SCHOOL
TODAY, EXPERTS RECOMMEND GETTING
YOUR CHILDREN BACK TO A NORMAL
ROUTINE, AS SOON AS POSSIBLE.
THAT IS MADE, THOUGH,
PARTICULARLY DIFFICULT HERE IN
CONNECTICUT, WHERE THE GOVERNOR
HAS ORDERED A MOMENT OF SILENCE
ON FRIDAY.
DIANE?
>> ALL RIGHT, AMY, THANK YOU.
>>> AND WE MOVE NEXT TO THE
INVESTIGATION THERE.
POLICE CANVASSING GUN SHOPS AND
FIRING RANGES WITHIN 15 MILES OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, SEARCHING
FOR MORE CLUES ABOUT THE GUNMAN
AND HIS MOTHER.
AND TONIGHT, SOME OF THOSE WHO
KNEW THEM ARE COMING FORWARD TO
US WITH DETAILS ABOUT A YOUNG
MAN WHO SEEMED TO BE UNRAVELING.
HERE'S ABC'S CHIEF INVESTIGATIVE
CORRESPONDENT BRIAN ROSS.
>> Reporter: INCREASINGLY, ADAM
WAS SO TROUBLED HE WOULD NOT
LEAVE THE HOUSE, AND HIS MOTHER,
NANCY, IN THE LAST FEW MONTHS,
TOLD FRIENDS SHE WAS LOSING
CONTROL OF HER 20-YEAR-OLD SON.
>> IT WAS JUST GETTING A LITTLE
HARDER FOR HER AS TIME WENT ON.
>> Reporter: NANCY LANZA WAS A
REGULAR THAT NEWTOWN BAR AND
RESTAURANT, WHERE THE OWNERS
SAY SHE TOLD THEM ABOUT HER
STRUGGLING WITH ADAM'S EMOTIONAL
AND BEHAVIORAL PROBLEMS FOR
YEARS.
>> SHE HOME SCHOOLED HIM AND
EVERYTHING.
SO, YOU KNOW, I KNEW HE WAS ON
MEDICATION, BUT THAT'S ALL I
KNOW.
>> Reporter: SINCE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AT SANDY HOOK, THROUGH
HIGH SCHOOL, ADAM WAS KNOWN BY
CLASSMATES AS STRANGE, SEVERELY
SHY.
>> HE HATED LOOKING INTO YOUR
EYES FOR MORE THAN A COUPLE
SECONDS.
HE'D ALWAYS LOOK DOWN AT HIS
PAPER, WHATEVER HE WAS DOING.
>> Reporter: A FORMER
BABY-SITTER SAYS HE WAS TOLD BY
THE MOTHER TO NEVER LEAVE ADAM
ALONE.
>> NEVER EVEN GO TO THE BATHROOM
OR TURN YOUR BACK ON HIM AT ANY
TIME.
>> Reporter: THE FORMER SCHOOL
SECURITY DIRECTOR WHO BECAME
CLOSE TO ADAM WHEN HE WAS IN THE
HIGH SCHOOL TECH CLUB, SAID ADAM
HAD SEVERAL DISORDERS, INCLUDING
THE INABILITY TO FEEL PAIN.
>> SO, IF HE HAD CUT HIMSELF OR
HURT HIMSELF, HE WOULD NOT KNOW
IT OR FEEL IT.
SO, WE WERE BEING VERY, VERY
CAREFUL WITH HIM.
>> Reporter: BUT DESPITE ADAM'S
ISSUES, FRIENDS SAY NANCY LANZA
TOOK HER SON TO LOCAL FIRING
RANGES AND INTRODUCED HIM TO THE
WORLD OF HIGH-POWERED GUNS,
INCLUDING THE BUSHMASTER
AR-15 STULT-ASSAULT-STYLE WEAPON
HE USED TO KILL HIS VICTIMS.
DEMONSTRATED HERE IN A VIDEO
POSTED ON THE COMPANY YOUTUBE
CHANNEL.
THE BUSHMASTER CAN FIRE 45
ROUNDS PER MINUTE AND IS THE
MOST POPULAR STYLE SEMIAUTOMATIC
RIFLE IN THE COUNTRY.
FEDERAL AGENTS SAY NANCY LANZA
BOUGHT HER BUSHMASTER LEGALLY IN
MARCH 2010.
A MODEL APPARENTLY TAILOR-MADE
BY THE COMPANY TO BE LEGAL, EVEN
UNDER CONNECTICUT LAW THAT
SUPPOSEDLY BANS ASSAULT WEAPONS.
>> OKAY, BRIAN ROSS REPORTING IN
ON HIS INVESTIGATION.
>>> AND TONIGHT, THE
CONVERSATION ABOUT ASSAULT
WEAPONS AND GUN VIOLENCE IS
UNDER WAY, AS YOU KNOW, BRIAN.
EVERY HOUR, THREE AMERICANS DIE
FROM A GUNSHOT WOUND.
AND CONSIDER THIS.
AMERICANS ARE 20 TIMES MORE
LIKELY TO BE KILLED BY A GUN
THAN CITIZENS LIVING IN ANY
OTHER DEVELOPED NATION IN THIS
WORLD.
LAST NIGHT, THE PRESIDENT SAID
WE CANNOT TOLERATE WHAT IS
HAPPENING, AND TODAY, A CHORUS
OF SURPRISING VOICES JOINED A
CALL FOR CHANGE.
HERE'S ABC'S JAKE TAPPER.
>> Reporter: STANDING BEFORE THE
DEVASTATED FAMILIES OF SANDY
HOOK LAST NIGHT, THE PRESIDENT
PLEDGED ACTION TO PREVENT MORE
TRAGEDIES.
TO SAVE FUTURE CHILDREN.
>> BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE DO WE
HAVE?
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
>> Reporter: FOR THE COUPLE
HUNDRED PEOPLE WHO MARCHED FROM
CAPITOL HILL TO THE LOCAL
OFFICES OF THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION TODAY.
AND FOR NEW YORK CITY MAYOR
MICHAEL BLOOMBERG, STANDING WITH
VICTIMS OF GUN VIOLENCE, THERE
IS ONE ISSUE TO CONFRONT.
ACCESS TO GUNS.
>> THIS IS JUST RIDICULOUS.
THIS IS AN OUTRAGE.
WE ARE KILLING EACH OTHER.
AND WE'RE THE ONLY
INDUSTRIALIZED COUNTRY IN THE
WORLD DOING IT.
>> Reporter: PROPOSALS BEING
PUSHED IN CONGRESS INCLUDE
REINSTATING THE BAN OF CERTAIN
TYPES OF SEMIAUTOMATIC RIFLES
WHICH EXPIRED IN 2004.
AND BANNING HIGH CAPACITY
MAGAZINES.
EVEN SOME GUN STALWARTS, SUCH AS
WEST VIRGINIA DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
JOE MANCHIN, TODAY SOUNDED A BIT
MORE COMPROMISING.
>> I DON'T KNOW OF ANYBODY IN
THE SPORTING OR HUNTING ARENA
THAT GOES OUT WITH AN ASSAULT
RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW ANYBODY THAT NEEDS
30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP TO GO
HUNTING.
>> Reporter: WHITE HOUSE
OFFICIALS SAY THE PRESIDENT DOES
NOT VIEW THIS TRAGEDY ONLY
THROUGH THE LENS OF ACCESS TO
GUNS, BUT ALSO WITH A FOCUS ON
EDUCATION, MENTAL HEALTH AND A
VIOLENT POPULAR CULTURE.
BUT WHILE THE PRESIDENT HAS
OCCASIONALLY TALKED ABOUT GUN
CONTROL --
>> THAT WEAPONS THAT WERE
DESIGNED FOR SOLDIERS, IN WAR
THEATERS, DON'T BELONG ON OUR
STREETS.
>> Reporter: ACTION IS A
DIFFERENT MATTER.
CAN YOU NAME ONE THING THE
PRESIDENT HAS DONE IN THE LAST
FOUR YEARS TO HELP REMOVE
WEAPONS OF WAR FROM OUR STREETS?
>> YOU KNOW, THERE'S NO
QUESTION, JAKE, THAT THE SCOURGE
OF GUN VIOLENCE IS A PROBLEM
THAT HAS NOT SUFFICIENTLY BEEN
ADDRESSED.
>> Reporter: IN OTHER WORDS, NO.
MANY AMERICANS TURN TO
WASHINGTON IN THEIR GRIEF FOR
ANSWERS AS TO WHAT THEY CAN DO,
WHAT SOCIETY CAN DO TO PREVENT
FUTURE SANDY HOOKS.
THEY DID NOT HEAR ANY ANSWERS
COMING FROM THE WHITE HOUSE.
DIANE?
>> ALL RIGHT, JAKE, THANKS.
>>> AND STILL AHEAD HERE ON
"WORLD NEWS," THAT QUESTION OF
MENTAL HEALTH.
WE HAVE BEEN HEARING FROM
PARENTS COMING OUT OF THE
SHADOWS AND WORRIED ABOUT THEIR
TROUBLED CHILDREN.
SAYING THEY NEED HELP.
WHAT IS THE SOLUTION FOR THEM?
WHAT CAN BE DONE?
THAT'S NEXT.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
WITH FREE Package Pickup
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service
THE HOLIDAYS ARE EASY.
VISIT USPS.com.
PAY, PRINT, AND HAVE IT PICKED
UP FOR FREE BEFORE DECEMBER 20H
FOR DELIVERY IN TIME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
YOU CAN EVEN GIVE US
SPECIAL INSTRUCTIONS
ON WHERE TO FIND IT.
FREE Package Pickup.
FROM THE U.S. Postal Service.
BECAUSE IT'S NICE TO HAVE
AN EXTRA PAIR OF HANDS AROUND
FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
A DELICIOUS NEW WAY TO GET
ESSENTIAL VITAMINS YOU NEED.
JUST BITE
INTO THE TASTY SHELL...
TO A CHEWY VITAMIN CORE
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
NEW CENTRUM FLAVOR BURST.
A BODY AT REST
TENDS TO STAY AT REST...
WHILE A BODY IN MOTION
TENDS TO STAY IN MOTION.
STAYING ACTIVE CAN ACTUALLY
EASE ARTHRITIS SYMPTOMS.
BUT IF YOU HAVE ARTHRITIS,
STAYING ACTIVE
CAN BE DIFFICULT.
PRESCRIPTION CELEBREX
CAN HELP RELIEVE ARTHRITIS PAIN
SO YOUR BODY
CAN STAY IN MOTION.
BECAUSE JUST ONE
200MG CELEBREX A DAY
CAN PROVIDE 24 HOUR RELIEF
FOR MANY WITH ARTHRITIS PAIN
AND INFLAMMATION.
PLUS, IN CLINICAL STUDIES,
CELEBREX IS PROVEN TO IMPROVE
DAILY PHYSICAL FUNCTION
SO MOVING IS EASIER.
CELEBREX CAN BE TAKEN WITH
OR WITHOUT FOOD.
AND IT'S NOT A NARCOTIC.
YOU AND YOUR DOCTOR
SHOULD BALANCE THE BENEFITS
WITH THE RISKS.
ALL PRESCRIPTION NSAIDS,
LIKE CELEBREX, IBUPROFEN,
NAPROXEN, AND MELOXICAM
HAVE THE SAME
CARDIOVASCULAR WARNING.
THEY ALL MAY INCREASE
THE CHANCE
OF HEART ATTACK OR STROKE,
WHICH CAN LEAD TO DEATH.
THIS CHANCE INCREASES
IF YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
OR RISK FACTORS
SUCH AS HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE
OR WHEN NSAIDS ARE TAKEN
FOR LONG PERIODS.
NSAIDS, INCLUDING CELEBREX,
INCREASE THE CHANCE OF SERIOUS
SKIN OR ALLERGIC REACTIONS
OR STOMACH AND INTESTINE
PROBLEMS,
SUCH AS BLEEDING AND ULCERS,
WHICH CAN OCCUR WITHOUT WARNING
AND MAY CAUSE DEATH.
PATIENTS ALSO TAKING ASPIRIN
AND THE ELDERLY
ARE AT INCREASED RISK FOR
STOMACH BLEEDING AND ULCERS.
DO NOT TAKE CELEBREX IF YOU'VE
HAD AN ASTHMA ATTACK, HIVES,
OR OTHER ALLERGIES TO ASPIRIN,
NSAIDS OR SULFONAMIDES.
GET HELP RIGHT AWAY IF YOU HAVE
SWELLING OF THE FACE OR THROAT,
OR TROUBLE BREATHING.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
YOUR MEDICAL HISTORY
AND FIND AN ARTHRITIS TREATMENT
FOR YOU.
VISIT CELEBREX.COM AND ASK
YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT CELEBREX.
FOR A BODY IN MOTION.
>>> AS WE SAID, TODAY AT ABC
NEWS, ACROSS ALL OF OUR PROGRAMS
AND OUR WEBSITE, WE HAVE BEEN
ASKING QUESTIONS ABOUT HOW WE
ALL MOVE FORWARD, AFTER THE
TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK.
THE SEARCH FOR SOLUTIONS,
TOGETHER.
INCLUDING, TONIGHT, TROUBLED
CHILDREN.
IN THE LAST FEW DAYS, PARENTS
HAVE BEEN COMING OUT OF THE
SHADOWS TO SPEAK TO US ABOUT
THEIR OWN CHILDREN.
ABC'S JOHN DONVAN HAS THEIR
STORIES.
>> Reporter: THERE ARE HOMES
THAT KNOW NOTHING OF THE REALITY
OF RAISING A TROUBLED CHILD.
AND THEN THERE ARE THOSE THAT
DO.
LIZA LONG PUT HER HOME IN THE
SECOND GROUP IN A BLOG POSTING
THIS WEEKEND CALLED "I AM ADAM
LANZA'S MOTHER" THAT ROCKETED
AROUND THE WORLD.
"I LOVE MY SON," SHE WROTE.
"BUT HE TERRIFIES ME."
>> MY BIGGEST FEAR IS THAT SOME
DAY HE'LL FLY INTO A RAGE AND
HURT ME OR HURT HIMSELF.
>> Reporter: "HE IS MENTALLY
ILL," LONG WRITES, AND HAS
THREATENED HER AT TIMES, EVEN
PULLED A KNIFE ON HER.
SHE CALLED THIS A CRY FOR HELP.
ONE THAT WAS IMMEDIATELY ECHOED
IN A REMARKABLE WAY BY OTHER
PARENTS ACROSS THE COUNTRY, BOTH
ONLINE AND TALKING WITH ABC
NEWS.
>> I'M AFRAID FOR MY DAUGHTER.
>> IT WAS MY STORY.
>> I AM FEARFUL FOR MY DAUGHTER.
I AM FEARFUL FOR WHAT WILL
HAPPEN TO HER OR WHAT WILL
HAPPEN TO ANYBODY THAT'S AROUND
HER IF SHE SNAPS IN A PUBLIC
PLACE.
>> YOU JUST DON'T KNOW.
>> WOULD THIS BE HER THAT I'M
GETTING A PHONE CALL ABOUT?
>> Reporter: IT WAS CONNECTICUT
THAT TRIGGERED THIS.
YET, THESE PARENTS' FEARS
CONFLICT WITH VIRTUALLY ALL
EXPERT OPINION ABOUT THE
MENTALLY ILL.
STATISTICALLY, THEY ARE NOT
DANGEROUS TO THE COMMUNITY AT
LARGE, NOR DO PERPETRATORS OF
LARGE-SCALE KILLINGS NECESSARILY
EXHIBIT THE KIND OF FREQUENT
EXPLOSIVE BEHAVIOR THOSE PARENTS
ARE WORRIED ABOUT.
ONE OF THE MOTHERS OF THE TWO
COLUMBINE KILLERS, FOR EXAMPLE,
TOLD AUTHOR ANDREW SOLOMON
IN HIS NEW BOOK, "FAR FROM THE
TREE" --
>> SUE KLEBOLD HAD NO SENSE THAT
DYLAN WAS CAPABLE OF DOING
ANYTHING LIKE WHAT HE DID.
SHE WAS SHOCKED WHEN IT
HAPPENED.
>> Reporter: YET, LONG DID TOUCH
ON SOMETHING.
SHE WAS, SAYS THE HEAD OF
AMERICA'S OLDEST MENTAL HEALTH
ORGANIZATIONS --
>> SPEAKING ON BEHALF OF
LITERALLY THOUSANDS OF FAMILIES.
>> Reporter: THOUSANDS?
>> THOUSANDS OF FAMILIES THAT
FIND THE SYSTEM TO BE EXTREMELY
FRAGMENTED.
>> Reporter: WHICH IS NOT
MUCH DIFFERENT FROM HOW THE
MENTALLY ILL USED TO BE
SEGREGATED IN NOW SHUT-DOWN
STATE INSTITUTIONS.
THE BETTER SOLUTIONS, LIKE CHILD
PSYCHIATRIC WARDS IN HOSPITALS.
DAY PROGRAMS WHERE KIDS CAN GET
COUNSELING IN BIG DOSES.
BUT THOSE ARE IN SHORT SUPPLY IN
MANY STATES.
WYOMING, FOR EXAMPLE, HAS SIX
CHILD PSYCHIATRISTS FOR ITS HALF
MILLION POPULATION.
TODAY, A CALL FOR ACTION, A
SUMMIT ON CHILDHOOD MENTAL
HEALTH BY THE AMERICAN ACADEMY
OF ADOLESCENT AND CHILD
PSYCHIATRY.
>> YEAH, THERE'S A LOT THAT WE
DO KNOW.
IT'S JUST THAT WE DON'T
COMPREHENSIVELY APPLY WHAT WE DO
KNOW.
>> Reporter: AND THAT'S BECAUSE
OF MONEY.
>> I BELIEVE SO, YES.
>> Reporter: MONEY THAT'S BEEN
SHRINKING WHILE BEHIND SOME OF
THOSE FRONT DOORS, THE FEARS
ONLY GET BIGGER.
JOHN DONVAN, ABC NEWS,
WASHINGTON.
>> AND IF YOU'RE CONCERNED ABOUT
A FAMILY MEMBER, WE POSTED
RESOURCES ON ABCNEWS.COM.
>>> AND TOMORROW, WE CONTINUE
THE SEARCH FOR SOLUTIONS.
WE ARE GOING TO LOOK AT THE
WEAPON THE GUNMAN USED.
ONE OF THE MOST POPULAR GUNS IN
THIS NATION.
>>> AND, WHEN WE COME BACK, TWO
OTHER STORIES IN THE NEWS
TONIGHT.
REMEMBERING THE SENATE'S LONGEST
SERVING MEMBER.
>>> AND SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON'S HEALTH.
WHAT WE LEARNED TODAY ABOUT HER
CONCUSSION AND HOW SHE'S DOING
OING HT.
GHT.
THE FINANCIAL OBSTACLES
MILITARY FAMILIES FACE,
WE UNDERSTAND.
AT USAA, WE KNOW
MILITARY LIFE IS DIFFERENT.
WE'VE BEEN THERE.
THAT'S WHY EVERY BIT
OF FINANCIAL ADVICE WE OFFER
IS GEARED SPECIFICALLY
TO CURRENT AND FORMER MILITARY
MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ laughs ]
DAD!         DAD!
[ applause ]
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
LIFE BRINGS OBSTACLES.
USAA BRINGS ADVICE.
CALL OR VISIT US ONLINE.
WE'RE READY TO HELP.
>>> AND NOW, WE HAVE SOME OTHER
TOP STORIES TONIGHT.
FIRST, THE LATE NEWS THIS
EVENING THAT SENATOR DANIEL
INOUYE FROM HAWAII HAS DIED.
HE WAS THE LONGEST SERVING
SENATOR, 50 YEARS WALKING IN
THOSE HALLS, THIRD IN LINE TO
THE PRESIDENCY.
HE HAD BEEN IN OFFICE SINCE
HAWAII BECAME A STATE IN 1959.
HE WAS HOSPITALIZED WITH
BREATHING PROBLEMS.
HIS STAFF SAID LATE TODAY THAT
HIS LAST WORD WAS "ALOHA,"
HAWAIIAN FOR "HELLO" AND "I LOVE
YOU," WHICH HE ONCE USED IN A
SPEECH.
AND, OF COURSE, ALSO FOR
"GOOD-BYE."
HE WAS 88 YEARS OLD.
>>> AND NOW, WE HAVE MORE ABOUT
SOME BIG NEWS THAT BROKE THIS
WEEKEND.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT SAYING THAT
SECRETARY OF STATE HILLARY
CLINTON FAINTED FROM DEHYDRATION
AFTER AN ILLNESS AND GOT A
CONCUSSION.
SHE HAS CANCELED ONE TRIP AND
ABC'S SENIOR FOREIGN AFFAIRS
CORRESPONDENT MARTHA RADDATZ HAS
THE LATEST ON HER CONDITION AND
JOINS US FROM WASHINGTON.
MARTHA?
>> Reporter: DIANE, THIS WAS A
PRETTY SERIOUS CONCUSSION,
ALTHOUGH SHE IS STARTING TO FEEL
BETTER.
SHE WAS HOME SICK FROM A STOMACH
VIRUS AFTER A LONG TRIP
OVERSEAS.
SHE APPARENTLY WAS SO DEHYDRATED
SHE FAINTED AND WHEN THAT
HAPPENS, YOU ON OBVIOUSLY DON'T
BRACE YOURSELF FOR THE FALL, SO,
SHE HIT HER HEAD HARD.
SHE WAS NOT TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITAL, BUT WHEN SHE EXHIBITED
MANY OF THE SIGNS OF CONCUSSION,
DIZZINESS, HEADACHE, SHE WAS
GIVEN ALL THE APPROPRIATE TESTS
TO RULE OUT ANYTHING MORE
SERIOUS.
I AM TOLD SHE WAS ON AN IV DRIP
FOR A PERIOD OF TIME AND HAD
SOMEONE LOOKING AFTER HER FOR
THOSE FIRST FEW DAYS.
I'M ALSO TOLD THE SECRETARY IS
FRUSTRATED BY THIS AND WOULD
LOVE TO GET BACK TO WORK, BUT
WHEN YOU GET A CONCUSSION, YOU
NEED TO REST YOUR BRAIN.
SHE WILL ALSO BE UNABLE TO
TESTIFY ABOUT BENGHAZI THIS
WEEK, ALTHOUGH SHE WILL LIKELY
DO THAT AT SOME POINT IN THE
FUTURE.
BUT FOR NOW, DIANE, IT IS ALL
ABOUT RESTING.
>> WELL, QUITE AN INCIDENT.
AND THIS IS A LONG TIME FOR
RECOVERY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, MARTHA.
>>> AND WHEN WE COME BACK, A
NATION'S TRUE GRIT MOMENT.
ALL THE HEROES WHO ARE SHOWING
US HOW TO FACE A NEW DAY.
TYOU WOULDN'T WANT YOUR
ADOCTOR DOING YOUR JOB,
HELLO....
SO WHY ARE YOU DOING HERS?
ONLY YOUR DOCTOR CAN DETERMINE
IF YOUR PERSISTENT HEARTBURN IS
ACTUALLY SOMETHING
MORE SERIOUS,
LIKE ACID REFLUX DISEASE.
OVER TIME, STOMACH
ACID CAN DAMAGE
THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
FOR MANY, PRESCRIPTION NEXIUM
NOT ONLY PROVIDES
24-HOUR HEARTBURN RELIEF,
BUT CAN ALSO HELP HEAL
ACID-RELATED EROSIONS
IN THE LINING OF YOUR ESOPHAGUS.
THERE IS RISK OF BONE FRACTURE
AND LOW MAGNESIUM LEVELS.
SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
HEADACHE, ABDOMINAL
PAIN AND DIARRHEA.
CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY IF
YOU HAVE PERSISTENT DIARRHEA.
OTHER SERIOUS STOMACH
CONDITIONS MAY EXIST.
DON'T TAKE NEXIUM IF
YOU TAKE CLOPIDOGREL.
LET YOUR DOCTOR DO HER JOB.
AND YOU DO YOURS.
ASK IF NEXIUM IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
IF YOU CAN'T AFFORD
YOUR MEDICATION,
ASTRAZENECA MAY BE ABLE TO HELP.
PLAYS A KEY ROLE
THROUGHOUT OUR LIVES.
One A Day Women's 50+
IS A COMPLETE MULTIVITAMIN
DESIGNED FOR WOMEN'S HEALTH
CONCERNS AS WE AGE.
IT HAS 7 ANTIOXIDANTS
TO SUPPORT CELL HEALTH.
One A Day 50+.
STARTS WITH GROUND BEEF,
UNIONS, AND PEPPERS
BAKED IN A KETCHUP GLAZE
WITH SAVORY GRAVY
AND MASHED RUSSET POTATOES.
WHAT MAKES STOUFFER'S MEATLOAF
BEST OF ALL?
THAT MOMENT YOU ENJOY IT
AT HOME.
STOUFFER'S. LET'S FIX DINNER.
A DELICIOUS NEW WAY TO GET
ESSENTIAL VITAMINS YOU NEED.
JUST BITE
INTO THE TASTY SHELL...
TO A CHEWY VITAMIN CORE
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
NEW CENTRUM FLAVOR BURST.
FOR A UNIQUE
MULTIVITAMIN SENSATION!
WE'VE DECIDED TO
WE'RE ALL HAVING SUCH A
GREAT YEAR IN THE GULF,
PUT ASIDE OUR RIVALRY.
'CAUSE ALL OUR STATES ARE GREAT.
AND NOW IS WHEN THE GULF
GETS EVEN BETTER.
THE BEACHES AND WATERS
COULDN'T BE MORE BEAUTIFUL.
TAKE A BOAT RIDE OR
JUST LAY IN THE SUN.
ENJOY THE WILDLIFE
AND NATURAL BEAUTY.
AND DON'T FORGET
OUR AMAZING SEAFOOD.
SO COME TO THE GULF,
YOU'LL HAVE A GREAT TIME.
ESPECIALLY IN ALABAMA.
YOU MEAN MISSISSIPPI.
THAT'S FLORIDA.
SAY LOUISIANA OR
THERE'S NO DESSERT.
BROUGHT TO YOU BY BP AND ALL
OF US WHO CALL THE GULF HOME.
BUT I'M STILL STUBBED UP.
[ Male Announcer ] TRUTH IS,
NYQUIL DOESN'T
UNSTUFF YOUR NOSE.
WHAT?
[ Male Announcer ]
Alka-Seltzer Plus Liquid Gels
SPEEDS RELIEF
TO YOUR WORST COLD SYMPTOMS
PLUS HAS A DECONGESTANT
FOR YOUR STUFFY NOSE.
THANKS.
THAT'S THE COLD TRUTH!
YOU SPEND ALL DAY COOKING IT.
SO WHY SPEND EVEN A MOMENT
CONSIDERING ANY BROTH
BUT SWANSON?
THE BROTH COOKS TRUST MOST
TO MAKE THE MEAL FOLKS SPEND
ALL YEAR WAITING FOR.
IN STUFFING AND MORE,
THE SECRET IS SWANSON.
>>> AND FINALLY TONIGHT, SO MANY
AMERICANS HAD HOPED TO CONSOLE
THE PEOPLE OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
BUT DISCOVERED THAT MANY OF THEM
WERE TEACHING US ABOUT STRENGTH.
A GIFT OF WISDOM, NOW, FROM
TEACHERS, GRIEVING PARENTS AND
CHILDREN, AS THE PRESIDENT SAID,
INSPIRING US TO LOOK FOR THE SUN
TO RISE EVERY DAY.
>> WE KNOW THAT THERE WERE OTHER
TEACHERS WHO KEPT STEADY THROUGH
IT ALL.
AND REASSURED THEIR STUDENTS BY
SAYING, "WAIT FOR THE GOOD GUYS.
THEY'RE COMING."
>> I JUST SAID, WE HAVE TO BE
ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
I SAID, THERE ARE BAD GUYS OUT
THERE NOW, WE NEED TO WAIT FOR
THE GOOD GUYS.
>> SHOW ME YOUR SMILE.
>> IF THEY STARTED CRYING, I
WOULD, LIKE, TAKE THEIR FACE AND
SAY, IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY, SHOW
ME YOUR SMILE.
>> THE SCHOOL'S STAFF DID NOT
FLINCH.
THEY DID NOT HESITATE.
>> SO, I SAID TO THEM, I SAID, I
NEED YOU TO KNOW THAT I LOVE YOU
ALL VERY MUCH.
AND THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY,
BECAUSE I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE
LAST THING THEY WERE EVER GOING
TO HEAR.
>> GIVING THEIR LIVES TO PROTECT
THE CHILDREN IN THEIR CARE.
>> MY COUSIN VICKI AND HER FIRST
GRADE CLASSROOM TOOK HER
STUDENTS AND HUDDLED THEM INTO A
CLOSET AND THEN SHIELDED THE
CHILDREN IN THE CLOSET.
UNFORTUNATELY, SHE LOST HER
LIFE, BUT KNOWING THE WAY SHE
LOST IT, WE'RE PROUD TO CALL HER
FAMILY AND THAT SHE WAS A HERO,
TRYING TO PROTECT THOSE
CHILDREN.
>> AS A COMMUNITY, YOU'VE
INSPIRED US, NEWTOWN.
YOU'VE LOOKED OUT FOR EACH
OTHER.
YOU'VE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED.
>> OUR HEARTS AND OUR PRAYERS GO
OUT TO THEM.
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
I CAN'T IMAGINE HOW HARD THIS
EXPERIENCE MUST BE FOR YOU.
>> MY LITTLE GIRL WAS SO FULL OF
LIFE.
AND WAS GOING TO GET COWGIRL
BOOTS FOR CHRISTMAS, ISN'T
COMING HOPE.
I FOUND A LITTLE JOURNAL, I
DON'T KNOW WHEN IT'S FROM, BUT
IT WAS EXACTLY WHAT I NEEDED,
BECAUSE IT SAYS, "I LOVE YOU SO
MUCH, MAMA, LOVE JESSICA."
WITH A LITTLE HEART.
IT'S LIKE SHE KNEW WE WERE GOING
TO NEED SOMETHING TO HELP US GET
THROUGH THIS.
THAT'S JUST LIKE, WHAT AN
AMAZING LITTLE GIRL SHE WAS.
>> AND WE DO THANK ALL OF YOU
FOR WATCHING TONIGHT.
WE'RE ALWAYS HERE AT
ABCNEWS.COM.
AND, AGAIN, "NIGHTLINE" WILL BE
HERE LATER TONIGHT, CONTINUING
THE ABC NEWS SEARCH FOR
SOLUTIONS.
AND WE'LL SEE YOU AGAIN TOMORROW
NIGHT, RIGHT BACK HERE.
YOU
>>> TONIGHT TRAGEDY ATjY;W÷ SANo
HOOK SCHOOL.
ABC 7'S LAURA ANTHONY IS IN
CONNECTICUT TO REPORT ON THE
OUTPOURING OF EMOTIONS THERE.
>> WE'RE LIVE TO SHOW HOW
LOCAL SCHOOLS ARE RESPONDING
INCLUDING SENDING OFFICERS TO
EVERY SCHOOL IN THE COUNTY
TODAY.
>> A HIGH SCHOOL FOOTBALL
PLAYER IS THE LATEST VICTIM OF
GUN VIOLENCE IN THE BAY AREA.
TONIGHT, FRIENDS REMEMBER A
NICE GUY, A PROMISING ATHLETE.
>> WET WEATHER RETURN TOGETHER
BAY AREA.
A STUDY RAIN THAT COULD BE
START OF WHAT IS STILL TO COME
THIS WEEK.
>> THEY'VE LOCKED DOORS AFTER
7:00.
IT'S HARSH.
BUT REALITY, YOU KNOW?
UNFORTUNATELY THAT IS THE
WORLD WE'RE LIVING IN.
>> IT IS THE NEW REALITY.
SCHOOLS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
TONIGHT.
STEPPED UP SECURITY ON A
MONDAY FILLED WITH ANXIETY
AFTER THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
GOOD EVENING, EVERYONE, I'M
CAROLYN JOHNSON.
>> WE BEGIN TONIGHT WITH THE
LATEST HEADLINES FROM NEWTOWN,
FUNERAL SERVICES HELD FOR TWO
VICTIMS OF THE SHOOTINGS
FRIDAY.
BOTH JUST SIX YEARS OLD.
POLICE ARE PROMISING A PAINS
TAKING INVESTIGATION INTO JUST
WHAT HAPPENED.
IT COULD TAKE MONTHS TO
COMPLETE.
AND SANDY HOOK SCHOOL MAY
NEVER REOPEN.
AND WE'VE LEARNED THE GUNMAN,
ADAM LANZA SHOT HIS MOTHER
WHILE SHE WAS IN BED.
HE SUFFERED FROM A CONDITION
IN WHICH HE FELT NO PAIN.
COVERING THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY IS
ABC 7 REPORTER LAURA ANTHONY
LIVE IN THE VILLAGE OF SANDY
HOOK.
LAURA ONE OF MANY HEART
BREAKING DAYS STILL TO COME.
>> YES.
THE HEART BREAK CONTINUES HERE
AND WHILE THE FAMILIES BEGIN
THEIR PRIVATE SERVICES, THEIR
GRIEVE PROG SES, CENTER OF
TOWN HERE HAS BECOME A PLACE
WHERE THE PUBLIC CAN COME TO
SHOW SUPPORT FOR THE
COMMUNITY.
WERK SHOW YOU WAYS THEY'RE
DOING THAT, WEATHER TOs]íI÷ COME
LIGHT A CANDLE, DROP A STUFFED
ANIMAL, TO SAY A PRAIRKS
PEOPLE FROM AROUND COUNTRY AND
THE WORLD AR