THAT IS WHERE WE'RE SEEING
BETTER ONES ON DUMBARTON BRIDGE
AND OUT TOWARD MILPITAS.
THIS IS MOVING EVER SO SLOWLY
FROM EAST TO WEST.
THEY'LL BE AROUND UNTIL 9:00
THEN ISOLATED AFTERNOON SHOWER.
TEMPERATURES IN HOVERING TO LOW
TO 50s AROUND THE COAST AND SEE
IF THE RAIN IS CAUSING PROBLEMS.
>> NOT YET.
BUT I CAN TELL YOU, I DROVE
THROUGH MARIN COUNTY,
HYDROPLANING AT TIMES AND
POOLING ALONG THE GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE.
IT'S WINDY AND VERY HAZARDOUS
DRIVING CONDITIONS.
NO MAJOR STALLS OR ACCIDENTS.
MacARTHUR MAZE, LIGHT TRAFFIC ON
TO THE BAY BRIDGE.
IT COULD BE WINDY.
ONE PROBLEM SPOTTED UP IN THE
NAPA AREA.
STONE CREST AND HAGEN, LIVE
WIRES DOWN AFTER AN EARLIER
ACCIDENT LAST NIGHT.
THAT SECTION OF THE ROAD IS
CLOSED AS OF THIS MORNING.
>> IN A FEW HOURS THE FIRST OF
THE MANY FUNERALS TO REMEMBER
TWO OF THE YOUNG VICTIMS OF THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
LIVE IN THE NEWSROOM WITH MORE
AND THE SERVICE ATTENDED BY
PRESIDENT OBAMA LAST NIGHT.
>> 6-YEAR-OLD AND JOSHUA AND
NOAH WILL BE REMEMBERED TODAY.
THEY SAY JACK WILL BE FOREVER
REMEMBERED FOR THE JOY WHO HAD
THE PLEASURE OF KNOWING HIM.
NOAH HAS A TWIN SISTER.
THEY HAVE STILL YET TO TELL HIS
SIBLINGS HOW HE PASSED.
RESIDENTS PACKED THE HIGH SCHOOL
AUDITORIUM AND HEARD PRESIDENT
BARACK OBAMA HEARD TO VOW TO
ENLIST HELP TO PREVENT SIMILAR
TRAGEDIES IN THE FUTURE.
>> AS A COMMUNITY YOU HAVE
INSPIRED US, NEW TOWN, IN THE
FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE VIOLENCE,
IN THE FACE OF UNCONSCIONABLE
EVIL, YOU HAVE LOOKED OUT FOR
EACH OTHER.
YOU HAVE CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEW I TOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED AND WITH TIME AND
GOD'S GRACE, THAT LOVE WILL SEE
YOU THROUGH.
>>> THERE ARE THAT NO CLASSES
TODAY AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
THE SCHOOL DISTRICT IS MAKING
PLANS TO SEND SURVIVING STUDENTS
TO A FORMER SCHOOL BUILDING IN A
NEIGHBORING TOWN.
AFTER JACK PINTO AND NOAH ARE
LAID TO REST THE NEXT FUNERAL IS
SET FOR TOMORROW.
>> BY ALL ACCOUNTS THE SHOOTER,
KEPT MOSTLY TO HIMSELF, NOT MANY
PEOPLE KNEW HIM WELL.
THOSE THAT DID SAW NO REASON TO
FEAR HIM BEFORE SATURDAY'S
KILLING SPREE.
A NEIGHBOR SAYS HE WAS A QUIET
KID.
RYAN SAYS HE NEVER SAW ANY
VIOLENT TENDENCIES OR RED FLAGS.
>> HE WAS REALLY QUIET.
WHEN WE WERE DOING SOMETHING,
BUILDING LEGOS HE WAS REALLY
FOCUSED ON IT.
HE WAS IN HIS OWN WORLD.
>> COMING UP ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA," THE MAN WHO MENTORED
ADAM LANZA WILL GIVE US HIS
MEMORIES AS A NATION TRIES TO
UNDERSTAND WHY HIT HAPPENED.
>> BAY AREA STUDENTS GOING BACK
TO SCHOOL FOR THE FIRST TIME
SINCE FRIDAY'S SHOOTING RAMPAGE.
ADMINISTRATORS WILL TRY TO CALM
NERVES AND REMIND STUDENTS,
PARENTS AND STAFF THE SAFETY
PLANS THEY HAVE IN PLACE.
AMY IS LIVE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
>> Reporter: IF YOU KNOW A
TEACHER, THEN YOU PROBABLY ARE
AWARE THEY SPENT A WEEKEND IN
REFLECTION.
ONE TEACHER SAID THIS IS LIKE
THE 9/11 FOR TEACHERS.
MANY TEACHERS SAY THEY SPENT THE
LAST COUPLE OF DAYS THINKING
ABOUT WHAT THEY WERE GOING TO
SAY TO THEIR STUDENTS AND HOW
THEY WERE GOING TO EASE TO THEIR
FEARS AND ABOUT FAITH AT SCHOOL.
THAT IS WHY THE UNITED EDUCATORS
SENT OUT AN E-MAIL THIS WEEKEND
WITH A GUIDE TO HELP STEER THE
CONVERSATION.
THIS IS HEAVY BURDEN FOR
TEACHERS.
>> THERE SHOULD BE A SAFE PLACE.
SCHOOLS SHOULD BE THE SAFEST
PLACE IN A CHILD'S LIFE.
IT SHOULD BE A PLACE OF REFUGE
IN TIOSH LEARNING.
>> CALIFORNIA EMERGENCY
MANAGEMENT OFFERS TIPS ON ITS
WEBSITE, YOU SHOULD KNOW YOUR
SCHOOL'S ACTION PLAN.
NO YOUR SCHOOL'S ALERT SYSTEM
FOR PARENTS AND CREATE OR REVIEW
YOUR FAMILY'S ACTION PLAN.
IF YOU YOU AREN'T FAMILIAR WITH
THESE PLANS, TODAY IS A GOOD DAY
TO START LEARNING ABOUT THEM AND
ASKING ABOUT THEM BECAUSE THEY
EXPECT A LOT OF QUESTIONS FROM
PARENTS.
>> Kristen: SINCE FRIDAY, HERE
IN THE BAY AREA, IT WAS A
WEEKEND FILLED WITH MEMORIALS TO
REMEMBER THE VICTIMS OF SANDY
HOOK.
IN SAN FRANCISCO, ST. MARY'S
CATHEDRAL DEDICATED REGULAR
SUNDAY MASS TO FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT.
IN OTHER CITIES, NUMEROUS VIGILS
AND MEMORIALS TO THE VICTIMS AS
PEOPLE COME TO TERMS WITH THE
TRAGEDY.
TONIGHT AT 7:00 THERE WILL BE A
SERVICE OF O THE PENINSULA.
IT WILL TAKE AT FIRST
PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH IN
BURLINGAME.
>> TWO KEY SENATORS ARE CALLING
FOR MORE RESTRICTIONS ON ASSAULT
RIFLES.
JOE LIEBERMAN WANTS A COMMISSION
TO REVIEW NATIONAL GUN LAWS AND
NATIONAL HEALTH SYSTEM.
HE WANTS TO CLOSE LOOPHOLES THAT
ALLOWS GUN BUYERS TO AVOID
BACKGROUND CHECKS.
CALIFORNIA SENATOR DIANNE
FEINSTEIN WANTS A VOTE ON A
ASSAULT WEAPONS BAN ON THE FIRST
DAY THE CONGRESS IS IN SESSION.
>> IT WILL BAN THE SALE,
TRANSPORTATION AND POSSESSION
BUT PROSPECTIVELY AND IT WILL
BAN THE SAME FOR BIG CLIP DRUMS
OR STRIPS OF MORE THAN TEN
BULLETS.
>> GUN RIGHTS GROUPS REMAINED
SILENCE SINCE THE SHOOTING
SPREE.
RIFLE NATIONAL ASSOCIATION
REMOVED A TWEET THAT CELEBRATED
1.7 MILLION LIKES ON FACEBOOK.
YOU CAN EXPRESS YOUR SYMPATHY
FOR THE SANDY HOOK SCHOOL
TRAGEDY BY POSTING THIS BADGE TO
THE FACEBOOK WALL.
YOU CAN USE IT AS SHOW SUPPORT
FOR EVERYONE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
WE'LL CONTINUE TO COVER THE
STORY AND FIND THE LATEST
DEVELOPMENTS ON OUR WEBSITE AND
FACEBOOK PAGE AND TWITTER FEEDS.
>> Kristen: DEVELOPING NEWS FROM
SAN FRANCISCO WHERE FIREFIGHTERS
RESCUED A MAN WHO WAS STUCK IN A
CHIMNEY OVERNIGHT.
IT HAPPENED AROUND MIDNIGHT AT
AN APARTMENT BUILDING NEAR CLAY
STREET IN LAUREL HEIGHTS
NEIGHBORHOOD.
IT CAUSED QUITE A COMMOTION FOR
PEOPLE THAT LIVE THERE.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHY THE MAN WAS
IN THE CHIMNEY BUT THEY SAY SHE
WAS NOT TRESPASSING.
FIRE CREWS HAD TO LOSEEN SEVERAL
BRICKS TO GET HIM OUT.
>> Eric: THERE IS LIGHT RAIN IN
SPOTS OUT THERE.
>> WE'LL GET A LITTLE BIT OF
SUNSHINE BUT THE RAIN IS COMING
IN.
RAIN UP IN THE VALLEYS IN THE
NORTH BAY AND INTO THE EAST BAY
THE RADAR OVERSHOOTING THAT
OVERLEVEL RAIN RIGHT NOW.
YOU CAN SEE WHEN YOU LOOK AT THE
VISIBILITY, FOUR MILES OF SANTA
ROSA.
GOT TO BE RAIN AND FOG HANGING
AROUND.
SFO AT 3 AND HALF MOON BAY AT
ONE-QUARTER SO WORST IS OUT
AROUND THE COAST.
LET'S BREAK DOWN WHAT IS GOING
TO HAPPEN TODAY.
GUSTY WINDS THROUGH THE MORNING
HOURS, GUSTS UP TO 30 AROUND
HALF MOON BAY.
SANTA ROSA TO 17 IN FAIRFIELD.
13 IN MOUNTAIN VIEW.
13 IN OAKLAND.
IT IS A LITTLE BREEZY OUTSIDE
THIS MORNING.
LIGHT RAIN AND TEMPERATURES LOW
TO MID-50s.
STEADIER RAIN WILL TAPER TO 9:00
TO A FEW SHOWERS AROUND NOON
THEN ISOLATED SHOWERS AFTER
4:00.
THEN THE CLOUDS CLEAR OUT AND
TEMPERATURES DROPPING TO THE MID
AND UPPER 50s BY 7:00.
FOR TUESDAY, WEDNESDAY AND
THURSDAY, MAINLY DRY TOMORROW.
BEST CHANCE OF SHOWERS OVER THE
OCEAN, COLD MORNING ON WEDNESDAY
AND THEN THE BILLING STORM COMES
IN FOR THURSDAY.
>>> IF YOU ARE HEADED TO THE
SIERRA THIS MORNING, CHAINS ARE
REQUIRED ON 50, 80 AND 88.
SO BRING THOSE AND MAKE SURE YOU
ARE HANDY.
BAY BRIDGE TOLL PLAZA, BREEZY
CONDITIONS, LIGHT TRAFFIC BUT IT
IS VERY WET OUT.
NO DELAYS ON THE UPPER DECK.
FIRST LOOK AT SAN MATEO BRIDGE,
LIGHT TRAFFIC HEADED IN THE
WESTBOUND DIRECTION HEADED
TOWARD FOSTER CITY.
NO DELAYS HERE BUT WINDY
CONDITIONS ON ALL THE SPANS THIS
MORNING.
A LOOK AT DRIVE TIMES, SOME OF
THE BUSIER COMMUTE STILL PRETTY
GOOD OVER THE ALTAMONT PASS
THROUGH LIVERMORE.
ANTIOCH, HIGHWAY 4 AT THE LIMIT
AND 80 INTO THE MacARTHUR MAZE
JUST UNDER 20 MINUTES.
>>> IT'S 4:40.
>> A QUIET DRIVE TURNS NEARLY
INTO A DEADLY ACCIDENT.
THE FRIGHTENING SCENE BEFORE
FIREFIGHTERS GOT OUT THERE.
>> THE STEPPING OUT.
PREGNANT DUCHESS OF CAMBRIDGE
MAKES HER FIRST PUBLIC
APPEARANCE
>> Kristen: IT'S 4:43.
LIVE LOOK AT THE EMBARCADERO.
YOU CAN SEE THE ROADS ARE WET.
GIVE THE KIDS A BIG HUG BEFORE
THEY GO TO SCHOOL AND MAYBE A
RAIN JACKET.
MIKE NICCO WILL TALK ABOUT HOW
LONG THE RAIN WILL STAY WITH US
IN JUST A MOMENT.
>> MORE NEWS FOR YOU.
ACTIVIST GROUP ANONYMOUS IS
RENEWING A ITS ATTACK ON BAPTIST
CHURCH AFTER THE ORGANIZATION
PRAISED THE ACTIONS OF THE
SHOOTER IN THE CONNECTICUT
SHOOTING MASSACRE.
KANSAS BASED CHURCH WILL PICKET
SAYING GOD'S WILL IS PUNISHING
PEOPLE BECAUSE OF GAY MARRIAGE.
>>> HERE IN THE BAY AREA PEOPLE
LOOKING FOR WAYS TO REACH OUT TO
THE GRIEVING FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT.
SINCE THE SHOOTING THERE HAVE
BEEN GRASSROOTS AND CHURCH
ORGANIZED VIGILS TO HELP START
THE HEALING.
TOMAS RAMON ASKED LOCAL CLERGY
WHAT THEY ARE TELLING THEIR
PARISHIONERS.
>> AT MORNING MASS IN SAN
FRANCISCO, THIS SPECIAL PRAYER
WAS WRITTEN FOR THE VICTIMS OF
NEWTOWN.
THE PASTOR OF ST. MARY'S SAYS
PEOPLE HAVE COME THERE NOT JUST
TO PRAY BUT MAKE SOME SENSE IN
THE EVIL THAT OCCURRED.
>> IN SEEKING TO FIND
CONSOLATION IN THE PROMISE AND
HOPE OF A GOD WHO FEELS WITH US
AND LONGS TO HELP US.
>> AT GLAD MEMORIAL CHURCH, IT
HELPED THE CONGREGATION
CELEBRATE LIFE WHILE RECOVERING
FROM THE SORROW OF THE TRAGEDY.
REVEREND SAYS THE RESPONSE HAS
BEEN INCREDIBLE.
>> I'VE NEVER SEEN LIKE IT
TOUCHED LIKE THIS IN MORE THAN
50 YEARS.
I'VE NEVER SEEN IT TOUCHED
COMMUNITIES AND INDIVIDUALS LIKE
THIS IS DOING.
>> Eric: THIS MORNING, ALAMEDA
COUNTY SHERIFF'S DEPUTIES ARE
LOOKING AT A FATAL COLLISION
BETWEEN A PEDESTRIAN AND TRAIN
NEAR HAYWARD.
IT HAPPENED ABOUT 7:00 LAST
NIGHT JUST OUTSIDE THE HAYWARD
CITY LIMITS.
TRACKS WERE SHUT DOWN WHILE
AUTHORITIES VERY INVESTIGATED
THE NAME OF THE VICTIM HAS NOT
BEEN RELEASED.
>> THE HIGHWAY PATROL IS
INVESTIGATING A FIERY ACCIDENT
IN ORINDA.
A CAR FLIPPED OVER AFTER THE
DRIVER LOST CONTROL OF THE
VEHICLE AS HE WAS EXITING ON
FISH RANCH ROAD YESTERDAY
AFTERNOON.
THE VEHICLE CAUGHT FIRE.
ALAN WANG WAS THERE BEFORE THE
FIRE DEPARTMENT GOT TO THE
SCENE.
THEY MANAGED TO GET OUT OF THE
VEHICLE SAFELY.
>> AUTHORITIES IN CONTRA COSTA
ARE INVESTIGATING A REPORT OF A
RAPE ON A POPULAR HIKING TRAIL.
WOMAN SAYS SHE WAS ATTACKED ON
MA DRONE TRAIL IN REGIONAL
WILDERNESS IN ALAMO.
MAN WAS IN HIS EARLY 40s AND
WALKING A HEAVY SET DOG.
ACCORDING TO THE PARK SERVICE IT
HAPPENED WEDNESDAY AROUND 3:30.
THEY SAY THE ATTACKER GRABBED
THE HIKER BY THE HAIR AND PULLED
HER TO THE GROUND BEFORE RAPING
HER.
THE MAN RAN OFF.
>> Eric: IT HAPPENS EVERY
CHRISTMAS SEASON AT SOMEBODY'S
HOUSE.
TODAY THE SAN FRANCISCO FIRE
DEPARTMENT AND OTHER AGENCIES
WILL DRAMATICALLY ILLUSTRATE
WHAT CAN HAPPEN IN YOUR LIVING
ROOM.
THEY INTENTIONALLY SET A DRIED
OUT CHRISTMAS TREE ON FIRE
SHOWING YOU IT ONLY TAKES
SECONDS TO TURN YOUR HOME INTO A
DEATH TRAP.
DON'T LEAVE A LIVE TREE UP FOR
TWO WEEKS.
KEEP IT MOIST AND DON'T PUT YOUR
WAUT TREE NEAR SOURCES OF HEAT.
>> Eric: I THINK A LOT OF PEOPLE
VIOLATE TWO WEEK RULE.
THEY HAVE TO MAKE SURE PLENTY OF
WATER, RIGHT.
PLENTY OF WATER COMING OUT OF
THE SKY THIS MORNING.
>> THERE IS THE PICTURE,
ESPECIALLY A LITTLE WET AROUND
THE EMBARCADERO AND STANDING
WATER IN THE GROOVES AS YOU LOOK
OVER TO THE SOUTHEAST AND SEEING
THE PORT OF OAKLAND BUT YOU
CAN'T BECAUSE OF THE LIGHT RAIN.
BEST RADAR RETURNS ARE STILL
AROUND FROM THE EAST BAY
DUMBARTON BRIDGE DOWN TO THE
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS.
BUT WE STILL HAVE LIGHT RAIN
EVERYWHERE WHEN YOU GET THESE
STRATO FORM RAINS AND THEY TEND
TO BE LOW TO THE GROUND.
84 GOING FROM ABOUT UNION CITY
ALL THE WAY BACK TO CLOSE TO THE
SUNOL GRADE.
THAT IS WHERE WE'RE SEEING WET
WEATHER.
HEADING DOWN AND JUST TO THE
SOUTH OF DUMBARTON, HEADING TO
237 BACK TO MILPITAS, GETTING
BETTER CHANCES OF RAIN THERE.
ALSO AROUND PAGE MILL ROAD.
AS WE LOOK AT THE BIG PICTURE
AND PUT IT INTO MOTION, MORE
RADAR RETURNS UP TO THE NORTH.
THAT IS THE COLD FRONT.
SO STEADY RAIN THIS MORNING.
COLD FRONT MOVES THROUGH THIS
AFTERNOON WITH A STRAY SHOWER.
TEMPERATURES VERY MILD OUT AHEAD
OF THE COLD FRONT.
WE'RE IN THE WARM CORRIDOR AND
THAT IS WHY WE'RE GETTING LIGHT
DURATION RAIN.
LOW TO MID-50s AND MONTEREY BAY
AROUND 57.
RAIN IN THE MORNING AND FEW
SCATTERED SHOWERS IN THE
AFTERNOON HOURS.
THIS IS GOING TO USHER IN SOME
COLD AIR ONCE AGAIN.
IT WILL BE FROSTY TONIGHT BUT
MORE SO WEDNESDAY MORNING.
THEN WE'LL HAVE THAT HEAVY RAIN
WEDNESDAY NIGHT INTO THURSDAY
WITH SOME GUSTY WINDS.
HERE IS OUR SYSTEM.
WE'RE OUT IN THE WARM SECTOR FOR
THAT IS WHY WE'RE GETTING THE
RAIN AND COLD FRONT WILL COME
THROUGH AND HAVE SHOWERS.
YOU CAN SEE THE COLDER AIR
BEHIND IT WITH THE NATURE OF
THOSE CLOUDS.
THE RAIN IS MOVING THROUGH AT A
PRETTY GOOD CLIP.
HEADING TOWARDS NOON, MORE
SCATTERED SHOWERS AND BY 5:00,
IT'S JUST ABOUT OVER.
OVERNIGHT THE CLOUDS CLEAR AND
TEMPERATURES WILL BE COOL.
A LOT OF 30s AND 40s AROUND THE
BAY.
AS WE HEAD TOWARDS TOMORROW,
BEST CHANCE OF SHOWERS OVER THE
OCEAN AND THE REST OF US IS
SUNNY.
TOMORROW NIGHT, WE'LL SEE FROST
IN INLAND VALLEYS.
WEDNESDAY EVENING, SOME RAIN
STARTS TO MOVE INTO NORTH BAY.
NOTICED IT'S GOING TO STAY UP
THERE THURSDAY NIGHT.
THURSDAY AFTERNOON WE'LL HAVE
OUR BEST CHANCE OF HEAVIER RAIN.
TEMPERATURES ABOUT WHERE THEY
ARE RIGHT NOW FOR AFTERNOON
HIGHS.
WE'LL HANG OUT IN THE 50s FOR
THE REST OF THE FORECAST.
BEST CHANCE FOR OUTDOOR
ACTIVITIES TUESDAY AND
WEDNESDAY.
>>> LOOK AT SAN RAFAEL,
SOUTHBOUND OUT OF NOVATO PAST
LUCAS VALLEY ROAD WHERE WE HAVE
STANDING WATER AND LIGHT TRAFFIC
AT THIS HOUR.
NO DELAYS THERE, SAN JOSE, THIS
IS 87 IN THE NORTHBOUND
DIRECTION.
YOU CAN SEE IT'S VERY LIGHT
TRAFFIC AT THE JULIAN OFF-RAMP.
THIS IS AN AREA THAT DOES GET
FLOODING WHEN THERE IS HEAVY
RAIN.
WE'LL KEEP AN EYE ON THE REST OF
THE MORNING COMMUTE.
BIG RIG OFF TO THE SHOULDER.
THAT IS BIG RIG IS ON FIRE SO
THEY ARE GETTING AN EXTINGUISHER
AND TOW TRUCK IS ON THE SCENE.
MAY BE SLOW DOWN WESTBOUND 580.
AND SILVERADO TRAIL, DOWNED
POWER LINES.
>> DUCHESS OF CAMBRIDGE MADE HER
FIRST PUBLIC APPEARANCE.
SHE WAS A PRESENTER AT SPORTS
AWARD SHOW IN LONDON.
DUCHESS SEEMED COMPOSED AND
COMFORTABLE.
THE ARE EXPECTING THEIR FIRST
CHILD.
SHE WAS HOSPITALIZED FOR MORNING
SICKNESS A FEW WEEKS AGO.
>>> A FUNERAL IS BEING ELD FOR
KATE'S NURSE THAT WAS INVOLVED
WITH THE PHONE CALL.
SHE WAS FOUND DEAD IN A LONDON
HOSPITAL DAYS AFTER THE HOAX WAS
MADE PUBLIC.
FAMILY AND FRIENDS WILL GATHER
AT A CHURCH IN SOUTH INDIA
BEFORE BURYING HER THERE.
THE DJ'S AND RADIO STATION HAVE
PUBLICLY APOLOGIZED.
>> COMING UP, KEEPING AN EYE ON
THE EYE IN THE SKY.
WHY BERKELEY WANTS TO KEEP
SURVEILLANCE DRONES OUT OF THEIR
AIRSPACE.
>> AND SWEET DIFFERENCE YOU CAN
NOW ENJOY.
>> AND WE'RE TRACKING THE RAIN
WITH LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD.
MIKE NICCO IS
[ Female Announcer ] NOW GET
HIGH SPEED INTERNET AT HOME
ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOU CAN COUNT ON.
INTRODUCING AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
WITH MORE SPEED OPTIONS,
RELIABILITY
AND Wi-Fi HOT SPOTS THAN EVER.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW TO GET
U-verse HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
IT'S ALL THE SPEED YOU NEED
ALL AT A GREAT PRICE.
OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network
GIVES YOU MORE
OF WHAT YOU ENJOY ONLINE.
AND WITH AT&T,
OUR WIRELESS GATEWAY
TURNS YOUR HOME
INTO A PRIVATE Wi-Fi HOT SPOT
THAT CONNECTS
YOUR Wi-Fi DEVICES
AND CAN EVEN SAVE ON YOUR
SMART PHONE DATA USAGE AT HOME.
GO TO OUR WEBSITE BELOW
TO GET AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET
FOR JUST 14.95 A MONTH
FOR 12 MONTHS WITH
A ONE-YEAR PRICE GUARANTEE.
THAT INCLUDES ACCESS ON-THE-GO
TO OUR ENTIRE NATIONAL
Wi-Fi HOT SPOT NETWORK,
WITH OVER 30,000 HOT SPOTS.
AT&T U-verse
HIGH SPEED INTERNET.
NOW ON OUR NEWLY EXPANDED
Advanced Digital Network,
A CONNECTION YOUR WHOLE HOUSE
CAN COUNT ON.
♪
>>> WE HAVE LIGHT RAIN IN THE
CENTRAL VALLEY AND UP NORTH,
HEAVY SNOW THROUGH THE MORNING
HOURS AND UP NORTH IN THE HIGHER
ELEVATIONS, WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
TEMPERATURES AROUND 39 IN TAHOE.
50s THROUGH CENTRAL VALLEY.
HEADING DOWN SOUTH, THAT IS
WHERE WE DON'T HAVE ANY RAIN,
CLOUDS AND SUNSHINE AND MID TO
UPPER 50s FOR LOS ANGELES AND
SAN DIEGO.
>> GOOD MORNING.
WE'VE GOT LIGHT CONDITIONS OUT
THERE AT THE BAY BRIDGE TOLL
PLAZA BUT WET AND WINDY.
NO METERING LIGHTS AND NO DELAYS
BUT EXTRA CAUTION.
EXTRA TIME WILL BE KEY THIS
MORNING.
PROBLEM IN THE DUBLIN AREA, WEST
580 AT SAN RAMON ROAD, BIG RIG
THAT CAUGHT FIRE.
IT'S ON A SHOULDER WAITING FOR
THE TOW TRUCK TO GET THE BIG RIG
OUT OF THERE.
SANTA ROSA, SOUTH 101 AND 880
TOWARD 101.
>>> RICHMOND CITY OFFICIALS MEET
TOMORROW TO CONSIDER PERMITS FOR
RECONSTRUCTION OF THE DAMAGED
PORTION OF THE CHEVRON REFINERY.
A PIPELINE RUPTURED IN AUGUST
CAUSING AN EXPLOSION AND FIRE.
THIS MORNING THE SAN FRANCISCO
CHRONICLE CHEVRON WILL HAVE TO
LAY OFF 500 WORKERS IF IT
DOESN'T GET THE PERMITS BY
THURSDAY.
THEY WANT TO REPLACE THE PIPE
WITH A METAL ALLOY THAT WILL
RESIST CORROSION.
CORROSION IS CONSIDERED THE
LIKELY CAUSE OF THE EXPLOSION.
>> MORE THAN 90 MILLION
AMERICANS WILL TRAVEL MORE THAN
50 MILES THIS MILLED SEASON AND
90% OF THEM WILL DO IT ON THE
ROAD.
THERE IS SOME GOOD NEWS.
GAS PRICES CONTINUED TO FALL.
IN CALIFORNIA, IT'S 3.52 A
GALLON.
BAY AREA IS AVERAGING 3.71.
MOST EXPENSIVE IS SAN FRANCISCO
AT 3.83.
VALLEJO AS CHEAPEST PRICES AT
3.49 A GALLON.
>> IN BERKELEY, SIT LEADERS WILL
CONSIDER A PROPOSAL TO DECLARE
IT A NO DRONE ZONE.
THEY FEAR AUTHORITIES WILL USE
THE TECHNOLOGY TO SPY ON
CITIZENS.
THIS PROPOSAL COMES A WEEK AFTER
ALAMEDA COUNTY SUPERVISORS
TABLED A PLAN BY THE SHERIFF'S
OFFICE TO SPEND $31,000 ON A
SURVEILLANCE DRONE.
SUPERVISORS AND SHERIFF CAME
UNDER CRITICISM.
>>> EARLIER THIS MONTH, A NEW
FORMULA HITS STORE SHELVES IN A
FIRST FOO TEST MARKETS INCLUDING
THE BAY AREA.
THIS NEW DIET PEPSI FORMULA
CONTAINS A NEW SWEETENER.
THE CHANGE IS DESIGNED TO HELP
THE DIET FROM DEGRADING.
IT COMES AS PEPSI TRYING TO
REINVIGORATE ITS BRAND.
PEPSI WILL START A NEW BRANDING
CAMPAIGN NEXT MONTH.
>>> 4:57.
IT'S GETTING OFF TO A WET START.
TAKE A LOOK OUTSIDE TOWARDS THE
EMBARCADERO.
YOU SEE THE WET STREAKS THERE.
MIKE NICCO IS TRACKING THE WET
WEATHER WITH LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD
AND SUE HALL IS WATCHING FOR
PROBLEMS ON THE COMMUTE.
>> THIS MORNING, FAMILIES BEGIN
THE HEARTBREAKING TASK OF LAYING
TO REST THE YOUNG VICTIMS OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
NEXT AT 5:00, THE WORDS OF COME
FORFEITURE PRESIDENT OBAMA IS
OFFERING THEM.
>>> IT'S MONDAY MORNING AT 5:00.
THANKS FOR JOINING US, I'M
KRISTEN SZE.
>> Eric: I'M ERIC THOMAS.
LIGHT RAIN FOR THE MOST PART BUT
LET'S FIND OUT WHERE IT IS RIGHT
NOW WITH MIKE NICCO.
>> GOOD QUESTION, IT'S JUST
ABOUT EVERYWHERE.
ALL REPORTING STATIONS, LIGHT
RAIN AND DRIZZLE.
YOU CAN SEE THE RADAR RETURNS
AREN'T QUITE AS INDICATIVE AS
HOW WIDESPREAD THE RAIN IS THIS
MORNING.
GREE