IT'S WORTH $1,000,
AND IT'S "FOOD & DRINK."
PPY TOVANNA,
WHENEVER YOU'RE SET.
LET'S GET THINGS GOING.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
HANNAH.
PEPPERMINT STICK.
NO. ANYBODY ELSE?
[ BELL CHIMES ]
FEDRECIA.
PEPPERMINT STICKS.
YEAH, WE NEEDED
ANOTHER STICK THERE, HANNAH.
I'M SORRY.
YOU HAD THE RIGHT IDEA.
DON'T WORRY
ABOUT IT.
BUT FEDRECIA CRUMP
GETS THE MONEY -- $1,000.
CONGRATULATIONS.
YES.
FROM RURAL HALL, NORTH CAROLINA,
IT SAYS HERE.
THAT'S CORRECT, PAT.
NOW, YOU'RE RETIRED
FROM WHAT?
I'M RETIRED FROM
AN EXECUTIVE-ASSISTANT POSITION
FOR OVER 30 YEARS WITH
A MAJOR MANUFACTURING COMPANY.
WELL, YOU'RE TOO YOUNG
TO RETIRE FROM ANYTHING, BUT --
I'M RETIRED, PAT.
WELL, THAT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M SURE YOU'RE ENJOYING IT.
'CAUSE YOU HAVE
LOTS OF FAMILY, RIGHT?
I DO.
I HAVE -- MY HUSBAND
AND I TOGETHER HAVE
SIX CHILDREN,
SIX GRANDCHILDREN,
AND THREE
GREAT-GREAT GRANDCHILDREN.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, YOU'RE OFF
TO A GOOD START WITH $1,000.
KEEP IT GOING.
THANK YOU.
HI, HANNAH. HOW ARE YOU?
HELLO. GOOD.
YOU WERE
ONE S AWAY THERE.
I KNOW.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THAT.
HANNA MYRES IS
FROM AUSTIN, TEXAS.
YES, SIR.
YOU MANAGE
A RETAIL STORE.
I DO. I MANAGE
A KITCHEN-AND-APPLIANCE STORE.
OKAY.
AND YOU'RE MARRIED?
I AM TO MY FANTASTIC HUSBAND,
MATTHEW.
MM-HMM.
AND THE DALLAS MAVERICKS?
I'M A HUGE
DALLAS MAVERICKS FAN.
SO MUCH SO
THAT MY DOG'S NAME IS MAVERICK.
OH, REALLY?
YES! [ LAUGHS ]
I THOUGHT IT WOULD HAVE
BEEN MARK, MAYBE.
NICE HAVING YOU, HANNAH.
THANK YOU.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU.
AND TO YOU, CONOR.
CONOR McHUGH IS
FROM RIGHT HERE IN LOS ANGELES.
IS THAT ORIGINALLY?
NO, I'M ORIGINALLY FROM
WINSTON-SALEM, NORTH CAROLINA.
AND YOU'RE
A COMPOSER/BARTENDER,
AND I'M GUESSING
ONE IS SUPPORTING THE OTHER.
IS THAT SORT OF
HOW THAT WORKS?
YES, I'D LIKE
TO DO FILM MUSIC,
BUT I'M DOING
SOME TELEVISION RIGHT NOW,
AND I'M DOING
A LITTLE BARTENDING ON THE SIDE.
WELL, GOOD FOR YOU,
AND I HOPE YOU WIN
A LITTLE MONEY TONIGHT
P THINGS OUT,
AND LET'S GET STARTED HERE
WITH OUR $2,000 PUZZLE
AND ALSO DETERMINE
WHO WILL START THE FIRST ROUND.
THE CATEGORY FOR THIS ONE
IS "PHRASE."
[ BELL CHIMES ]
FEDRECIA.
DOUBLE OR NOTHING.
THAT'S IT.
GOT THEM BOTH.
[ APPLAUSE ]
WELL, WE'LL SEE
HOW YOU SPIN THE WHEEL SOON.
RIGHT NOW, HERE'S JIM.
OKAY, PAT.
TONIGHT'S JACKPOT ROUND
IS BROUGHT TO YOU
BY SIMPLE GREEN
ALL-PURPOSE CLEANER.
MY NAME IS BRUCE FaBRIZIO.
IN 1975, I INVENTED SIMPLE GREEN
BASED ON PRINCIPLES.
IT HAD TO BE SAFER TO USE,
IT HAD TO WORK,
AND IT HAD TO BE
COMPLETELY MADE IN AMERICA.
AND HERE'S
TONIGHT'S FEATURED P THREE
OVERLOOKING
HISTORIC CHARLESTON'S
PRESTIGIOUS
SOUTH BATTERY WATERFRONT,
TWO MEETING STREET INN
INVITES YOU
TO EXPERIENCE
THE ROMANCE AND ALLURE
OF THE CITY'S MOST CELEBRATED
BOUTIQUE BED AND BREAKFAST.
AIRFARE PROVIDED
BY BedandBreakfast.com.
ESERVE YOUR NEXT GETAWAY
AT OVER 14,000
BED AND BREAKFASTS WORLDWIDE,
VISIT THE MOST COMPREHENSIVE
GLOBAL SITE
FOR FINDING
BED-AND-BREAKFAST PROPERTIES
AT BedandBreakfast.com.
AH. AHA.
[ APPLAUSE ]
ALL RIGHT, EVERYBODY.
"SONG LYRICS" IS
THE CATEGORY FOR THIS PUZZLE,
AND YOU'RE GONNA START
BECAUSE YOU GOT THAT TOSS UP,
FEDRECIA.
GO AHEAD.
SPIN!
WHOO!
YEAH.
OH.
GONNA TAKE
A LITTLE BREAK NOW.
HANNAH,
IT'S YOUR TURN.
COME ON, HANNAH.
COME ON, HANNAH!
T!
SOME T's FOR YOU.WE HAVE
SOME T's FOR YOU.
THERE ARE FOUR OF THEM,
ACTUALLY.
THAT'S $2,600.
[ HORN HONKS ]
WHOO!
AN H.
YOU GOT IT -- TWO H's.
PICK UP THAT HALF CAR.
IT'S A FORD FIESTA THIS WEEK.
I'D LIKE TO BUY A VOWEL,
PLEASE.
MM-HMM.
AN E.
YEP, FIVE E's.
Fedrecia:
GO, HANNAH!
OKAY.
R!
THERE ARE TWO R's.
YEAH.
THERE'S A BIG JACKPOT
OUT THERE,
BUT PROBABLY A LITTLE EARLY
TO TRY TO SOLVE IT.
S!
ONE S.
OVER $5,000.
I'D LIKE TO BUY ANOTHER VOWEL,
PLEASE -- AN I.
THERE'S AN I.
A Y.
AND YOU GET ONE Y.
I'D LIKE TO BUY A VOWEL --
AN A.
ONE A.
I'D LIKE TO BUY
ANOTHER VOWEL -- AN O.
AND HERE COME
THREE O's.
CAN SHE GET THAT JACKPOT?
OH, THAT WAS CLOSE.
AN M!
YES, TWO M's.
WELL,
YOU GOT ANOTHER $1,800.
YOU'RE UP TO $6,750,
AND YOU HAVE THAT HALF CAR.
I'D LIKE TO SOLVE, PLEASE.
SURE.
THE MOST WONDERFUL TIME
OF THE YEAR.
IYEAH.KE TO SOLVE, PLEASE.
WHOO!
SURE.
HI! CONGRATULATIONS.
NICE JOB.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
WELL, THAT WOULD HAVE
BEEN NICE,
BUT YOU DID VERY WELL,
ANYWAY. GOT HALF A CAR.
YOU GOT A COUPLE MORE ROUNDS
TO TRY TO GET THE OTHER HALF.
YOU HAVE $6,750.
GOOD FOR YOU.
THAT'S WHY SHE'S SMILING.
HERE. HANG ON TO YOUR CAR.
YOU.
HANG ON TO THIS THOUGHT.
WE'LL BE BACK.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
FROM THE "WHEEL OF FORTUNE"
PRODUCTION STAFF...
All: HAPPY HOLIDAYS!
IS BROUGHT TO YOU
BY THE FOLLOWING...
Woman: CH-CH-CH-CHIA!
Announcer: CHIA PETS,
THE POTTERY THAT GROWS!
Announcer: CHIA SPONGEBOB.
AND EVERYONE'S FAVORITE GAL --
CHIA HELLO KITTY.
SPREAD THE SEEDS, WATER,
AND WATCH IT GROW.
Woman: CH-CH-CH-CHIA!
Announcer: THERE'S EVEN
CHIA ALEX AND CHIA MARTY.
SO MANY CHIA PETS,
YOU CAN COLLECT THEM ALL!
AND TONIGHT'S MYSTERY ROUND
MAKES YOUR SEASON BRIGHT
WITH CASH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪ LA-DA-DA
"BEFORE & AFTER" --
THAT'S THE CATEGORY.
AND, HANNAH,
YOUR TURN TO START NOW.
Hannah: ALL RIGHTY.
SHE HAS HALF A CAR.
THERE ARE TWO OTHER HALVES
OUT ON THE WHEEL.
T!
TWO T's.
WHEW! H!
AND NO H.
ALL RIGHT, CONOR.
WELL, YOU'RE
ON A "FREE PLAY."
E!
U CAN GET THOSE E's
WITHOUT ANY MONEY.
THAT'S THE WAY
THE "FREE PLAY" WORKS.
WELL, YOU'RE
ON A "FREE PLAY"!
I!
AND YOU CAN GET
AN I WITHOUT ANY MONEY, YEAH.
WHY DON'T YOU SAVE TIME
AND SAY "FREE PLAY,"HEN...
[ LAUGHTER ]
A.
THERE YOU GO --
TWO A's.
THE BAD NEWS IS,
YOU HAVE NO MONEY.
I' AND TT SPIN AGAIN.
THERE YOU GO.
R.
WELL, THIS IS INTERESTING.
THERE ARE FIVE R's.
THAT IS $5,000,
PLUS YOU'RE GONNA GET
A LOT MORE INFORMATION UP THERE.
I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU WANT TO RISK THAT.
IT'S UP TO YOU.
I THINK I'M GOING TO.
YOU'RE GOING TO?
YEP.
WHOA! ALL RIGHT!
Fedrecia: WHOO!
WHOA, LOOK AT HIM!
RIGHT DOWN THERE.
MAN!
OH, MAN.
WELL, WE'LL LEAVE
THE 10 GRAND THERE, ANYWAY.
FEDRECIA,
IT'S YOUR TURN.
Fedrecia: L.
YES, TWO L's.
C!
TWO C's.
S!
ONE S.
AND I'D LIKE TO SOLVE.
ALL RIGHT.
LOWERCA--
LOWER LETTER CARRIER.
LOWERCASE LETTER CARRIER.
I'M NOW LOOKING
AT OUR EXECUTIVE PRODUCER.
HIS THUMB'S IN THE AIR.
THERE YOU GO. OKAY.
YEAH!
WELL, WE ALLOW YOU TO BACK UP,
AND -- I KNOW. I KNOW.
YOU WERE JUGGLING THOSE --
YOU HAD THE PUZZLE,
AND YOU KEPT
JUGGLING SYLLABLES THERE.
WHEW!
THE GREAT
SYLLABLE JUGGLER.
[ LAUGHS ]
ANYWAY, YOU END UP
WITH $2,650 THAT ROUND --
ALL TOGETHER, $5,650.
CONGRATULATIONS ON THAT,
AND WE'LL BE BACK
IN JUST A MINUTE.
WELL, EVENTUALLY YOU GOT IT
IN THE RIGHT ORDER, HUH?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Vanna: CAN YOU SOLVE THIS PUZZLE
FROM 2004?
IT'S A PHRASE.
WE'LL GIVE YOU THE ANSWER WHEN
WE COME BACK RIGHT AFTER THIS.
APPLY FOR THE SONY CARD, IDEAL
FOR "WHEEL" FANS LIKE YOU.
EARN SONY REWARDS POINTS
EVERYWHERE YOU SHOP,
PLUS EARN
A $50 STATEMENT CREDIT.
etthesonycard.com.
HERE'S THE CORRECT
PUZZLE SOLUTION.
WATCH TOMORROW NIGHT
FOR ANOTHER CLASSIC PUZZLE.
LL, NOW YOU CAN,
BECAUSE ALL THIS SEASON,
WE'LL BE ANSWERING QUESTIONS
PROBING MINDS WANT TO KNOW.
I'LL ASK THE FIRST ONE.
DO YOU GET TO KEEP YOUR CLOTHES?
NO, I DON'T GET
TO KEEP MY CLOTHES.
THEY'RE ON LOAN
FROM OUR GENEROUS DESIGNERS
OR THEY'RE AUCTIONED OFF
FOR CHARITY.
AND, YES,
THE OTHER QUESTION --
VANNA IS JUST AS NICE
AS SHE SEEMS.
YADDA, YADDA, YADDA.
HAVE ANY OTHER QUESTIONS SE.
GO TO WheelofFortune.com
FOR DETAILS.
SO, YOU'RE BACK, HUH?
YOU WANT MORE, HUH?
"FUN & GAMES" THE CATEGORY,
AND IT'S A PRIZE PUZZLE.
Woman: WHOO!
CONOR, THIS WOULD BE
AN EXCELLENT CHANCE
GAME.
TO JUMP RIGHT BACKBE
AN EIN THIS GAME.CE
GO AHEAD.
R, PLEASE.
YEAH, TWO R's.
I'D LIKE TO BUY AN A.
WELL, THERE IS AN A.
IN FACT,
THERE ARE THREE OF THEM.
YOU'RE DOWN TO $350.
I'LL BUY THE E.
ONE E.
STOP! WHOA.
S.
WELL, THERE'S NO S,
AS IT TURNS OUT.
FEDRECIA, YOUR TURN.
SPINNING!
Fedrecia: N!
ONE N.
VOWEL -- I!
THAT IS A VOWEL,
AND THERE ARE TWO OF THEM.
HOLD YOUR BREATH.
OKAY.
G!
YEAH, ONE G.
BUY A VOWEL -- O.
MM-HMM, ONE O.
THAT'S IT.
VOWELS ARE GONE.
WELL...
[ HOKS ]
OOH. D!
FOUR D's.
PICK UP THAT HALF CAR.
TWO OF OUR PLAYERS
HAVE HALF CARS.
THERE'S ONE MORE HALF
OUT THERE,
AND THIS IS THE LAST ROUND
TO GET IT.
ALL RIGHT.
OHH!
OH.
WELL, I HAVE TO
DRIVE OFF WITH THAT.
HANNAH, WHO HAS THAT OTHER HALF,
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
P!
YEAH, THERE'S P.
I'D LIKE
TO SOLVE THE PUZZLE.
YE
RIDING A PADDLEBOARD.
YEAH, THAT'S IT.
OH!
YEAH!
WELL, BECAUSE -- BECAUSE THAT
WAS THE THIRD ROUND,
NO MORE CHANCE TO WIN THAT,
SO THAT'S GONE.
THAT'S OKAY.
HEY, BUT YOU'RE GOING
TO HAWAII.
AAH! [ LAUGHS ]
HANNAH, EXTRA GOOD TIMES
ARE RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER.
AN ECO-FRIENDLY
OCEANFRONT OASIS AWAITS
HAT THE MAUNA LANI BAYES
ARHOTEL & BUNGALOWS, CORNER.
WITH UNDERSTATED ELEGANCE,
SUPERB CUISINE,
WORLD-CLASS GOLF, TENNIS, SPA,
AND GRACIOUS
HAWAIIAN-STYLE HOSPITALITY.
PLUS, EXPERIENCE AN
ECO-FRIENDLY HAWAIIAN ADVENTURE
FROM HAWAII FOREST & TRAIL.
TRAVEL P D BY Hotwire.com.
TAKE MORE OF THE TRIPS YOU LOVE
WITH RIDICULOUSLES,
LIKE FOUR-STAR HOTELS
AT TWO-STAR PRICES
AND AMAZING DEALS
ROVIDE CAR RENTALS AND AIRFAR.
VISIT Hotwire.com TODAY
AND START SAVING.
WELL, LOOK WHO HAS $14,514
AND A BIG LEAD.
BUT THINGS CHANGE QUICKLY
HERE AT THE OLD WHEEL.
WE'LL TAKE A BREAK
AND COME BACK
AND SEE WHAT HAPPENS
AS WE CONTINUE H
WE'RE GETTING
CLOSE TO CHRISTMAS.
YAY!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
ERE.                YAY!
Vanna: CLOSED CAPTIONING
SPONSORED BY...
Announcer: BREAK THE GRIP
OF ACHES OR ARTHRITIS PAIN
WITH ODOR FREE ASPERCREME.
POWERFUL MEDICINELIEVES,
SO ALL YOU NOTICE IS RELIEF.
ASPERCREME.
Progresso.
In what world do potatoes,
bacon and cheese
add up to 100 calories?
Your world.
♪
[ whispers ]
Real bacon...
Creamy cheese...
100 calories...
[ Chef ] Ma'am
[ Male Announcer ] Progresso.
You gotta taste this soup.
of Green Giant vegetables
it's easy to eat like
a giant...
♪
and feel like a Green Giant.
Ho Ho Ho
♪ Green Giant
STAY TUNED. YOUR SPIN I.D.
COULD BE WORTH $5,000!
ALL RIGHT,
EVERYBODY LOCKED AND LOADED
FOR OUR THIRD TOSS UP?
"THINGS" --
THAT'S THE CATEGORY.
VANNA WILL GET THINGS
GOING RIGHT NOW.
[ BELL CHIMES ]
CONOR.
FIVE GOLDEN RINGS.
OH, GIVE HIM
SOME MONEY.
WHOO!
[ APPLAUSE ]
GOOD GOING.
GOT $3,000.
CATEGORY IS "PLACE."
THERE IT IS.
[ BELL RINGS ]
AND THAT SOUND MEANS
TIME'S RUNNING A LITTLE SHORT.
SO I'M GONNA GIVE THE WHEEL
A FINAL SPIN,
ASK YOU
TO GIVE ME A LETTER.
IF IT'S IN THE PUZZLE,
THREE SECONDS TO SOLVE IT.
VOWELS WORTH NOTHING,
CONSONANTS --
OH,
THAT LOOKS PRETTY GOOD.
WE'LL ADD $1,000
HAT.
$6,000
FOR EVERY CONSONANT WE FIND.
AGAIN -- PARDON ME --
"PLACE" IS THE CATEGORY,
AND, CONOR, WE START WITH YOU.
LET'S HAVE A LETTER.
N.
ONE N.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
SOLVE IT NOW,
BUT WE'LL GIVE YOU
THREE SECONDS.
[ BUZZER ]
FEDRECIA.
L.
ONE L.
[ BUZZER ]
HANNAH.
T.
TWO T's.
$12,000.
"PLA
[ BUZZER ]
CONOR.
S.
YEAH. TWO S's.
"PLACE."
[ BUZZER ]
FEDRECIA.
H.
NO. HANNAH.
M.
NO. CONOR.
R.
ONE R.
QUIET, FOLKS.
[ BUZZER ]
ONE D.
A LOT OF MONEY
OUT HERE.
PRESIDENTIAL
SUITE.
THAT'S IT!
GOOD SOLVE. WOW.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
GOOD JOB.
LOOK WHAT YOU DID.
WHOO!
[ LAUGHS ]
BIG WINNER. $17,650, AND YOU GO
TO THE BONUS ROUND
IN JUST A MOMENT.
DON'T LEAVE THE AREA.
I'M NOT GOING.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WE GOT
PLENTY TO SMILE ABOUT.
YOU'RE TO HAWAII,
YOU GOT $14,514.
NICE JOB, HANNAH.
THANK YOU.
CONGRATULATIONS TO YOU.
GOOD JOB.
WELL, I'M GLAD
YOU GOT THAT TOSS UP.
YE GOING TOO.
3,000 BUCKS --
NOT A BAD NIGHT'S WORK.
THANKS VERY MUCH FOR BEING HERE.
GOOD LUCK TO YOU, CONOR.
ALL RIGHT, WE'LL TAKE A BREAK,
COME BACK,
SEE HOW SHE DOES
IN THE BONUS ROUND,
AND WE'LL ALL
GET EXCITED TOGETHER.
YEAH! WHOO!
[ LAUGHS ]
STAY TUNED.
FEDRECIA COULD DRIVE HOME
IN A NEW JEEP GRAND CHEROKEE.
THE BONUS ROUND IS NEXT.
FEDRECIA COULD DRIVE HOME
IN A NEW JEEP GRAND CHEROKEE.
where'd you get that top?
Sears
You look great.
Thanks.
Where'd you that dress?
Sears
Super Cute.
Where did you get those shoes?
Sears
Excuse me...
everyone!
I got the outfit at Sears!
Surprised? Don't be.
This is great fashionSears
at great prices.
This is Sears.
Plus save even more
with your savings pass.
♪
[ Girl ] DEAR SANTA...
DEAR SANTA,
I WANT A BALLERINA TUTU,
A PINK BIKE,
A UNICORN NIGHT-LIGHT...
[ Female Announcer ] THIS YEAR,
BRING THEIR WISH LIST TO LIFE.
[ Girl ]
...PRINCESS DOLL, MARKERS...
[ Male Announcer ]
THE RHYTHM OF LIFE.
[ whistle blowing ]
WHERE DO YOU HEAR THAT BEAT?
CAMPBELL'S HEALTHY REQUEST SOUP
LETS YOU HEAR IT...
IN YOUR HEART.
[ basketball bouncing ]
HEART HEALTHY.
GREAT TASTE.
MMM...
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
IT'S AMAZING WHAT SOUP CAN DO.
Whatever it takes, get to
Sears Last Minute Gift Sale.
Don't judge me!
[ Male Announcer ] SOUNDS GOOD.
Get 50% off sleepwear for
her, and more with pass.
Save up to 70% off
all diamonds,
and up to 30% off all Small
Kitchen Appliances.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
YES.
$17,000-PLUS.
WHO'S IN THE AUDIENCE
WITH Y
I HAVE MY HUSBAND, ARTIS,
WITH ME TODAY.
THERE YOU GO.
[ LAUGHS ]
A RELUCTANT WAVER,
BUT HE WAVED NONETHELESS.
[ LAUGHS ]
AND WE APPRECIATE THAT.
ALL RIGHT,
READY TO SPIN THAT WHEEL?
I'M READY.
GO DO IT.
♪ LA-DA-DEE, DA-DA
A FINE SPIN.
WHERE ARE WE HERE?
OKAY.
WOULD YOU
GRAB THAT FOR ME?
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
AND, IF I MAY, I'M GONNA ASK YOU
TO STEP RIGHT OVER HERE
ON THAT MATCHING
BLUE MARK.
THERE YOU GO.
ALL RIGHT, "PHRASE."
THAT'S OUR CATEGORY TONIGHT.
R, S, T, L, N, E.
VANNA WILL PUT SOME LETTERS UP.
WE HOPE A LOT OF THEM.
THE MORE DINGS,
THE BETTER.
[ BELL DINGING ]
THAT'S MY MOTTO IN LIFE,
BY THE WAY.
ALL RIGHT, WE NEED
THREE MORE CONSONANTS,
ONE MORE VOWEL.
Fedrecia: D.
THAT'S ONE.
P.
THAT WOULD BE TWO.
C.
AND A CON-- AND A VOWEL.
EXCUSE ME.
O.
ALL RIGHT.
CAN WE GET SOME HELP HERE?
A FAIR AMOUNT.
AUDIENCE, PLEASE.
IT'S TEMPTIN
PLEASE DO NOT.
SHE'S SMILING.
SHE'S DANCING.
SHE'S PROBABLY GONNA SAY
THE RIGHT ANSWER.
IT'S A PHRASE.
10 SECONDS. GOOD LUCK.
PROBLEM SOLVED!
I'LL SAY. YEAH!
WHOO!
HEY, CONGRATULATIONS.
SHOULD WE CHECK?
YOU WANT A JEEP?
AAH!
TAKE HIM OVER!
FEDRECIA,
CRUISE THE OPEN ROADS
IN THIS ALL-NEW
JEEP GRAND CHEROKEE.
ITS SPORTY
AND SPACIOUS FEATURES
ALLOW PLENTY OF ROOM
THE WHOLE FAMILY WILL LOVE.
FROM BUERGE MOTOR CAR COMPANY.
PLUS, $5,000 CASH.
YOUR GRAND PRIZE TOTAL --
$33,915.
WHOO!
Pat: PUZZLE SOLVED.
$51,565 CASH AND PRIZES.
THAT'S WONDERFUL.
BE RIGHT BACK.
GIVE ME A KISS.
MWAH!
CONGRATULATIONS ON WINNING
THE BONUS ROUND, FEDRECIA.
MAXWELL HOUSE COFFEE
WILL MAKE A $2,500 DONATION
TO REBUILDING TOGETHER
TO HELP COMMUNITIES IN NEED.
Vanna: IT PAYS TO BE
EEL WATCHERS CLUB MEMBER.
WE'RE GIVING AWAY $5K EVERY DAY!
IF THIS IS
YOUR SPIN I.D. NUMBER --
KS2879237 --
CONGRATULATIONS!
YOU'VE WON $5,000
JUST FOR WATCHING "WHEEL."
YOU HAVE 24 HOURS
TO LOG ON TO WheelofFortune.com
YAND CLAIM YOUR $5,000!
JUST FOR WATCHING "WHEEL."
IT WAS GREAT
SEEING HER WIN A CAR.
I KNOW IT WAS.
AND PEOPLE HAVE NOTICED,
I'M SURE.
BUT WHEN WE GIVE AWAY
A CAR,
YOU KNOW,
'CAUSE THERE ARE COSTS
INVOLVED
WITH THE TAX AND LICENSE --
YOU KNOW,
GET A HALF TANK OF GAS.
A LOT OF STUFF
LIKE THAT HAPPENS.
ANYWAY, SHE DID GREAT,
WE'LL SEE YOUWAY, SHE DID GREAT,
NEXT TIME FOR MORE.
BYE!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
PROMOTIONAL CONSIDERATION
PROVIDED BY...
TH  AND U, CURéL.
THANK YOU, CURéL.
Announcer:
CURéL ULTRA HEALING LOTION.
INSTANTLY RELIEVES
AND PREVENTS DRY SKIN.
YOUR SEARCH FOR DRY-SKIN RELIEF
IS OVER.
Announcer: WHEN CHEF TONY BAKER
IS IN THE KITCHEN,
HE NEVER GETS HURT.
THANKS TO MY 'OVE' GLOVE
HOT SURFACE HANDLER.
NOW WITH NONSLIP SILICONE GRIPS.
ITY HELPS ME
HANG ON TO SLIPPERY DISHES.
Announcer:
THE 'OVE' GLOVE PROTECTS
FROM HEAT UP TO 540 DEGREES.
Baker: I USE IT WITH HOT DINNER
PLATES, EVEN CERAMIC BAKEWARE.
IN M REALLHEN, I ALWAYS
MAKE SURE IT'S THE 'OVE' GLOVE.
[ APPLAUSE ]
-- Captions by VITAC --
www.vitac.com
Y KITC    [ APPLAUSE ]
GOOD MORNING, FRIDAY FAMILY!
[ ALL CHEERING ]
...CHRISTMAS COMES EARLY
TO NORTH CAROLINA
AS FIVE ADOPTED KIDS SPEND
THEIR FIRST HOLIDAY TOGETHER
WITH A FAMILY THEY CAN FINALLY
CALL THEIR OWN.
IF YOU HADN'T HAVE TAKEN IN
THESE FIVE SIBLINGS,
WHAT WOULD HAVE HAPPENED
TO THEM?
THE OLDER TWO
WOULD HAVE BEEN SPLIT UP.
THEY'VE GIVEN THOSE KIDS
A CHANCE
AT HOPE, AT A NEW BEGINNING.
AND, BOY, IS THIS GONNA BE
A SPECIAL CHRISTMAS.
HELLO, DESIGN TEAM.
Paige: SOMEONE HAS BEEN
SNEAKING AROUND, HELPING ME.