[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
SO, MICHAEL, PAIGE, AND XZIBIT,
MERRY CHRISTMAS!
ALL RIGHT!
HOW COOL IS THIS,
RIGHT?
SO, RIGHT NOW, WE'RE TRAVELING
JUST OUTSIDE OF SAN ANTONIO.
AND DO YOU GUYS REALIZE
THAT SAN ANTONIO IS KNOWN
AS "MILITARY CITY, U.S.A."?
WOW.
THERE'S SUCH A STRONG PRESENCE
OF MILITARY
SERVICEMEN AND -WOMEN,
AND RIGHT NOW, WE ARE ON OUR WAY
TO SURPRISE THE HARRIS FAMILY.
TAKE A LOOK AT THIS,
AND YOU'LL SEE WHY WE'RE HERE.
All: HI, ABC.
WE'RE THE HARRIS FAMILY
FROM FLORESVILLE, TEXAS.
YEE-HAW!
I'M SHILO.
I'M THE DAD.
I'M KATHREYN,
AND I'M THE MOM.
I'M ELIZABETH,
AND I'M 9.
AND THIS IS GLEN,
AND HE'S 2.
YAY!
MY LITTLE BROTHER
IS KIND OF CRAZY.
HE LIKES TO JUMP.
HE LIKES TRACTORS.
MY FAVORITE THING IS RIDING
HORSES BECAUSE THEY'RE SWEET.
Shilo: WE'VE BEEN MARRIED
A LITTLE OVER 10 YEARS NOW.
SHE BECAME THE PERSON THAT
TOOK CARE OF THIS ENTIRE FAMILY
FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
AFTER 9/11, I FELT LIKE
IT WAS MY DUTY TO DO MY PART,
SO I JOINED
THE UNITED STATES ARMY.
I THOUGHT I HAD A PRETTY GOOD
IDEA OF WHAT THE WORLD WAS,
BUT WHEN WE CROSSED IN TO IRAQ,
IT WAS AN EYE-OPENER.
ON THIS ROUTINE DAY,
WE WERE CALLED TO INVESTIGATE
A POSSIBLE I.E.D.
EN ROUTE TO THAT I.E.D.,
MY VEHICLE WAS HIT WITH
ABOUT 200 POUNDS OF EXPLOSIVES
BY A BOMB IN THE ROAD.
[ EXPLOSION ]
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
I REMEMBER WAKING UP
IN THE FRONT PASSENGER SEAT,
AND I'M TRYING TO OPEN UP
THE DOOR,
AND I LOOK AT THIS ARM, AND
MY UNIFORM WAS MELTED TO MY ARM.
I KNEW
MY BELL HAD BEEN RUNG,
BUT I HAD NO IDEA
HOW INJURED I WAS.
AS SOON
AS I ANSWERED THE PHONE
AND THE GENTLEMAN
INTRODUCED HIMSELF
AS THE REAR DETACHMENT
COMMANDER,
I KNEW THAT WHATEVER
WAS TO FOLLOW THAT
WAS GONNA CHANGE MY LIFE AND
THE LIFE OF MY FAMILY FOREVER.
WE WEREN'T REAL SURE WE'D
GET HIM BACK TO THE STATES,
SO HIS MOM AND DAD AND I FLEW
TO LANDSTUHL IN GERMANY.
SHILO HAD BEEN BURNED
APPROXIMATELY 1/3 OF HIS BODY,
AT LEAST THIRD DEGREE,
FULL THICKNESS.
AND I REMEMBER STANDING THERE
AND WONDERING IF HE WOULD
[Crying] BE ABLE TO WALK
OUR DAUGHTER DOWN THE AISLE
ON HER SPECIAL DAY.
I CAN'T EVEN REMEMBER
HOW MANY SURGERIES I'VE HAD.
KATHREYN SAYS
IT'S AROUND 50.
THEY'RE WANTING TO FIX THE NOSE
A LITTLE BIT MORE
BECAUSE I HAVE A HARD TIME
BREATHING
AND I DON'T FEEL LIKE
I GET ENOUGH AIR.
I STILL HAVE SOME
NECK AND BACK PROBLEMS.
THEY'VE TALKED ABOUT
TRYING TO FIX THESE FINGERS
SO IT'S MORE FUNCTIONAL.
I LOST 60% HEARING IN THIS SIDE
AND 40% IN THIS SIDE, ABOUT.
I HAVE PROSTHETIC EARS.
THEY'VE EVEN MADE ME SPOCK EARS.
[ Laughing ] SPOCK EARS.
SO, THIS HALLOWEEN,
I HAD A WIG
LIKE THE SPOCK HAIRCUT
AND HAD A "STAR TREK" SHIRT.
I'M LIGHTHEARTED ABOUT IT.
IT'S LIKE I ACCEPT WHO I AM.
I ACCEPT
WHAT HAS HAPPENED,
AND I'M PROUD
OF MY MILITARY SERVICE,
AND IF I WAS ASKED
TO DO IT AGAIN,
I'D RUN
AT THE OPPORTUNITY.
ONE OF THE BIG GOALS
FOR US AS A FAMILY
IS HELPING OTHERS
TO TRANSITION THROUGH THIS.
I CURRENTLY WORK FOR THE ARMY
WOUNDED WARRIOR PROGRAM,
OR "AW2."
IT'S AN ADVOCACY PROGRAM
FOR THE MOST SERIOUSLY INJURED
AND WOUNDED SERVICE MEMBERS
AND THEIR FAMILIES.
SHILO AND KATHREYN
ARE SO WILLING AND SO ABLE
TO ENCOURAGE AND MEET PEOPLE
WHERE THEY'RE AT.
I HAD MET SHILO A COUPLE
OF YEARS AGO AT THE HOSPITAL
WHEN I WAS GOING BACK
TO VISIT PATIENTS,
AND HE HAS SAID TO HIMSELF,
"I WANT TO TAKE
WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO ME,
AND I WANT TO HELP
OTHER PEOPLE."
IT WILL GET BETTER.
THE SCARS DON'T DEFINE ME.
I'M PROUD OF MY SCARS. BE PROUD
OF YOURS. YOU EARNED IT.
ONE OF THE MESSAGES
THAT I TRY TO CONVEY IS,
AS BAD AS IT LOOKS, EVERYTHING
IN YOUR LIFE IS A BLESSING.
I ALWAYS ASK WHENEVER
I'M GETTING READY TO WALK OUT,
"HOW'S MY HAIR?"
[ LAUGHTER ]
YOU CAN TURN SOMETHING REALLY
BAD INTO SOMETHING REALLY GOOD.
I MET SHILO IN THE HOSPITAL.
WE BECAME ROOMMATES.
CRISPY AND EXTRA CRISPY,
OR ORIGINAL AND CRISPY.
KIND OF LIKE "DUMB AND DUMBER."
WE'RE GONNA MAKE A MOVIE.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
I JUST WANT TO DO, LIKE,
A TYSON AND BITE HIS EAR OFF.
HE AIN'T GONNA FEEL IT.
AAH!
[ LAUGHTER ]
THE HOUSE THAT WE'RE CURRENTLY
IN, I THINK IT'S A NICE HOUSE.
YOU KNOW, WE FELL IN LOVE
WITH THE ATMOSPHERE
AND THE COUNTRYSIDE OUT HERE,
BUT WE DID NOT ANTICIPATE
THE HEAT OR THE DUST.
Kat: USUALLY,
PEOPLE CHANGE THEIR FILTERS
HALF A DOZEN TIMES A YEAR.
WE CHANGE OURS
EVERY COUPLE OF WEEKS.
HE HAS LUNG PROBLEMS ALREADY
AND SEVERE ALLERGY PROBLEMS,
SO THE DUST
REALLY DOESN'T ALLOW HIM
TO OVERCOME
THOSE PROBLEMS.
Evan: ONE OF THE UNIQUE ASPECTS
OF BEING A BURN SURVIVOR
IS THAT YOUR SKIN
HAS BEEN MARKEDLY CHANGED
IN TERMS OF ITS FUNCTION
AND ABILITY TO ACCOMMODATE
AND ADAPT TO YOUR ENVIRONMENT.
THEY CANNOT COOL OFF.
THEY CAN'T SWEAT.
THAT WILL SHORTEN THEIR LIFE
MUCH MORE.
OH, YEAH!
UNFORTUNATELY,
I CAN'T GET OUTSIDE
AND DO THE THINGS
THAT I WANT TO DO.
Kat: FIVE MINUTES
IN THE HEAT AND HE'S ZAPPED.
FOR US, 69° TO 70
IS WHERE WE HAVE TO KEEP
OUR THERMOSTAT YEAR-ROUND.
Kat:
WE'RE IN THE MAIN LIVING ROOM.
ONE OF THE CHALLENGES
WE HAVE WITH THIS
IS IT'S USUALLY A 10° DIFFERENCE
FROM THE HALLWAY
LEADING INTO IT,
SO WE HAVE A WINDOW UNIT
TO SUPPLEMENT THE A.C.,
TO HELP KEEP THIS ROOM
COOL ENOUGH
FOR SHILO TO BE ABLE TO ENJOY
SPENDING TIME IN HERE
WITH THE FAMILY.
WHEN OUR PATIENTS GO HOME TO A
CLEAN, SAFE, LOVING ENVIRONMENT,
THEY HEAL MUCH FASTER.
I'VE KNOWN SHILO.
I THINK HIS FAMILY'S GREAT,
AND I HOPE, ABC,
YOU GUYS BUILD HIM A HOME.
All: BYE, ABC!
THANKS FOR COMING!
BYE!
SO CUTE.
WOW.
WHAT A FAMILY.
Ty: INCREDIBLE GUY.
THE FACT THAT HE'S
BEEN THROUGH SO MUCH
AND JUST FIGURES OUT A WAY
TO HELP OUT
OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS --
I JUST SPENT TWO WEEKS
ON THE GROUND IN IRAQ
TO SUPPORT
OUR SERVICEMEN AND -WOMEN.
BUT THE INSPIRATION THAT SHILO
HAS GIVEN TO HIS FELLOW SOLDIERS
THAT HAVE BEEN WOUNDED
IS INCREDIBLE.
WHAT REALLY HITS ME
IS THAT DURING THE HOLIDAYS,
THOSE GUYS ARE MAKING HUGE
SACRIFICES FOR OUR COUNTRY --
MEANWHILE, WE'RE CELEBRATING
WITH OUR FAMILIES.
SOMETIMES THEY DON'T GET
A CHANCE TO DO THAT.
THIS WEEK, YOU KNOW,
NOT ONLY CAN WE BUILD
A NEW HOME FOR THIS FAMILY,
BUT WE CAN REALLY HONOR
A LOT OF THOSE OTHER SOLDIERS,
THOSE SERVICEMEN AND -WOMEN,
AND REALLY GIVE TRIBUTE
TO PEOPLE WHO REALLY PUT
THEIR LIFE ON THE LINE
AND MAKE
A LOT OF HUGE SACRIFICES.
SO, WHAT DO YOU SAY?
CAN WE DO THIS?
LET'S DO IT.        YES.
ALL RIGHT.
WELL, IT'S BEEN
A WHITE CHRISTMAS IN HERE.
LET'S MAKE IT A RED, WHITE,
AND BLUE ONE, SHALL WE?
I'M WITH YOU.
All: LET'S DO IT!
Ty: SHILO HAS NOT ONLY
MADE HUGE SACRIFICES,
HE'S STILL IN A LOT OF PAIN.
BUT HE WAKES UP EVERY DAY AND IS
THANKFUL FOR WHAT HE DOES HAVE.
THIS WEEK, IT'S NOT ONLY ABOUT
PAYING TRIBUTE TO THIS HERO,
BUT IT'S ALSO ABOUT
FOLLOWING IN HIS MISSION,
WHICH IS TO INSPIRE
OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS.
YOU GUYS READY?
Xzibit: YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
HERE WE GO.
GOOD MORNING,
HARRIS FAMILY!
YEAH! YEAH!
SHILO, KATHREYN, ELIZABETH,
GLEN, COME ON OUT HERE!
WHOO!
HEY!
OH, I LOVE THE HAT.
HI!
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
YEAH!
HI. HOW ARE YOU?
OH, MAN. WHOO!
SO, WE'RE HERE
TO BUILD YOU GUYS A NEW HOUSE.
[ SIGHS ]
[ Voice breaking ]
TO SEE Y'ALL HERE ON MY
FRONT YARD IS JUST...
IT'S OKAY.
IT FEELS LIKE
I'M HOME AGAIN.
IT'S OKAY.
THANK Y'ALL SO MUCH.
IT'S JUST AN AMAZING,
AMAZING -- NEVER DREAMED
IT WOULD HAPPEN.
IT'S OKAY, DAD.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S OKAY.
SO, ELIZABETH,
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF YOUR DAD?
HE'S STRONG AND BRAVE.
[ SNIFFLES ]
[ SMOOCHES ]
WELL, THE GOOD NEWS IS,
WE'RE GONNA TRY TO MAKE THINGS
A LITTLE BIT BETTER.
SOUND LIKE A GOOD PLAN?
YEAH!
[ LAUGHTER ]
SO, HERE'S WHAT I THINK
WE OUGHT TO DO.
LET'S GET YOU
OUT OF THE DUST.
WHY DON'T YOU GUYS
SHOW ME AROUND THE HOUSE?
DESIGN TEAM, WHY DON'T YOU
HANG OUT WITH THE KIDS,
TAKE A LOOK AROUND,
SEE WHAT THEY NEED?
WE'LL CATCH UP LATER.
OKAY.
SO, THIS IS THE HOUSE?
Shilo:
THIS IS THE HOUSE.
Ty: I'D ACTUALLY
LIKE TO TALK TO YOU GUYS
IN DEPTH ABOUT
EXACTLY WHAT HAPPENED.
Kat: OKAY. RIGHT.
BUT I THINK RIGHT NOW,
I JUST WANT TO SORT OF
GET AN IDEA OF WHAT'S
GOING ON IN THE HOUSE.
SO, LET'S TALK
ABOUT YOUR ENVIRONMENT.
WHAT NEEDS TO CHANGE?
'CAUSE I SAW YOU JUST, LIKE,
CHANGE THE TEMPERATURE. IS IT --
THE SKIN HAS A HARD TIME
BREATHING.
AS YOU CAN FEEL,
IT HOLDS THE HEAT.
OH, YEAH.
IT'S JUST LIKE PUTTING A PIECE
OF LEATHER OVER YOUR ARM.
I GOTCHA.
I WILL TURN THE WINDOW UNIT ON
IN THE RESTROOM
AND JUST GO IN THERE
AND SIT IN THE RESTROOM.
WHAT HAPPENS
IF YOU OVERHEAT?
I GET SICK.
OH, WOW.
ON US,
WE KIND OF FEEL LIKE
WE'RE GETTING A LITTLE QUEASY
OR MAYBE A LITTLE LIGHTHEADED.
HE DOESN'T DO THAT.
IT IS GO, GO, GO, GO,
AND THEN HE CAN JUST DROP OVER.
YEAH.
HE DOESN'T HAVE ALL THE WARNING
SIGNS THAT YOU AND I HAVE.
OKAY, SO YOU DEFINITELY
HAVE TO HAVE
A TEMPERATURE-CONTROLLED
ENVIRONMENT.
AND THEN, BECAUSE OF
THE RESPIRATORY SITUATION
AND THE DUST,
WHAT DO YOU DO NOW?
WE TRIED ONE OF THOSE
HEPA FILTER UNITS.
YEAH, YEAH.
IT'S, LIKE, I THINK IT'S JUST
SO DUSTY OUT HERE.
WELL, YOU ALSO HAVE TO
BE ABLE TO SEAL IT UP.
RIGHT. THIS HOUSE
DOESN'T SEAL UP AT ALL.
IT'S -- YEAH.
WE KNEW THAT THE HOUSE
WASN'T EXACTLY IDEAL,
BUT I'VE ALWAYS APPRECIATED
LIVING OUT IN THE COUNTRY
'CAUSE IT'S PEACEFUL.
BUT ALSO, THIS COMMUNITY
IS REALLY WELCOMING.
I DON'T KNOW IF IT'S
BECAUSE THEY'RE USED TO IT
OR IF IT'S JUST THAT THERE'S
THE HUGE POPULATION OF MILITARY
OR WHAT, BUT WE DON'T GET LOOKED
AT OR TREATED DIFFERENTLY.
WELL, THAT'S GOOD.
YEAH.
Xzibit:
HEY, IS THIS THE BACKYARD?
Michael:
DO YOU LIKE THE TRAMPOLINE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
OH, YEAH!
OH, THERE WE GO.
WHAT DO YOU LIKE THE MOST
ABOUT TEXAS?
YOU CAN BRING HORSES AND COWS
OUT HERE.
WHICH DO YOU LIKE BETTER --
HORSES OR COWS?
HORSES.
Paige: HORSES.
WE CAN GO WITH A WHOLE
WESTERN THEME OUT HERE.
YOU HAVE SOME
COWBOY BOOTS?
UH-HUH.
Ed: SHILO CAN'T GET OUT
AND PLAY WITH THE KIDS
BECAUSE OF THIS HEAT
AND THE DUST.
YOU KNOW, I THINK THIS WEEK,
WE CAN DEFINITELY MAKE THINGS
A LITTLE BIT EASIER,
WHERE HE CAN BE THE DAD THAT HE
USED TO BE AND WANTS TO BE.
LET ME JUST TALK TO YOU
FOR A SECOND
ABOUT SOMETHING LIKE
WHAT IT'S BEEN LIKE FOR YOU,
'CAUSE YOU'VE SORT OF BECOME
THE NUMBER-ONE CARETAKER.
IT'S CHANGED
A LOT OF WHO I AM.
DOING HIS WOUND CARE,
WE'D LITERALLY SIT THERE
WITH HIM
JUST SCREAMING IN AGONY,
AND I HAD TO LEARN
NOT TO LET THAT AFFECT ME,
BECAUSE IF IT DID,
I WOULDN'T BE ABLE TO DO
WHAT I NEEDED TO DO TO HELP HIM.
HE'S WHAT YOU CALL
"VERY SPECIAL."
YES, HE IS -- IN MANY WAYS.
IN MANY WAYS.
Ty: THESE ARE REAL SACRIFICES
THAT THE MEN AND WOMEN
IN THE MILITARY SERVICES
FOR OUR COUNTRY GO THROUGH.
AND I'M NOT TALKING ABOUT
JUST THE INJURIES.
I'M TALKING ABOUT THE SACRIFICES
THAT IT ALSO TAKES
ON THEIR FAMILIES.
AND THIS FAMILY STILL GIVES BACK
TO THE OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS
THAT HAVE ALSO MADE
THAT SACRIFICE,
SO I'M SO HONORED
THAT WE'RE GONNA BE ABLE
TO BUILD HIM AND HIS FAMILY
A NEW FUTURE.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT AT THE END OF THIS WEEK,
THAT SOLDIER'S GONNA FINALLY BE
ABLE TO KNOW HE'S COME HOME.
THANK YOU.
I NEED YOU.
I FEEL SO ALONE.
BUT YOU'RE NOT
ALONE.
I KNEW YOU'D COME.
LIKE I COULD STAY AWAY.
YOU KNOW I CAN'T DO THIS
WITHOUT YOU.
YOU'LL NEVER HAVE TO.
YOU'RE ALWAYS THERE
FOR ME.
SHH!
I'LL GET YOU
A RENTAL CAR.
I COULD ALSO USE
AN UMBRELLA.
FALL IN LOVE WITH
PROGRESSIVE'S CLAIMS SERVICE.
LET'S COMPARE.
GERM PARTY!
EWW!
NOW THE COLGATE TOTAL MOUTH.
NICE!
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL FIGHTS 90%
MORE PLAQUE GERMS.
I'M IN.
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL.
LESS GERMS. HEALTHIER MOUTH.
CAN YOUR MOISTURIZER DO THAT?
[ Female Announcer ]
DERMATOLOGIST RECOMMENDED
Aveeno HAS AN OAT FORMULA,
NOW PROVEN
TO BUILD A MOISTURE RESERVE,
SO SKIN CAN REPLENISH ITSELF.
THAT'S HEALTHY SKIN FOR LIFE.
ONLY FROM Aveeno.
Shilo: YEAH.
WHAT IS THIS?
THIS IS MY WORKSPACE.
THAT'S YOUR OFFICE.
WOW.
WHICH MUST BE REALLY
EASY WITH KIDS RUNNING
ALL OVER THE PLACE.
RUNNING THROUGH HERE,
SCREAMING.
[ LAUGHS ]
I TRY.
LET'S PUT IT THAT WAY.
HOW IS IT FOR YOU
ON THE KEYBOARD?
IT'S BASICALLY --
I JUST -- YOU KNOW,
IT'S NOT LIKE I CAN NORMALLY
TYPE, BUT, YOU KNOW...
YOU GET THE JOB DONE.
YEAH.
Michael:
SHILO'S ALL ABOUT REACHING OUT
TO EDUCATE OTHER SOLDIERS
TO MOTIVATE THEM,
AND I THINK WITH MANY PEOPLE
WITH DISABILITIES,
IT'S A REALLY IMPORTANT MESSAGE.
IT'S NOT WHAT YOU CAN'T DO.
IT'S WHAT YOU CAN DO.
I'M BUILDING BRIDGES
TO OPEN HEARTS.
YOU SEE A GUY LIKE ME
WALKING IN THE COMMUNITY,
EVEN OUR HOMETOWN, YOU KNOW,
SOME OF OUR FRIENDS
THAT WE'VE
KNOWN MOST OF OUR LIVES
STILL HAVE A HARD TIME
APPROACHING ME AND
VISITING WITH ME,
AND WE NEED TO MAKE SURE
THAT THESE COMMUNITIES
ARE WELCOMING
THESE VETERANS HOME.
ABSOLUTELY. YOU OBVIOUSLY WORK
A LOT AND WORK HARD.
WHAT DO YOU LIKE TO DO
IN YOUR FREE TIME?
I ENJOY
PLAYING VIDEO GAMES.
AS FAR AS OUTDOOR ACTIVITIES,
I LIKE PLAYING GOLF.
WELL,
IT USED TO BE MY PASSION.
SINCE I WAS INJURED, I HAVEN'T
BEEN ABLE TO PLAY GOLF
BECAUSE MY CLUBS WERE --
OH, THE GRIP.
YEAH, THE GRIPS.
MY DAUGHTER TALKED ME
INTO GOING OUT IN THE YARD
AND HITTING A GOLF BALL.
THE BALL WENT FLYING,
AND SO DID THE CLUB.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S FUNNY.
I SAW THESE SITTING OVER HERE.
HOW DO YOU --
OKAY. WATCH OUT.
WATCH OUT.
OBVIOUSLY, I DON'T HAVE
THE PINKIES ANYMORE.
SO, RIGHT NOW,
IF YOU WERE TO SWING THAT,
THE CLUB'S GONNA GO FLYING?
IT PROBABLY WOULD, YEAH.
LET'S TRY THIS OUT.
I SEE YOU GOT SOME REAL GOOD
COINS HERE, MAN.
YES, SIR.
I DO.
THEY'RE CALLED
CHALLENGE COINS.
RIGHT.
WHEN YOU'RE IN THE MILITARY
AND ONE OF YOUR SUPERIORS
THINKS THAT YOU HAVE DONE
AN EXEMPLARY JOB
OR HAVE DISPLAYED COURAGE,
YOU RECEIVE THESE COINS.
AND SHILO
HAS A LOT OF THEM.
THERE'S JUST
SOME THINGS
THAT THEY MEAN MORE TO A PERSON
THAN MONEY DOES.
THEY'RE BADGES OF HONOR,
KIND OF, AREN'T THEY?
ABSOLUTELY.
YEAH. BEAUTIFUL.
OH, THIS IS A COOL ROOM.
IS PURPLE YOUR FAVORITE COLOR?
Elizabeth: MM-HMM.
I SEE YOU HAVE HORSES HERE.
YEAH.
DO YOU RIDE, AS WELL?
MM-HMM.
I'M NOT VERY GOOD AT THAT.
I FALL OFF.
I COULD PROBABLY
TEACH YOU.
REALLY? OH, MY GOSH.
THAT WOULD BE SO FUN.
YOU LIKE "TOY STORY,"
DON'T YOU?
[ As Woody ]
HOW YOU DOING, PARTNER?
YOU LOOK LIKE
A REAL COWBOY, MAN!
[ Normal voice ]
LOOK HOW MANY TRUCKS YOU'VE GOT!
SO, YOU LIKE
YOUR TRACTORS, YEAH?
YEAH.
TRAIN.
TRAIN?
GREAT IDEA, BUDDY.
HAVE YOU GOT ANOTHER COWBOY HAT?
[ GASPS ] OH!
MY HAT!
OH, YOU CAN'T HAVE
TWO HATS.
Paige:
YOU HAVE A HORSE, RIGHT?
BUT NOT HERE.
AND WHY IS THAT?
BECAUSE I DON'T HAVE A PLACE
TO KEEP IT HERE.
OKAY.
AND IS IT TIME
FOR YOU TO, LIKE,
GET BACK TO THAT SORT
OF ACTIVITY?
YES.
I NEED TO FIND ME AGAIN,
BECAUSE HE'S -- HE DOESN'T
NEED ME SO MUCH ANYMORE.
RIGHT.
AND THAT'S BEEN
REALLY HARD TO DO.
'CAUSE YOU KIND OF LOST YOU.
YOU WERE TAKING CARE OF HIM.
RIGHT.
AND IT IS TIME
TO FIND YOU AGAIN.
YES.
Ty: WHEN YOU SAW J.R.
ON "DANCING WITH THE STARS,"
WHAT DID YOU THINK WHEN YOU SAW
A FELLOW SOLDIER BURN VICTIM?
Shilo:
HE'S AN AMAZING MAN.
HE SET THE STANDARD
FOR A LOT OF PEOPLE.
HE USED TO COME UP
TO THE HOSPITAL
AND VISIT WITH GUYS LIKE ME,
YOU KNOW, JUST COMING THROUGH,
AND THAT'S
WHAT I TRY TO DO NOW.
I GET TO HELP PEOPLE RECOVER
FROM THEIR WORST DAY,
AND THAT
MEANS THE WORLD TO ME.
DO YOU STILL HAVE
ANY OF THE, LIKE --
ANY THINGS THAT ARE LEFT OVER
FROM THAT DAY?
THESE WERE ACTUALLY
ON MY UNIFORM.
WOW.
AND THIS WAS EITHER
ON MY UNIFORM
OR ONE OF MY SOLDIERS'
UNIFORMS.
WOW. THAT'S JUST CRAZY
HOW BURNT THAT IS.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF
WHEN YOU LOOK AT IT?
[ CHUCKLES ]
THAT REPRESENTS
WHO WE WERE AND WHO WE ARE.
THERE WAS THREE AMERICAN HEROES
WERE KILLED THAT DAY.
I LOST MY GUNNER
AND MY TWO DISC MOUNTS,
AND THEY WEREN'T
JUST SOLDIERS.
THEY WERE MY FRIENDS.
I WONDER WHY I'M HERE
AND THEY'RE NOT.
IT COULD HAVE BEEN JUST
AS EASILY THE OTHER WAY AROUND.
Ty:
I'M GONNA BE HONEST WITH YOU.
IF I CAME BACK SEVERELY BURNED,
I'M NOT SO SURE
I WOULDN'T BE ANGRY.
WHAT'S REMARKABLE ABOUT SHILO
IS THE MAN LOVES THIS COUNTRY,
AND THE INJURIES THAT HE HAD,
IT HASN'T STOPPED HIM
FROM PICKING UP THE SPIRITS
OF OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS.
I'M, LIKE, SO HONORED
THAT WE CAN BUILD A HOME
FOR THIS GUY
WHO HAS GIVEN SO MUCH.
ALL RIGHT, EVERYBODY.
COME ON OUT.
Michael: ALL RIGHT!
THERE'S SOMETHING
I WANT YOU GUYS TO SEE.
ALL RIGHT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
DO YOU GUYS SEE
THE RED, WHITE, AND BLUE?
ABSOLUTELY.
THAT IS SO BEAUTIFUL.
Shilo: THE FIRST THING I NOTICED
WAS THAT RED, WHITE, AND BLUE,
AND THAT FORMATION
WALKING UP TO MY FRONT YARD --
I MEAN, THAT WAS JUST AMAZING.
THAT IS
A BEAUTIFUL SIGHT.
Ty: THAT IS AWESOME.
WHAT DO YOU SAY
WE GO MEET THE PEOPLE
WHO ARE GONNA BE BUILDING
YOU GUYS A NEW HOME?
ABSOLUTELY.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
[ CROWD CHANTING
"U.S.A.! U.S.A.!" ]
Ty:
SHILO, YOU DOING OKAY?
SO, I'D LIKE TO INTRODUCE YOU
TO GORDON HARTMAN.
THIS IS A MAN
WHO HAS DEDICATED HIS LIFE
TO HELPING PEOPLE
WITH SPECIAL NEEDS.
HE ALSO CREATED
MORGAN'S WONDERLAND,
RIGHT HERE IN SAN ANTONIO,
AND IT'S, IN THE WORLD,
THE VERY FIRST FULLY ACCESSIBLE
FAMILY FUN PARK.
AND THIS WEEK,
HE'S GONNA BE BUILDING YOU GUYS
A BRAND-NEW HOME.
I JUST WANT TO SAY
THAT ALL OF US ARE PROUD
TO BE ABLE TO GIVE BACK
TO AN AMERICAN HERO,
TO A FAMILY THAT HAS GIVEN
SO MUCH TO THIS COUNTRY.
THANK YOU.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
I CAN'T TELL Y'ALL WHAT THIS
MEANS TO ME AND MY FAMILY,
BECAUSE I DON'T THINK THERE'S
WORDS ENOUGH TO EXPRESS IT.
ALLS I CAN SAY IS THANK Y'ALL SO
VERY MUCH FOR WELCOMING US HOME,
AND I HOPE THAT Y'ALL
WILL CONTINUE YOU TO DO THAT
FOR EVERY VETERAN
AND EVERY MAN AND WOMAN
THAT'S BEEN IN UNIFORM.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THERE'S SOMEBODY
THAT WANTS TO SAY HI.
HE'S A GOOD FRIEND OF YOURS.
I'M TALKING ABOUT BOBBY HENLINE.
HERE HE IS.
[ APPLAUSE ]
HOW YOU DOING?
I WAS A ROOMMATE OF SHILO'S
IN THE HOSPITAL.
BUT, SHILO,
YOU DESERVE THIS HOUSE TODAY,
NOT FOR WHAT YOU DID OUT THERE
BUT FOR WHAT YOU DO TODAY --
GIVING BACK
TO OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS
AND HELPING INSPIRE
OTHER AMERICANS,
PEOPLE AROUND THE WORLD,
TO DO THEIR BEST.
I THANK YOU AND KATHREYN FOR
WHAT YOU GUYS CONTINUE TO DO.
THANK YOU, BROTHER.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
DO ME A FAVOR.
I WANT YOU TO HOLD THAT.
OKAY.
THINGS CAN GET A LITTLE DUSTY
SOMETIMES.
OH, OKAY.
I KNOW YOU GUYS REALLY LOVE,
YOU KNOW,
INSPIRING AND HELPING
WOUNDED SOLDIERS,
SO IT GOT ME THINKING
ABOUT A WAY YOU GUYS
COULD CONTINUE TO DO THAT,
MAYBE ON THE ROAD.
SO, CHECK THIS OUT.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
YOU GUYS, COME ON.
HERE WE GO.
HARRIS FAMILY,
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET
THE U.S.O. LIBERTY BELLS!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
♪ JINGLE BELLS
♪ J-JINGLE BELLS
♪ JINGLE ALL THE WAY
♪ OH, WHAT FUN IT IS TO RIDE
♪ IN A ONE HORSE OPEN
♪ SLEIGH
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
SO, HARRIS FAMILY,
GOVERNMENT VACATION REWARDS
IS SENDING YOU
ON YOUR VERY OWN U.S.O. TOUR
TO HEIDELBERG, GERMANY!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
YOU GUYS ARE GONNA BE ABLE
TO DO LOTS OF SIGHTSEEING,
AND, SHILO, ONCE AGAIN,
YOU'LL DO THE THING YOU LOVE,
WHICH IS HELPING OUT
OTHER SOLDIERS.
IN FACT, YOU'LL BE
GOING TO THE HOSPITAL
WHERE SOLDIERS
ARE RECOVERING
IN THE SAME HOSPITAL
YOU WERE IN IN LANDSTUHL.
GUYS, GET ON BOARD!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Ty: SHILO HAS A GREAT SENSE
OF HUMOR, BUT HE'S LOST A LOT.
HE'S STILL IN A LOT OF PAIN.
SO, THIS WEEK REALLY IS ABOUT
TRYING TO GET HIM
IN A HEALTHY ENVIRONMENT,
WHERE HE CAN NOT ONLY BE A
SOLDIER WHO'S FINALLY COME HOME,
BUT HE CAN FINALLY BE A DAD
AND BE ABLE TO, LIKE,
HANG OUT WITH HIS FAMILY
IN AN ENVIRONMENT
THAT'S NOT GONNA HARM HIM.
ALL RIGHT, PEOPLE!
LET'S GET THIS HOUSE STARTED!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
SO, IF YOU GUYS WILL
HELP ME, I KNOW YOU
GUYS ARE BOTH MILITARY.
ARMY, RIGHT?
SO, WE DEFINITELY WANT
TO SAVE THIS FLAG,
'CAUSE I KNOW
IT MEANS A LOT TO SHILO.
Ty: SHILO HAS SACRIFICED SO MUCH
FOR OUR COUNTRY,
AND IF HE COULD,
HE'D GO BACK AND DO IT AGAIN,
AND THAT'S
WHAT THIS WEEK IS ABOUT.
IT'S ABOUT HONORING HIM,
BUT IT'S ALSO ABOUT
FOLLOWING IN HIS MISSION,
WHICH IS GIVING BACK TO SO MANY
OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS.
YO, DESIGN TEAM!
WHAT IS UP?
SO, HERE'S THE THING --
SHILO NEEDS A HOME
THAT'S GOT STATE-OF-THE-ART
AIR FILTRATION,
TEMPERATURE CONTROL, INSULATION,
AND THIS HOUSE
JUST ISN'T CUTTING IT.
RIGHT.
SO, I GOT AN IDEA.
INSTEAD OF DEMOLISHING
THIS HOUSE,
I KNOW THERE'S AN ORGANIZATION
HERE IN TEXAS --
THEY TRY AND RAISE MONEY
SO THEY CAN BUILD
A.D.A.-ACCESSIBLE HOMES FOR
SOLDIERS THAT REALLY NEED THEM.
SO, I FIGURE, WHY DON'T WE
TRY AND SELL THIS HOUSE,
GET AS MUCH MONEY AS WE CAN,
GIVE IT TO THAT ORGANIZATION
SO WE CAN ACTUALLY HELP
OTHER SOLDIERS?
INSTEAD OF SELLING THE HOUSE,
WHY DON'T WE HAVE AN AUCTION?
I LIKE THAT. PRICE IS GONNA
GO UP WITH AN AUCTION.
I'LL LET THE FAMILY KNOW
WHAT'S GOING ON.
OUR HELICOPTER RIDE WAS AWESOME.
THEY DIDN'T FLY US
ALL THE WAY TO HEIDELBERG,
BUT I LOVED
BEING ABLE TO GO TO GERMANY.
DO YOU LIKE MY HAT?
[ LAUGHS ]
Kat:
EVERYBODY HAD SO MUCH FUN.
ALL THE STRESSES OF WORK
AND LIFE -- THEY WERE GONE.
I'M RIDING A MONKEY!
JUST TO BE ABLE TO HAVE A BLAST
WAS REALLY FUN FOR THE FAMILY.
ALL ABOARD!
THE MUSEUM WITH THE PLANES,
TRAINS, AND AUTOMOBILES...
BIG TRAIN!
...THAT WAS GLEN'S HIGHLIGHT.
[ LAUGHS ]
Shilo: TO SEE MY FAMILY
HAVE A GOOD TIME,
THAT WAS EXTREMELY SPECIAL.
NOT A WHOLE LOT OF PEOPLE
GET TO DO THIS.
Ty:
HELLO, HARRIS FAMILY!
HI, TY!
HI, TY!                  HI, TY!
SHILO, I KNOW WITH ALL THE HEAT
AND THE DUST OUT HERE,
THIS HOUSE
JUST WASN'T WORKING FOR YOU.
WELL, IT'S TIME FOR IT TO GO.
BUT INSTEAD OF DESTROYING IT,
WE'VE DECIDED TO SAVE IT.
IN FACT,
WE'RE GONNA AUCTION IT OFF,
AND THE PROCEEDS
ARE GONNA GO TOWARD
BUILDING A HOME
FOR A WOUNDED WARRIOR.
I KNOW THAT'S GONNA MEAN
A LOT TO YOU.
THAT'S AWESOME.
WE'RE GONNA NEED A LOT OF HELP
WITH THAT, SO I RANG UP SANTA,
AND HE SENT US HIS ELITE
TACTICAL GROUP OF ELVES,
OTHERWISE KNOWN AS...
THE SANTA TEAM SIX.
[ CROWD GASPS ]
WOW!
Kat:
OH, MY GOSH.
LET'S DO IT!
THAT'S COOL.
LET'S GET THIS DECK
OUT OF HERE, GUYS.
TO THE NORTH POLE!
[ LAUGHS ]
IN ORDER TO GET THIS THING
MOVED, WE HAD TO SEPARATE IT,
JACK IT UP, AND NOW WE
HAVE TO PUT SOME TIRES ON IT.
WOW!
NOW, THAT'S WORK.
WHAT'S GREAT IS
THIS IS A DOUBLE-WIDE TRAILER,
WHICH MEANS WE CAN TAKE IT APART
AND MOVE IT.
WHO WOULDN'T WANT
TO PURCHASE THIS?
I KNOW I DO.
WIDE OPEN SPACES,
PICTURE WINDOWS.
All: MOVE THAT HOUSE!
I MEAN,
THIS IS BEAUTIFUL.
SO, MY GOAL
BY AUCTIONING OFF THE HOUSE
IS TO RAISE ENOUGH MONEY TO
BUILD A.D.A.-ACCESSIBLE HOMES
FOR WOUNDED WARRIORS.
WE'RE GONNA START IT
AT AN EMBARRASSINGLY LOW $5,000.
THERE'S A $5,000.
WHO WILL BID THE $6,000?
THERE'S A $6,000, MR. GREEN.
$6,000, NOW WITH $7,000.
THERE'S FROSTY THE SNOWMAN
BIDDING $7,000.
[ LAUGHTER ]
SEEING OUR HOUSE
BEING AUCTIONED OFF
TO ASSIST ANOTHER
WOUNDED-WARRIOR FAMILY
WAS AWESOME.
$27,000!
GOING ONCE, TWICE, AND SOLD!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WHOO!
$27,000,
AND THIS IS JUST THE BEGINNING.
WE'LL SEE YOU WHEN YOU GET BACK.
BYE, TY!
BYE, TY!                BYE, TY!
MOVING THEM OUT!
NOW LET'S GET BACK
TO THE NEW HOUSE.
Paige:
THAT SOUNDS GOOD.
ALL RIGHT.
FROM UP HERE, YOU CAN REALLY
GET A GREAT BIRD'S-EYE VIEW
OF WHAT'S GOING ON
WITH THE HARRIS HOUSE.
NOW, THIS ISN'T JUST FOR SHILO.
IT'S FOR
THE ENTIRE HARRIS HOUSEHOLD,
AND LET ME SHOW YOU
HOW THAT'S GONNA HAPPEN.
IN THE BACKYARD, FOR MOM,
THERE'S GONNA BE A STABLE
FOR HER HORSE,
AND THEN FOR DAD,
BACK THERE IS GONNA BE
A PUTTING GREEN FOR HIM,
AND THEN RIGHT HERE,
THERE'S GONNA BE A FLAGPOLE
SO EVERY TIME THEY COME HOME,
THEY'RE GONNA SEE THAT FLAG.
IT'S A REMINDER
OF THEIR PATRIOTISM
AND EVERYTHING
THAT HE FOUGHT FOR.
WHOO-HOO!
HOW'S IT GOING? GOOD?
GOOD.
NOW, THIS IS OBVIOUSLY
GOING IN LITTLE GLEN'S ROOM.
TWO TRAIN TRACKS,
TOP AND BOTTOM.
OBVIOUSLY,
THE TOP TRACK WILL GO ON HERE.
BOTTOM TRACK WILL GO
BOTTOM 'ROUND YONDER, HERE.
Ed: GLEN LOVES ANYTHING
THAT'S GOT AN ENGINE,
SO ONE OF THE KEY FEATURES
IN LITTLE GLEN'S BEDROOM
IS THIS TRAIN
MOUNTAIN-SCENE TOWN.
LOOKING GOOD, LADS. KEEP IT UP
FOR ME, FELLAS. LOOKING GOOD.
THESE ARE CHERISHED, VALUABLE
POSSESSIONS TO SHILO.
THEY'RE CALLED CHALLENGE COINS,
AND WHEN YOU'RE IN THE MILITARY
AND SOMEBODY GIVES YOU
ONE OF THESE, IT'S A HUGE HONOR,
AND HE'S OBVIOUSLY COLLECTED
A LOT OF THEM.
THEY MEAN A LOT TO HIM.
THIS COFFEE TABLE IS GOING
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE HOUSE.
IT'S ALL GLASS ON THE TOP.
THE DRAWERS WILL HAVE
THESE PIECES RIGHT HERE,
CHECKERBOARD STYLE, AND THEN
THE MEDALS WILL BE DISPLAYED.
AND THEN ON THE OTHER DRAWERS,
I'M THINKING WE COULD PUT AN
AMERICAN FLAG AND A TEXAS FLAG.
THIS IS GONNA MEAN A LOT TO HIM,
SO LET'S DO A HECK OF A JOB
ON THIS PROJECT, OKAY, YOU GUYS?
Ed:
I CAN'T HELP BUT THINK
THEY'VE PICKED
THE TWO WRONG GUYS
TO BUILD
A WESTERN TOWN.
I'M FROM LONDON,
AND YOU'RE FROM LOS ANGELES.
YEAH. I THINK
WE CAN FIGURE IT OUT, THOUGH.
LOOK, WE'RE HERE
IN THIS WESTERN TOWN.
WE CAN GET A LOT OF IDEAS
FROM HERE.
Ed: SO, ME AND "X" HAVE GOT TO
GO TO THE WESTERN TOWN
AND GET SOME INSPIRATION
FOR THE BACKYARD,
AND THIS TOWN IS PHENOMENAL.
I MEAN, THEY SHOOT WILD WEST
FILMS HERE, FOR CRYING OUT LOUD.
SEE, WE NEED TO GET OURSELVES
ONE OF THOSE.
THAT WOULD LOOK SUPERB.
HOWDY, FELLERS.
HOW YOU DOING?
YOU'RE NOT FROM AROUND HERE,
ARE YOU?
NO.
HOW COULD YOU TELL?
EAST OF HERE.
HEY, PISTOL PACKIN' PAULA!
I'M TRYING TO CLEAN
MY GUNS.
Xzibit:
WHILE WE WERE GETTING IDEAS,
WE MET COWBOY STEVE
AND PISTOL PACKIN' PAULA.
SHE WAS A TOUGH HOMBRE.
HERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU.
STRAP THEM ON.
Ed: SO, THE FIRST STEP
TO BECOME A GREAT COWBOY
IS LEARNING HOW TO SPIN
AND TWIDDLE A GUN.
AND YOU'RE JUST GONNA TWIRL IT
LIKE SO ON THAT FINGER.
[ LAUGHS ]
GETTING THERE.
THERE YOU GO. YEAH.
SO, THE NEXT STEP
IS LEARNING HOW TO FIGHT.
NOW, YOU'RE NOT REALLY
HITTING THE POLE.
RIGHT.
OKAY, YOU READY?
YEAH.
[ GRUNTS ]
[ GROANS ]
YEAH!
ED WAS GETTING KNOCKED OUT,
GETTING KNOCKED OFF BUILDINGS,
GETTING THROWN INTO POLES.
PISTOL PACKIN' PAULA
PACKS A PUNCH.
WE GOT SOME GREAT IDEAS
TO BUILD A WESTERN TOWN
IN THE BACKYARD, MAN.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
I'M LOVING IT.
PAULA,
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE WELCOME!
TAKE CARE!
WATCH OUT FOR FALLING OFF
THOSE BUILDINGS!
[ LAUGHS ]
LET'S COMPARE.
GERM PARTY!
EWW!
NOW THE COLGATE TOTAL MOUTH.
NICE!
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL FIGHTS 90%
MORE PLAQUE GERMS.
I'M IN.
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL.
LESS GERMS. HEALTHIER MOUTH.
LET'S COMPARE.
GERM PARTY!
EWW!
NOW THE COLGATE TOTAL MOUTH.
NICE!
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL FIGHTS 90%
MORE PLAQUE GERMS.
I'M IN.
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL.
LESS GERMS. HEALTHIER MOUTH.
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL.
Michael: OKAY.
SO, YOU GUYS
ARE PROBABLY WONDERING
EXACTLY WHAT WE'RE GONNA DO
WITH THESE ROCKS.
THE FRONT YARD IS HUGE,
AND I WANTED TO COME UP
WITH SOMETHING THAT'S SORT OF
ENVIRONMENTALLY FRIENDLY
AND ALSO
DROUGHT-TOLERANT.
SO, WE'RE GONNA CREATE
THE BIGGEST
ROCK AMERICAN FLAG
YOU'VE EVER SEEN.
SO, THESE ARE GONNA REPRESENT
OUR RED STRIPES,
THESE ARE GONNA REPRESENT
OUR WHITE STRIPES,
AND THESE BLUES ONES
YOU'RE GONNA PAINT FOR ME
ARE GONNA BE
STARS AND STRIPES.
SO, LET'S GO AHEAD AND PAINT
SOME OF THESE BLUE, OKAY?
HI, THERE.
HEY, ARE YOU LEE?
I AM.
SO GOOD TO MEET YOU.
SO, THIS IS THE MOBILE
U.S.O. UNIT?
IT IS.
Ty: SO, THIS WEEK,
WE HAVE A U.S.O. MOBILE UNIT
RIGHT HERE ON THE BUILD SITE.
MOST OF US THINK OF,
LIKE, THE U.S.O.
AS PUT ON BIG SORT OF
ENTERTAINMENT FOR THE TROOPS,
BUT IT SEEMS LIKE THERE'S
A LOT MORE TO IT THAN THAT.
OH, THERE'S A TON OF THINGS.
WE GO TO FAMILY EVENTS,
LET THEM COME ON BOARD.
THEY CAN DO RECORDINGS
THAT WE SEND OVER
TO TROOPS
WHEN THEY'RE AWAY FROM HOME --
JUST TO LET THEM KNOW
THE AMERICAN PUBLIC
IS STANDING BEHIND THEM
AT ALL TIMES.
THE U.S.O. DO INCREDIBLE THINGS
FOR OUR TROOPS.
NOT ONLY DO THEY SEND
ENTERTAINMENT OVER THERE,
BUT THEY ALSO SEND BITS OF HOME
THAT REALLY MAKE THE MEN
AND WOMEN SERVING OUR COUNTRY
FEEL A LITTLE BETTER
ABOUT JUST BEING AWAY.
I JUST MET WITH THE LADY INSIDE
WITH THE U.S.O.,
AND THEY DO A LOT OF THINGS
TO BE ABLE TO SEND, LIKE,
JUST A LITTLE SLICE OF HOME
TO SOLDIERS THAT ARE SERVING.
I THINK THIS WEEK,
WE OUGHT TO FIGURE OUT A WAY
WE CAN TEAM UP
AND DO THE SAME THING.
WE CAN SEND THEM
VIDEO MESSAGES.
HOW COOL WOULD THAT BE
IF WE KIND OF SHOW
EVERYONE AROUND HERE GIVING
VIDEO MESSAGES BACK THERE?
THAT WOULD BE AWESOME.
I LIKE THE SOUND OF THAT.
ALL RIGHT.
Shilo: WHILE I WAS IN GERMANY,
I GOT TO GO BACK TO LANDSTUHL,
THE FIRST HOSPITAL I WENT
FOR RECOVERY, AND IT WAS GREAT.
I WANT TO SHOW SOLDIERS
THAT HAVE BEEN INJURED
THERE IS LIGHT
AT THE END OF THE TUNNEL.
HOW YOU DOING, SIR?
GOOD. HOW ARE YOU?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
I'M SHILO.
NICE TO MEET YOU.
DO YOU MIND TELLING ME
A LITTLE ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED?
WE WERE DOING A PATROL,
AND WE HIT AN I.E.D.
GOT AN OPEN FRACTURE
TO MY FOOT THERE
AND I GUESS A BURST FRACTURE
TO MY SPINE,
AND THEN I FRACTURED
MY COCCYX BONE.
I DID WHAT I LOVED
WHEN I WAS IN THE MILITARY,
AND NOW THAT I'M INJURED,
I'VE FOUND MY NEW LOVE --
WORKING WITH SOLDIERS
AND HOPEFULLY
GIVE THEM HOPE AND INSPIRATION
THAT IT'S GONNA GET BETTER.
YOU KNOW, I LOOK LIKE
I'M PRETTY SCARRED UP,
AND I'M NOT GONNA SAY
IT WAS AN EASY RECOVERY,
YOU KNOW,
BUT I FEEL VERY BLESSED.
Man: TO KNOW THAT HE CAME BACK
FROM WHAT HE HAD TO GO THROUGH,
IT'S GOOD TO SEE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR YOUR SERVICE, JOHN.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THANK YOU.
IS THIS
FOR ELIZABETH'S ROOM?
THIS IS!
CAN YOU SEE WHAT IT IS?
IT'S A TEPEE.
IT'S A TEPEE! YAY!
WE FOUND OUR JOB!
CHECK THIS OUT.
WE'VE GOT A 6-FOOT
ROUND MATTRESS
THAT'S GONNA GO
INSIDE HERE.
OH, SWEET.
AND THEN WE'VE GOT
THESE GREAT MURALISTS
THAT ARE GONNA PUT,
LIKE, KIND OF --
HIEROGLYPHICS
KIND OF THING?
YEAH, KIND OF,
YOU KNOW?
LIZZIE LOVES THE OLD WEST,
SO WE'RE GONNA PUT A MURAL
ON THE WALL OF HORSES,
MAKE HER BED THE TEPEE,
AND THEN ALSO TRY
TO MAKE IT GIRLY.
OKAY, THIS LOOKS GOOD, GUYS.
OKAY, SO, FOR
SHILO AND KATHREYN'S BEDROOM,
I WANT TO TAKE SOME OF THESE
NATURAL STICKS,
HANG THEM
FROM THE CEILING.
I'LL MEET YOU IN THERE
IN A MINUTE.
OKAY. I GOT IT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
HEY, TY.
MEREDITH!
HOW ARE YOU?
HEY, SWEETIE!
Ty: MEREDITH ILER
RUNS HELPING A HERO.
THEY BUILD ACCESSIBLE HOMES
FOR SOLDIERS THAT NEED THEM.
SO, HOW MUCH MONEY DOES
IT COST TO BUILD, YOU KNOW,
AN ACCESSIBLE HOME?
ABOUT $100,000 IN CASH.
SO, IF WE RAISE SOMETHING CRAZY,
LIKE $1 MILLION DOLLARS,
WE COULD BUILD LIKE
10 HOMES, YOU THINK?
WELL, WE HAVEN'T EVER
DONE THAT BEFORE, BUT
YOU KNOW WHAT, TY?
I'M READY TO TRY, AND I BET
WE CAN DO IT TOGETHER.
HOW INCREDIBLE WOULD IT BE
TO NOT ONLY BE ABLE TO BUILD
A HOME FOR SHILO AND HIS FAMILY
THIS WEEK,
BUT WE COULD ALSO BUILD
A FEW HOMES FOR MANY HEROES?
LET'S MAKE IT HAPPEN.
OKAY? AWESOME.
OKAY. I'M IN.
Paige: THIS WEEK, WE'RE TEAMING
UP WITH WITH HELPING A HERO
SO THAT WE CAN HELP RAISE MONEY
AND HELP EVEN MORE
WOUNDED VETERANS
GET HOMES THAT WORK FOR THEM,
HOMES THAT ARE
A.D.A.-ACCESSIBLE.
HEY, GUYS.
HOW'S IT GOING?
999.
GOOD. HOW YOU DOING?
Paige:
WE GOT A CHANCE TO GO TO A PLACE
CALLED THE CENTER
FOR THE INTREPID
TO SEE WHERE SHILO
DID HIS RECOVERY
AND THEN ALSO TALK
TO OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS
THAT MAYBE ARE GOING THROUGH
THE SAME THING THAT SHILO DID.
HOW DID YOU SUSTAIN
YOUR INJURY?
12 JULY, 2010.
WE WERE IN AFGHANISTAN.
I MUST HAVE JUST STEPPED
MAYBE A HALF FOOT OFF THE TRAIL,
AND I JUST WENT FOR A RIDE.
WOW. WHERE ARE YOU GUYS
STAYING AT RIGHT NOW?
OFF-POST HOUSING.
TRYING TO FIND A HOME
THAT IS HANDICAPPED-ACCESSIBLE
IS PRETTY DIFFICULT.
RIGHT.
Xzibit: IT'S BEEN REALLY HARD
FOR KYLE AND HIS WIFE, ALICIA,
TO MAKE THAT TRANSITION
BACK INTO CIVILIAN LIFE.
I'M A SERGEANT IN THE ARMY,
AND I WAS CLEARING A COMPOUND,
AND THERE WAS A GUY WATCHING US,
AND HE SET THE I.E.D. OFF ON ME.
THAT IS CRAZY.
YEAH.
IT WAS PRETTY INTENSE.
AND HOW DID YOU END UP
HERE IN SAN ANTONIO?
MY DAD IS IN COLORADO,
AND MY FIANCé IS IN TEXAS.
MY MOM'S IN GEORGIA, SO TEXAS
WAS A GOOD IN-BETWEEN POINT.
AND, YOU KNOW,
I HAD ALSO HEARD
THEY WERE REALLY GREAT
WITH ABOVE-THE-KNEE AMPUTEES.
Paige:
KENDRA WANTS NOTHING MORE
THAN TO BE IN THE BEST PLACE
FOR HER RECOVERY,
BUT SHE'S AWAY FROM FAMILY,
AND ESPECIALLY DURING THE
HOLIDAYS, I KNOW THAT'S SO HARD.
[ Voice breaking ] YOU KNOW,
MY MOM'S MY BEST FRIEND.
SHE HELPS ME
WITH EVERYTHING.
YOU KNOW, AND NOT HAVING
MY MOM HERE IS PRETTY TOUGH.
YOU THINK ABOUT THE NEEDS
OF OUR WOUNDED WARRIORS,
TO GIVE THEM THAT PEACE OF MIND
THAT YOUR HOUSE IS NOT GOING TO
BE AN OBSTACLE FOR YOU ANYMORE.
IT'S SO COOL TO BE ABLE
TO NOT ONLY BUILD THIS HOUSE
FOR THE HARRIS FAMILY
BUT TO BE A PART
OF BUILDING ADDITIONAL HOMES
FOR VETERANS
WHO NEED IT SO MUCH.
CAN I GIVE YOU A HUG?
YEAH.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
COMING UP...
All: MOVE THAT BUS!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Ed: WE'VE GOT OURSELVES
A SPANISH-STYLE RANCH HOME.
NOW, WE GOT
THE CONCRETE "S" TILE ON TOP,
WHICH MIMICS CLAY TILE,
BUT WHAT I LIKE
ABOUT THE FRONT OF THIS HOUSE
AND I KNOW THE FAMILY IS GONNA
LOVE IS THIS STONE ENTRYWAY.
THIS IS ACTUAL
FLAGG, TEXAS, STONE.
THIS IS WHAT'S GONNA SET
THIS HOUSE APART.
I LOVE THAT.
THIS IS COMING TOGETHER
INCREDIBLY, RIGHT?
IT LOOKS GREAT.
YEAH, WE GOT THIS
OUTSIDE AREA SO HE CAN
PLAY WITH THE KIDS.
AND THEN CHECK THIS OUT.
SEE ALL THAT BLUE?
THAT DUCTING IS GOING INTO
THIS SYSTEM RIGHT HERE.
THEY'RE GONNA HAVE
TWO OF THESE.
WOW.
IT'S GONNA MAKE SURE
THAT IT'S CLEAN AIR
QUALITY FOR THE FAMILY.
WOW. THAT'S INCREDIBLE, MAN.
LET'S GET TO WORK.
ALL RIGHT.
Xzibit: SHILO WANTS TO GET BACK
ON THE GOLF COURSE,
SO I FOUND A GUY NAMED JOSEPH
WHO RUNS A COURSE
FOR NOT ONLY VETERANS, BUT
REALLY ANYBODY WHO'S DISABLED.
WE'RE BUILDING A HOUSE
FOR SHILO.
HE IS A WOUNDED WARRIOR.
ONE OF HIS INJURIES
WERE IN HIS HANDS.
HE ACTUALLY LOST
SEVERAL FINGERS.
HE CAN'T HOLD A GOLF CLUB
RIGHT NOW.
GOTCHA.
ONE OF THE THINGS
THAT'S AVAILABLE TO HIM...
AHA!
...ATTACHES TO THE GRIP,
AND THEN HE'S ABLE THEN
TO SWING.
THAT'S AMAZING.
IT'S NOT ABOUT WINNING THE GAME
OR, YOU KNOW,
WHAT YOUR SCORE IS WHEN YOU'RE
IN SHILO'S CONDITION.
IT'S ABOUT PUTTING THE SHOES ON,
GETTING OUT THERE,
BEING WITH YOUR FRIENDS,
AND JUST DOING IT.
Joseph:
IT'S ABOUT BEING APPRECIATIVE
OF WHAT YOU DO HAVE
AND WHAT YOU DON'T HAVE.
SO WHAT IF YOU CAN'T GRIP A CLUB
THE WAY YOU USED TO?
YOU FIND A NEW WAY TO DO IT
AND STILL ENJOY THE GAME.
JUST GET OUT THERE.
YEAH.
FROM ONE MILITARY MEMBER
TO ANOTHER, THANK YOU
FOR WHAT YOU DO.
HOW ARE WE DOING
ON THE PACKAGES?
PLENTY OF WRITTEN MESSAGES
GOING OUT TO THE TROOPS.
WE'VE DOUBLED UP ON
THE VIDEO CAMERAS FOR
THE VIDEO MESSAGES.
I LOVE THE LINES -- WE'RE SEEING
ALL THESE VIDEO MESSAGES,
WE'RE GONNA BE ABLE TO PUT THEM
IN AND SEND THEM OVER?
YES.
Ed:
THIS IS CHRISTMASTIME.
THERE'S THOUSANDS OF ACTIVELY
SERVING MEN AND WOMEN
ALL OVER THE PLANET,
SO WITH THE U.S.O.'s HELP,
EVERYONE CAME OUT
AND DONATED THEIR TIME
JUST TO LET
THESE MEN AND WOMEN KNOW
THAT WE REALLY, REALLY DO
APPRECIATE WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
I REALLY CAN'T EXPRESS
MY GRATITUDE.
WITHOUT YOU,
IT WOULDN'T BE POSSIBLE
FOR US TO HAVE OUR FREEDOM.
Man:
THANK YOU FOR SACRIFICING TIME
WITH YOUR FAMILIES
DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
THANK YOU, THANK YOU FOR
EVERYTHING THAT Y'ALL HAVE DONE.
ALL RIGHT.
LET ME JUST LOAD YOU UP THERE.
PERFECT. LADIES, YOU
ARE DOING A GREAT JOB.
AND, GENTLEMEN --
WHAT IS GOING ON
WITH ALL THESE PRESENTS?
WE'RE HAVING
A WRAPPING PARTY.
SO, I WENT DOWN
TO THE HOSPITAL
WHERE ALL THE
WOUNDED WARRIORS ARE,
AND SOME OF THE FAMILIES
ARE THERE,
BUT A LOT OF THESE GUYS
ARE ALONE,
SO I'M THINKING
WE BRING CHRISTMAS TO THEM.
I THINK IT'S SO HARD
TO BE AWAY FROM YOUR FAMILY
AT ANY TIME OF THE YEAR, BUT
ESPECIALLY DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
SO, WE DECIDED TO THROW
A LITTLE CHRISTMAS PARTY
FOR THE CENTER FOR THE INTREPID
AND INVITE
ALL THE WOUNDED WARRIORS
SO THAT THEY COULD OPEN PRESENTS
ON CHRISTMAS
AND JUST HAVE A GOOD TIME
AT THE HOLIDAYS.
HEY, GUYS!
HI!         HI!
HI!                          HI!
EXCELLENT, EXCELLENT.
WELL, WE KNOW SHILO HAS SPENT
SO MUCH TIME HERE,
TALKING TO
WOUNDED WARRIORS.
WHAT DO YOU SAY WE LET THEM KNOW
WHAT'S GOING ON?
[ ALL CHEER ]
HELLO, HARRIS FAMILY.
HI, XZIBIT!
HI, XZIBIT!          HI, XZIBIT!
NOW, SHILO, WE KNOW
THAT YOU INSPIRED
A LOT OF MEN AND WOMEN HERE,
AND A FEW OF THEM HAVE
SOME REAL CHOICE WORDS FOR YOU.
MISS YOU, SHILO.
YOU'RE MISSING OUT, MAN.
XZIBIT'S PLAYING LIVE
FOR US TONIGHT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
Kendra:
I JUST WANTED TO SAY THANK YOU.
IF IT WASN'T FOR
PEOPLE LIKE YOU,
WE WOULDN'T HAVE THE FREEDOM
OF DOING WHAT WE ARE TONIGHT,
AND I WANT TO THANK YOUR WIFE
AND FAMILY FOR THEIR SUPPORT.
WELL, WE KNOW A LOT
OF THE SERVICEMEN AND -WOMEN
WHO ARE GETTING TREATED HERE
ARE AWAY FROM THEIR FAMILIES,
WHICH IS HARD ANY TIME OF
THE YEAR, BUT ESPECIALLY NOW.
WE PLANNED A LITTLE SURPRISE
FOR EVERYONE.
OUR FRIENDS AT SEARS KNOW
HOW IMPORTANT FAMILY IS,
ESPECIALLY
DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
AND WHY DON'T WE HAVE
A CHRISTMAS PARTY
WITH SOME FAMILY?
FAMILY MEMBERS, COME ON IN!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
Kat: KNOWING
THAT SEARS MADE IT POSSIBLE
FOR OUR FRIENDS
TO HAVE THIS HOLIDAY TOGETHER
WAS JUST A GREAT FEELING.
I LOVE YOU, I LOVE YOU,
I LOVE YOU. I MISS YOU.
LET ME SEE YOU.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
Kendra: TO HAVE MY MOM HERE
MEANS THE WORLD TO ME.
YOU HAVE FRIENDS
AND YOU MAKE FRIENDS
THAT YOU GO THROUGH RECOVERY
WITH, BUT FAMILY IS FAMILY.
Paige: ALL RIGHT, GUYS.
HOW GREAT IS IT TO BE TOGETHER
FOR THE HOLIDAYS AS A FAMILY?
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THAT'S RIGHT.
THEY LOVE IT.
AREN'T YOU FORGETTING
SOMETHING?
THAT'S RIGHT, SANTA.
SEARS ALSO WANTS TO MAKE SURE
THAT ALL OF YOUR HOLIDAY WISHES
COME TRUE,
SO THEY'VE PROVIDED PRESENTS
FOR ALL THE WOUNDED WARRIORS
AND THEIR FAMILIES.
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
WHO'S READY
FOR SOME PRESENTS?!
[ CHEERS AND APPLAUSE ]
THERE YOU GO.
LET'S DO IT.
ALL RIGHT.
Shilo:
I'M SITTING THERE WATCHING
EVERYBODY HAVING A GOOD TIME
AND THEIR SMILES, AND IT WAS
A REALLY GOOD FEELING.
THAT THESE PEOPLE
GOT TO BE WITH THEIR LOVED ONE
THAT'S BEEN INJURED IN COMBAT --
IT MEANT THE WORLD TO ME.
MERRY CHRISTMAS, AND WE'LL
SEE YOU WHEN YOU GET BACK.
BYE, GUYS!
All: BYE!
LET'S COMPARE.
GERM PARTY!
EWW!
NOW THE COLGATE TOTAL MOUTH.
NICE!
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL FIGHTS 90%
MORE PLAQUE GERMS.
I'M IN.
[ Female Announcer ]
COLGATE TOTAL.
LESS GERMS. HEALTHIER MOUTH.
SOMETHING THIS DELICIOUS
COULD ONLY COME FROM NATURE.
NEW NECTRESSE.
THE 100% NATURAL
NO-CALORIE SWEETENER
MADE FROM THE GOODNESS
OF FRUIT.
NEW NECTRESSE.
SWEETNESS NATURALLY.
Ty: HEY, MICHAEL!
Michael: YO!
I GOTTA SAY, MAN,
THIS THING IS LOOKING AWESOME.
RIGHT? CHECK IT OUT.
WE ARE IN THE GREAT ROOM HERE.
I LOVE IT.
CHECK OUT
THE ADOBE-STYLE FIREPLACE.
SWEET. EXCELLENT.
REALLY, REALLY COOL.
I LOVE THE DETAILS.
BEAMS.
WE HAVE LOTS OF BEAMS,
DARK WOOD.
ALSO, THE AIR-FILTRATION SYSTEM
IS IN.
YES. WHEREVER HE'S AT,
THE AIR WILL BE PURE AND CLEAN.
JUST GOT THE CUSTOM TILE IN.
CABINETS ARE GOING IN RIGHT NOW.
YEAH. LIKE THAT.
LOVE IT! LOOKING GOOD.
WHAT ARE WE
LOOKING AT HERE?
WELL, WE'RE GETTING READY
TO INSTALL
THE TRANSPARENT,
INTERACTIVE TOUCH SCREEN
THAT'S GONNA REPLACE
HIS OLD COMPUTER THAT HE HAS.
Xzibit: SHILO'S OFFICE,
HE HAS A COMPUTER
FROM, LIKE, THE STONE AGE
THAT HE'S TRYING TO TYPE,
AND IT CAN'T BE EASY,
ESPECIALLY WITH HIS INJURIES
ON HIS HANDS.
Man: JUST LIKE YOU SEE
IN THOSE FUTURISTIC MOVIES
WHERE THEY'RE KIND OF MOVING
STUFF AROUND ON GLASS...
YEAH.
JUST WALKING UP TO IT, THAT'S
BASICALLY WHAT WE HAVE HERE.
DESIGNED
A CUSTOM-MADE APPLICATION
JUST FOR HIM AND HIS FAMILY
WHERE HE'LL BE ABLE TO DO
EVERYTHING
AT A TOUCH OF A FINGER.
WELL, GUYS, WELL, HOW CAN I
HELP PUT THIS TOGETHER?
WE'RE GETTING READY TO ACTUALLY
APPLY IT TO IT, SO...
OKAY, LET'S GET IT.
HERE YOU ARE.
OH, THAT LOOKS AWESOME.
I'M THINKING WE CAN
PUT THIS ON THE STAR
THAT YOU'RE WORKING ON
THAT GOES ON THE BARN.
I LOVE IT!
Man: HEY, MICHAEL!
YO.
HEY, WE GOT ALL THIS CHRISTMAS
STUFF OUT OF STORAGE.
OKAY.
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO DO?
RED, WHITE, AND BLUE
IN THE BACKYARD.
WHITE LIGHTS ONLY
IN THE FRONT.
Michael: WE'RE HERE
TO CELEBRATE AND HONOR
ALL OF THE TROOPS AND VETERANS
ACROSS THIS COUNTRY,
SO WE'RE GONNA HAVE A RED,
WHITE, AND BLUE CHRISTMAS.
THIS IS ALL GOOD.
[ DRILL WHIRS ]
[ HAWK CRIES ]
[ WESTERN THEME PLAYING ]
[ SNARLS ]
ED, WHAT IS THIS?
[ American accent ]
WHO'S ASKIN'?
I'M ASKIN'.
WESTERN TOWN.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I THOUGHT
I'D COME HERE...
SEE IF YOU NEEDED ANY HELP.
[normal voice] I DO, ACTUALLY.
THIS BATTERY'S DEAD.
THANKS VERY MUCH.
PERFECT. TAKE CARE.
GOOD JOB. CHEERS, PAIGE. LOVELY.
♪
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
WE HAVE BEEN JUST REALLY BLESSED
TO BE ABLE TO GO BACK TO GERMANY
AND GETTING TO GO TO THE U.S.O.
I KNOW FIRSTHAND
FROM WHEN I WAS THERE
DURING THE RECOVERY PROCESS,
HOW IMPORTANT IT IS
TO BE ABLE TO COMMUNICATE
WITH YOUR LOVED ONES.
YOU'RE THOUSANDS OF MILES
AWAY FROM THEM.
THAT'S ALL THAT'S ON YOUR MIND
DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
[ CELL PHONE RINGS ]
HANG ON.
HANG, HANG, HANG, HANG.
HELLO?
HEY, GUYS.
SO HOW'S THE VACATION GOING?
WELL, WE'RE HANGING OUT
AT THE U.S.O. HERE IN LANDSTUHL
AND HAVING A VERY GOOD
CHRISTMAS PARTY.
EXCELLENT.
SHILO, HERE'S THE THING, MAN.
NOT ONLY HAVE WE BEEN
WORKING REALLY HARD
ON BUILDING YOU A NEW HOME,
BUT WE'RE ALSO DOING
EVERYTHING WE CAN
FOR OUR SOLDIERS OVERSEAS.
We can only imagine how tough
it can be in the hospital
over there, especially
around this time of year.
SO, DO ME A FAVOR. CHECK OUT
WHAT'S BEHIND THOSE BLUE DRAPES.
We're bringing the
wounded warriors of Landstuhl
a little taste of home.
AWESOME. WOW!
OH, WOW.
THAT IS AWESOME.
WE ACTUALLY HAVE LETTERS
WRITTEN, WE SHOT VIDEO MESSAGES,
VIDEO GAMES, YOU KNOW, COFFEE --
THINGS THAT ARE JUST
LITTLE BITTY TIDBITS
THAT REMIND YOU OF HOME,
AND ESPECIALLY DURING
THE HOLIDAYS,
A LITTLE
REALLY WILL GO A LONG WAY.
THIS IS MY NEW BEST FRIEND.
[chuckles]
Shilo: HAVING THOSE LUXURIES
THAT YOU DON'T ALWAYS GET
TO EXPERIENCE, YOU KNOW,
WHEN YOU'RE
IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE --
THOSE ARE MOMENTS
THAT YOU JUST CAN'T REPLACE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH, TY.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
THIS IS SWEET.
I CAN CALL HOME.
Shilo: WATCHING THE VIDEOS
FROM TEAM MEMBERS AND VOLUNTEERS
AND STUFF OUT THERE --
THAT MEANS SO MUCH
DURING THE HOLIDAYS.
Man: WE THANK YOU. WE KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE GOING THROUGH.
JUST KNOW
THAT WE'RE PROUD OF YOU,
AND KEEP UP THE GOOD FIGHT.
Man #2:
LIKE ALL OF YOU, I SERVED.
I KNOW WHAT IT MEANS
TO BE AWAY FROM FAMILY,
ESPECIALLY DURING
THIS HOLIDAY SEASON.
KNOW THAT WE'RE HERE,
YOUR FAMILY'S HERE,
AND THE COUNTRY IS BEHIND YOU.
THANK YOU AGAIN
FOR YOUR SERVICE.
Man #3:
I JUST WANT TO LET YOU KNOW
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT YOU,
THAT YOU'RE NOT BY YOURSELF.
MERRY CHRISTMAS.
STAY STRONG.
SEMPER FIDELIS.
Man #4: IT MEANS A LOT.
IT MEANS THAT PEOPLE ARE STILL
THINKING ABOUT US AT HOME.
SO EVEN THOUGH
WE'RE NOT IN THEIR SIGHT,
WE'RE STILL IN THEIR HEARTS.
WHEN I WAS HERE,
WE DIDN'T EVEN HAVE
COMPUTERS WE COULD GET TO,
LIKE WHEN YOU WERE
IN THE I.C.U.
KNOWING THAT U.S.O.
HAS THOSE TOOLS NOW,
MORE OF THOSE TOOLS TO GET IT
IN MORE HANDS OF FOLKS,
AND MORE OPPORTUNITY
TO CALL HOME --
IT'S JUST A PHENOMENAL FEELING
TO KNOW THAT SHILO AND I
WERE PART OF THAT.
♪ JUST SIT RIGHT THERE,
WE'RE NOT QUITE DONE ♪
♪ THERE IS AN HOUR MORE
♪ WE'LL FINISH THE BUILD,
WE'LL MOVE THE BUS ♪
♪ AND SEND THEM
THROUGH THE DOOR ♪
♪ TY AND PAIGE AND ED AND X
♪ AND MICHAEL
HAVE MORE IN STORE ♪
♪ SO PLEASE KEEP WATCHING ON
♪ PAY NO ATTENTION
TO THE CREDITS ♪
♪ THE SHOW IS NOT YET DONE
WOW. I COULDN'T HAVE SUNG IT
ANY BETTER MYSELF.
STAY TUNED, PEOPLE,
BECAUSE WE'VE STILL GOT
ONE MORE HOUR OF SHOW.
WELL DONE, LADIES.
[ HUMMING ]
[ HUMS OFF-KEY ]
YEAH, MINE WAS THE BAD VOICE
AT THE VERY END.
,
GOOD MORNING, HARRIS FAMILY!
SHILO IS A GUY
WHO'S GIVEN SO MUCH
AND SACRIFICED SO MUCH
FOR OUR COUNTRY.
Shilo: MY VEHICLE WAS HIT
BY A BOMB IN THE ROAD.
Ty:
HE WAS SEVERELY BURNED IN IRAQ.
THREE AMERICAN HEROES
WERE KILLED THAT DAY.
I WONDER WHY I'M HERE
AND THEY'RE NOT.
BUT NO MATTER HOW MUCH PAIN
HE'S BEEN THROUGH,
IT HASN'T STOPPED HIM FROM
VISITING OTHER WOUNDED WARRIORS
AND MOTIVATING THEM
TO KEEP FIGHTING.
I FEEL VERY BLESSED.
COMING UP NEXT...
Paige:
WE'RE GONNA HAVE A RED, WHITE,
AND BLUE CHRISTMAS THIS YEAR.
WE CAN HELP
EVEN MORE WOUNDED VETERANS.
WE HAVE RAISED $1.1 MILLION!
Shilo: Y'ALL BROUGHT
SOMETHING VERY SPECIAL