THROUGH SUNDAY MAYBE UMBRELLA
A GOOD PRESENT TO LIVE DOPPLER
7 HD, CLEAR OVER LAND, OVER
THE OCEAN NEAR THE SHOWERS
EVEN A FEW THUNDERSTORMS
POPPING UP TO OUR NORTH AROUND
UKIAH AND POINTS NORTH, BUT
OVER THE OCEAN.
COOL CONDITIONS MID TO UPPER
30s NORTH BAY VALLEYS, LOW TO
MID 40s EAST BAY VALLEYS, MID
TO UPPER 40s ELSEWHERE, THROW
IN THE WINDS AND ONCE YOU GET
UP TO A WIND SIX, SEVEN, EIGHT
MILES PER HOUR DROPS
TEMPERATURE OR WHAT IT FEELS
LIKE SO THERE'S A BIT OF A
WIND CHILL THIS MORNING.
STRAY SHOWER NEAR THE COAST AS
WE HEAD THROUGH THE AFTERNOON,
LOW 50s, PARTLY CLOUDY AROUND
THE BAY, LOW TO MID 50s,
APPARENTLY CLOUDY INLAND LOW
TO MID 50s MORE SUNSHINE,
COOLER THAN YESTERDAY.
BIG TIME FREEZE TONIGHT.
THOSE AREAS COMING UP AND THE
STORMS.
FIRST TRAFFIC.
>>> SHOT HERE TWEETED BY THE
PALO ALTO POLICE DEPARTMENT
CAR HIT A FIRE HYDRANT NEAR
SANFORD SHOPPING CENTER ON
SAND HILL ROAD YOU CAN SEE ALL
THE WATER BOTH DECKS OF
SAND HILL ROAD CLOSED -- BOTH
DIRECTIONS OF SAND HILL ROAD
CLOSED.
NO ESTIMATED TIME OF OPENING,
A LOT OF WATER NOT CERTAIN IF
THAT THEY HAVE THAT CAPPED
YET.
THE ROADWAY IS STILL FLOODED.
IF YOU GO TO SANFORD, NO
EXCUSES THERE.
SAN MATEO BRIDGE LIGHT TRAFFIC
FEW BRAKE LIGHTS ON FLAT
SECTION UP THE HIGHRISE
TOWARDS FOSTER CITY, NICE
DRIVE KNEW MacARTHUR MAZE FROM
580 TO EAST 880 SOUTH 80 INTO
THE TOLL A BIT OF A BACK-UP --
METERING LIGHTS JUST TURNED
ON.
>>> WE ARE CONTINUING TO
FOLLOW BREAKING NEWS IN
CONCORD POLICE INVESTIGATING A
SMASH AND GRAB ROBBERY AT A
VIDEO GAME STORE.
>> Reporter: WHAT AN
UNCONVENTION 5 ROBBERY.
LOOK WHERE HE BUSTED INTO THE
-- STORE THROUGH THE GLASS
WALL A WALL OF WINDOWS THAT
DON'T EXIST ANY MORE THIS IS
WHERE THE CAR SMASHED INTO THE
STORE LOOK AT VIDEO IT
HAPPENED 4:00 THIS MORNING IN
CONCORD AT THE GAMESTOP ON
IGNACIO RALLY ROAD.
IT WAS 4:00 IN THE MORNING
WHEN THE CAR SMASHED THROUGH
THE STORE AND THE GUY OR GAL
WHOEVER DID IT, JUMPED OUT,
RAN INTO THE STORE AND STOLE
ITEMS.
THEY ARE ASSESSING WHAT THEY
GOT.
THEY KNOW THE THIEVES TWO A
PREOWNED CELL PHONES, iPHONES
THEY SAY THOSE ARE TRACEABLE
AND THEY ARE HOPE THAT WILL
LEAD POLICE TO WHOEVER DID
THIS.
WHOEVER DID THIS TOOK OFF, NOT
IN A CAR THEY LEFT THE CAR
THEY HAD TO KNOW THAT AWAY.
-- THEY HAD TO TOW THAT AWAY.
THIEVES ARE OUT OF HERE.
POLICE HAVE TO FIGURE OUT WHO
DID THIS.
PEOPLE HERE ARE TRYING TO GET
THE STORE CLEANED UP AND GET
OPEN FOR BUSINESS.
THEY DON'T KNOW WHEN THAT IS
GOING TO HAPPEN.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF GLASS TO
CLEANUP AND A WALL THEY HAVE
TO FIX.
THEY BOARDED IT UP AND THEY
HAVE A DOOR PEOPLE CAN USE TO
GET INTO THE STORE.
THEY ARE HOPING TO OPEN TODAY,
THEY DON'T KNOW, THEY ARE
HOPING THE GLASS COMPANY WILL
BE HERE FIRST THING TO START
TALKING ABOUT REPLACING THIS
BIG PANEL.
POLICE SAY THEY SUSPECT THE
CAR WAS STOLEN.
THEY DON'T KNOW IT HASN'T BEEN
REPORTED STOLEN BUT THAT I
SEEN CASES LIKE THIS BEFORE
THAT IS THEIR SUSPICION.
AMY HOLLYFIELD, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> 6:04.
LATEST ON THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY
IN CONNECTICUT.
STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN BACK IN
CLASS FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
FRIDAY.
HOWEVER, SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
REMAINS CLOSED INDEFINITELY.
STUDENTS FROM THAT SCHOOL WILL
BE RETURNING TO A NEIGHBORING
SCHOOL.
FOUR MORE FUNERALS WILL TAKE
PLACE TODAY, THREE SERVICES
FOR STUDENTS THE FOURTH FOR A
TEACHER VICKI SOTO.
AUTHORITIES HAVE RECOVERED A
COMPUTER BELONGING TO SUSPECT
ADAM LANZA, BUT BADLY DAMAGED
INFORMATION IS UNLIKELY TO BE
RECOVERED.
TAHMAN BRADLEY IS IN
CONNECTICUT AND REPORTS ON HOW
THE TOWN IS TRYING TO COPE.
>> Reporter: THE TOWN IS
PERFORMING A GRIM TASK.
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH LIKED ANIMALS,
VIDEO GAMES AND MEXICAN FOOD.
AN ONLOOKER COLLAPSED INSIDE
HIS MOTHER MOVED EVERYONE TO
FATHERS.
>> SHE TOLD HIM, I LOVE YOU.
>> Reporter: ANOTHER FUNERAL
FOR JACK PINTO, ALSO SIX.
>> IT WAS JUST SAD.
HEAVY HEARTED.
>> Reporter: JACK LOVE THE
NEW YORK GIANTS HIS FAVORITE
PLAYER VICTOR CRUZ WORE HIS
NAME ON HIS CLEATS DURING
SUNDAY'S GAME.
>> TO HAVE MY JERSEY BE HIS
FAVORITE PLAYER THEY WANT TO
BURY HIM WITH IT, I TOLD THEM
I WAS HONORED.
>> Reporter: SO MUCH PAIN FOR
ALL CLOSE TO FRIDAY'S
SHOOTING.
GOVERNOR MALLOY WIPED AWAY
TEARS RECALLING THE MOMENT HE
INFORMED PARENTS THEIR
CHILDREN DIED NOW HE WILL
ATTEND SO MANY FUNERALS.
>> YOU SEE LITTLE COFFINS AND
YOUR HEART HAS TO ACHE.
>> Reporter: NEW INFORMATION
ABOUT THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTING
ADAM LANZA PAINS A PICTURE OF
A YOUNG MAN WHO SEEMED TOBACCO
UNRAVELING.
FOR YEARS HIS MOTHER -- SEEMED
TO BE UNRAVELING.
FOR YEARS HIS MOTHER STRUGGLED,
SHE TOLD HER FRIENDS ADAM WAS
SO TROUBLED HE WOULD NOT LEAVE
THE HOUSE.
>> SHE HOME SCHOOLED HIM AND
EVERYTHING.
I KNEW HE WAS ON MEDICATION
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
>> Reporter: IN FRIDAY THE
GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT IS
CALLING FOR A MOMENT OF
SILENCE AND FOR CHURCHES TO
RING BELLS THE EXACT MOMENT OF
THE SHOOTING.
TAHMAN BRADLEY, ABC NEWS.
>>> 6:06.
BACK HERE SAN FRANCISCO POLICE
ASKING FOR THE PUBLIC'S HELP
SOLVING THE MURDER OF A
17-YEAR-OLD FOOTBALL PLAYER,
HE PLAYED OFFENSE AND DEFENSE
FOR THE CONCORD HIGH MINUTEMEN
AND WAS A SENIOR HE WAS SHOT
AND KILLED IN THE BAYVIEW
SATURDAY NIGHT MANY STUDENTS
SHOWED UP WEARING BLACK
YESTERDAY, MOURNING HIS DEATH.
>>> WESTFIELD SHOPPING CENTER
EXPECTED TO OPEN THIS MORNING
AFTER A FIRE.
THE FIRE BROKE OUT AT A
RESTAURANT ON THE 4th FLOOR
AFTER 8:30 LAST NIGHT.
THE THEATER WAS TEMPORARILY
EVACUATED NO WORD ON A CAUSE.
>>> 6:07.
TRAFFIC AND WEATHER TOGETHER,
NEXT ON THE ABC7 MORNING NEWS.
LIVE LOOK OUTSIDE NOW, HIGHWAY
87, HELD LIGHTS MOVING ALONG
JUST FINE, NO MOISTURE ON THE
ROADS THIS MORNING.
IN A COUPLE OF DAYS THAT IS
GOING TO CHANGE.
MIKE WILL FILL YOU IN COMING
UP.
SUE IS FOLLOWING YOUR TRAFFIC.
>>> RANKING RELIGION.
!
>>> WELCOME BACK.
LIVE DOPPLER YOU SEE SHOWERS
EVEN THUNDERSTORMS OVER THE
OCEAN CLEAR OVER LAND WITH OUR
COAST TILTING NORTHWEST SHOWER
OFF THE SHORE NEAR FT. BRAGG
COULD GET CLOSE TO SEA RANCH
MOVE -- MOST OF US ARE GOING
TO BE SAFE VISIBILITY LIMITED
OTHER THAN A FEW CLOUDS HERE
AND THERE NOT MUCH TO TALK
ABOUT AS FAR AS FOG OR FROST,
YET THIS MORNING.
OFF TO A COOLER START, LOW TO
MID 40s, 30s NORTH BAY VALLEYS,
NEAR 50 AND MORE SUN 4:00,
BACK INTO THE 40s, FOR THE
EVENING.
>>> INCHING ALONG BEHIND THE
BAY BRIDGE TOLL, METERING
LIGHTS ON TRAFFIC BACKING PAST
OVERCROSSING SLUGGISH UPPER
DECK TOWARDS SAN FRANCISCO ON
YOUR APPROACH MERE MacARTHUR
MAZE TRAFFIC FLOWING NICELY ON
80 APPROACHING THE BAY BRIDGE,
580 GOOD, 880 NO DELAYS
THROUGH THE MAZE.
PROBLEM WITH A BIG RIG AND CAR
OUT OF LANES, FREMONT
NORTHBOUND 880 AT MISSION NOT
CAUSING MUCH SLOWING.
SOME OF THE BUSIER DRIVE TIMES
HIGHWAY 4 OUT OF ANTIOCH, EAST
SHORE FREEWAY FROM THE
CARQUINEZ BRIDGE TO THE MAZE
20 MINUTES AND HIGHWAY 87
NORTH TOWARDS 101 GOOD DRIVE
UNDER 10 MINUTES.
>>> 6:12.
A JUST RELEASED STUDY SAYS ONE
IN SIX PEOPLE WORLDWIDE NOW
HAVE NO RELIGIOUS AFFILIATION.
THE STUDY FROM THE PEW
RESEARCH CENTER SAYS 16% OF
THE WORLD'S POPULATION HAS NO
RELIGIOUS AFFILIATION,
CHRISTIANS REMAIN THE LARGEST
GROUP WORLDWIDE WITH 32%.
FOLLOWED BY MUSLIMS 23%.
HINDUS 15%.
BUDDHISTS AT 7%.
>>> 6:12.
THE NEW TROUBLE FACING
FACEBOOK AND REMEMBER IT IS
MAY IPO?
NEW INFORMATION ON THAT.
>>> THE SPORTING GOODS STORE
TAKING NEW ACTION IN RESPONSE
TO THE TRAGEDY IN
>>> GOOD MORNING.
6:15.
I JUST UPDATED TEMPERATURES,
33 FAIRFIELD, NAPA 34,
SANTA ROSA 36, CONCORD 37
LIVERMORE, SAN JOSE LOS GATOS
41, 42 FREMONT, 44 OAKLAND, 45
SAN FRANCISCO, SAN RAFAEL.
48 HALF MOON BAY.
EIGHT TO 21° COOLER THAN
YESTERDAY DEFINITELY BUNDLE UP
AS YOU STEP OUT.
SUNSHINE TODAY, LOW TO MID 50s
SHOWERS OVER THE OCEAN FROSTY
JUST ABOUT EVERYWHERE TOMORROW
MORNING, HIGH CLOUDS AND SUN
LOW TO MID 50s, GET READY FOR
THE WET WEATHER BLUSTERY
CONDITIONS THURSDAY INTO
FRIDAY.
>>> SPECIAL TRIBUTE GOT
UNDERWAY IN CONNECTICUT
HONORING THE LIVES LOST IN
FRIDAY'S TRAGIC SHOOTING IN
NEWTOWN.
THE UNIVERSITY OF CONNECTICUT
MEN'S BASKETBALL TEAM PLAYED
ITS FIRST GAME.
THE TEAM, CHEERLEADERS AND
OTHERS FORMED A CIRCLE AROUND
CENTER COURT, SOME HELD
CANDLES, WORE SPECIAL PATCHES
SH FOR SANDY HOOK SOME HAD IT
ON THEIR FACES.
MONDAY NIGHT FOOTBALL ALSO
PAID TRIBUTE.
THE NEW YORK GIANTS AND TITANS
HELD A MOMENT OF SILENCE
BEFORE THE START OF THE GAME
LAST NIGHT FLAGS FLEW AT
HALF-STAFF, YOU CAN SEE A
TRIBUTE ON THE HELMETS RUNNING
BACK JOHNSON PAID TRIBUTE BY
WRITING THE NAME OF ALL 26
VICTIMS ON HIS CLEATS.
HE SAID HE WANTED THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES TO KNOW HE'S THINKING
OF THEM.
>>> SPORTING GOODS CHAIN PLANS
TO PULL CERTAIN TYPES OF
SEMI-AUTOMATIC RIFLES OFF ITS
SHELVES NATIONWIDE.
DICK'S SPORTING GOODS MAKING
THE MOVE OUT OF RESPECT FOR
THE FAMILIES.
NOT CLEAR EXACTLY WHICH RIFLES
WILL BE PULLED OR HOW LONG
THEY WILL BE UNAVAILABLE.
INVESTIGATORS IN CONNECTICUT
LOOKING INTO WHETHER SUSPECT
LANZA TRIED TO PURCHASE A GUN
FROM A DICK'S STORE IN DANBURY,
CONNECTICUT.
>>> THE COMPANY THAT UNDER
WROTE FACEBOOK'S TROUBLED
PUBLIC STOCK OFFERING WILL PAY
FIVE MILLION DOLLARS TO
MASSACHUSETTS.
MORGAN STANLEY ACCUSED
DISCLOSING FALL IN REVENUE TO
CERTAIN ANALYSTS NOT THE
PUBLIC FACEBOOK STOCK PLUNGED
AFTER THE NEWS BECAME PUBLIC
MASSACHUSETTS SUED BECAUSE THE
DROP FORCED STATE OFFICIALS TO
REVISE EXPECTED REVENUE
ESTIMATES.
>>> ONE OF THOSE BUNDLE UP
MORNINGS OUT THERE.
>> IT IS.
[ UNINTELLIGIBLE ]
>>> ONE MORE COLD MORNING
BEFORE WE GET TO THE RAIN.
THE RAIN WILL BRING WARMER
WEATHER.
WE MAY SEE SNOW OUT OF THE
NEXT SYSTEM?
PROBABLY NOT THE SIERRA THEY
WILL GET A NICE DUMPING, IF
YOU WAIT UNTIL THURSDAY IT MAY
BE TOO LATE AND YOU MAY HAVE
ONE OF THOSE EIGHT OR NINE
HOUR TRIPS TO THE HIGH
COUNTRY.
LOOKING DOWN FROM
MOUNT TAMALPAIS BEAUTIFUL
PICTURE SAUSALITO, TIBURON,
SAN FRANCISCO, ALL THE WAY
DOWN TO SAN MATEO BRIDGE,
CLEAR THIS MORNING AND LIVE
DOPPLER 7 HD REINFORCING THE
FACT THAT WE HARDLY HAVE ANY
CLOUDS OVER LAND BUT WE HAVE
THEM OVER THE OCEAN AND A FEW
STRAY SHOWERS OVER THE OCEAN
KEEP FINGERS CROSSED THAT
WHERE I THINK THEY WILL STAY.
IT IS COOLER, 30s AND 40s THIS
MORNING THE SAME AROUND THE
MONTEREY BAY, TEMPERATURES
COOLEST AROUND SANTA CRUZ AND
WATSONVILLE UPPER 30s, LOW TO
MID 40s GILROY AND SALINAS, 49
MONTEREY.
PARTLY CLOUDY TODAY, SHOWERS
OVER THE OCEAN NEAR BEACH OR
TWO POSSIBLE FREEZING COLD
TONIGHT NORTH BAY, COLDEST IN
THE 20s FREEZE WARNING EAST
BAY VALLEYS BAY SHORELINE
SANTA ROSA -- SANTA CLARA
VALLEY A FROST ADVISORY
TONIGHT BEACHES NOT EXPECTING
FROST SOME VALLEYS CLOSE TO
THE BEACHES DEFINITELY, STORMY
PATTERN STARTS THURSDAY.
YESTERDAY'S COLD FRONT PULLING
WAY, JET STREAM DIVING DOWN
FROM ALASKA, PUSHING PUTTING
US IN THE COLDEST AIR NOW LOW
TO MID 50s THIS AFTERNOON.
NEXT SYSTEM UP TO THE NORTH
ALASKA NEXT BEHIND THAT IS
FARTHER SOUTH PACIFIC OCEAN
THAT'S WHY TEMPERATURES ARE
GOING TO RISE WITH THE NEXT
SYSTEMS, HIGHER TEMPERATURE
MORE LIKELY WE GET HEAVIER
RAIN.
A LOT OF US DEALING WITH FROST,
FIND YOUR CREDIT CARD OR ICE
SCRAPER.
5:00, LIGHT SHOWER POSSIBLE
NORTH BAY WHERE THE BEST
CHANCE OF RAIN OVERNIGHT GOING
TO BE THURSDAY MORNING MOST OF
US DRY EXCEPT NORTH BAY
HEAVIEST RAIN NORTH BAY FROM
11 UNTIL MOST OF THE EVENING
HOURS WHILE THE REST OF US ARE
STARTING TO GET LIGHT TO
MODERATE RAIN BY THE TIME WE
GET TO THURSDAY NIGHT,
HEAVIEST OF THE RAIN MORE THAN
AN INCH TO NEARLY TWO INCHES
IN THE NORTH BAY, THE REST OF
US HARDLY ANYWHERE IN THE
SANTA CLARA VALLEY TO QUARTER
TO HALF INCH BULK OF THE RAIN
AND WINDS FRIDAY FOR THE REST
OF BAY AREA SECONDARY SYSTEM
COMES IN SATURDAY AND SUNDAY,
HEAVY RAIN, GUSTY WINDS
POSSIBLY POWER OUTAGES AND
FLOODING OVER THE WEEKEND.
>>> BAY BRIDGE TOLL, METERING
LIGHTS ON, CENTER SECTION JUST
PAST TOLLS ON INCLINE STALL,
CARPOOL LANES AND FASTRAK
LANES GETTING BY NICELY.
INTO THE BAY BRIDGE OR
MacARTHUR MAZE I SHOULD SAY
TRAFFIC GETTING BUSY FIRST
REPORTS OF ACCIDENT WESTBOUND
UNIVERSITY OFF TO THE RIGHT
I'M NOT SEEING IT, MAYBE THE
CHP HAS THE WRONG LOCATION
DEFINITELY GETTING CROWDED
WESTBOUND ON 80 UP TO NAPA
SILVERADO TRAIL AT HARDMAN
LANES BLOCKED A CAR RAN INTO
THE CENTER DIVIDE AND SLAMMED
BACK ON TO THE ROADWAY.
NORTH 88 OMISSION BIG RIG AND
CAR OFF TO THE -- NORTH 880 AT
MISSION BIG RIG AND CAR OFF TO
THE SHOULDER.
ALL MASS TRANSIT LOOKING GOOD.
EVERYBODY IS RUNNING ON
SCHEDULE.
>>> WHAT DOESN'T WORK WELL
ON ED WINDSHIELDS, HOT WATER,
-- DO NOT POUR IT ON YOUR
WINDSHIELD IT WILL CRASH.
-- IT WILL CRACK.
>>> THIS MORNING THE QUEEN IS
STILL MAKING MYSTERY.
>>> HIGH TEMPERATURES TODAY,
PARTLY CLOUDY, MORE SUN COOLER
AS WE ARE IN THE HEART OF THIS
COLD AIR MASS, TOP OUT IN THE
LOW TO MID 50s.
UNSTABLE AIR MASS SNOW IN THE
MOUNTAINS THIS MORNING, ALSO
SNOW POSSIBLY UP IN THE SIERRA
AND IN FACT WE NEED CHAINS ON
80 AND FIVE THIS MORNING IF
YOU ARE HEADING TO THE SOUTH
WATCH OUT FOR RAIN AROUND
LOS ANGELES AND SAN DIEGO, MID
60s.
>>> 6:24.
QUEEN ELIZABETH IS MAKING
HISTORY TODAY.
THIS MORNING, THE QUEEN BECAME
THE FIRST MONARCH IN BRITAIN
IN MORE THAN 100 YEARS TO
SIT-IN ON A CABINET MEETING
THIS IS NEW VIDEO OF
PRIME MINISTER CAMERON BREATHE
GREETING HER AT THE DOOR.
QUEEN -- VICTORIA WAS THE LAST
MONARCH TO SIT IN.
>>> RECALL ON THIS MORNING FOR
A POPULAR TOY, THE TOYS EXPAND
WHEN PLACED IN WATER SOLD
UNDER THE NAME WATER BALLS,
GROWING SKULLS, AND FABULOUS
FLOWERS THE SIZE OF A MARBLE
CAN EXPAND TO 400 TIMES
ORIGINAL SIZE UNDERWATER BIG
TROUBLE IF A KID SWALLOWS ONE,
LIQUIDES IN THE BODY CAN CAUSE
THEM TO EXPAND.
>> --
>>> ANOTHER TOY COMPANY
CHANGING THE WAY IT MARKETS
ONE OF ITS MOST POPULAR
PRODUCTS TO BE MORE GENDER
INCLUSIVE, EASY BACK OVEN HAS
BEEN A FAVORITE OF GIRLS FOR
GENERATIONS UNTIL NOW IT WAS
ONLY IN PINK AND PURPLE AFTER
A 13-YEAR-OLD GIRL FROM
NEWT GINGRICH STARTED A
PETITION HASBRO AGREED TO --
NEW JERSEY STARTED A PETITION
HAS AGREED TO MAKE IT IN MORE
GENDER NEUTRAL COLORS.
>>> THE WATER FORD CRYSTAL
BALL IN TIMES WILL HAVE 288
NEW CRYSTAL PANELS WITH DOVES
TO MARK THE THEME LET THERE BE
PEACE.
THE NEW PANELS WILL REPLACE
OLD ONES.
PEOPLE ARE INVITED TO SEND IN
PERSONAL MESSAGES OF PEACE VIA
SOCIAL MEDIA.
SOME MESSAGES WILL BE READ
DURING A LIVE WEBCAST.
THE REST WILL BE POSTED ON THE
INTERNET.
>>> 6:26.
STILL AHEAD, TOXIC SITUATION
ON THE PENINSULA.
MISTAKE ONE FAMILY MADE THAT
FORCED A HAZ-MAT TEAM TO --
[ INAUDIBLE ]
>>> AHEAD WHAT IS HAPPENING
TODAY IN NEWTOWN AS PEOPLE,
ESPECIALLY STUDENTS, TRY TO
RETURN TO NORM
>> Reporter: A SPORTING GOODS
STORE IS GOING TO HAVE A GRAND
OPENING SATURDAY.
AFTER WHAT HAPPENED IN
CONNECTICUT LAST FRIDAY AND
THE FACT IT IS GOING TO BE
SELLING RIFLES THIS IS NOW A
CONTROVERSY.
THE STORY ON THE WAY.
>>> BACK-UP AT THE BAY BRIDGE
METERING LIGHTS ON, FASTRAK
AND COMMUTE LANES ARE GETTING
BY NICELY.
STALL ON INCLINE, FURTHER
DELAYS ON THE BAY BRIDGE.
WE'LL UPDATE THAT SITUATION IN
PALO ALTO WHEN WE COME BACK.
>>> GOOD TUESDAY MORNING.
BAY BRIDGE AND YOU CAN SEE
CLEAR AND THAT NORMALLY MEANS
COLD, RIGHT?
WE HAVE CLOUDS HEADED THIS WAY
FULL OF MOISTURE IT IS GOING
TO DUMP ON US.
>> I'M LOOKING AT THE BRIGHT
SIDE.
WHEN IT IS GOING TO BE WARMER
IN THE MORNING.
>>> ALWAYS A SILVER LINING
THOSE CLOUDS ARE GOING TO BE
FULL OF IT.
WE DON'T HAVE MANY CLOUDS THIS
MORNING OVER LAND LOOK HOW
QUIET OVER THE OCEAN THERE'S
THE STORMS WE TALKED ABOUT
YESTERDAY, A FEW CLAPS OF
THUNDER AND LIGHTNING OUT OF
THOSE, KEEP AN EYE, ESPECIALLY
NORTHWEST CORNER SONOMA COUNTY
ONE OR TWO MAY GRAZE YOUR
BEACHES.
FOR THE DAY TODAY DRY THIS
MORNING LOW TO MID 40s PARTLY
DOWDY BY NOON, MAY GET TO 40
BY 4:00, MORE SUN THAN
YESTERDAY, LOW TO -- MID 40s
BY THE EVENING.
INLAND LOW TO MID 40s 30s
NORTH BAY, 40s NOON NEAR 50
4:00, 30s BACK BY 7:00,
MEDICINE OVER TO THE COAST,
OCEAN SHOWERS LIKELY -- 4:00,
MID TO UPPER 40s, QUIETER
STARTING AT 7:00.
>>> THIS IS WHAT HAPPENED
EARLIER SAND HILL ROAD IN
PALO ALTO, DRIVER HIT THE FIRE
HYDRANT AND FLOODED SAND HILL
ROAD BOTH DIRECTIONS BETWEEN
ARBORETUM AND EL CAMINO, STILL
SHUTDOWN THEY HOPE TO HAVE
THAT OPEN IN THE NEXT 10
MINUTES THEY'VE GOT THE
HYDRANT CAPPED.
BACK TO THE SAN MATEO BRIDGE,
A LITTLE BIZ , TAIL LIGHTS
WESTBOUND, A FEW -- BRAKE
LIGHTS FLAT SECTION NORTH --
ACCIDENT NORTHBOUND 680 AT
DUBLIN TRUCK SCALES OFF TO THE
SHOULDER.
>>> BREAKING NEWS FROM
COLORADO.
THIS IS IN THAT DENVER AREA
AND THESE ARE LIVE PICTURES
FROM WELLS COUNTY YOU CAN SEE
A LOT OF AUTHORITIES ON SCENE
OF WHAT THEY ARE CALLING A
MURDER-SUICIDE AT A
SUBDIVISION OUTSIDE OF DENVER.
THEY ARE SAYING THAT AT LEAST
FOUR ARE DEAD, POSSIBLY FIVE.
AGAIN, MURDER-SUICIDE ON HOT
SPRINGS DRIVE.
POLICE TAPE, INVESTIGATORS ON
THE SCENE.
TRAGIC SITUATION.
VICTIMS AND CIRCUMSTANCES OF
THE DEATHS NOT BEING RELEASED.
THIS HAPPENING IN THE PAST
HOUR OR SO, BREAKING NEWS FROM
COLORADO, FOUR OR FIVE DEAD IN
A MURDER-SUICIDE.
>>> FUNERALS CONTINUE TODAY
FOR THE VICK OF THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
IN THE LAST HOUR STUDENTS HAVE
TAKEN THE FIRST STEP TOWARD
RETURNING TO SCHOOL.
KATIE MARZULLO JOIN US LIVE
FROM THE NEWSROOM.
>> Reporter: FOUR MORE
FUNERALS SCHEDULED FOR TODAY
IN NEWTON, THREE STUDENTS AND
ONE TEACHER.
TWO 6-YEAR-OLD BOYS HAVE
ALREADY BEEN LAID TO REST.
SO MUCH GRIEF AND YET
BACK-TO-SCHOOL FOR THE
DISTRICT.
ALL SCHOOLS REOPEN EXCEPT OF
COURSE, SANDY HOOK.
POLICE SAY THE COOL COULD
REMAIN A CRIME SCENE FOR
MONTHS.
UP TO 100 VOLUNTEERS IN
NEIGHBORING TOWN ARE WORKING
TO GET UNUSED MIDDLE SCHOOL
READY FOR SANDY HOOK STUDENTS
TO ATTEND, NO WORD ON WHEN.
>> DEFINITELY AT THE LEAST
WANT TO GIVE THE CHILDREN THE
OPPORTUNITY TO SEE THEIR NEW
SCHOOL, AND TO BE AS
COMFORTABLE AS THEY CAN IN
THAT NEW AREA.
>> Reporter: AS FOR THE
INVESTIGATION, POLICE ARE
TRYING TO GET AS MUCH
INFORMATION AS POSSIBLE OUT OF
A DAMAGED COMPUTER FOUND AT
THE HOME OF SHOOTING ADAM
LANZA AND HIS MOTHER NANCY.
THEY HOPE TO RECOVER SOMETHING
THAT WILL POINT TO A MOTIVE.
AUTHORITIES HAVE TOLD ABC NEWS
THE WEAPONS WERE USED WERE
PURCHASED BY NANCY AND SHE
TOOK ADAM TO A FIRING RANGE AT
LEAST ONCE.
WE'VE LEARNED OF A NEW
HEARTWRENCHING DETAIL ABOUT
ONE OF THE VICTIMS,
29-YEAR-OLD TEACHER WOULD HAVE
BECOME ENGAGED ON NEW YEAR'S
EVE, SHE DIDN'T KNOW HER
BOYFRIEND ASKED HER PARENTS
PERMISSION TO PROPOSE DAYS
BEFORE THE SHOOTING.
KATIE MARZULLO, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> IN THE WAKE OF WHAT
HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT, THE
NATION'S SECOND LARGEST
PENSION PLAN IS QUICKLY
DISTANCING ITSELF FROM AN
UNEXPECTED CONNECTION TO THE
TRAGEDY.
THE CALIFORNIA STATE TEACHERS
?áÑ REVEALED
YESTERDAY IT WAS REVIEWING ITS
INVESTMENT WITH THE EQUITY
FIRM CERBERUS WHO OWNS BUSH
MASTER THE MAKER IN OF THE
RIFLE USED IN THE SHOOTING.
NEW THIS MORNING, CERBERUS
ANNOUNCED IT WAS PUTTING THAT
PART OF THE COMPANY UP FOR
SALE.
>>> GUN SALES ARE UP FOLLOWING
THE SCHOOL SHOOTING AS GUN
OWNERS WORRY ABOUT NEW
LEGISLATION.
THERE'S NEW CONTROVERSY OVER A
NEW GUN STORE IN THE SOUTH
BAY.
>> Reporter: IN LOS GATOS
UNIVERSITY AVENUE THIS COMING
SATURDAY, TELL SPORTS HAVING
ITS GRAND OPENING, --
TELL SPORTS HAVING ITS GRAND
OPENING, IT HAS BEEN PLANNED
FOR QUITE A WHITE THERE IS
CONTROVERSY.
THIS IS A SPORTING GOODS STORE
GOING TO BE SELLING FISHING
GEAR, ALSO DESCRIBED AS A HIGH
END CUSTOM GUN SHOP, THAT'S
WHERE THE DEBATE COMES IN.
>> KILL THINGS.
THAT'S WHY AS A COMMUNITY, WE
WOULD LIKE TO KNOW ABOUT THAT
PRODUCT BEFORE IT IS AVAILABLE
ON OUR SHELVES IN OUR OUTLETS.
>> ANY TIME YOU CAN BRING
BUSINESS TO TOWN IT IS
POSITIVE.
I DON'T THINK THAT THERE IS --
THEY ARE GOING TO BE HANDING
OUT GUNS LIKE CANDY, WHY IS IT
A REAL PROBLEM?
>> REPORTER: DEBORAH IS NOT
GOING TO GET ANY HELP FROM
CITY HALL -- THE TOWN MANAGER
SAYS THE CODE IS FROM 1987 NO
REVIEW ON A RETAILER WANTING
TO SELL FIREARMS.
IN SACRAMENTO, ACTION ABOUT
TOUGHER GUN CONTROL LAWS,
SENATOR LELAND YE AMONG OTHERS
PLANNING TO WRITE TOUGHER LAWS
EFFORT IN WASHINGTON, D.C. TO
GET IT GOING THOSE WHO SUPPORT
FIREARMS RIGHTS, SAY IF
SOMEONE WANTS TO KILL SOMEBODY
THEY ARE GOING TO DO IT WITH
OR WITHOUT AN AUTOMATIC OR
SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPON.
TERRY McSWEENEY, ABC7 NEWS.
>>> ABC NEWS WILL CONTINUE TO
COVER THE TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN.
EXPRESS YOUR SYMPATHY BY
POSTING THIS BADGE TO YOUR
FACEBOOK WALL.
GO TO FACEBOOK.COM/ABC7NEWS.
>>> TRAFFIC AND WEATHER
TOGETHER, NEXT.
OUTSIDE RIGHT NOW, EMBARCADERO,
DRY STREETS, THAT IS GOING TO
CHANGE IN THE NEXT COUPLE OF
DAYS.
>>> HAZ-MAT TEAM SURROUNDS
PENINSULA MOBILE HOME PARK.
THE MISTAKE THAT ñ  Ñ,ÑzÑpríÑY"t
>>> TEMPERATURES ARE COLDER
THIS MORNING, MID TO UPPER 30s
NORTH BAY VALLEYS TOWARDS
CONCORD, LOW TO MID 40s FOR
THE REST OF US, TEMPERATURES
ANYWHERE FROM 8 TO 21° COOLER
THAN YESTERDAY, PUT THE
UMBRELLA AN ADD HEAVIER COAT,
SUNGLASSES THIS AFTERNOON
PARTLY CLOUDY, LOW TO MID 50s
SHOWERS OVER THE OCEAN WATER
CLOSER TO ONE OR TWO OF OUR
BEACHES, MAYBE.
TOMORROW FROST EVERYWHERE HIGH
CLOUDS AND SUN IN THE
AFTERNOON, GET READY FOR WET
BREWSTER -- BLUSTERY
CONDITIONS THURSDAY AND
FRIDAY.
>>> NORTH 87 AS YOU APPROACH
KURTNER SLOW DEW ACCIDENT
BLOCKING LANE NORTH 680 DUBLIN
TRUCK SCALES STALL PARTIALLY
BLOCKING RIGHT LANE NORTH 880
ALVARADO BOULEVARD REPORTS OF
ACCIDENT BLOCKING RIGHT LANE.
LIVE LOOK AT BAY BRIDGE TOLL,
METERING LIGHTS ON, TRAFFIC
BACKING TOWARDS THE MacARTHUR
MAZE.
EARLIER STALL UPPER DECK
CLEARED, SLOW CONDITIONS AS
YOU MAKE YOUR WAY WESTBOUND.
>>> 6:40.
BREAKING NEWS OUT OF CONCORD.
THE SEARCH WAY FOR THE SMASH
AND GRAB THIEF WHO USED A CAR
TO BREAK INTO A STORE.
POLICE SAY THE DRIVER USED
THIS CAR TO PLOW INTO THE
GAMESTOP STORE ON IGNACIO
VALLEY ROAD.
THE DRIVER TOOK MERCHANDISE,
INCLUDING USED CELL PHONES
WHICH INVESTIGATORS MAY BE
ABLE TO TRACE.
THE CRASH HAPPENED AROUND 4:00
THIS MORNING.
CONCORD POLICE BELIEVE THE CAR
MAY BE STOLEN.
>>> THIS MORNING EIGHT
RECOVERING AFTER BEING EXPOSED
TO TOXIC CHEMICALS, INCLUDING
PART OF A SAN MATEO COUNTY
HAZ-MAT CREW EIGHT WERE RUSHED
TO THE HOSPITAL AFTER BEING
EXPOSED TO CHEMICALS FROM A
HOUSE BUG BOMB, TWO SET OFF
THE DEVICE INSIDE THE TRAILER
BUT DID NOT LEAVE, THE COUPLE
WITH A NEIGHBOR BECAME ILL.
WHEN RESPONDERS ARRIVED THEY
WENT IN WITHOUT REALIZING
THERE WAS TOXIC AIR INSIDE.
ALL EIGHT WERE TAKEN TO THE
HOSPITAL AND ARE EXPECTED TO
BE FINE.
>>> 6:41.
AHEAD, AVOIDING THE FISCAL
CLIFF.
POTENTIAL DEAL HOUSE SPEAKER
BOEHNER IS TRYING TO SELL
HOUSE REPUBLICANS.
>>> TRADING UNDERWAY ON WALL
STREET(añ;x;x;x;x;x
.
>> WELCOME BACK.
LIVE DOPPLER 7 HD LAST THREE
HOURS IN MOTION, SHOWERS OVER
THE OCEAN GETTING CLOSE TO SEA
RANCHING FALLING PART AS THEY
COME DOWN THE MENDOCINO COUNTY
COAST, A FEW LIGHTNING BOLTS
OUT OF THAT STORM EARLIER.
RAINING NOW GRAPEVINE, AROUND
L.A., SNOW IN THE SIERRA AND
HIGHER ELEVATIONS AROUND MOUNT
SHASTA WHERE IT IS GOING TO
STAY THE BETTER PART OF TODAY
50s EVERYWHERE SEPTA 39,
YOSEMITE 45, MID TO UPPER --
60s, SAN DIEGO, LOS ANGELES
AND PALM SPRINGS.
STRAIGHT AHEAN
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA."
>>> IN DIFFICULT TIMES LIKE
THESE, JOSH, I THINK A LITTLE
NOSTALGIA, A LITTLE SONG,
REALLY GOOD FOR EVERYBODY.
DO THEY SING?
>> THEY SING A FEW BARS DURING
THE INTERVIEW, WE ARE GOING TO
HAVE A PERFORMANCE COMING UP
AND AGAIN YOU ARE RIGHT, NOSE
STALLIA, A LITTLE BIT OF --
NOSTALGIA A LITTLE BIT OF
COMFORT THIS MORNING.
>>> THIS MORNINGER SPEAKER
BANE -- THIS MORNING HOUSE
SPEAKER BOEHNER WILL
-- THE OFFER WOULD NOT CHANGE
THE ELIGIBILITY AGE FOR
MEDICARE.
[ UNINTELLIGIBLE ]
>>> NEWTOWN TRAGEDY IS HAVING
A RIPPLE EFFECT ON SPORTING
GOODS INDUSTRY.
>> THERE ARE GOOD DEALS FOR
ANYONE SHOPPING FOR A NEW
TRUCK.
JANE KING IS LIVE AT THE NEW
YORK STOCK EXCHANGE.
>>> GOOD MORNING.
MANAGER AT DICK'S SPORTING
GOODS IN DANBURY, CONNECTICUT,
TEMPORARILY HALTING SALES OF
ALL SEMI-AUTOMATIC WEAPONS,
CERBERUS CAPITAL PRIVATE
EQUITY FIRM MANAGE MORE THAN
20 BILLION DOLLARS IS GOING TO
SELL ITS STAKE IN FREEDOM
GROUP WHICH MANUFACTURES THE
BUSHMASTER RIFLE THAT
AUTHORITIES SAY LANZA USED TO
MURDER HIS VICTIMS.
CERBERUS SAID IT WAS SHOCKED
AND SADDENED BY THE ATTACK.
THIS MORNING A LITTLE HIGHER,
THERE DOES SEEM TO BE SOME
PROGRESS GOING ON IN
WASHINGTON.
THAT'S HIGHER DAY BASED ON
WHAT WE HAD YESTERDAY WHICH
WAS POSITIVE MOVEMENT THERE
TOWARD THE MIDDLE BOTH SIDES
TALKING A DEAL.
BLOOMBERG INDEX TRADING UP.
CONTINUING TO WATCH APPLE
TODAY, INVESTORS WATCHING
LEGAL BATTLE BETWEEN APPLE AND
SAMSUNG OVER SMARTPHONE
TECHNOLOGY AND TRY TO FIGURE
OUT HOW WELL THE iPHONE IS OR
ISN'T SELLING.
SAMSUNG DROPPING SOME OF IS
DEMANDS AGAINST APPLE
TECHNOLOGY IN EUROPE.
DEALER INCENTIVES ON PICK-UP
TRUCKS GETTING BETTER, GENERAL
MOTORS OFFERING UP TO $9,000
OFF A GLUT OF CHEVIES, AND
PICK-UPS, CLOSE TO $4500 OVER
2013 MODELS.
LIVE AT THE NEW YORK STOCK
EXCHANGE, I'M JANE KING.
>>> IT IS COLD THIS MORNING.
GOING TO GET COLDER?
>> YES WE WILL HAVE FROST
TOMORROW MORNING JUST ABOUT
ALL AREAS NOT THIS MORNING
MAINLY NORTH BAY VALLEYS,
APOLOGIZE, I FOR TO MENTION,
80 AND 50, YOU NEED CHAINS.
-- SOME OF THE CLOUDS HUGGING
THE SIERRA THIS MORNING
BRINGING SNOW THERE, YOU CAN
SEE HOW UNLIMITED THE
VISIBILITY IS RIGHT NOW.
LET'S LOOK AT LIVE DOPPLER 7
HD, SPINNING ON TOP OF MOUNT
ST. HELENA OVER THE OCEAN
CHECKING OUT STORMS THAT ARE
OUT THERE AND FALLING APART AS
THEY HEAD TOWARDS OUR
NEIGHBORHOODS.
MID TO UPPER 30s FAIRFIELD,
NAPA, SANTA ROSA, CONCORD, LOW
TO MID 40s FOR THE REST OF US,
HALF MOON BAY WARM SPOT AT 48°,
UPPER 30s, WATSONVILLE,
SANTA CRUZ LOW TO MID 40s
GILROY AND SALINAS, MONTEREY
WARM SPOT, 49.
TODAY PARTLY CLOUDY, SHOWERS
OVER THE OCEAN, FREEZING COLD
TONIGHT, THE STORMY PATTERN
FOR THURSDAY, IT STARS
THURSDAY IT LASTS FRIDAY, --
IT STARTS THURSDAY, IT LASTS
FRIDAY THROUGH SUNDAY, IF YOU
HAVE WEEKEND PLANS YOU ARE
GOING TO GET WET.
IF YOU HAVE BASEBALL PLANS,
YOU MAY NOT PLAY.
HEART OF THE COLD AIR NOW JET
STREAM FROM CANADA.
BEHIND THAT SYSTEM, SYSTEMS
COMING FROM THE GULF OF ALASKA,
ONE FROM THE PACIFIC, A LITTLE
FARTHER SOUTH.
EACH ONE IS GOING TO RAISE OUR
TEMPERATURE AND BRING HEAVIER
AMOUNTS OF RAIN.
WE ARE GOING TO GET A ONE-TWO
PUNCH.
7:00 TOMORROW MORNING FROST
EVERYWHERE EXCEPT BEACHES,
SOME OF THE VALLEYS NEAR THE
BEACHES COULD HAVE FROST, BE
CAREFUL WITH THAT PET, PLANTS
AND TO A LESSER EXTENT PIPES
TONIGHT.
5:00, STRAY SHOWER POSSIBLE IN
THE NORTH BAY, OVERNIGHT BEST
CHANCE OF RAIN NORTH BAY
THROUGH 7:00.
AS WE HEAD INTO NOON, STEADIER
RAIN MOVING THROUGH THE HEART
OF THE BAY, SAN FRANCISCO,
OAKLAND, 80 TOWARDS FAIRFIELD,
DURING THE AFTERNOON INTO THE
EVENING, START TO SLIDE INTO
THE SOUTH BAY REST OF US LIGHT
TO MODERATE, HEAVY AT TIMES
NORTH BAY RAIN GOING TO STAY
MODERATE TO HEAVY NORTH BAY
THROUGH THURSDAY EVENING
HEAVIEST RAINFALL, ONE TO TWO
INCHES NORTH BAY, THE REST OF
US JUST A TRACE SOUTH BAY UP
TO AN INCH IN THE NORTH BAY
VALLEYS, JUST THE BEGINNING OF
THE STORM.
HARDER PUSH OF WET WEATHER FOR
THE REST OF US WEDNESDAY WHEN
IT WILL GET BREEZY AND SECOND
STORM COMES IN SATURDAY WITH
FLOODING RAIN AND POSSIBILITY
OF POWER OUTAGES BY THE TIME
MONDAY ROLLS AROUND IT IS OVER.
>>> LIVE SHOT SOUTH 101 PAST
LUCAS VALLEY ROAD TERRA LINDA
AREA FARTHER NORTH FROM THAT
NEAR ALAMEDA DELL DOUGH STALL
BLOCKING LANE TWO, BACKING
TOWARDS -- NOVATO ONCE YOU GET
HERE EVERYTHING IS AT THE
LIMIT PAST THE CIVIC CENTER
SOUTHBOUND.
SOUTHBOUND 680 AT MONUMENT,
FIRST REPORTS OF ACCIDENT
BLOCKING TRAFFIC, SOME RED
SENSORS, SLOW APPROACHING THE
SCENE.
NORTH 87 SAN JOSE KURTNER
ACCIDENT TWO LEFT LANES, SLOW
APPROACHING THERE AS WELL.
SOUTHBOUND 680 AT DUBLIN TRUCK
SCALES ACCIDENT PARDON ME
STALL PARTIALLY BLOCKING RIGHT
LANE NORTHBOUND 880 ALVARADO
BOULEVARD CAR CLEARED OUT OF
LANES.
NORTHBOUND 680 McKEY CAR AND
BIG RIG BLOCKING LANE OF
TRAFFIC SLOW AS YOU HEAD NORTH
ON 680 THROUGH SAN JOSE.
>>> 6:52.
>>> STRAIGHT AHEAD, FIVE
THINGS TO KNOW BEFORE YOU GO.
>> THE ABC7 MORNING NEWS
>>> GOOD TUESDAY MORNING.
SUN ABOUT TO RISE, GORGEOUS
SHOT LOOKING AT FERRY BUILDING
IN SAN FRANCISCO AND BRIDGE
TRAFFIC DOING FINE.
IT IS CLEAR AND COLD.
DETAILS IF MIKE IN A SECOND.
>>> HERE ARE FIVE THINGS TO
KNOW BEFORE YOU GO:
>> NUMBER ONE, BREAKING NEWS
OUT OF COLORADO FOUR PEOPLE
HAVE BEEN FOUND DEAD FOLLOWING
AN PATIENT MURDER-SUICIDE.
IT WAS ORIGINALLY REPORTED TO
BE FIVE THAT NUMBER HAS BEEN
CHANGED TO FOUR.
INVESTIGATORS ON THE SCENE
NORTH OF DENVER.
>> NUMBER TWO, BREAKING NEWS
FROM CONCORD, POLICE BELIEVE A
THIEF USED A STOLEN CAR TO
CRASH INTO THE FRONT OF A
VIDEO GAME STORE TO STEAL
MERCHANDISE.
THE DRIVER TOOK OFF WITH
SEVERAL USED.
PHONES.
>> NUMBER THREE, STUDENTS IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT GOING
BACK-TO-SCHOOL FOR THE FIRST
TIME SINCE FRIDAY ALL STUDENTS
EXCEPT THOSE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY GO TO SCHOOL IN A
NEIGHBORING TOWN WHERE IT IS
GOING TO BE PREPARE NO WORD ON
WHEN THEY WILL GO BACK TO
CLASS FOUR MORE FUNERALS
TODAY.
>> NUMBER FOUR, OPENING OF A
GUN SHOP IN LOS GATOS IS
FACING CHALLENGES BY SOME WHO
CLAIM IT TOO CLOSE TO PARKS
AND SCHOOLS.
GUN SALES ACROSS THE NATION
ARE ON THE RISE AS BUYERS
PURCHASE WEAPONS BEFORE
CONGRESS PASSES NEW
RESTRICTIONS.
>>> NUMBER FIVE, POTENTIAL
SINKHOLE CAUSING CONCERNS IN
CONTRA COSTA COUNTY, MARSH
CREEK BETWEEN DEER VALLEY AND
PINE LANE IN CLAYTON CLOSED.
RECENT RAIN HAS COMPROMISED
THE ROAD.
>> LET'S GET ONE FINAL CHECK
ON WEATHER AND TRAFFIC.
>>> STILL TRACKING SHOWERS AND
THUNDERSTORMS OVER THE OCEAN
WITH LIVE DOPPLER, PICKING UP
YELLOWS, THAT WAS A
THUNDERSTORM EARLIER WITH
PRESENT TRACK GOING TO SLIDE
THE SONOMA COUNTY COAST THIS
IS THE MOST LIKELY AREA TO GET
A SHOWER OUT OF THIS STORM
MOST WILL STAY OVER THE OCEAN,
SEA RANCH POSSIBLY TOWARDS
BODEGA AND POINT REYES.
FOR THE REST OF US, PARTLY
CLOUDY AND COOLER WITH LOW TO
MID 50s.
BIG STORM ON THE WAY THURSDAY
AND FROST TONIGHT.
>>> TOLL PLAZA, METERING
LIGHTS ON, FASTRAK AND CARPOOL
LANES MOVING NICELY, SLUGGISH
UPPER DECK WESTBOUND.
COUPLE OF ACCIDENTS 87 AT
KURTNER, ACCIDENT BLOCKING
RIGHT LANE.
NORTH 880 McKEY, RIGHT LANE
BLOCKED ACCIDENT INVOLVING BIG
RIG POLICE ON SCENE.
DRIVE TIMES HEADING OUT NOW,
80 WESTBOUND TOWARDS THE MAZE
OUT OF CARQUINEZ BRIDGE AREA
25 MINUTES, NOT BAD.
SLOW OUT OF ANTIOCH HIGHWAY 4
WEST TYPICAL AND SLOW UP AND
OVER THE ALTAMONT TOWARDS
LIVERMORE INTO THE DUBLIN
PLEASANTON AREA.
OTHERWISE NOT BAD.
CHILLY, BUT NOT BAD.
>>> THE ABC7 MORNING NEWS
CONTINUES IN 25 MINUTES WITH
NEWS, WEATHER AND TRAFFIC,
DURING "GOOD MORNING AMERICA."
>> VERY SHORTLY THERE WILL BE
A NEWS CONFERENCE, HERE'S A
LIVE PICTURE FROM
WASHINGTON, D.C..
JOHN BOEHNER WITH WILL HOLD
THAT CONFERENCE ON FISCAL
CLIFF TALKS.
WE ARE GETTING REPORTS THAT
BOEHNER WILL PROPOSE EXTENDING
BUSH ERA TAX RATES FOR THOSE
EARNING $250,000 OR LESS.
MORE COMING UP.
>>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA.
BREAKING NEWS OVERNIGHT.
A TOP NETWORK FOREIGN
CORRESPONDENT FREED IN A HAIL OF
GUNFIRE AFTER BEING KIDNAPPED
FOR FIVE DAYS IN SYRIA.
RICHARD ENGEL AND HIS CREW.
HELD BOUND AND BLINDFOLDED,
DETAILS STILL COMING IN ON HIS
HARROWING ORDEAL.
>>> THIS MORNING, TWO LITTLE
SANDY HOOK BOYS LAID TO REST IN
EMOTIONAL TRIBUTES.
A HEARTBREAKING MOTHER'S SALUTE,
SAYING THE SKY IS CRYING.
THIS, AS THE REST OF THE
STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN HEAD BACK TO
SCHOOL RIGHT NOW.
WE'RE LIVE ON THE SCENE.
>>> WINTER WEATHER SLAM.
100-MILE-PER-HOUR WINDS SLAM THE
NORTHWEST.