HOW ABOUT GETTING THEM A
SUBSCRIPTION OF THE FRUIT
AND VEGGIE OF THE MONTH CLUB?
FARMERS IN YOUR AREA
HARVEST AND BRING FRUITS AND
VEGETABLES RIGHT TO YOUR DOOR.
I LOVE THIS IDEA BECAUSE
IT'S A GREAT WAY TO INTRODUCE
PEOPLE TO FRUITS AND VEGETABLES
THEY WOULDN'T TRY.
THE BEST WAY TO FIND
THIS SERVICE NEAR YOU IS
TO GO ON THE INTERNET.
SOME OTHER GREAT GIFT IDEAS
COULD BE GIVING
SOMEONE A GYM MEMBERSHIP,
SOME FITNESS DVDS, OR
EVEN A SUBSCRIPTION
TO HEALTH MAGAZINE.
COMING UP, I LOVE
PRETZELS, I HAVEN'T
HAD ONE IN FOREVER.
BUT FIRST.
IT'S A GREAT EXERCISE
FOR ANYONE BASICALLY
9 YEARS TO 90 YEARS.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS EVERYONE.
TODAY WE'RE
UNWRAPPING SOME GREAT
HOLIDAY GIFT IDEAS.
RIGHT HERE FROM
THE AMAZING STATS
CHRISTMAS STORE.
SO WHEN YOU'RE MAKING YOUR
LIST AND CHECKING IT TWICE
MAKE SURE THOSE IDEAS
PROMOTE HEALTH
AND WELLNESS.
WHEN YOU'RE THINKING OF
BUYING TOYS FOR YOUR KIDS
OR NIECES AND NEPHEWS THIS YEAR
WHY NOT INCLUDE
SPORTING EQUIPMENT,
SOMETHING TO ENCOURAGE THEM
TO GET OUTSIDE AND PLAY
AND WILL ENCOURAGE YOU
TO GET OUT WITH THEM.
EVERYONE LOVES A BALL.
THEY HAVE THESE HIGH
TECH BALLS NOW THAT HAVE
SPECIAL GLASSES,
I SAY WHATEVER IT TAKES TO
GET THE FAMILY MOVING
IS WHAT YOU NEED.
IS THERE SOMEONE IN
YOUR LIFE THAT SPENDS A
LOT OF TIME TRAVELING
AND HAS NO TIME
FOR THE GYM.
GET THEM A GYM
IN A BRIEF CASE.
IT'S CALLED THE
JOURNEY GYM.
YOU NEED A BIG VARIETY
TO KEEP THEM INTERESTED.
YOU NEED TO INCLUDE
RESISTANCE AND CARDIO
IN YOUR ROUTINE.
THIS LITTLE TINY GYM IS
A GREAT WAY TO COMBINE
EVERYTHING IN ONE SMALL BUNDLE.
IT'S GOT ALL THESE
INTERESTING RESISTANT
BANDS INSIDE OF IT.
THAT WAY YOU CAN USE
THAT FOR YOUR RESISTANCE
TRAINING AND IT'S BASICALLY
LIKE AN AEROBIC STEP FOR STEP UP
OR PLYOMETRIC EXERCISES.
HOW DO I DO IT?
LET ME SHOW YOU THE
RESISTANCE EXERCISES HERE.
SO DEPLOY THE HANDLE
WITH THIS BUTTON.
THAT WAY THERE IS NO
PRESSURE ON MY JOINTS
WHILE I'M GETTING READY HERE.
I'M JUST GOING TO SHOW
YOU A BASIC BICEP CURL.
YOU'RE SHAKING.
I'VE GOT TWO BANDS HERE.
I WAS SHOCKED HERE.
I DIDN'T REALIZE THAT WAS
QUITE SO MUCH RESISTANCE.
IT'S A GOOD WORKOUT,
I LIFT A LOT AND BELIEVE ME.
I JUST SAW THAT.
IT STARTED SHAKING.
OBVIOUSLY STRONG AND THIS
IS MAKING YOU WORKOUT.
AND THIS IS TWO BANDS, AND
THERE IS UP TO FIVE THERE
SO IT CAN CHALLENGE YOU.
THIS IS KIND OF AN ALL IN ONE
SOLUTION AND IF I GO ON A
ROAD TRIP I THROW IT IN MY CAR.
IT'S A PERFECT WAY TO
MAKE SURE YOU DON'T
SKIP YOUR WORKOUTS.
FOR THE REALLY ADVENTUROUS
PERSON ON YOUR LIST HOW
ABOUT A PAIR OF KANGAROO JUMPS.
THESE LOOK LIKE
SKY BOOTS RIGHT.
YOUR FOOT IS IN THERE
NICE AND FIRM AND TIGHT.
AND I'M GOING TO
BE OKAY IN THEM.
TOTALLY IF YOU CAN STAND
UP STRAIGHT YOU'RE GOOD.
THIS IS ALL ABOUT
HAVING FUN WHILE
WERE WORKING OUT.
IT'S A GREAT EXERCISE
FOR ANYONE NINE YEARS
TO NINETY YEARS.
SO IT ABSORBS THE IMPACT,
BUILDS BONE DENSITY AND
YOU BURN TONS OF CALORIES.
I TEACH AEROBICS IN
THEM, SO I LITERALLY
DO AEROBIC TYPE STEPS.
REMEMBER THE DAY'S RIGHT.
KNEE LIFTS.
SKI FRONT AND BACK.
SO YOU'RE REALLY
WORKING YOUR MUSCLES ON
THE INSIDE OF YOUR BODY.
AND JOG FORWARD AND BACK.
JUMPING JACKS.
GO, GO , GO, GO.
WOOO.
FAST.
OFF WE GO.
I'M NOT RUNNING AS MUCH.
STILL AHEAD.
YOU KNOW I CALL WHAT
I DOUGH PLAYING.
YEAH IT IS.
I PLAYED IN THE
KITCHEN TODAY.
THIS WOULD BE FUN TO
HAPPY HOLIDAYS EVERYONE SO
ONE OF THE BIGGEST ISSUES
I FACE DURING THE HOLIDAY SEASON
IS I WANT TO GO TO ALL THESE
HOLIDAY PARTIES AND DINNERS BUTI
DON'T WANT TO BLOW MY DIET.
SO I WANTED TO SHARE WITH
YOU THREE GREAT TIPS THAT
I FOUND HELPED ME HAVE FUN
DURING THE HOLIDAY SEASON.
NUMBER ONE, YOU WANT TO
MAKE SURE YOU EAT DINNER
BEFORE YOU GO OUT.
AND WHEN YOU GET THERE,
DON'T BRACE, GRAB A SMALL
PLATE, FILL IT UP WITH
HEALTHY CHOICES AND MOVE
AWAY FROM THE FOOD TABLE.
NUMBER TWO YOU'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO WATCH YOUR ALCOHOL
AND SKIP THE EGGNOG ALL TOGETHER
IT'S LOADED WITH CALORIES,
INSTEAD TRY ONE OF MY FAUX
COCKTAILS OR BETTER YET
BE THE DESIGNATED DRIVER.
AND NUMBER THREE I ALWAYS LIKE
TO BRING SOMETHING TO THE PARTYI
CAN ENJOY AND KNOW IS HEALTHY.
ARE YOU LOOKING FOR THAT
PERFECT TREAT THAT YOU CAN
TAKE TO THE NEXT PARTY
THAT'S NOT LOADED IN
CALORIES, ME TOO, SO I WAS
LOOKING THROUGH MY COOK BOOK
AND I NOTICED CHEF ALEXANDER'S
COOK BOOKS, AND I THOUGHT
I'M GOING TO CALL DEVIN.
SO MY FAVORITE KITCHEN
ELF DEVIN ALEXANDER.
HEY HOW ARE YOU?
GREAT I'M SO
EXCITED TO BE HERE.
OKAY SO IT'S THE HOLIDAYS
WE NEED TO SET FOR PARTIES
AND I THOUGHT WE NEED SOME
GOOD TREATS, WHAT
CAN WE MAKE TODAY?
I'M MAKING SOFT
PRETZEL CANDY CANES.
ACTUALLY YOU AND
I ARE MAKING SOFT
PRETZEL CANDY CANES.
THESE ARE SO EASY
AND FUN FOR CHILDREN.
YOU CAN GET YOUR KIDS
INVOLVED WITH THESE AND
THEY WILL HAVE A BLAST AND
IF YOU'RE TAKING THESE TO
A PARTY YOU WANT TO MAKE
THEM BOILED BUT NOT BAKED,
I'LL TELL YOU MORE ABOUT
THAT LATER AND WE'RE
ALSO MAKING RUM BALLS.
OKAY WE'RE CUTTING
THIS, THIS IS WHOLE
WHEAT PIZZA DOUGH.
EASY.
THE GOAL WHERE IS TO ROLL
THEM INTO 24 INCH ROPES.
YOU DO BY SIMPLY ON
YOUR CUTTING BOARD.
GO LIKE THIS FIRST.
YOU WANT PRESSURE ON
THERE BECAUSE YOU DON'T
WANT AIR BUBBLE IN IT.
THAT'S IMPORTANT.
YOU KNOW WHAT I LOVE ABOUT
COOKING WITH YOU IS WERE
ALWAYS BAKING SOMETHING
AND I THINK BAKING AND I
THINK CALORIES YOU CAN'T
HAVE BAKED GOODS
AND BE HEALTH AND CALORIE
CONSCIOUS, BUT YOU CAN YOU
JUST HAVE TO DO IT RIGHT.
AND BE CREATIVE, I SAID
THE AMOUNT OF CALORIES YOU
HAVE IN THE SUGAR,
AND THIS IS WHOLE WHEAT DOUGH
AND WE PUT SOME SUGAR, BECAUSE
THEY ARE CINNAMON SUGAR PRETZELS
BUT WE USE COCONUT SUGAR,
AND IT IS IMPORTANT THAT
THEY'RE 12 INCHES OR LONGER
AND THEY STAY 12 INCHES.
YOU LINK THEM
TOGETHER AT ONE END
AND TWIRL IT TOGETHER.
LIKE SO.
YOU WANT LOTS
OF TWIRLS IN IT.
AS TIGHTLY AS POSSIBLE
THEY LOOK COOLER.
THAT WOULD BE
YOUR CANDY CANE.
THE NEXT STEP IS WE
HAVE BOILING WATER
WE'RE PUTTING BAKING SODA IN.
SO NOW OUR GOAL HERE, THIS
IS THE TRICKY PART IS
GETTING THESE TO STAY
IN THIS SHAPE AS
THEY'RE FORMING.
SO WHAT I DO, YOU CAN USE
A STEAMER IF YOU HAVE ONE
OR USE A SPATULA OR SOMETHING
LIKE THIS AND I SPRAY IT
WITH SPRAY AND THEN
I LAY MY CANDY CANE ON THERE.
OKAY.
SO NOW WE HOPE IT GOES IN
THE WATER, AND YOU WANT
TO MAKE SURE YOU GET IT.
SEE HOW IT'S LIKE
GOING AWAY BUT IF YOU
GENTLY GUIDE IT HERE.
OKAY.
SO AND THEN IT WILL FORM
AND STAY LIKE THAT.
AND THEN YOU SIMPLY WAIT
FOR IT TO POP TO THE TOP.
I'M SO EXCITED
TO TAKE THESE.
YAY.
I'M GOING TO LOOK LIKE
I KNOW WHAT I'M DOING AND THIS
IS IN YOUR RECIPE BOOKS RIGHT?
YES IT'S IN THE
DESSERT COOK BOOK.
SO NOW IT'S FORMED AND
AGAIN GENTLY TAKE IT OUT.
IT'S GOING TO KEEP SHAPE
THOUGH, YOU CAN SEE NOW.
AND THEN YOU PUT
IT ON A PARCHMENT
LINE BAKING SHEET.
AND THEN YOU HAVE
YOUR CANDY CANE.
YOU GO TO THESE HOLIDAY PARTIES,
EVERYTHING THAT IS FUN AND
HOLIDAY IS LOADED WITH SUGAR.
AND LOADED WITH FAT.
AND LOADED WITH
EVERYTHING.
OKAY SEE, NO BUT ITS FINE
CAUSE THEN WELL BAKE THEM
AND IT WILL STICK EVEN MORE
AND ITS PERFECT THE
PERFECT ALI PRETZEL.
SO AND THE COOL THING
THESE ARE ONLY 142 CALORIES WITH
TWO GRAMS OF FAT AND FIBER.
SO FROM HERE WE DO WHAT?
BAKE THEM IN THE OVEN 450
DEGREES FOR TEN MINUTES.
TEN MINUTES THAT'S IT?
10-12 YEAH.
SO ONCE THEY'RE OUT OF THE
OVEN YOU WANT TO LET THEM
COOL FOR A COUPLE MINUTES.
OBVIOUSLY THEY'RE PRETZELS
YOU WANT THEM TO BE HOT, BUT
NOT SO HOT YOU BURN YOURSELF.
SO MIX THE SUGAR HERE.
CINNAMON IS LIKE ONE OF
MY MOST FAVORITE THINGS.
I LOVE CINNAMON.
ANYTHING CINNAMON.
SO NOW THIS IS
THE SUBSTITUTE.
SO BRUSH THE
PRETZELS VERY WELL.
GET THE NOOKS
AND CRANNIES.
AND THEN LITERALLY
DO BOTH SIDES.
IT'S ALL ABOUT MAKING THE
STUFF THAT EVERYBODY'S
USED TO LOOKING AT SO THEY
DON'T KNOW IT'S HEALTHY
AND THEN SPRINKLE OUR
GLITTER AFTER EVERYTHING.
YES YOU SPRINKLE
THE GLITTER.
I USUALLY PUT THEM
ON A PLATTER FIRST.
THIS HAS A NICE SHAKER.
YOU SEE THIS HAS
A TINY AMOUNT.
I PUT THEM ON THERE AND
THEN SPRINKLED, IT'S
PRETTY AND FESTIVE TO HAVE
THE SUGAR BITS FALLING.
AND IT SEEMS
MORE DECADENT.
I CAN TASTE THESE THEN?
THEY'RE READY TO GO.
I'M SO EXCITED.
WHY DO I GET
EXCITED TO EAT?
BECAUSE WE ALL DO.
I LOVE BREAD PRETZEL,
I HAVEN'T HAD
ONE IN LIKE FOREVER.
SO I CAN MAKE THIS TAKE IT
TO MY HOLIDAY PARTY AND
THEN I CAN WRAP UP YOUR BOOK.
WELL OF COURSE.
AND I'M GIVING YOU THE GIFT OF
THE PRETZEL SO THIS IS
THE PERFECT HOLIDAY GIFT.
AWESOME.
RUM BALLS HOW
DO WE MAKE THEM.
THESE ARE REALLY COOL, RUM
BALLS TRADITIONALLY THEY
HAVE BUTTER, CHOCOLATE,
CHOCOLATE BARS.
SO I USE DATES
AS THE BASE.
WHICH I KNOW MAY NOT SOUND
VERY GOOD BUT BELIEVE IT
OR NOT YOU'LL NEVER KNOW
IN THE END
I PROMISE, SO PULSE
THESE, BREAK THEM UP.
SEE THAT'S PRETTY GOOD.
WE DON'T HAVE ANY
BIG CHUNKS IN THERE.
OKAY THEN WERE GOING
TO ADD SOME OATS, WHICH
HELP BIND THEM TOGETHER.
COCOA POWDER, INSTEAD OF
CHOCOLATE, YOU GET THE FLAVOR BT
NOT THE OILS IN CHOCOLATE.
AND OF COURSE RUM
THEY ARE RUM BALLS YOU
HAVE TO USE REAL RUM.
TIS THE SEASON FA LA LA.
AND THEN WE JUST PULSE
THESE SOME MORE AND IT WILL BE
NICE AND STICKY AND GOOEY.
OOO IT SMELLS GOOD, IT
SMELLS LIKE CHOCOLATE.
OKAY, ALRIGHT.
IT SMELLS REALLY GOOD.
DOESN'T IT?
YOU CAN REALLY SMELL
THE WAFTING RUN.
SO ALWAYS OBVIOUSLY TAKE
YOUR BLADE OUT BEFORE YOU STICK
YOUR HAND IN THE FOOD PROCESSOR.
THEY MOST PE.ING ABOUT THIS.
NOW THESE ARE LITERALLY
ITS VERY STICKY.
WHICH IS FINE.
OKAY.
YOU CAN SEE IT
WILL COME TOGETHER.
IT'S BASICALLY BREAKING
IT IN HALF AND DO
SEVEN PIECES OUT OF IT.
BUT IT'S ABOUT THAT.
SO, DO THIS.
I LOVE HOW ALL
THESE THINGS.
LIKE THESE ARE.
LIKE YOUR RECIPES
YOU GET IN THERE YOU
GIVE IT SOME LOVE.
ITS YOU KNOW I
CALL IT PLAYING.
LIKE WE PLAYED IN
THE KITCHEN TODAY.
LIKE THIS WOULD BE FUN
TO MAKE WITH THE KIDS.
EXACTLY.
AND TWO OF THESE WILL ONLY
BE 155 CALORIES, 4 GRAMS OF
FIBER AND ONLY 2 GRAMS OF FAT.
SO NOW THERE A LITTLE
STICKY ON THE OUTSIDE AND
LIKE YOUR TRADITIONAL RUN
BALL YOU ROLL THEM IN
HERE, AND THE SUPER
IMPORTANT STEP IN HERE IS
GET THE COCO POWDER OFF,
OTHERWISE WHEN YOU GO TO
EAT IT YOU MIGHT INHALE
THE COCOA POWDER.
WOULD I FIND THIS
RECIPE AND THE PRETZEL
IN THE SAME COOK BOOK.
CAUSE HOW MANY BOOKS
DO YOU HAVE RIGHT NOW.
EIGHT.
EIGHT COOK BOOKS, GEEZ.
OKAY I'VE GOT
IT ALL OVER ME.
SHAKE OFF MY COCO CAUSE
I OVERLY DID IT RIGHT.
A LITTLE BIT BUT
ITS ALL GOOD.
OKAY.
IT'S GOOD.
IT IS GOOD.
IT'S NOT LIKE MY SISTERS.
I'M SORRY AMBER.
STILL TO COME.
YOU NEVER MADE A
GINGER BREAD HOUSE?
I'VE DECORATED
A HOUSE BUT I'VE NEVER
MADE THE GINGER BREAD.
ARE YOU LOOKING FOR THAT
GIFT FOR THAT PERSON WHO
HAS EVERYTHING?
WELL DEVIN'S GOT THE ANSWER,
DEVIN WHAT CAN WE GET FOR
SOMEBODY WHO HAS EVERYTHING?
I LOVE TO GIVE FOOD GIFTS,
THERE IS SO MANY VARIETIES
FOR INSTANCE I HAVE
A BOTTLE OF
CHAMPAGNE VINEGAR.
SO MANY PARTIES YOU BRING
WINE AND YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT KIND OF WINE PEOPLE LIKE
OR IF EVERYBODY DRINKS SO I LIKE
TO BRING A CHAMPAGNE VINEGAR LIE
A DECADENT PORT VINEGAR.
OKAY CAUSE YOU CAN PUT IT
IN A CUTE BAG LIKE THAT
AND 30 SECONDS AND DONE.
AND THEN THEY'LL ACTUALLY
HAVE IT AFTER THE PARTY.
MANY TIMES IF YOU DO WINE
YOU DRINK IT DURING THE PARTY
AND DON'T KNOW WHAT YOU BROUGHT.
SO ALSO TOO ESPECIALLY WITH YOU
DO PEOPLE SAY LIKE DEVIN
PLEASE MAKE ME SOMETHING.
YES PEOPLE WANT ME
TO BRING SOMETHING.
SO AGAIN IF YOU'RE TAKING
SOMETHING TO A PARTY OR
YOU WANT TO GIVE IT AS A GIFT
I SUGGEST MAKING
GINGERBREAD TRUFFLES.
BECAUSE THAT'S ONE OF THE
THINGS I LOVE WHEN PEOPLE
SPEND THE TIME I KNOW
THEY'RE THINKING ABOUT ME
WHEN THEY'RE MAKING THE
GIFT FOR ME SO THIS IS GREAT.
HOW DO WE MAKE THE
GINGER BREAD TRUFFLES.
I THINK YOU KNOW THAT
GINGERBREAD MEN, MANY
PEOPLE WANT THE GINGER BREAD,
WITH HOLIDAYS
BUT MOST ARE MADE WITH LARD.
REALLY?
YEAH.
OH.SOMETHING YOU REL
NOT SOMETHING YOU REALLY
WANT TO BE EATING SO SOME
CAN BE OBVIOUSLY WITH BUTTER
BUT TRADITIONALLY WITH LARD.
SO THE THING IS THE
MOLASSES AND NICE
SPICES IN THERE.
SO I'M GONG TO DO SOMETHING
SIMILAR TO THE RUM BALL BUT SPIE
IT LIKE GINGER BREAD.
AND AGAIN YOU CAN TELL ME.
SO START WITH DATES AGAIN.
DATES ARE GREAT BECAUSE
THEY GET NICE AND STICKY
AND HOLD THINGS TOGETHER
BUT STAY MOIST,
BECAUSE YOU DON'T
WANT DRY BAKED GOODS.
OKAY PULSE THEM IN
YOUR FOOD PROCESSOR.
AGAIN ANOTHER
REALLY EASY ONE.
SO WE HAVE OUR DATES
KIND OF CHOPPED UP.
ADD OUR MOLASSES.
THAT'S WHERE I CAN
ALREADY SMELL WHAT'S
GOING ON IN HERE.
THIS SMELLS GOOD.
I WISH THAT YOU COULD SEND
SMELLS THROUGH THE TV.
I KNOW THAT
WOULD BE GREAT.
SO THEN THE OATS.
AGAIN.
YOU'RE NOTICING A PATTERN.
AND THEN I HAVE A SPICE
MIXTURE HERE, THESE ARE
INDIVIDUAL SPICES, OF ALL
SPICE, NUTMEG,
CLOVES AND GINGER.
WHICH ARE THE
GINGER BREAD SPICES.
THEY ARE?
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT.
I'VE NEVER MADE COOKIES.
YOU'VE NEVER MADE A
GINGER BREAD HOUSE.
I'VE DECORATED
A HOUSE BUT I NEVER
MADE THE GINGER BREAD.
FROM SCRATCH.
THIS SMELLS GOOD.'VE GOE
YOU'VE GOT THE WHOLE
GINGER BREAD THING RIGHT.
SO NOW THIS ONE COMES
TOGETHER EVEN A LITTLE
MORE THAN THE OTHER ONE.
AGAIN TAKE THE BLADE
OUT BEFORE YOU DO THIS.
NEVER REACH AROUND IT
BECAUSE WITHOUT FAIL
YOU'LL STAB YOURSELF.
SO THIS ONE BREAKS
INTO 12 PIECES.
SO WELL DO HALF AND
YOU DO HALF OF THEM.
SO I NEED SIZE BALLS OUT
OF THIS AND YOU COULD
PRESS THIS INTO GINGER
BREAD MEN IF YOU WANT TO.
HOW LONG CAN I KEEP THESE.
THESE WILL STAY IN A
TUPPERWARE FOR A LONG
TIME, I MEAN LIKE A WEEK.
NOW GRAB SOME OATS
FROM DOWN THERE.
ALRIGHT.
OKAY.
HERE'S THE OATS AND THEN
PUT THEM IN THIS BOWL AND
ROLL AWAY AND THE PURPOSE
OF THIS IS THEY ARE STICKY SO IT
PUTS OATS ON THE OUTSIDE SO IT
DOESN'T MAKE IT AS STICKY.
EXACTLY.
AND YOU JUST PRESS THESE YOU
WANT TO PRESS IN A LITTLE BIT
TO MAKE THE OATS STICK.
TWO OF THESE IS 151
CALORIES, ONLY A TRACE OF
FAT, LIKE VERY LITTLE BIT,
AND THEN THREE
GRAMS OF FIBER.
OKAY.
I'M GOING TO TAKE
YOUR BALLS BECAUSE
YOURS ARE PRETTIER.
THERE YOU GO.
OKAY.
SO THEN PUT THEM IN A GIFT
BOX AND THEN YOU KNOW IF
YOU PUT SOME TISSUE IN THERE.
OR CARDBOARD TOO.
TWO LAYERS,
SUPER CUTE GIFT.
CUTE.
BECAUSE YOU KNOW MY THING.
IS IT WORTH THE CALORIES.
THAT'S REALLY GOOD.
THAT IS GOOD.
I THINK THIS
IS MY FAVORITE.
THANKS FOR HAVING ME AGAIN
DEVON, THESE ARE AWESOME.
BUT BEFORE WE LEAVE I WANT
TO MAKE SURE EVERYONE KNOWS
YOU HAVE THE BEST COOK BOOK EVER
THE BEST GIFT YOU CAN GIVE
ANYBODY, BECAUSE IT'S
THE REST OF YOUR LIFE.
IT'S THE GIFT
THAT KEEPS GIVING.
THIS IS THE MOST
DECADENT OF MY RECIPES.
THESE ARE THE GOOD ONES.
SINCE WERE TALKING ABOUT
GIFTS, LOOK WHAT I FOUND.
OH MY GOD.
I LOVE IT.
THANKS SO MUCH.
ABSOLUTELY.
YOU'RE ALWAYS SO
GOOD TO ME ALI.
THANKS FOR HAVING ME.
HAPPY HOLIDAYS.
THANK YOU.
GOOD HUG.
I'M GOING TO TAKE MY
TREATS AND LEAVE.
TO FIND ANY OF TODAY'S
RECIPES OR FOR MORE
INFORMATION ABOUT THE GIFT
IDEAS FEATURED
ON TODAY'S SHOW GO TO
LIVEWELLNETWORK.COM
AND TYPE IN LIVE BIG HOLIDAY
IN THE SEARCH BAR.
FROM EVERYONE HERE AT
LIVE BIG WITH ALI VINCENT
HAPPY HOLIDAYS
AND A HAPPY HEALTHY NEW YEAR.
IF YOU LAY IT DOWN ITS
MORE EASY FOR YOU.
TINY LITTLE CROSSES.
MAKE IT NICE.
SEE HOW TIGHT
I'M MAKING IT.
LIKE GLITTER.
YEAH I SEE HOW TIGHT
YOU'RE MAKING IT.
AND YOU DON'T EVEN HAVE TO
PUT CINNAMON SUGAR ON IT.
SORRY.
I'M GOING TO START OVER.
IT'S REALLY FUN WHEN YOU
OPEN UP YOUR STRIDE.
EVEN RUN BACKWARDS.
OH I DON'T KNOW
ABOUT THAT.
DEFINITELY.
FUN.