>> PLUS, THE HEROES, STORIES OF
BRAVERY FROM INSIDE THE SCHOOL,
INCLUDING THE YOUNG TEACHER WHO
PROMISED HER FIRST GRADERS
THEY'D LIVE TO SEE CHRISTMAS.
>> I WANTED THEM TO KNOW THAT
SOMEBODY LOVED THEM AND THAT TO
BE ONE OF THE LAST THINGS THEY
HEARD.
NOT THE GUNFIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
IT'S SO HORRIBLE.
>> AND THE SHOOTER, A
20-YEAR-OLD ARMED WITH AN
ASSAULT RIFLE AND TWO HANDGUNS.
HIS MOTHER AMONG THE DEAD.
THE LATEST BREAKING DETAILS ON
WHO HE IS AND WHY HE DID IT.
>> Announcer: FROM THE GLOBAL
RESOURCES OF ABC NEWS, WITH
TERRY MORAN AND BILL WEIR IN NEW
YORK CITY AND CYNTHIA McFADDEN
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, THIS IS
A SPECIAL EDITION OF
"NIGHTLINE," TRAGEDY AT
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>>> GOOD EVENING.
I'M CYNTHIA McFADDEN.
TONIGHT WE JOIN YOU FROM A
COMMUNITY JUST BEGINNING TO
PROCESS A GREAT TRAGEDY THAT
UNFOLDED HERE THIS MORNING.
A LITTLE WHILE AGO I WAS JUST
DOWN THE STREET WHERE A THOUSAND
PEOPLE GATHERED INSIDE AND
OUTSIDE SAINT ROSE CATHOLIC
CHURCH HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TO MOURN THE LOSS
OF 26 PEOPLE, INCLUDING 20
SCHOOLCHILDREN, MOST BETWEEN THE
AGES OF 5 AND BETWEEN YEARS OLD,
SHOT AND KILLED IN THEIR
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL CLASSROOMS
THIS MORNING.
SCHOOLS IN THIS TOWN ARE PART OF
THE DRAW FOR PEOPLE WHO LIVE
HERE WITH SOME OF THE HIGHEST
TEST SCORES IN THE STATE.
THE KIND OF PLACE PARENTS MOVE
FOR THE SAKE OF THEIR CHILDREN.
ABC'S DAN HARRIS HAS BEEN AT THE
SCENE SINCE EARLY TODAY.
DAN?
>> Reporter: CYNTHIA, GOOD
EVENING.
IT ALL STARTED A LITTLE WAY
BEHIND THE VOLUNTEER FIRE
DEPARTMENT, DOWN THE ROAD AT A
SUBURBAN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WHICH
TONIGHT IS IN THE HISTORY BOOKS
FOR THE WORST OF ALL POSSIBLE
REASONS.
AND THIS TOWN, WHICH ONE PARENT
TODAY DESCRIBED AS THE SAFEST
PLACE IN AMERICA, IS IN TOTAL
SHOCK.
90 MINUTES INTO THE SCHOOL DAY
ON A BRIGHT WINTER MORNING HERE,
POLICE GOT A CALL FROM THE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, CALLER'S
INDICATING SHE THINKS THERE'S
SOMEONE SHOOTING IN THE
BUILDING.
>> Reporter: AT AROUND 9:30, THE
SHOOTER, 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA,
A FORMER STUDENT IN THE LOCAL
SCHOOLS, SHOWN HERE AS A
TEENAGER, HAD BARGED IN.
ACCORDING TO THE POLICE, HE WAS
HEAVILY ARMED, COATED IN BODY
ARMOR, AND READY TO KILL.
>> WE HEARD THIS RACKET AT OUR
CLASSROOM AND WE WERE LIKE ALL
SCARED, SO THEN WE HEARD THEM
SAY, GO IN YOUR CUBBIES.
>> Reporter: THERE WERE MORE
THAN 600 CHILDREN FROM
KINDERGARTEN THROUGH FOURTH
GRADE INSIDE.
>> IT WAS REALLY SCARY.
TEACHERS JUST SAID, SIT DOWN
INSIDE THE CORNER AND BE QUIET.
>> Reporter: CALLS WENT OUT TO
POLICE EVEN AS SHOTS WERE STILL
BEING FIRED AND WITHIN FIVE TO
TEN MINUTES, TACTICAL TEAMS WITH
LONG GUNS DRAWN SWARMED THE
SCHOOL, A STARK CONTRAST AGAINST
THE BACKDROP OF THIS BUCOLIC,
WOODSY NEIGHBORHOOD.
>> REPORTS THAT THE TEACHERS SAW
TWO RUNNERS PAST THE BUILDING
WHICH WOULD THE REAR OF THE
BUILDING.
>> I NEED UNITS IN THE SCHOOL, I
GOT BODIES HERE.
>> Reporter: PETRIFIED STUDENTS
AND TEACHERS LOOKED FOR SAFE
PLACES TO HIDE.
ONE TEACHER LOCKING HER CHILDREN
IN A BATHROOM AS POLICE COMBED
THE BUILDING LOOKING FOR THE
SHOOTER.
>> NEWTOWN POLICE IMMEDIATELY
UPON ARRIVAL ENTERED THE SCHOOL
AND BEGAN A COMPLETE ACTIVE
SHOOTER SEARCH OF THE BUILDING.
THAT INCLUDED CHECKING EVERY
DOOR, EVERY CRACK, EVERY
CREVICE, EVERY PORTION OF THAT
SCHOOL.
>> WE HEARD SCREAMING.
AND THEN THE POLICE CAME IN.
AND HE'S LIKE, IS HE IN HERE?
THEN HE RAN OUT.
>> Reporter: 8-YEAR-OLD ALEXIS
WAS IN HER THIRD GRADE CLASSROOM
AT THE TIME.
>> YOU HEAR AN AMBULANCE AND
POLICE OFFICER COME AND
EVERYBODY WAS A LITTLE SCARED,
CRYING.
I FELT ACTUALLY A LITTLE SICK.
AND I THOUGHT I WAS GOING TO
THROW UP.
>> Reporter: WERE KIDS CRYING
AND SCREAMING?
>> YEAH, KIDS WERE CRYING.
NOT SCREAMING.
THEY WERE ALL HUDDLING TOGETHER.
AND THEY GOT -- THEY FELT SO
SICK.
>> Reporter: TEACHERS LED THE
STUDENTS SINGLE FILE FROM THE
SCHOOLHOUSE TO A NEARBY FIRE
STATION.
>> WE GOT IN A LINE.
WE HAD TO CLOSE OUR EYES.
AND WE ALL PUT OUR HANDS ON
OTHER PEOPLE'S SHOULDERS.
AND THEN OUR TEACHER HELD THE
FIRST PERSON'S HAND AND SHE LED
US OUT.
>> Reporter: PARENTS WERE
ALERTED BY TEXT MESSAGE IN A
FRANTIC PARADE OF THEM ARRIVED
AT THE FIRE STATION HOPING TO
FIND THEIR CHILDREN ALIVE.
>> HEARTBREAKING.
IT'S HEARTBREAKING.
I MEAN, I DON'T -- WHEN I HEARD,
I -- I STARTED CRYING.
>> Reporter: ALEXIS' PARENTS
WERE AMONG THE LUCKY.
HER MOM SAID WHEN SHE ARRIVED AT
THE FIREHOUSE, ALEXIS WAS
ALREADY WITH HER FATHER.
>> HE HAD HER IN HIS ARMS.
AND CRYING.
AND SO SHE IS JUST, SHE GOES
MOM, I'M OKAY, I'M HERE.
>> Reporter: THE RAMPAGE AND
EVACUATION HAPPENED IN A FLASH.
BUT WE WOULDN'T KNOW THE FULL
SCOPE OF THE HORROR FOR HOURS.
>> THE SHOOTER IS DECEASED.
DECEASED IN THE SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: BY 10:30, PRESIDENT
OBAMA WAS BRIEFED ON THE
SITUATION AND SCHOOLS THROUGHOUT
THE AREA WERE ON LOCKDOWN.
POLICE WERE SURROUNDING A SECOND
CRIME SCENE, THE SHOOTER'S
MOTHER'S HOME, NEARBY.
AT AROUND NOON, THE HORRIFYING
NUMBERS WERE ANNOUNCED.
ABC NEWS LEARNED THAT LANZA HAD
KILLED 27 PEOPLE.
MOST OF THEM CHILDREN.
AT THE LOCAL HOSPITAL, THEY WERE
BRACING FOR AN ONSLAUGHT, BUT
THEY ONLY GOT THREE PATIENTS.
TWO OF WHOM DIED.
>> A NUMBER OF US IMAGINED WHAT
IT MAY HAVE FELT LIKE ON 9/11.
WHEN THERE WERE PEOPLE BRACING
FOR SCORES OF INJURED AND THEY
DIDN'T ARRIVE.
>> Reporter: AT THE FIREHOUSE
WHERE STUDENTS WERE GATHERED
WAITING FOR THEIR PARENTS, WE
MET ANOTHER MOTHER WHOSE
CHILDREN GO TO A NEARBY SCHOOL.
SHE TOLD US SHE WAS HERE TO
SUPPORT HER FRIEND AND TO PUT
OFF PICKING UP HER OWN CHILDREN
BECAUSE SHE DIDN'T WANT TO TELL
THEM ABOUT THIS MASSACRE.
>> THIS IS THE LAST TWO HOURS OF
THEIR LIFE THAT THEY'RE GOING TO
BE A KID.
>> I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
>> Reporter: SHORTLY AFTER 3:00
IN THE AFTERNOON, THE PRESIDENT
ADDRESSED THE NATION.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
AMONG THE FALLEN WERE ALSO
TEACHERS.
MEN AND WOMEN WHO DEVOTED THEIR
LIVES TO HELPING OUR CHILDREN
FULFILL THEIR DREAMS.
>> Reporter: NOT LONG AFTER THAT
POLICE ANNOUNCED LANZA HAD SHOT
HIS MOTHER, WHO WAS BELIEVED TO
HAVE WORKED AT THE SCHOOL AT
SOME POINT, AT HER HOME BEFORE
HE THEN WENT AND STORMED THE
SCHOOL.
>> WE NEED TO ANSWER EVERY
SINGLE QUESTION TO DETERMINE
EXACTLY HOW AND WHY THIS
INCIDENT OCCURRED.
>> Reporter: TONIGHT AT THE
CAPITOL BUILDING IN WASHINGTON,
FLAGS LOWERED TO HALF STAFF.
WHILE BACK IN NEWTOWN, TRUE TO
THE GRIM AND ALL TOO FAMILIAR
SCRIPT OF THE MASS SHOOTINGS, A
CANDLELIGHT VIGIL.
ALL DAY LONG AS WE WATCHED THE
DRAMA UNFOLD HERE, ADDING TO THE
SHOCK IN THIS COMMUNITY, THE
FACT THAT THIS IS SUCH AN
UNLIKELY VENUE FOR VIOLENCE.
A SMALL, SLEEPY TOWN, WITH A
POPULATION OF FEWER THAN 30,000,
THE KIND OF BUCOLIC NEW ENGLAND
PLACE WHERE PEOPLE MOVE
PRECISELY FOR THE SCHOOLS AND
THE SAFETY.
>> LIKE, SHOULD I BE PINCHED TO
SEE IF IT REALLY IS REAL?
I'D JUST -- HEARTWRENCHING.
>> Reporter: FEELS LIKE A DREAM,
A BAD DREAM.
>> IT'S A NIGHTMARE.
>> Reporter: FOR THOUGH LUCKY
ENOUGH TO BE REUNITED WITH THEIR
CHILDREN TONIGHT, A WAKE-UP
CALL.
>> COUNT YOUR BLESSINGS EVERY
DAY FOR WHAT YOU HAVE.
>> Reporter: ALEXIS, I AM REALLY
GLAD YOU'RE OKAY.
REALLY GLAD YOU'RE OKAY.
YOU'RE PRETTY TOUGH.
SHE IS A GREAT KID AND SHE'S HAD
A VERY TOUGH DAY.
AND TONIGHT, ABC NEWS HAS
LEARNED THAT THE FBI IS
INTERVIEWING FRIEND AND FAMILY
OF THE GUNMAN NOT ONLY HERE IN
CONNECTICUT BUT ALSO IN NEW
JERSEY AND IN MASSACHUSETTS AS
THEY TRY TO GO ABOUT ANSWERING
THE BIG, BURNING QUESTION --
WHY?
WHAT WAS HIS MOTIVE?
CYNTHIA.
>> THANKS TO YOU, DAN HARRIS
REPORTING.
>>> NEXT UP, HEROES IN THE MIDST
OF TERROR, THE BRAVE TEACHER WHO
LOCKED HER FIRST GRADERS IN THE
CLASSROOM BATHROOM AND PROMISED
THEM THEY WOULD MAKE IT TO
CHRISTMAS.
>> WE JUST HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET.
AND WE HAVE -- I SAID, THERE ARE
BAD GUYS OUT THERE NOW AND WE
NEED TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD GUYS.
CHANGE ENGINEERING IN DUBAI,
ALUMINUM PRODUCTION
IN SOUTH AFRICA,
AND THE AEROSPACE INDUSTRY
IN THE U.S.?
AT T. ROWE PRICE,
WE UNDERSTAND THE CONNECTIONS
OF A COMPLEX, GLOBAL ECONOMY.
IT'S JUST ONE REASON
OVER 75% OF OUR MUTUAL FUNDS
BEAT THEIR 10-YEAR
LIPPER AVERAGE.
T. ROWE PRICE.
INVEST WITH CONFIDENCE.
REQUEST A PROSPECTUS
OR SUMMARY PROSPECTUS
WITH INVESTMENT INFORMATION,
RISKS, FEES AND EXPENSES
TO READ AND CONSIDER CAREFULLY
BEFORE INVESTING.
AND YOU LEARNED SOMETHING
ALONG THE WAY.
THIS IS THE AGE OF KNOWING
WHAT YOU'RE MADE OF.
SO, WHY LET
ERECTILE DYSFUNCTION
GET IN YOUR WAY?
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT VIAGRA.
20 MILLION MEN ALREADY HAVE.
ASK IF YOUR HEART
IS HEALTHY ENOUGH FOR SEX.
DO NOT TAKE VIAGRA IF YOU TAKE
NITRATES FOR CHEST PAIN;
IT MAY CAUSE AN UNSAFE DROP
IN BLOOD PRESSURE.
SIDE EFFECTS INCLUDE
HEADACHE, FLUSHING,
UPSET STOMACH,
AND ABNORMAL VISION.
TO AVOID LONG-TERM INJURY,
SEEK IMMEDIATE MEDICAL HELP
FOR AN ERECTION
LASTING MORE THAN FOUR HOURS.
STOP TAKING VIAGRA
AND CALL YOUR DOCTOR RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU EXPERIENCE
A SUDDEN DECREASE OR LOSS
IN VISION OR HEARING.
THIS IS THE AGE
OF TAKING ACTION.
VIAGRA.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR.
SEE IF AMERICA'S
MOST PRESCRIBED ED TREATMENT
IS RIGHT FOR YOU.
I HAD[ Designer ]EELING
ENOUGH OF JUST COVERING UPTMENT
MY MODERATE TO SEVERE
PLAQUE PSORIASIS.
I DECIDED ENOUGH IS ENOUGH.
♪
[ Spa Lady ]
I STARTED ENBREL.
IT'S CLINICALLY PROVEN
TO PROVIDE CLEARER SKIN.
[ RV Guy ] ENBREL MAY NOT WORK
FOR EVERYONE --
AND MAY NOT CLEAR YOU
COMPLETELY,
BUT FOR MANY, IT GETS SKIN
CLEARER FAST, WITHIN 2 MONTHS,
AND KEEPS IT CLEARER
UP TO 9 MONTHS.
[ Male Announcer ]
BECAUSE ENBREL®, ETANERCEPT,
SUPPRESSES YOUR IMMUNE SYSTEM,
IT MAY LOWER YOUR ABILITY
TO FIGHT INFECTIONS.
SERIOUS, SOMETIMES FATAL,
EVENTS INCLUDING INFECTIONS,
TUBERCULOSIS, LYMPHOMA,
OTHER CANCERS,
AND NERVOUS SYSTEM AND
BLOOD DISORDERS HAVE OCCURRED.
BEFORE STARTING ENBREL,
YOUR DOCTOR SHOULD TEST YOU
FOR TUBERCULOSIS
AND DISCUSS WHETHER
YOU'VE BEEN TO A REGION
WHERE CERTAIN FUNGAL INFECTIONS
ARE COMMON.
DON'T START ENBREL IF YOU HAVE
AN INFECTION LIKE THE FLU.
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
IF YOU'RE PRONE TO INFECTIONS,
HAVE CUTS OR SORES,
HAVE HAD HEPATITIS B,
HAVE BEEN TREATED
FOR HEART FAILURE,
OR IF, WHILE ON ENBREL, YOU
EXPERIENCE PERSISTENT FEVER,
BRUISING, BLEEDING,
OR PALENESS.
IF YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH, ASK
YOUR DERMATOLOGIST ABOUT ENBREL.
>>> THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"NIGHTLINE," TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, CONTINUES
WITH CYNTHIA McFADDEN.
>> WELL, FAR TOO MANY INNOCENT
LIVES WERE LOST TODAY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL HERE IN
CONNECTICUT.
IT IS IMPOSSIBLE TO KNOW HOW
MANY CHILDREN WERE SAVED BY THE
COURAGEOUS ACTIONS UNDER FIRE BY
THE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
TEACHERS AND STAFF.
THE STORIES OF HEROISM ARE ONLY
BEGINNING TO UNFOLD.
ABC "WORLD NEWS" ANCHOR DIANE
SAWYER MET ONE YOUNG TEACHER
WITH AN EXTRAORDINARY STORY.
>> I KNEW IT WAS A SHOOTING
IMMEDIATELY.
>> IT WAS JUST REPETITIVE
SOUNDS?
>> YEAH, IT SOUNDED LIKE THE
TYPE OF GUN THAT JUST SHOOTS
OVER AND OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
I TOLD ALL OF MY STUDENTS THAT
WE HAD TO GET IN THE BATHROOM.
IT WAS ALL I COULD THINK OF.
I PUT ONE OF MY STUDENTS ON TOP
OF THE TOILET.
I JUST KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN
THERE.
I WAS JUST TELLING THEM IT'S
GOING TO BE OKAY, YOU'RE GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
I PULLED THE BOOKSHELF BEFORE IN
-- BEFORE I CLOSED THE DOOR IN
FRONT OF IT, SO WE WERE
COMPLETELY BARRICADED IN, TURNED
THE LIGHTS OFF.
>> DID YOU TELL THEM TO BE
QUIET?
>> OH YES.
I TOLD THEM TO BE QUIET.
I TOLD THEM WE HAD TO BE
ABSOLUTELY QUIET BECAUSE I WAS
JUST SO AFRAID THAT IF HE DID
COME IN AND THEN HE WOULD HEAR
US AND HE WOULD MAYBE START
SHOOTING THE DOOR.
I SAID WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET.
AND WE HAVE -- I SAID, THERE ARE
BAD GUYS OUT THERE NOW, WE NEED
TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD GUYS.
I WANTED US TO BE OKAY.
AND I'M SO SADDENED THAT THERE
ARE PEOPLE IN THIS SITUATION WHO
ARE NOT OKAY.
AND MY HEART GOES OUT TO ANYONE
WHO KNEW THEM AND WAS PART OF
THEIR LIVES.
I JUST CAN'T IMAGINE.
>> DID THEY CRY?
>> IF THEY STARTED CRYING, I
WOULD TAKE THEIR FACE AND SAY
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
SHOW ME YOUR SMILE.
I REALLY TRIED TO -- ONE OF MY
STUDENTS WOULD SAY THINGS LIKE I
KNOW KARATE, SO IT'S OKAY.
I'LL LEAD THE WAY OUT.
>> THEY SAID TO YOU WE WANT TO
GO HOME FOR CHRISTMAS.
>> OH YEAH.
OH, YEAH.
UH-HUH.
YEP.
I JUST WANT TO HUG MY MOM, JUST
THINGS LIKE THAT THAT WERE
JUST -- JUST HEARTBREAKING.
YOU KNOW?
IN MY MIND --
BECAUSE YOU'RE HEARING -- I'VE
NEVER BEEN PART OF SOMETHING
ANYWHERE NEAR THIS TRAUMATIC.
AND SO I'M HEARING THE GUNFIRE
IN THE HALLWAY.
I'M THINKING IN MY MIND --
I'M THINKING I'M THE FIRST
CLASSROOM.
WHY ISN'T HE COMING -- I'M
THINKING WE'RE NEXT.
IN MY MIND, I'M THINKING AS A
6-YEAR-OLD, 7-YEAR-OLD, WHAT ARE
YOUR THOUGHTS?
I'M THINKING THAT I HAVE TO
ALMOST BE THE PARENT.
I HAVE TO TELL THEM -- YOU KNOW.
SO I SAID TO THEM, I NEED YOU TO
KNOW THAT I LOVE YOU ALL VERY
MUCH.
AND THAT IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
BECAUSE I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE
LAST THING THEY WERE EVER GOING
TO HEAR.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
AND I DON'T KNOW IF THAT'S
OKAY -- YOU KNOW, TEACHERS.
BUT I WANTED THEM TO KNOW
SOMEONE LOVED THEM AND I WANTED
THAT TO BE ONE OF THE LAST
THINGS THEY HEARD.
NOT THE GUNFIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
IT'S JUST SO HORRIBLE.
HORRIBLE, HORRIBLE.
>> HOW DID YOU KNOW YOU WERE
GOING TO BE OKAY?
>> I DIDN'T.
WHAT FINALLY HAPPENED WAS THE
GUNFIRE STOPPED.
THE GUNFIRE WASN'T THAT LONG.
SO THAT STOPPED.
BUT I SAID WE'RE NOT GOING
ANYWHERE.
WE'RE STAYING HERE UNTIL SOMEONE
GOOD COMES IN AND GETS US OUT.
SO EVENTUALLY WHAT HAPPENED WAS
THE POLICE CAME AND STARTED
KNOCKING, AND OBVIOUSLY I WAS
COMPLETELY BESIDE MYSELF.
AND I SAID, I DON'T BELIEVE YOU,
YOU NEED TO PUT YOUR BADGES
UNDER THE DOOR.
SO THEY PUT THEIR BADGES UNDER
THE DOOR.
I SAID IF YOU'RE REALLY A POLICE
OFFICER, THEN YOU WOULD HAVE A
WAY TO GET IN HERE.
YOU WOULD HAVE A KEY OR YOU --
IF EVERYTHING'S OKAY, YOU WOULD
HAVE FOUND THE KEYS.
SO HE HAD THE KEYS AND HE FOUND
THE RIGHT ONE AND HE UNLOCKED
THE DOOR AND THEN THEY BROUGHT
US OUT TO THE FIREHOUSE TO MEET
UP WITH THE REST OF THE TEACHERS
AND STUDENTS WAITING FOR PARENTS
TO COME AND PICK THEM UP.
>> I THINK THERE ARE A LOT OF
PEOPLE WHO WISH THAT -- WANT ALL
THE TEACHERS TO KNOW HOW MUCH IT
MEANS TO THEM, HOW MUCH THEY
CARE ABOUT THEIR CHILDREN.
>> UH-HUH.
HOW COULD YOU NOT?
>> THANK YOU.
>> OUR THANKS TO DIANE, AND ONE
TEACHER'S REMARKABLE BRAVERY.
BUT SHE WASN'T THE ONLY ONE
INSIDE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
WHOSE QUICK THINKING AND
INSTINCTS HELPED SO MANY
CHILDREN OUT OF HARM'S WAY.
ABC'S AMY WOBACH REPORTS FROM
OUTSIDE DANBURY HOSPITAL TO
BRING US THE MANY HEROS WHO
EMERGED TODAY.
AMY?
>> Reporter: TONIGHT, CYNTHIA,
WE ARE LEARNING MORE ABOUT THE
VICTIMS OF TODAY'S DEADLY
RAMPAGE.
AMONG THE 20 CHILDREN AND SIX
ADULTS KILLED TODAY, WE NOW KNOW
THAT THE SCHOOL'S PRINCIPAL,
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, WAS AMONG THOSE
KILLED.
PARENTS DESCRIBE HER AS A LOVING
AND CARING EDUCATOR WHO WAS
ALWAYS EXCITED ABOUT THE
CHILDREN IN HER SCHOOL.
WE NOW KNOW THE TEACHERS WHO SHE
LED MADE A BIG DIFFERENCE TODAY
SAVING LIVES.
FOR MORE THAN 600 STUDENTS WHO
ATTEND SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL, IT IS THE TEACHER'S
WORDS THEY FOLLOWED DAY IN AND
DAY OUT.
TODAY THOSE WORDS MIGHT JUST
HAVE SAVED THEIR LIVES.
>> TEACHERS DID GET THEM IN A
SINGLE LINE FORMAT.
THEY TOLD THEM TO PUT THEIR
HANDS OVER THEIR EYES AS THEY
EXITED IN THE SCHOOL AND QUICKLY
WALKED THEM DOWN THE STREET TO
THE FIREHOUSE.
>> Reporter: TODAY AMID THE
HORROR, STORIES OF EXTRAORDINARY
COURAGE AND HEROISM.
TEACHERS WHO BARRICADED DOORS
ENDED UP IN THE LINE OF FIRE,
LED THEIR STUDENTS TO SAFETY.
RICHARD WILFORD'S 7-YEAR-OLD SON
IS IN THE SECOND GRADE.
>> HIS TEACHER WENT AND CHECKED.
SHE CAME IN, CLOSED AND LOCKED
THE DOOR.
THEY WENT INTO A CORNER UNTIL
THEY WERE RECOVERED BY POLICE.
>> MY DAUGHTER'S TEACHER HEARD
SOME SHOTS AND IMMEDIATELY
LOCKED THE DOOR.
THE STATE POLICE CAME AND
KNOCKED ON THE DOOR AND TOLD
THEM IT WAS SAFE TO LEAVE.
>> Reporter: THE FACTS ARE STILL
EMERGING ABOUT WHAT HAPPENED.
THERE WAS THIS TWEET THIS
MORNING, AN ASSISTANT PRINCIPAL
SHOT TWICE AND IN SURGERY.
AND THIS FACE TELLING IT ALL.
THIS WOMAN'S SISTER, ONE OF
THOSE TEACHERS INSIDE THE
SCHOOL, HER WHEREABOUTS UNKNOWN.
>> IT DOES SOUND AS THOUGH THAT
THE TEACHERS DID EVERYTHING
HUMANLY POSSIBLE, DOWN TO
RISKING THEIR OWN LIVES, TO
PROTECT THE CHILDREN IN THIS
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: BEING PREPARED IS
INCREASINGLY BECOMING PART OF
THE NEW MATH OF CLASSROOMS
NATIONWIDE.
>> TEACHING KIDS TO LOCK DOWN,
SECURING YOUR ROOMS, AND IN SOME
CASES TEACHERS STEPPING FORTH TO
PROTECT THE CHILDREN AT THE RISK
OF THEIR OWN LIFE IS SOMETHING
THAT WE SEE OCCURRING MORE AND
MORE OVER THE YEARS IN SCHOOL
SAFETY.
MASS PARENT NOTIFICATION SYSTEMS
ARE A CRITICAL PART OF SCHOOL
EMERGENCY PLANNING TODAY.
>> Reporter: IN FACT, JUST THIS
YEAR, SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL PUT INTO PLACE A SECURITY
PLAN, MAKING IT MANDATORY FOR
VISITORS TO RING A DOORBELL AND
ONLY BE LET IN IF STAFF
RECOGNIZED THEM THROUGH THE
VIDEO MONITOR.
AND IF STAFF DIDN'T RECOGNIZE
THE VISITOR, HE OR SHE NEEDED TO
PRESENT PICTURE I.D., SIGN IN,
AND ONLY THEN WOULD BE LET INTO
THE SCHOOL.
>> IT REALLY HAS TO BE A
COMBINATION OF NOTIFICATION,
THEN THE SCHOOL, THE TEACHERS,
THE STUDENTS, AND LAW
ENFORCEMENT HAVE TO BE VERY
CLEAR ABOUT WHAT THEIR ROLES ARE
DURING AN ACTIVE SHOOTING.
SO THAT REALLY GOES TO TRAINING.
>> Reporter: THIS IS AT LEAST
THE 31st SCHOOL SHOOTING IN THE
UNITED STATES SINCE THE STUNNING
RAMPAGE 13 YEARS AGO AT
COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL.
>> ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS ACROSS THE
COUNTRY HAVE BEEN PREPARING FOR
LOCKDOWN DRILLS, EVACUATIONS AND
OTHER SECURITY MEASURES SINCE
COLUMBINE.
WE'RE NOT GOING TO TEACH
CHILDREN TO ATTACK ARMED
INTRUDERS AND THROW PENCILS AND
NOTEBOOKS, BUT WE DO EXPECT TO
HAVE SCHOOL STAFF TRAINED ON
LOCKING DOWN, ON EVACUATION
PROCEDURES, WORKING WITH LAW
ENFORCEMENT ON ACTIVE SHOOTER
DRILLS AND THOSE ARE THE THINGS
THAT ARE IMPORTANT.
>> THERE'S LITTLE DEFENSE
AGAINST SOMEONE WHO'S WILLING TO
DIE THAT ARRIVES AT A SCHOOL
WITH MULTIPLE FIREARMS, BODY
ARMOR, AND WILLING TO KILL
ANYBODY THAT GETS IN THEIR WAY.
BUT THE REAL KEY IS BECAUSE YOU
CAN'T MAYBE STOP THAT, YOU
CLEARLY CAN REDUCE THE NUMBER OF
PEOPLE INJURED OR KILLED WITH
PROPER MOVEMENT, WHICH IS THE
RESULT OF TRAINING.
>> THERE'S NO WORDS THAT I CAN
COME UP WITH THAT WOULD EVEN
COME CLOSE TO DESCRIBING THE
SHEER TERROR OF HEARING THAT
YOUR SON IS IN A PLACE OR YOUR
CHILD IS IN A PLACE WHERE
THERE'S BEEN VIOLENCE.
YOU DON'T KNOW THE DETAILS OF
THAT VIOLENCE.
YOU DON'T KNOW THE CONDITION OF
YOUR CHILD.
AND YOU CAN'T DO ANYTHING TO
IMMEDIATELY HELP THEM.
IT IS A POWERLESS AND TERRIFYING
EXPERIENCE.
>> Reporter: HERE AT DANBURY
HOSPITAL, WE KNOW THAT 80
DOCTORS AND NURSES WERE
ANXIOUSLY AWAITING TO TREAT AS
MANY AS TWO DOZEN WOUNDED
VICTIMS FROM TODAY'S SHOOTING.
SADLY, ONLY THREE ARRIVED, AND
EVEN MORE TRAGIC, WE NOW KNOW
TWO OF THOSE VICTIMS HAVE SINCE
DIED.
BOTH OF THEM CHILDREN.
A CRUSHING BLOW TO THIS
COMMUNITY.
CYNTHIA?
>> THANKS, AMY.
>>> NEXT UP, WHO COULD DO THIS,
AND WHY?
WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THE
20-YEAR-OLD GUNMAN BEHIND THE
TRAGEDY.
SOMETIMES LIFE CAN BE WELL,
A LITTLE UNCOMFORTABLE.
BUT WHEN IT'S HARD OR HURTS
TO GO TO THE BATHROOM,
THERE'S DULCOLAX
STOOL SOFTENER.
DULCOLAX STOOL SOFTENER
DOESN'T MAKE YOU GO,
IT JUST MAKES IT
EASIER TO GO.
DULCOLAX STOOL SOFTENER.
MAKE YOURSELF COMFORTABLE.