COMPANY, CRACKING THE GLASS
CEILING FOR FUTURE GENERATIONS.
BUT IT'S NOT WHO YOU THINK.
IT WAS ALL FOR HER LITTLE
BROTHER.
>>> AND A GOOD TUESDAY MORNING,
EVERYONE.
A RITUAL RETURNS FOR THOUSANDS
OF OLDER STUDENTS IN NEWTOWN.
THEY'RE GOING BACK TO SCHOOL
TODAY.
BUT THOSE WHO ATTENDED SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY ARE STILL
WAITING FOR THEIR NEW
CLASSROOMS.
>> AND THIS LONG LINE OF
FUNERALS.
THESE VERY SAD DAYS.
IT ALL CONTINUES LATER TODAY.
ABC'S TAHMAN BRADLEY JOINS US
THIS MORNING FROM NEWTOWN.
GOOD MORNING, TAHMAN.
>> Reporter: GOOD MORNING, ROB
AND PAULA.
IT IS REMARKABLE TO SEE THIS
COMMUNITY THIS MORNING.
THE SIGNS OF REMEMBRANCE ARE
EVERYWHERE.
PEOPLE ARE PAYING THEIR RESPECTS
AT MEMORIALS AND FUNERALS.
NEWTOWN IS PERFORMING A GRIM
TASK.
PARENTS ARE DOING WHAT THEY
SHOULDN'T HAVE TO.
6-YEAR-OLD NOAH POZNER WAS
EULOGIZED AS A BOY WHO LIKED
ANIMALS, VIDEO GAMES AND MEXICAN
FOOD.
AT HIS FUNERAL, AN ONLOOKER
COLLAPSED.
INSIDE THE FUNERAL, HIS MOTHER
MOVED EVERYONE TO TEARS WITH HER
STORIES.
>> SHE TOLD HIM, I LOVE YOU.
AND IT MATTERS THAT I LOVED YOU.
>> Reporter: ANOTHER FUNERAL,
FOR JACK PINTO, ALSO 6.
>> IT'S SAD.
SAD.
HEAVY HEART.
>> Reporter: THERE'S STILL SO
MUCH PAIN FOR ALL CLOSE TO
FRIDAY'S SHOOTING.
CONNECTICUT GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY
WIPED AWAY TEARS RECALLING THE
MOMENT HE INFORMED PARENTS THEIR
CHILDREN HAD DIED.
NOW, HE WILL ATTEND SO MANY
FUNERALS.
>> YOU SEE LITTLE COFFINS AND
YOUR HEART HAS TO ACHE.
>> Reporter: NEW INFORMATION
ABOUT THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER,
ADAM LANZA, PAINTS A PICTURE OF
A YOUNG MAN THAT SEEMED TO BE
UNRAVELING.
FOR YEARS, HER MOTHER, NANCY,
SHARED HER STRUGGLES WITH ADAM'S
BEHAVIORAL AND EMOTIONAL
PROBLEMS WITH PEOPLE AT A
NEWTOWN BAR AND RESTAURANT,
ACCORDING TO THE OWNERS.
AND NANCY'S FRIENDS SAY SHE TOLD
THEM IN THE LAST FEW MONTHS,
ADAM WAS SO TROUBLED, HE WOULD
NOT LEAVE THE HOUSE.
>> SHE HOMESCHOOLED HIM AND
EVERYTHING.
I KNEW HE WAS ON MEDICATION.
BUT THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
>> Reporter: A FORMER BABYSITTER
SAYS HE WAS TOLD BY NANCY TO
NEVER LEAVE ADAM ALONE.
>> NEVER GO TO THE BATHROOM OR
TURN YOUR BACK ON HIM AT ANY
TIME.
>> Reporter: DESPITE HIS
PROBLEMS, FRIENDS SAY NANCY TOOK
HER SON TO LOCAL FIRING RANGES
AND INTRODUCED HIM TO THE WORLD
OF HIGH-POWERED GUNS.
THIS FRIDAY, THE GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT IS CALLING FOR A
MOMENT OF SILENCE AND FOR
CHURCHES TO RING BELLS AT THE
EXACT MOMENT OF LAST WEEK'S
SHOOTING.
ROB AND PAULA?
>> AN APPROPRIATE TRIBUTE, FOR
SURE.
AND, TAHMAN, WE KNOW STUDENTS IN
OTHER SCHOOLS, THEY WILL GET
BACK TO CLASS LATER TODAY.
BUT WHAT, SPECIFICALLY, ABOUT
THOSE SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
STUDENTS?
>> Reporter: THAT'S EXACTLY
RIGHT, ROB.
THE STUDENTS AT OTHER SCHOOLS
WILL RETURN TO CLASS.
BUT WITH A LOT OF POLICE AND
WITH GRIEF COUNSELORS.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
THEY'RE WORKING ON A NEARBY
SCHOOL TO GET READY FOR THEM.
IT'S GOING TO BE CHALK HILL
SCHOOL.
THE SCHOOL HASN'T HAD STUDENTS
FOR A FEW YEARS.
THEY'RE MOVING DESKS AND OTHER
FACILITIES FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL TO GET THE NEW
SCHOOL READY.
THEY STARTED TO WORK ON IT
YESTERDAY.
AND THEY HOPE TO HAVE IT
PREPARED SOON.
ROB AND PAULA?
>> ALL RIGHT.
TAHMAN BRADLEY LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, THIS MORNING.
THANK YOU FOR THAT REPORT,
TAHMAN.
>>> ON TOP OF THAT, WE ARE
LEARNING MORE ABOUT GUNMAN ADAM
LANZA'S PARENTS AND THEIR
TROUBLES.
ACCORDING TO A SOURCE CLOSE TO
PETER LANZA, THE BOY'S FATHER
MOVED OUT OF THE HOUSE BACK IN
APRIL OF 2001.
NOW, PETER AND ADAM LANZA SPENT
MOST OF THEIR WEEKENDS TOGETHER
UNTIL 2010.
THAT YEAR WAS THE LAST TIME ADAM
LANZA SAW EITHER HIS FATHER OR
HIS BROTHER, RYAN.
THOSE WHO KNEW ADAM SAY HE HAD
BEHAVIORAL ISSUES, NEEDED
CONSTANT SUPERVISION AND SIMPLY
DIDN'T RESPOND TO EITHER
PHYSICAL OR EMOTIONAL PAIN.
>> IF HE HAD CUT HIMSELF OR HURT
HIMSELF, HE WOULD NOT KNOW IT OR
FEEL IT.
SO, WE WERE BEING VERY, VERY
CAREFUL WITH HIM.
>> POLICE ARE STILL HAVING
TROUBLE FINDING A MOTIVE IN ALL
OF THIS.
A COMPUTER, THOUGH, TAKEN FROM
ADAM LANZA'S HOME IN NEWTOWN WAS
BADLY DAMAGED.
INVESTIGATORS ALSO SAY THEY
FOUND, QUOTE, SIGNIFICANT
EVIDENCE IN THAT HOUSE THAT
LANZA SHARED WITH HIS MOTHER
BEFORE KILLING HER.
>>> AND IN LIGHT OF THE TRAGEDY,
AMERICANS ARE TALKING ONCE AGAIN
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
A NEW ABC NEWS POLL FOUND THAT
54% OF AMERICANS FAVOR STRICTER
GUN CONTROL LAWS.
AND MORE THAN HALF SAY THE
SHOOTING REFLECTS BROADER
PROBLEMS IN OUR SOCIETY, NOT
JUST ONE TROUBLED PERSON.
ONE LEADING DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
SAYS, THIS MAY BE THE TIPPING
POINT.
BUT ANOTHER LAWMAKER SAYS, MORE
GUNS ARE THE ANSWER.
>> I DON'T KNOW ANYONE IN THE
SPORTING OR HUNTING ARENA THAT
GOES OUT WITH AN ASSAULT RIFLE.
I DON'T KNOW ANYONE THAT NEEDS
30 ROUNDS AND A CLIP TO GO
HUNTING.
>> SHE TAKES HIM OUT, TAKES HIS
HEAD OFF BEFORE HE CAN KILL
THOSE PRECIOUS KIDS.
>> AND TEXAS GOVERNOR, RICK
PERRY, SAYS HE SUPPORTS ARMING
TEACHERS IF THAT'S WHAT IT TAKES
TO KEEP STUDENTS SAFE.
>>> WE LEARNED OVERNIGHT THAT
THE MAJOR RETAILER, DICK'S
SPORTING GOODS, HAS STOPPED
SALES OF SOME RIFLES AND PULLED
GUNS FROM ITS STORE NEAR
NEWTOWN.
BUT MANY GUN STORES, INCLUDING
THIS ONE IN INDIANA, ARE
REPORTING A BIG INCREASE IN THE
SALE OF HANDGUNS, SEMIAUTOMATIC
WEAPONS, AS WELL AS AMMUNITION.
SOME CUSTOMERS ARE BUYING GUNS
IN CASE NEW ANTI-GUN LAWS GO
INTO EFFECT DOWN THE ROAD.
>>> ANOTHER MAJOR HEADLINE WE
ARE COVERING THIS MORNING, NEW
PROGRESS IN TALKS TO AVOID THE
FISCAL CLIFF.
BUT MAJOR DIFFERENCES DO REMAIN.
UNDER NEW CONCESSIONS MADE BY
THE WHITE HOUSE, THE BUSH TAX
CUTS WOULD BE EXTENDED FOR
ANYBODY EARNING UNDER $400,000 A
YEAR.
THE OFFER INCLUDES $1.22
TRILLION IN SPENDING CUTS.
BUT TOP REPUBLICANS WARNED LATE
LAST NIGHT THAT THERE IS NO
AGREEMENT ON SUBSTANTIAL ISSUES.
IF A DEAL ISN'T REACHED, TAX
INCREASES AND SPENDING CUTS KICK
IN TWO WEEKS FROM TODAY.
>>> DANIEL INOUYE, WAR HERO AND
LONG-TIME SENATOR, IS BEING
REMEMBERED THIS MORNING FROM
WASHINGTON TO HIS HOME STATE OF
HAWAII.
INOUYE WAS A WORLD WAR II MEDAL
OF HONOR WINNER, WHO LOST AN ARM
DURING A BATTLE IN ITALY.
HE BECAME THE FIRST
JAPANESE-AMERICAN IN CONGRESS.
AND SERVED 50 YEARS IN THE U.S.
SENATE.
DANIEL INOUYE DIED YESTERDAY AT
A WASHINGTON AREA HOSPITAL OF
BREATHING PROBLEMS.
HE WAS 88 YEARS OLD.
>>> AND SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON IS SAID TO BE
FEELING A LITTLE MORE LIKE
HERSELF AFTER SUFFERING A
CONCUSSION LAST WEEK.
TWO TEAMS OF DOCTORS CHECKED HER
OUT.
EVEN PUTTING HER ON AN I.V. DRIP
FOR A SHORT TIME.
AIDES SAY SHE IS FRUSTRATED AND
WANTS TO RETURN TO WORK.
SHE WILL BE UNABLE TO TESTIFY AT
THE CONGRESSIONAL HEARINGS ON
BENGHAZI THIS WEEK.
BUT SHE MAY DO SO DOWN THE ROAD.
>>> AND THE PACIFIC NORTHWEST IS
RECOVERING FROM THE STRONGEST
STORM OF THE SEASON, COMPLETE
WITH BLINDING SNOW, DRENCHING
RAIN AND DAMAGING WINDS.
80-MILE-PER-HOUR WINDS TOPPLED A
HUGE TREE THAT CRASHED INTO A
HOME IN WESTERN WASHINGTON,
NARROWLY MISSING A BABY IN HIS
CRIB.
FORTUNATELY, THAT CHILD WAS
UNINJURED.
AND THAT STORM BURIED CITIES,
LIKE YAKIMA, UNDER FIVE INCHES
OF SNOW.
HIGHER ELEVATIONS GOT UP TO TWO
FEET.
AND THOUSANDS OF FOLKS LOST
POWER.
NOW, THEY DO GET A SLIGHT BREAK
IN THE WEATHER TODAY.
BUT A NEW STORM IS MOVING IN
TOMORROW.
AND THAT STORM COULD DUMP
ANOTHER FOOT OF SNOW.
>> WINTER JUST DAYS AWAY,
OFFICIALLY.
>>> IT IS TIME, NOW, FOR THE
REST OF THE WEATHER FROM ACROSS
THIS NATION.
RAIN AND LIGHT SNOW FROM SEATTLE
TO PORTLAND.
WINDY WITH RAIN IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA.
BUT THE HEAVY SNOW, BRINGING UP
TO TEN INCHES TO SALT LAKE CITY.
WINTER STORM WATCHES FROM DENVER
TO GREEN BAY.
RAIN TAPERING OFF FROM D.C. TO
NEW YORK.
AND SNOWSHOWERS IN NORTHERN NEW
ENGLAND.
>> MOSTLY 40s IN THE NORTHEAST
AND MIDWEST.
70s FROM DALLAS TO NEW ORLEANS.
JUST 20s IN SALT LAKE CITY AND
IN FARGO.
>>> AND STILL TO COME, SOME
CHANGES FOR A POPULAR FACEBOOK
APP THAT ARE CAUSING CONCERN.
>>> ALSO, WANT TO TELL YOU HOW
YOU OR YOUR CHILD COULD END UP
IN AN ADVERTISEMENT WITHOUT EVEN
GIVING YOUR PERMISSION.
>>> ALSO AHEAD, A LITTLE GIRL
WHO COOKED UP SOME BIG PROGRESS.
WHILE HER QUEST TO HELP HER
LITTLE BROTHER SPARKED A NEW
I'M ONLY IN MY 60's...
I'VE GOT A NICE LONG LIFE AHEAD.
BIG PLANS.
SO WHEN I FOUND OUT
Medicare DOESN'T PAY
ALL MY MEDICAL EXPENSES,
I GOT A Medicare
SUPPLEMENT INSURANCE PLAN.
[ Male Announcer ] IF YOU'RE
ELIGIBLE FOR Medicare,
YOU MAY KNOW
IT ONLY COVERS ABOUT 80%
OF YOUR Part B
MEDICAL EXPENSES.
THE REST IS UP TO YOU.
CALL AND FIND OUT
ABOUT AN AARP Medicare
Supplement Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED Medicare
SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
IT COULD SAVE YOU THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
CALL NOW TO REQUEST
YOUR FREE DECISION GUIDE.
I'VE BEEN WITH MY DOCTOR
FOR 12 YEARS.
NOW I KNOW I'LL BE ABLE
TO STICK WITH HIM.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO VISIT
ANY DOCTOR OR HOSPITAL
THAT ACCEPTS Medicare PATIENTS.
PLUS, THERE ARE NO NETWORKS,
AND YOU NEVER NEED A REFERRAL.
SEE WHY MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
HAVE ALREADY ENROLLED
IN THE ONLY Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plans
ENDORSED BY AARP.
DON'T WAIT. CALL NOW.
>>> AND WELCOME BACK, EVERYBODY.
DRIVERS ARE FINDING A LITTLE
CHRISTMAS PRESENT AT THE GAS
STATION.
PRICES ARE DOWN 9 CENTS A
GALLON, JUST IN THE PAST WEEK.
THE NATIONAL AVERAGE FOR A
GALLON OF SELF-SERVE REGULAR IS
ABOUT $3.25 A GALLON.
THAT'S THE LOWEST PRICE IN A
YEAR.
AND THE FIRST TIME THIS YEAR THE
PRICES ARE BELOW $4 A GALLON IN
ALL 50 STATES.
>>> ALSO DOWN THIS MORNING ARE
SHARES IN COMPANIES THAT MAKE
GUNS.
INVESTORS ARE WORRIED ABOUT
TOUGHER RESTRICTIONS ON SALES IN
THE WAKE OF THAT CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING.
ASSAULT RIFLES IN PARTICULAR
HAVE BEEN A BIG GROWTH AREA FOR
THE INDUSTRY.
BUT MANY OF THE MOST FAMOUS
FIREARMS BRANDS LIKE BUSHMASTER,
WINCHESTER, COLT AND BARETTA ARE
PRIVATELY OWNED.
>>> YOU MAY BE STARRING IN AN AD
ON INSTAGRAM.
COMPANIES WILL USE THEM WITH
YOUR PHOTOS AND USER NAME.
THE ADVERTISERS WILL PAY
INSTAGRAM FOR USE OF THE PHOTOS.
BUT NOT YOU.
>>> AND EASY BAKE OVENS AREN'T
JUST FOR GIRLS ANYMORE.
McKENNA POPE PUSHED HASBRO FOR A
VERSION THAT'S SUITABLE FOR
BOYS.
THE BLACK AND SILVER MODEL GOES
ON SALE NEXT YEAR.
AND HASBRO WILL INCLUDE BOYS IN
ITS PACKAGING AND ADS.
McKENNA GOT THE IDEA WATCHING
HER YOUNGER BROTHER PLAY WITH
THE EASY BAKE OVEN.
>> GENDER EQUAL BY.
WELL DONE, LITTLE GIRL.
>>> COMFORT WHEN WORDS AREN'T
ENOUGH.
HOW SPECIALLY-TRAINED DOGS ARE
TRAVELING HUNDREDS OF MILES TO
HELP EASE THE PAIN OF THE
NEWTOWN COMMUNITY.
>>> PLUS, SEVERE STORMS.
A NEIGHBORHOOD GETS SLAMMED BY
SOME POUNDING SURF, MAKING IT
PRETTY TOUGH TO GET AROUND.
WHAT YOU CAN EXPECT FOR YOUR
TUESDAY COMMUTE.
right?
2:30 in the afternoon, a lot to
do...and you've hit the wall.
But you gotta get stuff done.
So take 5-hour® ENERGY.
Just open it up, knock it back
and roll up your sleeves.
5-hour ENERGY® is faster and
easier than coffee...
man, does it work!
You'll get that alert,
energized feeling you
need to get stuff done...
A lot of stuff.
Wow! Look at you go.
5-hour ENERGY®...When
You Gotta Get Stuff Done.
I GET CONGESTED.
BUT NOW, WITH ZYRTEC-D®,
I HAVE THE PROVEN ALLERGY RELIEF
OF ZYRTEC®,
PLUS A POWERFUL DECONGESTANT.
ZYRTEC-D® LETS ME BREATH FREER,
SO I CAN LOVE THE AIR.
[ Male Announcer ] ZYRTEC-D®.
BEHIND THE PHARMACY COUNTER.
NO PRESCRIPTION NEEDED.
WITHOUT FRESHLY-MADE PASTA.
YOU COULD ALSO CUT CORNERS
BY MAKING IT WITHOUT
100% REAL CHEDDAR CHEESE.
BUT THEN...IT WOULDN'T BE
STOUFFER'S MAC & CHEESE.
JUST ONE OF OVER 70
SATISFYING RECIPES FOR ONE
FROM STOUFFER'S.
FOR WHAT?
WHEN THINGS WERE TOUGH,
YOU KEPT BELIEVING IN ME...
YOU HELPED
MAKE THIS HAPPEN.
[ Jane ] BEHIND EVERY OPEN HEART
IS A STORY.
TELL YOURS WITH MY OPEN HEART
COLLECTION AT KAY JEWELERS.
KEEP YOUR HEART OPEN...
AND LOVE WILL ALWAYS
FIND ITS WAY IN.
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
FLAVOR BOOST, MEET BEEF.
IT'S SWANSON FLAVOR BOOST.
CONCENTRATED BROTH
TO ADD DELICIOUS FLAVOR
TO YOUR SKILLET DISH
IN JUST ONE STIR.
MMM!
[ Female Announcer ]
COOK, MEET COMPLIMENTS.
GET RECIPES AT FLAVORBOOST.COM.
FIVE DAYS LATER,
I HAD A MASSIVE HEART ATTACK.
BAYER ASPIRIN WAS THE FIRST
THING THE EMTS GAVE ME.
NOW, I'M ON
A BAYER ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Male Announcer ] BE SURE
TO TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE YOU BEGIN
AN ASPIRIN REGIMEN.
[ Woman ]
LEARN FROM MY STORY.
>>> THE STORM THAT BATTERED THE
WESTERN PART OF WASHINGTON STATE
ALSO FLOODED HOMES AND
BUSINESSES AROUND THE PUGET
SOUND.
THE TIDE WAS SO HIGH AND PUSHED
WATER FROM THE SOUND INTO HOUSES
ON DAY ISLAND.
BOAT LAUNCHES AND ROADS WERE
DAMAGED.
AND STREETS WERE LITTERED WITH
DEBRIS.
>>> WITH THAT, LET'S LOOK AT
YOUR MORNING ROAD CONDITIONS ON
THIS TUESDAY.
SLICK AT TIMES FROM SEATTLE TO
SAN DIEGO.
SNOW-COVERED ROADS IN THE MORN
AND CENTRAL ROCKIES.
LIGHT SNOW MAKES NOR A SLIPPERY
COMMUTE IN NORTHERN NEW ENGLAND.
WET HIGHWAYS FROM D.C. UP TO THE
BIG APPLE.
>>> IF YOU'RE PLAYING, AIRPORT
DELAYS ARE POSSIBLE IN SALT LAKE
CITY, PHILADELPHIA, NEW YORK
CITY, BOSTON, MINNEAPOLIS AND
LOS ANGELES.
FULL BOARD THERE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
>>> RECAPPING OUR TOP STORY,
NOW.
OF COURSE, THE TRAGEDY IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THREE MORE FUNERALS ARE EXPECTED
TODAY, AS WELL AS THE WAKE FOR
TEACHER VICKI SOTO.
MIDDLE AND HIGH SCHOOL STUDENTS
GO BACK TO CLASS TODAY.
BUT STUDENTS FROM SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY ARE WAITING FOR THEIR
NEW SCHOOL TO BE MADE READY.
>> AS FOR THE SHOOTER, A
COMPUTER TAKEN FROM ADAM LANZA'S
HOME WAS BADLY DAMAGED, PERHAPS
BY A HAMMER.
BUT INVESTIGATORS HOPE TO
RECOVER INFORMATION ON THAT HARD
DRIVE.
>> SUGGESTING IT REALLY WAS
PREMEDITATED IF HE TOOK THE TIME
TO DO THAT.
>>> ALSO, SOME HEALING SPIRITS
ON FOUR LEGS HAVE ARRIVED TO
COMFORT PEOPLE IN THE TOWN OF
NEWTOWN.
THERAPY DOG, SOME THAT TRAVELED
FROM THE MIDWEST, ARE PROVIDING
THE SUPPORT A CANINE ONLY CAN.
>> THE HANDLERS SAID JUST
PETTING THE DOGS CAN HELP PEOPLE
FOCUS ON SOMETHING ELSE, IF ONLY
FOR A FEW MOMENTS.
A BRIEF BREAK FROM THIS TRAGIC
REALITY.
>>> AND SUPPORT IS FLOWING INTO
NEWTOWN FROM EIGHTH GRADERS MORE
THAN 1,000 MILES AWAY.
STUDENTS FROM SHREVEPORT,
LOUISIANA, WROTE LETTERS OF HOPE
AND ENCOURAGEMENT TO FAMILIES
IMPACTED BY THE TRAGEDY.
ONE OF THE LETTERS READ, THIS
TRAGEDY HAS LEFT A SCAR ON MY
HEART TO WILL TAKE SOME TIME TO
HEAL.
>>> AND THE UCONN HUSKIES
BASKETBALL TEAM, THEY'RE PAYING
TRIBUTE TO THE STUDENTS OF SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY.
THERE WAS A MOMENT OF SILENCE
BEFORE LAST NIGHT'S GAME.
THEY WORE A GREEN PATCH WITH
S.H.
THE LADY HUSKIES WILL REMAIN ON
THE UNIFORMS OF BOTH TEAMS FOR
THE REMAINDER OF THE SEASON.
>> SUPPORT FROM AROUND THE
WORLD.
SO GOOD TO SEE.
>>> STICKING WITH SPORTS OF A
DIFFERENT KIND NOW.
WITH PLAYOFF HOPES ON THE LINE,
THE JETS SUFFERED A
DISAPPOINTING AND EMBARRASSING
LOSS MONDAY NIGHT.
WE GET MORE FROM ESPN NEWS.
>> CASSIDY HUBBARTH WITH YOUR
"SPORTSCENTER" UPDATE.
THE JETS KEEPING THEIR HOPES
ALIVE ON "MONDAY NIGHT
FOOTBALL."
A MOMENT OF SILENCE TO REMEMBER
THOSE INVOLVED IN THE SHOOTINGS
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
PLAYERS WITH S.H.E.S. DECALS TO
HONOR THOSE AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
SECOND QUARTER, TITANS FROM
THEIR OWN 6 YARD LINE.
LET'S SEE WHAT JOHNSON'S 94-YARD
DASH LOOKS LIKE.
CHRIS JOHNSON, JUST TAKING OFF.
OUTRUNS EVERYBODY FOR A 94-YARD
TOUCHDOWN RUN, IN 10.48 SECONDS.
THE LONGEST RUN IN TITANS'
HISTORY.
THIRD QUARTER.
THIRD AND 12 FOR MARK SANCHEZ.
HE GETS THE 23-YARD TOUCHDOWN.
JETS TAKE THE 10-7 LEAD.
ENSUING DRIVE.
TITANS TRYING TO ANSWER.
JAKE LOCKER ON THE DESIGNED RUN.
GETS THE SCORE TO GIVE THE
TITANS THE LEAD, 14-10.
FOURTH QUARTER, TWO MINUTES
LEFT.
JETS DOWN 14-10, ON THE 23 YARD
LINE.
AND SANCHEZ DROPS BACK.
INTERCEPTED.
HIS FOURTH PICK OF THE GAME.
HIS FOURTH GAME WITH AT LEAST
FOUR PICKS.
TITANS PUNTING, WITH 53 SECONDS
REMAINING.
AND THIS WAS A TERRIBLE PUNT.
IT GOES TO THE 25 YARD LINE.
SANCHEZ AND THE JETS WITH ONE
LAST CHANCE TO WIN THE GAME.
WOULD HE TAKE ADVANTAGE?
SANCHEZ, WOULD YOU?
NOPE.
FUMBLES THE SNAP.
SANCHEZ, TURNOVERS THIS SEASON,
THE MOST IN THE NFL.
TITANS WIN, 14-10.
>>> THAT WAS YOUR "SPORTSCENTER"
UPDATE.
I'M CASSIDY HUBBARTH.
HAVE A GREAT DAY.
>> THANKS, CASSIDY.
>>> AND A MILESTONE FOR A
LEGENDARY BASKETBALL COACH.
>> SYRACUSE BEAT DETROIT LAST
NIGHT, GIVING JIM BOEHEIM HIS
900th WIN.
HE'S THE THIRD NCAA DIVISION I
COACH TO REACH THAT MARK.
BOEHEIM IS 68 YEARS OLD AND 37th
YEAR AS COACH OF THE ORANGEMEN.
>> 37 YEARS AT ONE UNIVERSITY.
THAT'S UNPRECEDENTED.
>> YOU DON'T SEE THAT LONGEVITY
THESE DAYS.
>>> UP NEXT, AN EMOTIONAL NIGHT
FOR THE LATE-NIGHT COMICS.
>>> AND SANTA CAME EARLY FOR
SOME FAMILIES.
AND IT'S A SENTIMENT THAT'S
DEFINITELY SPREADING.
STAY WITH UTHIS
A REGULAR GUY
WITH AN IRREGULAR HEARTBEAT.
THE USUAL, BOB?
NOT TODAY.
[ Male Announcer ]
BOB HAS AFIB:
ATRIAL FIBRILLATION NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
A CONDITION THAT PUTS HIM
AT GREATER RISK FOR A STROKE.
[ GPS ] TURN LEFT.
I DON'T THINK SO.
[ Male Announcer ]
FOR YEARS, BOB TOOK WARFARIN,
AND MADE A MONTHLY TRIP TO THE
CLINIC TO GET HIS BLOOD TESTED.
BUT NOT ANYMORE.
BOB'S DOCTOR RECOMMENDED
A DIFFERENT OPTION:
ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
XARELTO® IS THE FIRST AND ONLY
ONCE-A-DAY PRESCRIPTION
BLOOD THINNER
FOR PATIENTS WITH AFIB
NOT CAUSED
BY A HEART VALVE PROBLEM,
THAT DOESN'T REQUIRE
ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING.
LIKE WARFARIN,
XARELTO® IS PROVEN EFFECTIVE
TO REDUCE THE RISK
OF AN AFIB-RELATED STROKE.
THERE IS LIMITED DATA
ON HOW THESE DRUGS COMPARE
WHEN WARFARIN IS WELL MANAGED.
NO ROUTINE BLOOD MONITORING
MEANS BOB CAN SPEND HIS
EXTRA TIME HOWEVER HE LIKES.
NEW ZEALAND!
XARELTO®
IS JUST ONE PILL A DAY,
TAKEN WITH THE EVENING MEAL.
AND WITH
NO DIETARY RESTRICTIONS,
BOB CAN EAT THE HEALTHY FOODS
HE LIKES.
DO NOT STOP TAKING
XARELTO® RIVAROXABAN
WITHOUT TALKING TO THE DOCTOR
WHO PRESCRIBES IT FOR YOU.
STOPPING MAY INCREASE YOUR RISK
OF HAVING A STROKE.
GET MEDICAL HELP RIGHT AWAY
IF YOU DEVELOP ANY SIGNS
OR SYMPTOMS OF BLEEDING,
LIKE UNUSUAL BRUISING
OR TINGLING.
YOU MAY HAVE A HIGHER RISK
OF BLEEDING
IF YOU TAKE XARELTO®
WITH ASPIRIN PRODUCTS,
NSAIDS OR BLOOD THINNERS.
TALK TO YOUR DOCTOR
BEFORE TAKING XARELTO®
IF YOU CURRENTLY HAVE
ABNORMAL BLEEDING.
XARELTO® CAN CAUSE BLEEDING,
WHICH CAN BE SERIOUS,
AND RARELY MAY LEAD TO DEATH.
YOU ARE LIKELY TO BRUISE
MORE EASILY ON XARELTO®,
AND IT MAY TAKE LONGER
FOR BLEEDING TO STOP.
TELL YOUR DOCTORS
YOU ARE TAKING XARELTO®
BEFORE ANY PLANNED MEDICAL
OR DENTAL PROCEDURES.
BEFORE STARTING XARELTO®,
TELL YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ANY CONDITIONS,
SUCH AS KIDNEY, LIVER
OR BLEEDING PROBLEMS.
READY TO CHANGE YOUR ROUTINE?
ASK YOUR DOCTOR
ABOUT ONCE-A-DAY XARELTO®.
FOR MORE INFORMATION
INCLUDING COST SUPPORT OPTIONS,
CALL 1-888-XARELTO
OR VISIT GOXARELTO.COM.
>>> AND IT WAS AN EMOTIONAL
NIGHT FOR LATE-NIGHT TALK SHOW
HOSTS RETURNING TO THE AIR LAST
NIGHT FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
THE TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK.
>> JIMMY KIMMEL FOUGHT BACK
TEARS.
AND "THE LATE SHOW'S" DAVID
LETTERMAN, STRUGGLED TO FIND THE
RIGHT WORDS, AS BOTH MEN, OF
COURSE, TALKED ABOUT THE
SHOOTING.
>> YOU THINK ABOUT YOUR OWN KID.
I TAKE HIM TO SCHOOL EVERY NOW
AND THEN.
YOU KNOW?
WHAT?
ARE WE SUPPOSED TO BE WORRIED
ABOUT DROPPING OUR KIDS OFF AT
SCHOOL NOW?
I DON'T KNOW.
I NEVER WORRIED ABOUT IT BEFORE.
I THOUGHT, WELL, HERE, SCHOOL IS
A GOOD PLACE, WHERE MY SON WILL
BE FREE OF THE IDIOT DECISIONS
MADE BY HIS FATHER.
>> IT FEELS WEIRD TO DO A SHOW
WITH SO MUCH SADNESS.
AND SOMETIMES, THOUGH, THAT'S
WHAT NEEDS TO HAPPEN.
I THINK THE PRESIDENT SAID WHAT
NEEDED TO BE SAID LAST NIGHT ON
TELEVISION.
I THINK HE SPOKE BEAUTIFULLY.
I JUST WANT THE PEOPLE IN
CONNECTICUT TO KNOW THAT WE DO
NOT TAKE WHAT YOU'RE GOING
THROUGH LIGHTLY.
AND WE ARE THINKING ABOUT YOU
HERE A LOT, ALL OF US.
EVEN THOUGH WE'RE AT A TALK
SHOW.
>> ALWAYS GOOD TO SEE THOSE GUYS
CHANGE THE MOOD A LITTLE BIT
WHEN THERE IS A NATIONAL
TRAGEDY.
THE LAST TIME I REMEMBER THAT
WAS DAVE LETTERMAN DURING 9/11,
WHEN HE WAS SUPREMELY EMOTIONAL.
AND GUIDED THE NATION TO A TIME
WHERE IT FELT OKAY TO LAUGH
AGAIN.
IT IS A TOUGH JOB FOR THOSE
GUYS.
>> IT IS.
AND EVEN THOSE GUYS ARE AT A
LOSS FOR WORDS.
AND SEEKING SOME KIND OF
COMFORT.
>>> ALL EYES WERE ON A HAPPY
COUPLE AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
IT WASN'T THE OBAMAS, THOUGH.
>> A U.S. MARINE MADE HISTORY BY
PROPOSING TO HIS BOYFRIEND IN
THE GRAND FOYER AFTER A HOLIDAY
TOUR.
IT IS BELIEVED TO BE THE FIRST
SAME-SEX MARRIAGE PROPOSAL EVER
TO TAKE PLACE AT THE WHITE
HOUSE.
CAPTAIN MATTHEW PHELPS SAYS HIS
ENGAGEMENT HAS BEEN
WELL-RECEIVED BY HIS MARINE
CORPS PEERS.
>> IT'S NOT CLEAR IF THE
PRESIDENT KNOWS ABOUT THE
ENGAGEMENT.
THE WHITE HOUSE DECLINED TO
COMMENT.
>> IT'S NICE ENDING TO A YEAR
WHEN THE PRESIDENT CAME OUT AND
SUPPORTED SAME-SEX MARRIAGE.
>>> AND THE HOLIDAY SPIRIT LIVES
ON.
A CERTAIN SANTA CLAUS WENT TO
THIS WALMART IN SOUTH HOUSTON
AND PAID OFF SEVERAL LAYAWAY
ACCOUNTS THAT WERE TOYS ONLY.
SANDRA GARZA OWED NEARLY 300
BUCKS WHEN THE STORE CALLED HER
TO TELL HER IT WAS ALL PAID.
>> AND IN NORTH CAROLINA, SANTA
PAID OFF FIVE LAYAWAY ACCOUNTS,
HANDING OVER A TOTAL OF $800 ON
THE DAY BEFORE THAT PAYMENT WAS
DUE.
SO, WE WANT TO SAY, TAKE THAT,
MR. GRINCH.
>> IN THE HOLIDAY SPIRIT.
VERY COOL.
>>> FOR SOME OF YOU, YOUR LOCAL
NEWS IS NEXT.
>> AND FOR EVERYONE ELSE, WE'LL
BE RIGHT BACK.
Jack?!
Looks good
ladies!
Jack!
Come on,
stop the car.
JACK!
No, no, no, no, no!
The only thing more surprising
than finding the
perfect gifts..
Niice.
...is where you find them.
How did you know?
I had a little help.
This is how to gift.
This is Sears.
♪ YOU MAKE ME HAPPY
[ Female Announcer ]
CHOOSE THE SAME BRAND
YOUR MOM TRUSTED FOR YOU.
CHILDREN'S TYLENOL,
THE #1 BRAND
OF PAIN AND FEVER RELIEF
RECOMMENDED BY PEDIATRICIANS
AND USED BY MOMS
DECADE AFTER DECADE.
STARTS WITH GROUND BEEF,
UNIONS, AND PEPPERS
BAKED IN A KETCHUP GLAZE
WITH SAVORY GRAVY
AND MASHED RUSSET POTATOES.
WHAT MAKES STOUFFER'S MEATLOAF
BEST OF ALL?
THAT MOMENT YOU ENJOY IT
AT HOME.
STOUFFER'S. LET'S FIX DINNER.
>>> THE FIRST DAY BACK TO
CLASS FOR SOME NEW S IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> GUN DEBATE -- RAINS ON IN
THE WAKE OF THE SHOOTING WHAT
STATE LAWMAKERS ARE PLANNING
TO DO TO RESTRICT GUN SALES IN
CALIFORNIA.
>>> TRACKING SHOWERS, LIVE
DOPPLER OVER THE OCEAN NOW
WE'LL SEE IF THEY COME INLAND.
FREEZING COLD TONING RAIN IN TH.
AND LIGHT SNOW IN NORTHERN
NEW ENGLAND.
>>> AND FINALLY FROM US THIS
MORNING, THE SCHOOL SHOOTING
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT IS
TOUCHING LIVES, NOT ONLY HERE IN
THE NORTHEAST.
BUT REALLY ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
>> THE EXPRESSION OF SUPPORT ARE
EVEN COMING IN FROM AROUND THE
GLOBE.
AND THE RESPONSE HAS BEEN
INCREDIBLE.
WABC'S LUCY YANG HAS THE STORY.
>> Reporter: IF IT IS ANY
COMFORT, NEWTOWN DOES NOT SUFFER
ALONE.
TAKE A LOOK AT IRENE'S FLOWER
SHOP.
THEY HAVE RECEIVED ORDERS FOR
BOUQUETS FROM AROUND THE WORLD.
>> WE GOT SOME FROM GERMANY.
WE GOT SOME FROM NEW BRITAIN.
WHERE ELSE?
CALIFORNIA.
FLORIDA.
KANSAS.
ANY PLACE YOU CAN THINK OF,
WE'VE GOTTEN A CALL.
>> Reporter: AT THE POST OFFICE,
SO MANY CONDOLENCE CARDS AND
LETTERS HAVE POURED IN, A
SPECIAL BOX HAS BEEN SET UP TO
COLLECT A MOUNTAIN OF NOTES FOR
LATER DISTRIBUTION TO THE
FAMILIES.
THE FIREHOUSE WHICH WAS THE
EMOTIONAL EPICENTER FOR PARENTS
FRANTICALLY LOOKING FOR THEIR
CHILDREN ON THAT MORNING,
RECEIVED 26 BREATHES FROM A
CHRISTMAS FARM IN OREGON.
MIKE TADRY MADE SIMPLE CROSSES
FOR EACH VICTIM.
AND DELIVERED THEM TODAY.
>> NOBODY CAN STOP THE PAIN OF
WHAT THESE PEOPLE ARE GOING
THROUGH.
IT'S A TRAGEDY BEYOND
COMPREHENSION.
IT REALLY IS.
>> Reporter: AND THERE'S THE
LOCAL WATERING HOLE.
THE NEWTOWN GENERAL STORE.
THE MANAGER GOT A CALL THIS
MORNING FROM A STRANGER OFFERING
TO BUY COFFEE FOR ANYBODY WHO
NEEDED SOME WARM COMFORT.
A KIND GESTURE POURED OUT INTO
100 CUPS.
>> EVERYBODY WAS HERE CRYING.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE FROM THE TOWN.
IT WAS VERY KIND.
>> Reporter: WE FOUND THE DONOR,
TOM CAVANAGH, IN LOS ANGELES.
A 991 CALL OPERATOR, WHO HAS
HANDLED PLENTY OF EMERGENCIES.
BUT THIS ONE MOVED HIM TO ACT.
>> AFTER THE LAST FUNERAL, THEY
MAY BREAK APART.
THERE'S THINGS ABOUT THEIR LIVES
THAT WILL NEVER BE THE SAME.
A CUP OF COFFEE GOES A LONG
WAYS.
>> IT CAN BE THE SIMPLE THINGS
SOMETIMES.
>> THE LIGHT SHINES BRIGHTEST IN
THE DARKNESS.
>>> THAT'S WHAT'S MAKING NEWS IN
AMERICA THIS MORNING.
>> THANKS FOR WATCHING,
EVERYBODY.
CAPTIONED BY
CLOSED CAPTIONING SERVICES, INC.
>>> TUESDAY MORNING, 4:30
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US, I'M
KRISTEN SZE.
>>> AND I'M ERIC THOMAS.
IT IS NOT RAINING.
>>> BUT IT IS STILL COLD.
>> IT IS A LITTLE BIT COLD.
IN THE 40s IN MOST
NEIGHBORHOODS.
CHECK OUT DOPPLER 7 HD, RATHER
QUIET THIS MORNING.
PUT AWAY THE WET WEATHER GEAR
FOR THE NEXT COUPLE OF
MORNINGS, WE ARE GOING TO HAVE
COOL CONDITIONS THAT IS