>> A PARENT INSIDE OF THE
SCHOOL AT THE TIME SAID SHE
BELIEVED 100 ROUNDS HAD BEEN
FIRED.
THE FIRST 911 CALL CAME AT
AROUND 9:30.
POLICE BEGAN A SEARCH FOR THE
GUNMAN.
>> THEY WERE POLICE WITH
RIFLES AND HANDGUNS.
THE,áM
POLICE CAN VERIFY THE SHOOTER
HAD NO PRIOR RECORD.
>> CORNELL, THANK YOU.
A TEARFUL PRESIDENT OBAMA
ADDRESSED THE NATION THIS
AFTERNOON.
>> HE EXPRESSED PRO FOUND
SADNESS AND OFFERED DEEPEST
CONDOLENCES TO THE FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS.
>> THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO
DIED TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
AND... BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS
BETWEEN AGES OF FIVE AND 10
YEARS OLD.LJ29Q
THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
KIDS ARE GONE.
SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY.
THIS EVENING, MICHELLE AND I
WILL DO WHAT I KNOW EVERY
PARENT IN AMERICA WILL DO.
WHICH IS HUG OUR CHILDREN A
LITTLE TIGHTER AND WE'LL TELL
THEM WE LOVE THEM.
AND WE'LL REMIND EACH OTHER
HOW DEEPLY WE LOVE ONE
ANOTHER.
BUT THERE ARE FAMILIES IN
CONNECTICUT WHO CANNOT DO THAT
TONIGHT.
AND THEY NEED ALL OF US RIGHT
NOW.
IN THE HARD DAYS TO COME THE
COMMUNITY NEEDS US TO BE AT
OUR BEST AS AMERICANS ASK I
WILL DO EVERYTHING IN MY POWER
AS PRESIDENT TO HELP.
>> THE PRESIDENT ORDERED FLAGS
TO BE LOWERED TO HALF STAFF IN
HONOR OF THE VICTIMS.
HE SAID AMERICA HAS ENDURED
TOO MANY TRAGEDIES AND SAYS
MEANINGFUL ACTION NEEDS TO BE
TAKEN TO PREVENT INCIDENTS
LIKE IT REGARDLESS OF THE
POLITIC AUTOS ABC 7 NEWS
VIEWERS EXPRESSING CONDOLENCES
TO THOSE TOUCHED BY THE
TRAGEDY ON OUR FACE BOOK PAGE,
WE INVITE TO YOU SHARE YOUR
THOUGHTS.
>> BUT IT'S VERY DIFFICULT TO
EXPRESS WITH WORDS HOW
DEVASTATING THIS TRAGEDY IS.
>> YES.
WAYNE FREEDMAN SHOWS US THE
MOMENTS OF RAW EMOTION TODAY,
BETWEEN HEADLINES.
>> THIS IS THE DAY WHEN THE
NAMES SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT CHANGED FOREVER.
ONCE OBSCURE, THEY'RE NOW
INFAMOUS.
>> LIKE YOU, YOU KNOW, YOU
READ IT IN THE PAPER AND SEE
IT IN THE NEWS, YOU'RE LIKE,
OH, MY GOD, THEN, YOU HEARD
SOMETHING HAPPENED CLOSE TO
HOME.
IT'S LIKE... I THINK I'M STILL
IN SHOCK.
>> BUT RELIEVED SHOCK AS
DIFFICULT AS THIS STORY IS TOo
BELIEVE, IMAGINE LIVING IT.
LEARNING YOUR CHILD'S FATE IN
BITS AND PIECES.
>> MY NEIGHBOR HEARD GUNSHOTS.
AND THEN, I JUST SAID TO HER
DON'T WORRY. SHE SAID NO.
I CALLED THE SCHOOL, NO ONE
ANSWERED.
>> SOMEONE CAME INTO THE ROOM
AND SHOTjU4U A TEACHER.
THAT IS ALL I KNOW.
SORRY.
>> I JUST HEARD THE PRINCIPAL
WAS SHOT AND KILLED.
I HEARD KIDS WERE SHOT.
I -- A TEACHER, MISS HAM ONS
WAS SHOTTED.
>> THEY WAITED.
FEARFUL PARENTS AND CHILDREN.
>> THERE WERE THREE CHILDREN
THAT CAME OUT.
ONE WAS, HAD A VERY BLOODY
FACE, IT WAS VERY VIOLENT
SCENE Z THERE ARE TWO OTHER
ONES THAT THEY WERE YOU KNOW,
THEY WERE IN THE ARMS OF THE
STATE TROOPER.
THEY DID NOT MOVE.
THEIR FACE WAS VERY PALE.
AND IT WAS VERY TRAGIC IT WILL
REMAIN SO, THIS WON'T BE EASY.
>> IT'S GOING TO BE ONE OF THE
THINGS THEY'RE TRYING TO
UNDERSTAND WHAT HAPPENS WH. WE
TELL THEM WHAT HAPPENED IN
DETAILS I THINK IT'S GOING TO
MAKE IT WORSE.
>> IN THE UNITED STATES WE
FOCUS ON THE ISSUE THAT'S
DIVIDE US, THEN, THIS COMES
ALONG.
AND HERE, 3,000 MILES AWAY,
WE'RE TOUCHED AS IF IT
HAPPENED NEXT DOOR RMTzE< IN SAN
FRANCISCO, WAYNE FREEDMAN, ABC
7 NEWS.
>> SOME BAY AREA SCHOOLS ARE
TAKING PRECAUTIONS TODAY THIS,
IS VIDEO FROM SKY 7 IN OAKLAND
OVER LOCKWOOD ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL IN RESPONSE, THE
OAKLAND POLICE DEPARTMENT MADE
SCHOOL OFFICERS AVAILABLE AT
ANY CAMPUS THAT WANTED EXTRA
COVERAGE.
OFFICERS ARE ASSIGNED TO SIX
CAMPUSES IN THE DISTRICT.
>> CALIFORNIA SUPERINTENDENT
OF SCHOOLS RELEASED THIS
STATEMENT TODAY.
THIS MORNING'S SHOOTING IS A
TERRIBLE, SENSELESS@3RRm TRAGED.
OUR GRIEF IS DEEPER WHEN
THINKING OF THE INNOCENCE OF
LIVES LOST AND EFFORTS OF
TEACHERS AND SCHOOL LEADERS TO
PROTECT THEM.
OUR HEARTS GO OUT TO VICTIMS,
FAMILIES AND SCHOOL COMMUNITY
ITS AFFECTING COMMUNITIES
ACROSS THE NATION.
AT 4:30 ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER
LAURA ANTHONY WILL TELL WHAUS
BAY AREA SCHOOLS ARE DOING TO
REACH OUT TO PARENTS, CHILDREN
AND STAFF.
WE'LL BE JOINED BY A
PSYCHOLOGY PROFESSOR FROM
SANTA CLARA UNIVERSITY TALKING
ABOUT HOW I COMMUNITY DEAL WAS
THIS TRAUMA, AND HOW PARENTS
SHOULD TALK TO THEIR KIDS
ABOUT VIOLENCE.
>> ONE OF THE DEADLIEST
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
HAPPENED IN 1989 IN STOCKTON.
FIVE CHILDREN KILLED AND 29
OTHERS WOUNDED.
THE GUNMAN THEN SHOT AND
KILLED HIMSELF.
SEVEN PEOPLE WERE KILL AT
OIKOS UNIVERSITY.
THE GUNMAN IS UNDERGOING A
SKRIK EVALUATION.
IN FEBRUARY, THREE STUDENTS
KILLED TWO, WOUNDED IN OHIO.
STUDENTS WAITED FOR BUSES TO
THE SCHOOL.
THE 17-YEAR-OLD GUNMAN IS
BEING CHARGED AS AN ADULT
THERE.
THE DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTING
HAPPENED IN 2007.
THAT WAS AT VIRGINIA TECH.
THE GUNMAN THERE KILLED 32
PEOPLE, THEN SHOT AND KILLED
HIMSELF.
AND WE REMEMBER IN 1999 AT
COLUMBINE HIGH SCHOOL, TWO
STUDENTS OPENED FIRING,
KILLING 12 CLASSMATES AND A
TEACHER BEFORE KILLING
THEMSELVES.
26 OTHERS WERE WOUNDED.
>> IT'S BEEN A HARROWING SCENE
IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT ALL
DAY.
WE'RE ALSO HEARING LIFE SAVING
STORIES.
>> ABC FWHUS REPORTER MARK
GLENNBLATT JOINS FRUS SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WITH
MORE.
>> WE HAVE NEW INFORMATION.
SOURCES NOW TELLING US THAT
THIS RAMPAGE ALL BEGAN AT THE
MOTHER -- THE GUNMAN'S
MOTHER'S HOME, HE WENT THERE,
APPARENTLY PULLED OUT A GUN,
SHOT HER IN THE FACE, THEN
WENT OVER TO SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WITH A
BULLETPROOF VEST ON, PULLING
OUT ANOTHER GUN AND BEGAN CAN
Z.CONTINUE THAT HAD RAMPAGE
THERE, FIRING AT ANY YOUNG
CHILD COSEE.
WE'RE HEARING THAT THE
GUNSHOTS BEGAN AFTER SOME KIND
OF AN ALTERCATION AT THEkY,g
SCHOOL WITH THE PRINCIPAL AT
THAT SCHOOL THIS, IS REALLY
TURNED OUT TO BE AN ALMOST
UNFATHOMABLE TRAGEDY FOR THIS
VERY, VERY PEACEFUL TOWN IN
WESTERN CONNECTICUT.
>> NOW, WE'VE BEEN HEARING
REPORTS OF JUST HOW HEROIC
SOME TEACHERS WERE, LOCKING
KIDS IN BATHROOMS.
WHAT CAN YOU TALK TO BUS THAT?
AND WHAT UNFOLDED DURING THIS
TRAGEDY?
>> IF THERE IS POSITIVE SILVER
LINING TO THIS THIS, IS ONE
STORY.
WE'RE HEARING HOW ONE TEACHER
HEARD THE SHOTS RINGING INTO
THE AIR AND SHE NEEDLY REACTED,
INSTINCTS KICKED IN AND SHE
STARTED GETTING EVERYONE OF
THE CHILDREN INTO A SMALL
BATHROOM LOCATED INSIDE OF HER
CLASSROOM.
IN ORDER TO FIT THE KIDS INTO
THE BATHROOM SHE HAD TO PILE
SOME ON TOP OF EACH OTHER AND
ON TOP OF A TOILET Z NOW, OF
COURSE, WE KNOW SHE PROBABLY
SAVED ALL OF THE LIVES.,.ZMp
>> MARK, THANK YOU FOR YOUR
TIME.
AS THIS TRAGEDY UNFOLDS AND WE
LEARN MORE ABOUT THIS, STAY
WITH US FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE.
YOU CAN RECEIVE UPDATES ON
YOUR SMART PHONE BYñDa DOWN
LOADING OUR FREE ABC 7 NEWS
APP.
>> WE'LL CONTINUE TO
POSTULATEST INFORMATION ON ABC
7 NEWS.COM AND ALSO UPDATING
OUR FACEBOOK PAGE,
FACEBOOK.COM/ABC 7 NEWS AND ON
TWITTER.
WE'LL HAVE CONTINUING COVERAGE
OF THE TRAGEDY THROUGHOUT THE
NEWSCAST.
>> POLICE FOLLOWING UP ON
LEADS AFTER THE THREATS THAT
FORCED A SHUT DOWN TWO OF
SCHOOLS THERE YESTERDAY.
>> THE THREATS WERE SPRAY
PAINTED IN SEVERAL SOUTH BAY
SCHOOLS.
>> YOU WON'T SEE A DIFFERENCE
THIS MORNING OUTSIDE OF THE
SCHOOL IN CUPERTINO.
BUT YOU CAN HEAR IT.
>> THIS TEACHER GOT THE
THREAT.
HE'S SAFE.
>> SHE'S REFERRING TO THE HIGH
SCHOOLTEACHER WHOSE NAME WAS
INCLUDED IN THIS BOMB THREAT
FALL ON THE WALL AT LYNN BROOK
HIGH SCHOOL IN SAN JOSE.
WE'VE OBSCURED A NAME TO
PROTECT HIS IDENTITY.
NOW, WE'RE LEARNING OF ALMOST
IDENTICAL BOMB THREATS AT TWO
OTHER CUPERTINO SCHOOLS
YESTERDAY.
THE HIGH SCHOOL, AND KENNEDY
MIDDLE SCHOOL AROUND THE
CORNER.
>> THERE IS MORE THAN ONE
GRAFFITI DONE THAT WAS
DISCOVERED YESTERDAY.
>> THE SAME TEACHER?
>> YES.
>> THE THREAT LED TO A SHUT
DOWN OF MONTE VISTA HIGH NEXT
DOOR.
THE CAMPUS WAS SEARCHED,
NOTHING FOUND.
INVESTIGATORS SAY THERE MAY BE
MORE THAN ONE SUSPECT AND
THERE IS MORE THAN ONE LEAD.
>> OUR DETECTIVES AND DEPUTIES
HAVE BEEN WORKING AROUND THE
CLOCK ON SEVERAL LEADS AND WE
HAVE BEEN GETTING MORE TIPS
SINCE LAST NIGHT.
>> THIS REACTION FROMJP8Oj A FAR
AND SON THIS MORNING.
>> STILL PRETTY COMFORTABLE.
THEY SEEM TO HAVE A PRETTY
GOOD HANDLE YESTERDAY.
>> I FEEL COMFORTABLE.
I KNOW THERE IS NOT A BOMB
HERE.
AND AM PRETTY SURE POLICE HAVE
A GOOD HANDLE ONjj& IT.
>> THE SHERIFF HAS DEPUTIES
HERE ON THE MONTE VISTA HIGH
SCHOOL CAMPUS AS WELL AS A
COUPLE AT THE HOME OF THE
TEACHER MENTIONED IN THE BOMB
THREATS.
>> ALL RIGHT.
IT'S TIME TO CHECK ON THE
WEATHER.
>> HERE IS SANDHYA PATEL IN
FOR SPENCER CHRISTIAN.
>> WE HAVE SOME RAIN AS YOU
LOOK AT LIVE DOP DOPPLER 7 HD.
IT'S INCREASING IN COVERAGE.
RADAR IS WATCHING MOISTURE,
MODERATE RAINFALL AROUND
HIGHWAY 35.
MOST OF THIS IS FALLING IN THE
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS SOME OF
IT REACHED SOUTH BAI. I WANT
TO SHOW YOU LIGHT RAIN NOW IN
SAN JOSE.
OAKLAND ROAD, YOU'LL NOTICE
THERE, ALLEN ROCK HEAD OUT
TOWARDS THE EACH BAY AROUN$&X/M
UNION CITY.
WE'RE SEEING RAINFALL.
AND AS WE PULL OUT HERE, THERE
ARE SPOTTY SPRINKLES, SHOWERS,
OUT TOWARDS SAN FRANCISCO UP
TOWARDS NORTH BAY WE GO.
THERE IS OUR RADAR BEAM.
I'LL LET YOU KNOW IF OUR OWN
RADAR WILL BE TRACKING MORE
RAIN OVER THE WHEEKD I COME
BACK.
AMA?
LARRY?
>> THANK YOU.
WE DO HAVE CONTINUING COVERAGE
OF THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
THESE ARE LIVE PICTURES FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
NOW, PEOPLE ARE INSIDE OF THE
CHURCH GATHERING FOR A VIGIL
TO REMEMBER THE VICTIMS.
>> ALSO, INVESTIGATORS LOOKING
INTO A MASSIVE FIRE DESTROYING
A FREMONT PLANT WHAT. WORKERS
ARE BEING TOLD SEWED.
>> MICHAEL FINNEY IS TAKING
YOUR QUESTIONS ON TWITTER AND
FACEBOOK AND WILL ANSWER THEM
HERE LIVE A LITTLE BIT LATER,
YOU CAN CONTACT MICHAEL ON
FACEBOOK.COM AND ON TWITTER.
M FINNEY.
>> AT 4:13, TAKING A LOOK AT
FRIDAY AFTERNOON COMMUTE.
s
DIRECTIONS.
AT THE SKYWAY IN DOWNTOWN SAN
FRANCISCO, LEFTx,WJm TO RIGHT
HEADING TOWARDS BAY BRIDGE,
AND ALSO, VERY, VERY SLOW
HEADING SOUTHBOUND IF YOU'RE
HEADING TOWARDS THE PENINSULA.
STAY WITH US, MORE STILL
>>> WE INTRAEKING NEWS.
YOU CAN SEE ACCIDENT SCENE
RIGHT HERE, THREE KILLED IN AN
AUTO ACCIDENT THIS, IS IN SAN
MATEO COUNTY.
WE'RE TOLD REDWOOD CITY ON
NORTHBOUND 280.
AND BOY, YOU CAN SEE TWO
VEHICLES MANGLED TLCHL THE CHP
SAYS ONE DRIVER WAS CHANGING A
TIRE IN THE CENTER DIVIDE.
THEY WERE STRUCK BY A CAR.
AS YOU CAN SEE, YOU'VE GOT
EMERGENCY PERSONNEL ON THE
SCENE TRYING TO GET THIS
SORTED OUT.
TRAFFIC RESTRICTED TO ONE LANE
IN THAT DIRECTION Z WE'LL
CONTINUE TO MONITOR THE STORY
AND WILL BRING DETAILS AS THEY
BECOME AVAILABLE TO US.
HERE ON ABC 7 NEWS.
YOU CAN SEE TRAFFIC BACKED UP
THIS IS GOING TO TAKE A WHILE
TO CLEAR AWI.
>> POLICE CLOSED A TERMINAL
AFTER A MAN WAS SHOT THIS
AFTERNOON.
>> PLEEL PLEES TELL US IT
HAPPENED JUST BEFORE 1:00.
SKY 7 WAS OVER THE SCENE.
toSD
OUT OF A SEDAN AND SHOT THE
A GUARD GAVE THE VICTIM FIRST
AID.
THE VICTIM TAKEN TO MARIN
COUNTY GENERAL HOSPITAL.
AND THE TERMINAL SHOULD REOPEN
IN ABOUT AN HOUR.
>> THIS IS DETERMINING 373
YEARS TO LIFE IN STATE PRISON.
A CRIME HE'S COMMITTED.
>> THAT IS THE SENTENCE HANDED
DOWN JUST OVER AN HOUR AGO AS
THE MAN KNOWN AS THE MISSION
RAPIST.
HE GOT 373 YEARS TO LIFE FOR
RAPING THREE WOMEN ALONG SAN
FRANCISCO 24th STREET CORRIDOR
LAST YEAR.
HIS FAMILY STORMED OUT OF THE
COURTROOM AFTER THE SENT YENGS
WAS READ.
ONE VICTIM CRIED AS SHE SPOKE
IN FRONT OF DOZER.
THE JUDGE SAYS HE SHOWED NO
REMORSE AS SHE HEAD
THE -- READ THE SENTENCE.
>> PLEASANTON POLICE
DEPARTMENT RELEASED THIS
SURVEILLANCE FOT YOF A SUSPECT
WANT FORWARD A CRIME SPREE
TARGETING FOUR DRUG STORES IN
JUST 36 HOURS STARTING ONS
WEDNESDAY, THE LAST ONE
YESTERDAY AFTERNOON AT DUBLIN
SAFEWAY DRUG STORE.
THIS SUSPECT DESCRIBED AS
ROUGHLY FIVE EIGHT, 180 POUNDS,
A WHITE MALE.
IN ALL, FOUR OF THE CASES HE
GAVE A CLERK A NOTE SAYING HE
WAS ARMED AND WANTED DRUGS.
HE WAS FOILED IN ALL BUT THE
LAST ATTEMPT.
>> THIS FIRE DESTROYED A
MACHINERY SHOP YESTERDAY.
TODAY, MORE THAN 50 WORKERS
ARE WONDERING WHEN, AND IF,
THEY'LL GET BACK TO WORK.rZlñ
>> C AND H ENTER PRIZES MAIDS
MADE PARTS.
OWNERS NOW WONDER WHEN THEY'LL
BE ABLE TO HONOR KRACHBLGTS
WORKERS WONDER WHAT THE
HOLIDAY SEASON WILL BE LIKE
NOW THEY'RE OUT OF A JOB.
INVESTIGATORS POSTED A DANGER
SIGN ON THE BUILDING TODAY,
THE BUILDING IS UNINHABITABLE.
THE FUTURE OF THE BUSINESS,
UNKNOWN, WORKERS GATHERED TO
FIND OUT WHEN, AND IF, THEY'LL
GET BACK ON THE JOB.
THE MANAGER SAYS THINK THE
HAVE CONTRACTS TO HONOR.
>> WE HAVE CUSTOMER THAT'S
NEED PARTS.
>> MOST PARENTS DESTROYED IN
THE FIRE.
THE BLAZE STARTED WITHOUT
WARNING AT 1:45 THURSDAY,
FLAMES REACHING AS HIGH AS 50
FEET.
BLACK SMOKE BILLOWED OUT INTO
THE HILLS, INVESTIGATORS
COMBED THROUGH DEBRIS, TRYING
TO DETERMINE HOW IT STARTED.
THE DEPUTY FIRE MARSHAL SAYS
THE FIRE WAS ACCIDENTAL.
>> A MOLTEN PIECE OF MATERIAL
GETTING INTO A PART OF THE
EXHAUST SYSTEM IGNITING A
FIRE.
>> THE FIRE SPREAD THROUGH THE
ROOF.
MANY OF THE MORE THAN 50
WORKERS LOOKING FORWARDS TO
THE HOLIDAYS WONDER WHEN THEY
MIGHT GET BACK TO WORK.
>> YOU WORRY ABOUT THE FUTURE
OF THE COMPANY.
WHAT IS GOING TO HAPPEN. HOW
WE'RE GOING TO MOVE FORWARD.
>> MANY DEPRESSED AND
RELUCTANT TO TALK.
THEY'RE TOLD YORNS WERE
LOOKING FOR ANOTHER SITE.
AND THAT PAY WOULD CONTINUE
THROUGHOUT THE HOLIDAYS BUT
THAT WON'T BE CERTAIN UNTIL AN
INSURANCE COMPANY WEIGHS IN.
>> THIS IS WAGES INTO -- UNTIL
WE, WE DON'T KNOW WHAT THEY'RE
GOING TO DO.
>> MANAGERS TELL US OWNERS
FOUND BUILDINGS THEY CAN LEASE
TO TRY TO GET BACK TO
PRODUCTION AS SOON AS POSSIBLE
BUT FIRST THEY'RE GOING TO
HAVE TO REPLACE THOR THAN $1
MILLION WORTH OF MACHINERY
DESTROYED DURING THIS FIRE.
LIVE IN FREMONT ABC 7 NEWS.
>> THANK YOU FOR THE UPDATE.
>> LOOKING AHEAD TO THE
WEEKEND WEATHER FORECAST NOW
AND SANDHYA PAT JELL IN.
>> YES.
LOOKS LIKE YOU'RE GOING TO
NEED UMBRELLAS HITTING THE
WEEKEND BUT NOT A WASH JOU. SO
I'LL PINPOINT WHEN YOU'RE
GOING TO NEED UMBRELLAS NOW.
A LIVE PICTURE YOU'LL SEE WHAT
IT LOOKS LIKE FROM OUR CAMERA.
THERE IS A RAY OR TWO OF HOPE
FOR A NICE WEEKEND.
YOU CAN SEE SUN SUN TRYING TO
POKE THROUGH CLOUDS.
WE DO HAVE RAIN DROPS RIGHT
NOW.
THE LIGHT RAIN HAS BEEN
INCREASING IN COVERAGE ALL
AFTERNOON.
SO OUR COMPUTER MODELS PAINTED
A CHANCE OF RAIN THIS
AFTERNOON.
AS MENTIONED MOST OF IT HAS
BEEN LIGHT.
YOU'LL NOTICE IT'S OUT TOWARDS
THE EAST BAY.
AND LIVERMORE VALLEY DOWN
TOWARDS SOUTH BAY THAT.
IS WHERE CONCENTRATION IS.
SAN JOSE NOW, KERTNER AVENUE,
SCOTT BOULEVARD WE'RE GETTING
SOME LIGHT RAINFALL TOWARDS
TULLY ROAD AND MORE MODERATE
IN INTENSITY AROUND SANTA CRUZ
MOUNTAINS AND BOULDER CREEK.
AND AS YOU LOOK AT THE EAST
BAY, PASEO PADRE PARKWAY,
UNION BRIDGE, FREMONT, WE'RE
GETTING SOME LIGHT RAINFALL.
NORTH BAY A COUPLE HUNDREDTHS
OF AN INCH.
TEMPERATURES UP THERE, IT'S
CHILLY, UPPER 40S TO LOW 50s
AT THIS HOUR, EXACTLY WHAT IS
EXPECTED.
CHILLY CONDITIONS, COLD, WET
TOMORROW.
AND A FEW MORNING SHOWERS FOR
SUNDAY AND THE REST OF THE
SUNDAY LOOKING JUST FINE.
CHECKING OUT THE SYSTEM THAT
IS PRODUCING LIGHT RAINFALL.
IT'S JUST SKIRTING THE
COASTLINE.
THERE IS ENOUGH MOISTURE THATJ'ñ
WE'RE SQUEEZING OUT SHOWERS.
NEXT WEAK SYSTEM COMES THROUGH
HERE SATURDAY.
SO... MAKE SURE HAVE YOU A
COAT OR A JACKET FOIRS THING
IN THE MORNING AND UMBRELLAS.
YOU'LL NOTICE RAIN ARRIVING
AND IT WILL BE LIGHT, SPREAD
BIG AFTERNOON.
EVERYONE IS GETTING SOME LIGHT
RAINFALL AT 1:00 P.M.
COULD SEEohÑ RAIN-SNOW MIX AROD
THE LAKE COUNTY AREA.
WE'VE HAD SNOW FLURRIES AROUND
MOUNT HAMILTON TODAY.
JUST OVER 4,000 FEET.
WE'LL SEE POSSIBLY ANOTHER
ROUND, SUNDAY MORNING SHOWERS
AND IT'S PRETTY MUCH DONE
SATURDAY LOOKS LIKE WETTER OF
THE TWO DAYS, RAINFALL TOTALS
THROUGHOUT SUNDAY EVENING A
TENTH TO A THIRD OF AN INCH IN
THE NORTH BAY.
UP TO A FOUR-TENTHS OF AN
INCH.
PENINSULA, 5/100ths TO
15/100ths.
TRACE AMOUNTS TO 5/100ths IN
THE SOUTH BAY.
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS COULD SEE
UP TO A QUARTER INCH OF RAIN.
TONIGHT IT WILL BE A LITTLE
BIT HIGHER IN TERMS OF
TEMPERATURES.
BUT STILL, KOMD, NOT DOWN TO
30, 31 LIKE THIS MORNING 34 IN
NAPA.
34 IN SANTA ROSA.
MID-30s CONCORD, LIVERMORE, 38
IN SAN JOSE.
UPPER 30s FREMONT AND PALO
ALTO.
SO BUNDLE UP IN THE MORNING.
YOU CAN SEE SNOW, LOW 50 AS
CROSS THE REST OF THE REGION.
AND UPPER 40S TO LOW 50s,
CHILL WITH US THROUGHOUT THE
WEEKEND.
THE REST OF THE SUNDAY IS
NINE.
MORE RAIN MONDAY, TUESDAY,
THEN, WE CAN GET A BREAK WINS,
POSSIBLY DROPPING THURSDAY.
CHANCE OF RAIN INTO FRIDAY.
NOW, COMPUTER MODEL NOT LOOK
SOG WET IN TERMS OF THE
INTENSITY FORMS.
AND THAT IS ABOUT IT WE'RE
GOING TO TAKE ANOTHER LOOK IN
CONNECTICUT NOW THIS, IS
WHERE' VIGIL IS BEGINNING TO
TAKE PLACE THIS MORNING THIS,
IS INSIDE OF A CHURCH THERE.
MANY GATHERED TO REMEMBER
THOSE THAT WERE KILLED IN THIS
TRAGEDY TODAY.
WE'LL HAVE MORE FOR YOU COMING
UP AND WE'LL HEAR FROM MORE
WITNESSES.
>> WE HAVE A LOOK.
THESE ARE PICTURES SKY 7 HD.
A CAR ACCIDENT CLAIMED LIVES
OF THE THREE PEOPLE THIS, IS
TAKING PLACE IN NORTHBOUND 280,
NORTH OF EDGEWOODS ROO.D YOU
CAN SEE TRAFFIC HAS BEEN
RESTRICTED DOWN TO ONE LANE
THERE.
THE BACK UP WILL STRETCH FOR
QUITE A DISTANCE, WE'LL
CONTINUE TO FOLLOW THIS STORY,
BRINGING YOU MORE DETAILS AS
>>> WE THOUGHT THEY WERE
POLICE OFFICERS OUT OF THE
DOOR TRYING TO FIND THE GUY.
AND THE GYM TEACHER DIRECTED
US TO STAY AGAINST THE WALL.Czd
AND EVERYBODY STARTED TO KIND
OF PANIC.
>> DOESN'T SEEM RILE.
IT JUST DOES NOT SEEM LIKE
IT'S POSSIBLE.
>> YES.
THOSE ARE THE WORDS FROM
STUDENTS AND PARENTS OF THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL SHOOTINGS.
OUR COVERAGE WILL CONTINUE IN
JUST A MOMENT.
>> A TEXAS FAMILY IS BLASTING
AIRPORT SECURITY SCREENERS IN
DALLAS FORT WORTH AIRPORT FOR
THE TREATMENT OF THEIR
12-YEAR-OLD DAUGHTER WHO IS
DISABLED.
>> IT'S OKAY.
WE'RE GOING GET YOU ON YOUR
WAY.
>> THAT WAS THE VOICE OF A TSA
SCREENER TALKING TO SHELBY.
THE OVERWHELMED LITTLE GIRL
DETAINED AFTER THE TSA CLAIMED
SHE TESTED POSITIVE FOR
EXPLOSIVES.
HER MOM ORDERED TO KEEP BACK
AND NOT ALLOWED TO COMFORT HER
CRYING DAUGHTER FOR THE HOUR
IT TOOK HIM TO CALL BOMB
EXPERTS IN.
>> I AM BY NO MEANS
UNDERMINING OUR SAFETY IN THE
AIR.
AFTER SEPTEMBER 11thá÷x-ç, BY NO
MEANS AM I DOING THAT.
WHEN I COMES TO CHILDREN
COMMON SENSE ISN'T IN A
TEXTBOOK.
>> THEY WENT DOWN EACH FINGER.
>> SCREENERS SAY THEY DETECTED
EXPLOSIVE RESIDUE ON HER
HANDS.
HER FAMILY BELIEVES IT CAME
FROM FERTILIZER ON THEIR FARM.
HER MOM SAYS THE TSA NEVER
TESTED THE WHEELCHAIR.
THE TSA SAYS IT UNDERSTANDS
CONCERNS BY STANDS BY ACTIONS.
>> AND WE HAVE MORE COVERAGE
AHEAD ON TD DEADLY SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
>> A GUNMAN OPENED FIRE IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, KILLING
NEARLY 30 PEOPLE, MOST VICTIMS
ARE YOUNG CHILDREN.
>> THESE ARE PICTURES FROM A
CHURCH.
A VIGIL IS UNDERWAY NOW.
YOU CAN SEE A LOT OF PEOPLE
THERE IN THE BACKGROUND,
STUDENTS, TEACHERS AND PARENTS
ALL REMEMBERING THOSE THAT
WERE KILLED TODAY.
>> COMING UP, WE'LL HAVE
ADVICE FOR PARENTS ON HOW THEY
CAN TALK TO THEIR KIDS ABOUT
THE VIOLENCE THEY SEE ON
TELEVISION.
ALSOy@q...
>> AND WE'LL FIND OUT WHAT
SCHOOL OFFICIALS ARE TELLING
THEIR TEACHERS AND STUDENTS
ABOUT THIS TRAGEDY.
IN UNION CITY, I'LL HAVE A
LIVE REPORT.
>> PG&E SAYS ONCE AGAIN,
INSPECTIONS THAT SHOULD HAVE
BEEN DONE, WERE NOT, MAYBE
THEY WEREN'T.
THIS TEAM IN -- TIME IN IT'S
>> WE'RE GOING TO CARRY THIS
AROUND FOREVER, THE TOWN WILL
NEVER BE THE SAME.
>> AN UNSPEAKABLE TRAGEDY IN A
SCHOOL IN THE CONNECTICUT
TOWN.
A GUNMAN KILLS 26 PEOPLE, 20
CHILDREN IN THE SECOND WORST
MASS SHOOTING IN U.S. HISTORY
IN NEWTOWN, A MIDDLE CLASS
COMMUNITY 60 MILES OUTSIDE OF
NEW YORK STI WE HAVE NEW
INFORMATION ON THE GUNMAN IN
THIS SHOOL SHOOTING.
>> YES.
WE'RE GETTING A FIRST LOOK AT
THE GUNMAN TONIGHT.
WE SPONSIBLE FOR THE
CONNECTICUT SCHOOL MASSACRE
THIS, IS ADAM LANZ YACHL THE
20-YEAR-OLD POLICE SAY GUNNED
DOWN 26 PEOPLE TEED IN AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN NEWTOWN
BEFORE KILLING HIMSELF.
20 OF THE VICTIMS WERE
CHILDREN.
POLICE SAY WEAPONS WERE
PURCHASED LEGALLY REGISTERED
TO HIS MOTHER, NANCY KILLED AT
HER HOME IN NEWTOWN.
WE HAVE NEW VIDEO OF THE
SHOOTER'S BROTHER, RYAN LANZA
BEING DETAINED FOR QUESTION IN
NEW JERSEY.
HE'S UNDER ARREST.
OFFICIALS SAY HE HAS BEEN
COOPERATIVE.
POLICE SAY RYAN LANZA HAS NO
CONNECTION TO THE SHOOTINGS
TODAY AND SAYS HE HAS NOT BEEN
IN TOUCH WITH HIS BROTHER,
ADAM FOR SEVERAL YEARS.
THAT IS THE LATEST LIVE IN THE
NEWSROOM, ABC 7 NEWS.
>> NOT A SUSPECT BUT APPEARED
TO BE IN HANDCUFFS THERE.
>> SCHOOLS AROUND THE BAY AREA
DOING THEIR PART TO TRY TO
KEEP P HELP STUDENTS, AS WELL
AS PARENTS AND STAFF DEAL WITH
THE TRAGEDY.
>>.
>> YES.
HI.
AT THIS HIGH SCHOOL, THIS
SCHOOL DISTRICT THAT SCHOOL
DISTRICTS AROUND THE BAY AREA,
E MAIL GOINGS OUT ALMOST
IMMEDIATELY.
LETERS CRAFTED TO GO HOME TO
PARENTS AND NOTIFY TEACHERS
ABOUT WHAT THEY SHOULD DO
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY AFTER WE
KNEW ABOUT THIS SHOOTING.
HERE SCHOOL OFFICIALS
CONCENTRATED EFFORTS ON MIDDLE
SCHOOL AND HIGH SCHOOL
FIGURING THAT THE OLDER
STUDENTS WERE GOING TO LEARN
ABOUT THE SHOOTING FIRST
THROUGH SOCIAL MEDIA ASK TOOK
PHONE CALLS FROM PARENTS.
BY THE TIME THE NEWS WAS OUT
ABOUT THE SHOOTING IN A
CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
MOST STUDENTS WERE IN CLASS
GIVING TIME TO FIGURE OUT A
STRAD JI AND A MESSAGE.
>> WE HAVE HAD CALLS FROM
PARENTS WANT TOK COME, PICK UP
THEIR CHILDREN AT THE SCHOOL
WHICH IS UNDERSTANDABLE.
AND WE DON'T ENCOURAGE THAT
SORT OF THING WE DON'T
DISCOURAGE IT.
>> IN UNION CITY, NEW HAVEN
SCHOOL DISTRICT OFFICIALS
DISPATCHED MEMBERS OF THE
CRISIS TEAM TO VARIOUS SITES.
>> WE'RE NOT HEARING A LOT
FROM THE KIDS RIGHT NOW.
>> THIS PSYCHOLOGIST WENT TO
LOGAN HIGH SCHOOL, FIGURING
OLDER KIDS WOULD LEARN ABOUT
THE SHOOTING THROUGH SOCIAL
IMMEDIATA, HELPING CRAFT AN E
MAIL TO GO OUT TO STAFF AND848a3
TEACHERS.
>> WHAT SO LOOK FOR IN
STUDENTS THAT MIGHT HAVE A BIG
IMPACT ON. WHEN TO REFER THEM
FOR SERVICES.
>> IN OAKLAND, A SPOKESMAN
AvS HIS OFFICE WAS GETTING
CALLS MOSTLY FROM ADULTS,
TEACHERS AND PARENTS WANTING
ADVISES ON HOW TO DELIVER THE
NEWS AND ANSWER QUESTION AUTOS
PART THAT HAVE IS GIVING THEM
THE INFORMATION WITHOUT DRAMA
TIESING Z YOU PRESENT THE
INFORMATION IMPRESS UPON THEM
THAT THEY HAVE, AS A CHILD
HAVE MANY PEOPLE LOOKING OUT
FOR THEM.
>> ONE'g&1p DISTRICT THAT CRAFTA
LETTER FR STUDENTS IN MARCH
ARE PLANNING AS IT TURNS OUT
THEIRS FIRST ACTIVE EVER
SHOOTER DRILL WITH THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
IT'S TIMELY GIVEN TODAY'S
EVENTS BUT ONE CONCERN IS HOW
DO YOU CONDUCT A DRILL LIKE
THAT AND EXPLAIN IT TO THE
STUDENTS WITHOUT TRAUMATIZING
THEM WITH A SCENARIO SUPPOSED
TO BE IMAGE NAIRY?
WE'LL HAVE MORE ON THAT
TONIGHT ON ABC 7 NEWS AT 6:00
IN UNION CITY, ABC 7 NEWS.
>> THAT IS AN EXCELLENT
QUESTION.
WE DO HAVE MORE NOW ABOUT HOW
PARENTS SHOULD TALK TO THEIR
CHILDREN ABOUT THE VIOLENCE
AND IMAGES THEY'RE SEEING ON
TV TODAY.
>> IN THIS SATURDAY DIFFICULT
SITUATION TODAY.
>> IT S NICK, THESE[5CGs DAYS IS
HARD TO ESCAPE IT WITH TV,
INTERNET, EVERYTHING.
CHILDREN HAVE ACCESS TO
EVERYTHING.
HOW DO YOU BEGIN TO TALK TO
YOUR KIDS TONIGHT ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED?
>> THE FIRST THING TO DO IS
RECOGNIZE WHAT IS GOING ON
INSIDE OF YOURSELF, KIDS MODEL
HOW PARENTS ARE REACTING.
IF YOU FEEL ANXIOUS, SCARED,
THE FIRST STEP IS TO CALM
YOURSELF, WORK THROUGH WHAT
YOU CAN BEFORE TALKING TO
THEM.
SECOND STEP IS TO BEGIN TO
LISTEN TO THEM.
AND FULLY LISTEN, TRY NOT TO
JUMP IN TOO QUICKLY TO FIX THE
SITUATION.
THIRD THING IS÷sá EMPHASIZE AND
NORMALIZE REACTIONS WHETHER
IT'S FEAR, OR ANGER, BE THERE,
BE ABLE TO LISTEN TO WHAT IS
GOING ON FOR THEM.
AND LAST THING, EXPLAIN WHAT
IS GOING ON TO THEM IN A WAY
THEY CAN HEAR IT.
WHETHER YOUNGER, OLDER.
TRY TO AS BEST YOU CAN
RECOGNIZE SCHOOLS ARE
GENERALLY SAY SAFE.
THESE ARE RARE INSTANCES,
TRAGIC AS THEY ARE.
AND EXPECT A DELAYED REACTION,
KIDS WILL HAVE A REACTION
SOMETIMES A WEEK TWO, WEEKS OR
A YEAR OR TWO LATER IF THEY'RE
HEARING BIT IN SCHOOLS.
>> THAT COMMUNITY IN NEWTOWN
IS NEVER GOING TO BE THE SAME.Xñ
WE'RE SOME DISTANCE AWAY.
BUT HOW ABOUT FOR THOSE
PARENTS?
THAT ARE GRIEVING OR SAW THEIR
KIDS FRIENDS WILL NO LONGER BE
COMING HOME?
>> I DON'T THINK THERE IS
ANYTHING THAT CAN PREPARE YOU
FOR SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
THERE IS A PERIOD OF SHOCK
THAT IS NORMAL THE THING
PEOPLE CAN DO THAT IS MOST
HELPFUL IS JUST BE THERE.
IT SOUNDS SIMPLE BUT NOT EASY
WHEN YOU WANT TO HELP AS BEST
YOU CAN.
BEING PRESENT AND AVAILABLE TO
THE FOLKS THERE IS CRITICAL.
AND TO USE COMPASSION OR
FRUSTRATION TO HAVE A DIALOGUE
AROUND WHAT ARE THE CAUSE ASKS
THINGS WE CAN DO TO PREVENT
THIS?
MENTAL HEALTH ISSUES OR
ACCESSIBILITY TO WEAPONS AND
HAVE, IT'S TIME TO HAVE A MORE
NATIONAL DIALOGUE ON THESE
CONCERNS.
>> THAT IS A CONVERSATION THAT
IS NECESSARY.
>> ABC 7 NEWS IS PRODUCING A
SPECIAL HOUR LONG EDITION OF
WORLD NEWS WITH DIANE SAWYER
WILL AIR AT 5:30, RIGHT AFTER
ABC 7 NEWS AT 5:00.
WE'LL BRING YOU A SPECIAL HALF
HOUR EDITION OF ABC 7 NEWS AT
6:00.
>> COMING UP NEXT, HERE ON ABC
7 NEWS AT 4:00 DOZENS OF
FIREFIGHTERS ON THE JOB.
NEW GRADUATES OF THE Fú1F8
FIGHTER ACADEMY.
>> I'M SANDHYA PATEL.
WE'LL GET THIS SHOT FROM OUR
CAMERA.
WE HAVE SUN, AND LIGHT SHOWERS
ON LIVE DOPPLER 7.
AND... RAIN COULD BE IMPACTING
WEEKEND PLANS I'LL HAVE
DETAILS COMING UP.
>> BREAKING NEWS IN REDWOOD
CITY.
SKY 7 IS LIVE OVER OVER A CAR
SCENT THAT LEFT THREE PEOPLE
DEAD ON NORTHBOUND551V 280 NORTH
OF EDGEWOOD ROAD.
AND IT'S TRYING -- TYING UP
AND...
TAKE CARE OF THEM,
YOU KNOW?
I FEEL LIKE WE'VE
COME FULL CIRCLE.
LIKE THAT!
THIS IS HOW
I'LL DO IT.
Sarah:
THERE YOU GO.
>>> FIRE DEPARTMENT GRADUATED
IN ITS 146 YEARS HISTRY. 48
RECRUITS TOOK THE OATH
FOLLOWING A 17 WEEK COURSE.
THE CHIEF THEN PINNED BADGES
ON THE NEW FIREFIGHTERS.
SOME OF WHO WILL REPORT TO
WORK TOMORROW.
THE NEW FIREFIGHTERS LEFT
CAREERS IN EDUCATION, MEDICAL
FIELD AND POLICE FORCE TO JOIN
THE DEPARTMENT.
>> READY FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO
FIRE DEPARTMENT IT'S A DREAM
COME TRUE FOR ME.
YOU CAN HELP AND SERVE THE
COMMUNITY.
HELP PEOPLE.
>> SAN FRANCISCO NOW HAS ABOUT
1500 FIREFIGHTERS.
THE FIRE DEPARTMENT HAS
ANOTHER ACADEMY SET FOR NEXT
YEAR, MAY SCHEDULE A SECOND
ONE IN 2013 JUST TO TRY TO
KEEP UP WITH RETIREMENT AUTOS
LOOKING INTO THE FORECAST, I
JUST TOOK A GLIMPSE OVER YOUR
SHOULDER THERE AND THERE IS A
BEAUTIFUL SUNSET.
>> YES.
DON'T BE SO BLEAK, LARRY.
THIS IS KIND OF MATCHING HIS
PERSONALITY.
>> OH!
>> WEsTNtg HAVE OUR OWN RADAR ON
MOUNT ST. HELENA. WE'VE BEEN
PICKING UP RAIN INCREASING IN
COVERAGE ALL AFTERNOON LONG.
WE GO INTO THE SOUTH BAY,
STORY ROAD, HIGHWAY 101, SNELL
AVENUE, WE'RE GETTING LIGHT
RAINFALL NOW.
THERE IS CONFIRMATION FROM
VIEWERS CAMPBELL, LIVERMORE
SAYING RAIN DROPS NOW, LIGHT
RAIN IS MORE MODERATE HEADING
OUT TOWARDS EAST BAY.
YOU'LL NOTICE AROUND FREMONT
HEADSING TOWARDS MISSION
BOULEVARD, LIGHT RAINFALL
HERE, VERY LIGHT SPRINKLES
SHOWING UP ACROSS THE BRIDGE
HEADING INTO UNION CITY.
IF YOU'RE TRAVELING SNOW, 48
IN CHICO IS GOING TO BE COLD.
SNOW REDEVELOPING TOMORROW
NIGHT.
IT'S LEADING UP TO TAHOE, 62
IN LOS ANGELES, HIGHS FOR
SATURDAY, YOU'LL)/Ñ SEE THAT
TEMPERATURES WILL BE CHILLY
MID-40s TO LOW 50s, LIGHT RAIN,
CARRYING UMBRELLAS MAKE SURE
HAVE YOU A JACKET OR COAT.
>> ON A DAY LIKE TODAY, ANY
KIND OF LAUGHTER IS WELCOME,
REALLY.
>> THANK YOU.
>> OUR COVERAGE OF TODAY'S
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT
CONTINUES HERE ON ABC 7 NEWS,
WE'LL CONTINUE TO BRING YOU
UPDATES THROUGHOUT THE EVENING
AS INFORMATION BECOMES
AVAILABLE.
GIS
INTO FULL GEAR, WHAT ABOUT
RETURNS? IS IT LEGAL TO ONLY
OFFER SCORE CREDITS?
I'VE GOT
>>> A BREAKING NEWS COVERAGE
TRAGIC SHOOTING
CONTINUES.
26 PEOPLE, INCLUDING 20
CHILDREN WERE KILL BID A
GUNMAN WHO WENT ON A RAMPAGE
YAIJ IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THE GUNMAN IDENTIFIED AS ADAM
LANZA OPENED FIRE INSIFD A
SCHOOL.
AUTHORITIES NOW SAYING HE
KILLED HIS MOTHER, NANCY%dqq LAA
INSIDE OF HER HOME BEFORE
GOING TO SCHOOL.AI A
WE NOW KNOW LANZA WAS ARMED
WITH TWO SEMI AUTOMATIC
HANDGUNS AND A RIFLE.
IT APPEARS HE DIES FROM A SELF
INFLICTED GUNSHOT.
THE GUNMAN'S BROTHER, RYAN
TAKEN INTO CUSTODY AND
QUESTION BID OFFICERS HE IS
NOT A SUSPECT IN THIS
SHOOTING.
AUTHORITIES SAY HE'SDBBHó
COOPERATING FULLY.
STAY WITH US FOR UPDATES ON
THIS BREAKING STORY.
>> WE'RE GOING TURN TO
CONSUMER NEWS NOW, MICHAEL
FINNEY IS HERE ANSWERING
QUESTIONS SENT THROUGH
FACEBOOK AND TWITTER AND E
MAIL X OUR FIRST QUESTION
COMES FROM SCOTT WHO E MAILED
HOW LEGITIMATE ARE THE CLAIMS
SUBSCRIPTIONS?
DO THEY BENEFIT FROM SIGN UPS?
GOING TO BE A -- FOR A LOCAL
NEWSPAPER THENREñ HAVE ID FROM
THE NEWSPAPER AND A SIGN UP
SHEET FROM THAT NEWSPAPER THEN
THEY'RE PROBABLY PRETTY LEGIT.
THEY MAY NOT BE ACTUALLY
WINNING A TRIP TO DISNEYLAND
AS WE WERE TOLD SO-TO-SAY WHEN
WAYS A KID, WE DID NOT SAY
THAT.
WE TOLD SOLD OUR SUBSCRIPTIONS
STRAIGHT UP.
ONCES YOU SEE KIDS WANDERING
STREET3íkCS, A LOT OF THEM ARENT
FROM THE BAY AREA, THEY'VE
BEEN BUSED HERE, BE CAREFUL
WITH THEM, DON'T OPEN THE DOOR
TO HEM.
THEY BRING ME A LOT OF CONCERN
WELL. SEE THEM DOWN ON THE
EMBARCADERO.
THESE POOR KIDS, YOU WONDER
WHERE ARE THEY FROM?
>> NEXT QUESTION COMES FROM
SUZY G.
ASKING I TRIED TO RETURN ITEMS
TO A STORE AND WAS TOLD I CAN
ONLY HAVE STORE CREDIT.
THE SALES CLERK SAID POLICY!7çIS
ON THE REGISTER, NOTHING ON
THE RECEIPT.
IS THAT SFLEL.
>> YES. IT S RECEIPT ISN'T A
LEGAL WAY OF LETTING YOU KNOW
STLE. TO LET YOU KNOW WHAT
RETURN AND EXCHANGE POLICY IS
BEFORE YOU MAKE PURCHASES SO
THEY HAVE TO HAVE A SIGN ON
THE REGISTER.
HERE IS THE BASIC RULE IN THE
STATE OF CALIFORNIA THEY ARE
TO ACCEPT A RETURN OR EXCHANGE
FOR SEVEN DAYS AND UNLESS THEY
POST RULES, THE RULES CAN BE
ANYTHING.
THEY CAN BE CRAZY.
IT WOULD BE PAT YOUR HEAD AND
RUB YOUR STOMACH BEFORE GIVING
YOU A RUSH RETURN.
THEY CAN MAKEUP RULES IF THEY
POST IT BUT THEY'VE GOT TO
POST IT.
>> AND ONE ASKED I'D LIKE TO
KNOW WHAT SITES ARE ADDRESSES
ARE AVAILABLE FOR LETTERS AND
HOLIDAY CARDS TO THE ELDERLY.
>> NICE THING TO DO.
I ASSUME YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT
CARDS AND POST CARDS AND
HOLIDAY GREETINGS FOR THOSE
WHO PROBABLY WON'T RECEIVE
THEM OTHERWISE.
THERE IS PROBABLY A LOT OF
CHARITIES AROUND THE BAY AREA.
LET ME SHOW TWOU THAT I KNOW
OF FOR SURE.
CATHOLIC CHARITIES, AGING
SERVICES THEY HAVE A PROGRAM,
JEWISH FAMILY CHILDREN
SERVICES, THEY HAVE A PROGRAM
CALLED SENIORS AT HOME.
BOTH OF THEM WOULD BE HAPPY TO
GET CARDS FROM YOU.
THERE IS GOING TO BE PASSED ON
TO THEM.
>> STILL TO COME ON ABC 7 NEWS
AT 4:00 NEW QUESTIONS ABOUT
PG&E POLL SKPIZ WHY THOUSANDS
OF UNDERGROUND ENCLOU SHURZ
MagacIñ NOT HAVE BEEN PROPER
INSP
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>>> P GOOD AND E HAS TO ANSWER
QUESTIONS ABOUT MORE LAPSES IN
MAINTENANCE AND INSPECTIONS.
ABC 7 NEWS REPORTS.
>> THIS VIDEO SHOWS WHAT THEY
CALL AN UNDERGROUND ENCLOU
SURE NORKT A VAULT FITTING TWO
PEOPLE, THE ENSURE YOURS
REQUIRE ONLY ONE INSPECTOR.
OVER TWO YEARS, PG&E HAD TO
REINSPECT THOUSANDS OF THEM
AFTER FINDING OUT SOME
EMPLOYEES AND CONTRACTORS
NEVER OPENED THEM AS LEGALLY
REQUIRED EVERY THREE YEARS.
THE FIRST ROUND WAS DONE LAST
YEAR.
>> WE REINSPECTED EVERY
FACILITY THAT WAS INSPECTED IN
2010 AND 2011.
ABOUT 26,000 FACILITIES.
ñTARTED REQUIRING
INSPECTORS TO LEAVE BEHIND A
VERIFICATION TAG INSIDE.
THIS YEAR, LIFTING TAGS
POINTED TO MORE GIFT INSPECKS.
DOZENS OF EMPLOYEES HAVE BEEN
FIRED OR SUSPENDED.
>> WE'VE ALSO ADDED 48
INSPECTORS EMPLOYEES SO MORE
SOURCES ARE EMPLOYEES.
>> IT'S NOT JUST A PROBLEM
ISOLATED TO UNDERGROUND TRANCE
FORMERS OR GAS LEAKS OR PIPES.
IT GOES THROUGH THE COMPANY.
>> THE ATTORNEY GOT AN
UNDISCLOSED SETTLEMENT FOR
LISA NASH, BADLY BURNED WHEN A
PG&EiT(
EXPLODE INTO FLAMES UP THROUGH
A SIDEWALK IN 2005.
THE UTILITY SAID PROPER
MAINTENANCE HAD BEEN DONE
THERE.
HE DOESN'T BELIEVE IT
MANAGEMENT IS REWARDED FOR
MAKING MONEY, QUARTER BY
QUARTER.
MAKE MONEY.
AND GOING AROUND AND
INSPECTING VAULTS OR FINDING
LEAKS OR RIPPING UP OLD PIPE
SNOT HOW THEY MAKE MONEY.
>> CPUC CITED PG&E BUT NOT
FINED THEM.
>> ALL RIGHT.
THANK YOU.
AND THANKS FOR JOINING US FOR
ABC 7 NEWS AT 4:00 I'M LARRY
BEIL.
AY MINDER ABOUT THE APP THAT
IS AVAILABLE FOR FREE.
YOU CAN DOWN LOAD IT FOR FREE
AND IT'S AVAILABLE ON GOOGLE
PLAY.
IT'S STILL VIBL IF YOU HAVE AN
iPHONE.
ABC 7 NEWS AT 5:00 BEGINS
RIGHT NOW WITH AMA AND DAN.
>> THANK YOU.
A NATION IN GRIEF.
INNOCENT CHILDREN ARE KILLED
IN A SCHOOL SHOOTING TONIGHT.
WE'RE LEARNING ABOUT THE
GUNMAN'S KECKS TO THE SCHOOL.de÷
>> AND A SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
NORTHERN CALIFORNIA OVER 20
YEARS AGO THAT.
LED TO SOME OF THE TOUGHEST
GUN CONTROL LAWS IN THE
NATION.
>> SO OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY FOR THE PARENTS, AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN.
>> THE PRESIDENT CONSOLES THE
NATION DEALING WITH
UNBELIEVABLE GRIEF TONIGHT
AFTER 20 YOUNG CHILDREN ARE
KILLED AT SCHOOL BY A GUNMAN
WHOSE MOTHER WE NOW KNOW WAS A
TEACHER THERE.
GOOD EVENING, I'M DAN ASHLEY.
>> AND I'M AMA DAETTZ IT
HAPPENED IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT BAN HOUR INTO THE
SCHOOL DAY.
>> 28 PEOPLE ARE DEAD
INCLUDING THE GUNMAN.
TONIGHT THEY'VE TAKEN THE
GUNMAN'S BROTHER IN CUSTODY
FOR QUESTIONING.
AT THIS MOMENT THEY DO NOT
BELIEVE THE BROTHER WAS
INVOLVED NOR THE FATHER.
BUT, THEY'RE QUESTIONING THEM
AS THEY TRY TO PIECE TOGETHER
WHAT HAPPENED IN CONNECTICUT
THIS TRAGIC MORNING.
ABC 7 NEWS REPORTER MARK
GREENBLATT IS THERE.
>> EVIL.
VISITED THIS COMMUNITY TODAY.
>> NUMBERS STAGGERING.
AT LEAST 37 PEOPLE SHOT DEAD.
MANY YOUNG DMIRN A NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT ELEMENT TRAILER
SCHOOL.
POLICE GOT THE FIRST 911 CALL
AT 9:40 IN THE MORNING AND
DISPATCHED EMERGENCY UNITS TO
THE SCHOOL.
LOCKING DOWN EVERYTHING IN THE
AREA.
MANY STUDENTS WERE TRAPPED IN
THE CLASSROOMMENT.
>> I SID SED I NEED TO KNOW I
LOVE YOU ALL VERY MUCH.
AND THAT IT'S GOING TO BE
OKAY.
I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE LAST
THING THEY'RE GOING TO HEAR.
I THOUGHT WE WERE GOING TO
DIE.
>> THIS 9-YEAR-OLD HEARD
GUNSHOTS DURING HER ART CLASS.
>> POLICE CAME.
AND WE HEARD IT OVER LOUD
SPEAKER AUTOS THIS 4th GRADER
WAS IN GYM CLASS.
>> POLICE CAME IN.
IT'S LIKE... IS HE IN HERE?
THEN RAN OUT.
OUR TEACHERS, SOMEONE YELLED
GET TO A SAFE PLACE.
>> HIS FATHER RELIEVED HIS SON
IS OKAY.
>> IT'S TERRIFYING.
IT I'M STILL IN SHOCK.
>> SHOCK THAT IS SO MANY ARE
NOW DEAD.
MANY CHILDREN WERE LED OUT OF
THE SCHOOL WITH HANDS UP, THE
SHOOTER IS DECEASED INSIDE OF
THE BUILDING.
>> THE GUNMAN MOTHER WAS AMONG
THE DEAD.
THE SHOOT SGT WORST SHOOTING
IN U.S. ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IN
RECENT MEMORY.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ADDRESSED THE
NATION LATE IN THE AFTERNOON.
>> AS A COUNTRY WE'VE BEEN
THROUGH THIS TOO MANY TIMES.
AND WE'RE GOING HAVE TO COME
TOGETHER AND MAKE MEANINGFUL
ACTION TO PREVENT MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
REGARDLESS OF THE POLITICS.
>> AUTHORITIES SAY THE GUNMAN
TOOK HIS OWN LIFE IN THE
SHOOTING AND THERE ARE SOME
HEROIC STORIES LIKE A TEACHER
SHEPHERDED EVERYONE OF HER
PUT SOMETHING ON TOP OF A TOIL
OIT YIT IN ORDER TO SHIELD
THEM IN AN HOUR WHEN THEY
SHOULD HAVE BEEN LEARNING
THEIR ARITHMETIC.
>> THANK YOU, MARK.
SHEER WHAT WE KNOW ABOUT THE
GUNMAN.
20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA OPENED
NIR SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
28 PEOPLE ARE DEAD, INCLUDING