TO HER MOM WHEN SHE GOT OUTSIDE,
WAS, MOMMY, I'M OKAY, BUT ALL OF
MY FRIENDS ARE DEAD.
>> THE CLEAREST PICTURE YET OF
THE SHOOTER'S PATH INSIDE THAT
SCHOOL, WHAT ENDED HIS RAMPAGE
AND THE STAGGERING NUMBERS ON
GUNS IN AMERICA.
MORE GUN SELLERS THAN McDONALDS.
ARE THERE SOLUTIONS?
TONIGHT THE ONE THING TO
REASSURE YOUR CHILDREN BEFORE
THEY GO BACK TO SCHOOL TOMORROW.
"WORLD NEWS" BEGINS NOW.
>>> GOOD EVENING, ON THIS SUNDAY
NIGHT FROM NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
WE ARE HERE TONIGHT IN FRONT OF
THE NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL WHERE AN
ENTIRE COMMUNITY IS COMING
TOGETHER.
THE FAMILIES OF THE VICTIMS, THE
SURVIVORS TOO, AND THEY ARE
GATHERING HERE TONIGHT TO HEAR
FROM PRESIDENT OBAMA, WHO IS
HERE NOW AT THE SCHOOL RIGHT
NOW.
TONIGHT IN HIS ROLE HAS
COMFORTER IN CHIEF AS A FATHER
HIMSELF, HELPING TO HEAL A
NATION IN MOURNING.
HE IS SPEAKING WITH THE FAMILIES
AT THIS HOUR AND AROUND THIS
COUNTRY TONIGHT, OUTSIDE
PHILADELPHIA, A VIGIL FOR THE
VICTIMS.
IN WASHINGTON, D.C., REMEMBERING
THEM WITH SONG, HOLDING CANDLES
AGAINST THE NIGHT.
AT A CHURCH IN DETROIT, KEEPING
THE CHILDREN, THE TEACHERS, IN
THEIR PRAYERS.
AND ON TELEVISION TODAY, NFL
PLAYERS, LIKE THE TEAMS IN THE
NEW ORLEANS SUPERDOME OFFERING A
MOMENT OF SILENCE.
AND THIS EVENING A NEW IMAGE OF
THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA IN A
SIXTH GRADE YEARBOOK PICTURE
YEARS BEFORE HE WOULD TAKE THE
LIVES OF 12 LITTLE GIRLS, EIGHT
LITTLE BOYS AND THE SIX WOMEN
WHO TAUGHT AND GUIDED THEM.
OUR ERN TIRE -- ENTIRE ABC NEWS
TEAM IS ON THE GROUNDS TONIGHT
AND WE BEGIN WITH THE PORTRAITS
OF THE LIVES LOST.
♪
THIS IS AN ABC NEWS SPECIAL
REPORT.
TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK.
>> GOOD EVENING TO ALL OF YOU,
I'M DIANE SAWYER, HERE WITH
GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS AT ABC HTD
QUARTERS IN NEW YORK AND WE
SBOIN YOU ON THE AIR THIS SUNDAY
NIGHT BECAUSE THE PEOPLE OF
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT ARE HOLDING
A VIGIL AND PRESIDENT OBAMA IS
ABOUT TO SPEAK.
HE IS IN THE AUDITORIUM AT THE
NE
NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL, ABOUT A
MILE FROM WHERE SO MANY LOST
THEIR LIVES.
>> THE PRESIDENT LANDED EARLIER
TODAY.
FOUR TIMES NOW AS PRESIDENT HE'S
HAD THIS SOMBER TASK.
THIS MAY BE THE MOST WRENCHING
ONE, WE SAW THE PRESIDENT GET
CHOKED UP TALKING ABOUT THIS ON
FRIDAY.
WE SHOULD ADVISE EVERYONE AT
HOME THIS COULD BE DIFFICULT FOR
YOUNG FAMILY MEMBERS TO WATCH.
>> THE PRESIDENT HAS ALWAYS SAID
THE HARDEST AND MOST IMPORTANT
THING HE DOES IS TRY TO FILL A
HOLE IN THE HEARTS OF THOSE
SUFFERING WITH WORDS.
I WANT TO GO TO DAVID MUIR
OUTSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL RIGHT
NOW IN RAINY SOMBER NEWTOWN.
>> REALLY APPROPRIATE, IN FACT,
A RAINY COLD NIGHT HERE IN A
TOWN THAT NEEDED THE PRESIDENT
TO COME, IN HIS ROLE AS
COMFORTER IN CHIEF.
AS A FATHER HIMSELF, I CAN TELL
YOU HE MET WITH THE FAMILIES OF
THE VICTIMS HERE BEFORE GOING TO
THE AUDITORIUM.
THE HIGH SCHOOL IS BEHIND ME AND
IT'S FULL.
BEFORE THE PRESIDENT WALKED IN,
THERE WAS A PAUSE IN THAT ROOM.
WHEN WE SAW THE IMAGES, WE
REALIZED IT WAS THE FIRST
RESPONDERS THE COMMUNITY WAS
THANKING FOR ALL OF THEIR WORK
IN THE FIRST 24 TO 48 HOURS
AFTERWARDS.
I CAN TELL YOU FROM BEING HERE
ALL WEEKEND LONG THAT THERE ARE
REALLY TWO KINDS OF PAIN BEING
FELT HERE IN THIS COMMUNITY.
FIRST, THE FAMILIES, THE PARENTS
OF THOSE 20 CHILDREN, THE
MOTHERS AND FATHERS WHOSE
CHILDREN DID NOT COME HOME FROM
SCHOOL, OUT OF THAT ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL THAT DAY AND THEIR LOSS.
THEN THERE'S THE PAIN OF THE
COMMUNITY AT LARGE.
STILL MANY MOTHERS AND FATHERS
THAT I TALK TO SAY THEY FEEL A
GUILT BECAUSE THEY'RE ABLE TO
HOLD THEIR CHILD'S HANDS, ABLE
TO HUG THEIR CHILDREN.
ONE WOMAN SAID TO ME, I DRIVE TO
WORK EVERY MORNING AND SEE THOSE
FACES ON MY WAY TO WORK AND I'M
SIMPLY NOT SURE, AT THE END OF
THE DRIVEWAYS WHICH FACES I
WON'T SEE.
BUT WHEN SCHOOL BEGINS HERE.
IT'S BEEN A VERY PAINFUL COUPLE
OF DAYS HERE AND THEY ARE
WAITING TO HEAR FROM THIS
PRESIDENT.
>> ALL RIGHT, DAVID.
WE'VE BEEN HEARING FROM
INTERFAITH MINISTERS, ONE OF
WHOM SAID WE NEED TO BE HERE TO
WEEP AND TO REMEMBER, BUT TO
SHOW WE ARE TOGETHER.
AND RIGHT NOW WE'RE GOING TO
JOIN THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE,
GOVERNOR DAN MALLOY, WHO WILL BE
INTRODUCING THE PRESIDENT.
>> WE WILL IN MANY WAYS BE MADE
STRONGER FOR WHATEVER HAS
TRANSPIRED.
AND WE WILL GET BETTER.
WE ARE BLESSED TODAY TO HAVE
WITH US THE PRESIDENT OF THE
UNITED STATES, WHO, UPON MEETING
WITH PAT AND I JUST A LITTLE
WHILE AGO, SAID THAT THE MOST
DIFFICULT DAY OF HIS PRESIDENCY
WAS FRIDAY, WHEN HE HEARD THE
NEWS OF THAT WHICH HAD BEFALLEN
THIS COMMUNITY.
I ASSURED HIM THAT CONNECTICUT,
NE
NEWTOWN, AND SANDY HOOK ARE
STRONG AND I WELCOMED HIM ON
YOUR BEHALF TO OUR COMMUNITY.
I NOW INTRODUCE THE PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES.
[ APPLAUSE ]
>> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
THANK YOU, GOVERNOR, TO ALL THE
FAMILIES, FIRST RESPONDERS, THE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN, CLERGY,
GUES
GUESTS.
SCRIPTURE TELLS US, DO NOT LOSE
HEART.
THOUGH OUTWARDLY WE ARE WASTING
AWAY, INWARDLY WE ARE BEING
RENEWED DAY BY DAY.
THE LIGHT AND MOMENTARY TROUBLES
ARE ACHIEVING FOR US AN ETERNAL
GLORY THAT FAR OUTWEIGHS THEM
ALL.
SO WE FIX OUR EYES NOT ON WHAT
IS SEEN, BUT ON WHAT IS UNSEEN.
WHAT IS SEEN IS TEMPORARY.
WHAT IS UNSEEN IS ETERNAL.
FOR WE KNOW THAT THE EARTHLY
AREA WE LIVE IN IS DESTROYED, WE
HAVE A HOUSE IN GOD.
THE ETERNAL HOUSE IN HEAVEN, NOT
BUILT BY HUMAN HANDS.
WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF 20
BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND SIX
REMARKABLE ADULTS.
THEY LOST THEIR LIVES IN A
SCHOOL THAT COULD HAVE BEEN ANY
SCHOOL, IN A QUIET TOWN FULL OF
GOOD AND DECENT PEOPLE THAT
COULD BE ANY TOWN IN AMERICA.
HERE IN NEWTOWN, I COME TO OFFER
THE LOVE AND PRAYERS OF THE
NATI
NATION.
I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTHS OF
YOUR SORROW, NOR CAN THEY HEAL
YOUR WOUNDED HEARTS.
I CAN ONLY HOPE IT HELPS FOR YOU
TO KNOW THAT YOU'RE NOT ALONE IN
YOUR GRIEF.
THAT OUR WORLD, TOO, HAS BEEN
TORN APART.
THAT ALL ACROSS THIS LAND OF
OURS, WE HAVE WEPT WITH YOU.
WE'VE PULLED OUR CHILDREN TIGHT.
AND YOU MUST KNOW THAT WHATEVER
MEASURE OF COMFORT WE CAN
PROVIDE, WE WILL PROVIDE.
WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS THAT
WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO EASE
THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL GLADLY
BEAR.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
AS THESE DIFFICULT DAYS HAVE
UNFOLDED, YOU'VE ALSO INSPIRED
US.
THE STORIES OF STRENGTH AND
RESOLVE AND SACRIFICE.
WE KNOW THAT WHEN DANGER ARRIVED
IN THE HALLS OF SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY, THE SCHOOL'S STAFF
DID NOT FLINCH.
THEY DID NOT HESITATE.
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG, MARY SHERLACH,
VICKI SOTO, LAUREN ROUSSEAU,
RACHAEL DAVINO, AND ANNE MARIE
MURPHY, THEY RESPONDED AS WE ALL
HOPED WE MIGHT RESPOND IN SUCH
TERRIFYING CIRCUMSTANCES.
WITH COURAGE AND WITH LOVE.
GIVING THEIR LIVES TO PROTECT
THE CHILDREN IN THEIR CARE.
WE KNOW THAT THERE WERE OTHER
TEACHERS WHO BARRICADED
THEMSELVES INSIDE CLASSROOMS AND
KEPT STEADY THROUGH IT ALL.
AND REASSURED THEIR STUDENTS BY
SAYING WAIT FOR THE GOOD GUYS,
THEY'RE COMING, SHOW ME YOUR
SMILE.
AND WE KNOW THE GOOD GUYS CAME.
THE FIRST RESPONDERS WHO RACED
TO THE SCENE, HELPING TO GUIDE
THOSE IN HARM'S WAY TO SAFETY
AND COMFORT THOSE IN NEED.
HOLDING AT BAY THEIR OWN SHOCK
AND THEIR OWN TRAUMA BECAUSE
THEY HAD A JOB TO DO AND OTHERS
NEEDED THEM MORE.
AND THEN THERE WERE THE SCENES
OF THE SCHOOLCHILDREN HELPING
ONE ANOTHER, HOLDING EACH OTHER,
DUTIFULLY FOLLOWING INSTRUCTIONS
IN THE WAY THAT YOUNG CHILDREN
SOMETIMES DO.
ONE CHILD EVEN TRYING TO
ENCOURAGE A GROWN-UP BY SAYING,
I KNOW KARATE, SO IT'S OKAY,
I'LL LEAD THE WAY OUT.
AS A COMMUNITY, YOU'VE INSPIRED
US, NEWTOWN.
IN THE FACE OF INDESCRIBABLE
VIOLENCE, IN THE FACE OF
UNCONSCIONABLE EVIL, YOU LOOKED
OUT FOR EACH OTHER.
YOU CARED FOR ONE ANOTHER.
AND YOU'VE LOVED ONE ANOTHER.
THIS IS HOW NEWTOWN WILL BE
REMEMBERED.
AND WITH TIME AND GOD'S GRACE,
THAT LOVE WILL SEE YOU THROUGH.
BUT WE AS A NATION, WE ARE LEFT
WITH SOME HARD QUESTIONS.
YOU KNOW, SOMEONE ONCE DESCRIBED
THE JOY AND ANXIETY OF
PARENTHOOD AS THE EQUIVALENT OF
HAVING YOUR HEART OUTSIDE OF
YOUR BODY ALL THE TIME.
WALKING AROUND.
WITH THEIR VERY FIRST CRY, THIS
MOST PRECIOUS, VITAL PART OF
OURSELVES, OUR CHILD, IS
SUDDENLY EXPOSED TO THE WORLD,
POSSIBLE MISHAP OR MALICE.
EVERY PARENT KNOWS THERE'S
NOTHING WE WILL NOT DO TO SHIELD
OUR CHILDREN FROM HARM.
AND YET WE ALSO KNOW THAT WITH
THAT CHILD'S VERY FIRST STEP AND
EACH STEP AFTER THAT, THEY'RE
SEPARATING FROM US.
THAT WE WON'T, THAT WE CAN'T
ALWAYS BE THERE FOR THEM.
THEY'LL SUFFER SICKNESS AND
SETBACKS AND BROKEN HEARTS AND
DISAPPOINTMENTS.
AND WE LEARN THAT OUR MOST
IMPORTANT JOB IS TO GIVE THEM
WHAT THEY NEED TO BECOME
SELF-RELIANT AND CAPABLE AND
RESILIENT, READY TO FACE THE
WORLD WITHOUT FEAR.
AND WE KNOW WE CAN'T DO THIS BY
OURSELVES.
IT COMES AS A SHOCK AT A CERTAIN
POINT WHERE YOU REALIZE, NO
MATTER HOW MUCH YOU LOVE THESE
KIDS, YOU CAN'T DO IT BY
YOURSELF.
THAT THIS JOB OF KEEPING OUR
CHILDREN SAFE AND TEACHING THEM
WELL, IS SOMETHING WE CAN ONLY
DO TOGETHER.
WITH THE HELP OF FRIENDS AND
NEIGHBORS.
WITH THE HELP OF A COMMUNITY.
AND THE HELP OF A NATION.
AND IN THAT WAY WE COME TO
REALIZE THAT WE BEAR
RESPONSIBILITY FOR EVERY CHILD,
BECAUSE WE'RE COUNTING ON
EVERYBODY ELSE TO HELP LOOK
AFTER OURS.
THAT WE'RE ALL PARENTS, THAT
THEY'RE ALL OUR CHILDREN.
THIS IS OUR FIRST TASK, CARING
FOR OUR CHILDREN.
IT'S OUR FIRST JOB.
IF WE DON'T GET THAT RIGHT, WE
DON'T GET ANYTHING RIGHT.
THAT'S HOW, AS A SOCIETY, WE
WILL BE JUDGED.
AND BY THAT MEASURE, CAN WE
TRULY SAY, AS A NATION, THAT
WE'RE MEETING OUR OBLIGATIONS?
CAN WE HONESTLY SAY THAT WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM, SAFE FROM
HARM?
CAN WE CLAIM AS A NATION THAT
WE'RE ALTOGETHER THERE, LETTING
THEM KNOW THAT THEY'RE LOVED,
AND TEACHING THEM TO LOVE IN
RETURN?
CAN WE SAY THAT WE'RE TRULY
DOING ENOUGH, TO GIVE ALL THE
CHILDREN OF THIS CHILDREN THE
CHANCE THEY DESERVE TO LIVE OUT
THEIR LIVES IN HAPPINESS AND
WITH PURPOSE?
I'VE BEEN REFLECTING ON THIS THE
LAST FEW DAYS.
IF WE'RE HONEST WITH OURSELVES,
THE ANSWER IS NO.
WE'RE NOT DOING ENOUGH.
AND WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE.
SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT, THIS
IS THE FOURTH TIME WE HAVE COME
TOGETHER TO COMFORT A GRIEVING
COMMUNITY TORN APART BY MASS
SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS, FOURTH TIME WE'VE
CONSOLED THE FAMILIES OF
VICTIMS.
AND IN BETWEEN, THERE HAVE BEEN
AN ENDLESS SERIES OF DEADLY
SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE COUNTRY,
ALMOST DAILY REPORTS OF VICTIMS,
MANY OF THEM CHILDREN, IN SMALL
TOWNS AND BIG CITIES, ALL ACROSS
AMERICA, VICTIMS WHO MUCH OF THE
TIME THEIR ONLY FAULT WAS BEING
IN THE WRONG PLACE AT THE WRONG
TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE.
THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
WE WILL BE TOLD THAT THE CAUSES
OF SUCH VIOLENCE ARE COMPLEX AND
THAT IS TRUE.
NO SINGLE LAW, NO SET OF LAWS
CAN ELIMINATE EVIL FROM THE
WORLD OR PREVENT EVERY SENSELESS
ACT OF VIOLENCE IN OUR SOCIETY.
BUT THAT CAN'T BE AN EXCUSE FOR
INACTION.
SURELY WE CAN DO BETTER THAN
THIS.
IF THERE'S EVEN ONE STEP WE CAN
TAKE TO SAVE ANOTHER CHILD, OR
ANOTHER PARENT, OR ANOTHER TOWN,
FROM THE GRIEF THAT'S VISITED
TUCSON AND AURORA AND OAK CREEK
AND NEWTOWN, AND COMMUNITIES
FROM COLUMBINE TO BLACKSBURG
BEFORE THAT.
SURELY WE HAVE AN OBLIGATION TO
TRY.
IN THE COMING WEEKS, I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
TO ENGAGE MY FELLOW CITIZENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT, TO MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONALS, TO PARENTS
AND EDUCATORS, IN AN EFFORT
AIMED AT PREVENTING MORE
TRAGEDIES LIKE THIS.
BECAUSE WHAT CHOICE DO WE HAVE?
WE CAN'T ACCEPT EVENTS LIKE THIS
AS ROUTINE.
ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
THAT THE POLITICS ARE TOO HARD?
ARE WE PREPARED TO SAY THAT SUCH
VIOLENCE VISITED ON OUR CHILDREN
YEAR AFTER YEAR AFTER YEAR IS
SOMEHOW THE PRICE OF OUR
FREEDOM?
IN ALL THE WORLD'S RELIGIONS, SO
MANY OF THEM REPRESENTED HERE
TODAY, START WITH A SIMPLE
QUESTION.
WHY ARE WE HERE?
WHAT GIVES OUR LIFE MEANING?
WHAT GIVES OUR ACTS PURPOSE?
WE KNOW THAT OUR TIME ON THIS
EARTH IS FLEETING.
WE KNOW THAT WE WILL EACH HAVE
OUR SHARE OF PLEASURE AND PAIN.
THAT EVEN AFTER WE CHASE AFTER
SOME EARTHLY GOAL, WHETHER IT'S
WEALTH OR POWER OR FAME OR JUST
SIMPLE COMFORT, WE WILL IN SOME
FASHION, FALL SHORT OF WHAT WE
HAD HOPED.
WE KNOW THAT NO MATTER HOW GOOD
OUR INTENTIONS, WE'LL ALL
STUMBLE SOMETIMES IN SOME WAY.
WE'LL MAKE MISTAKES, WE'LL
EXPERIENCE HARDSHIP, AND EVEN
WHEN WE'RE TRYING TO DO THE
RIGHT THING, WE KNOW THAT MUCH
OF OUR TIME WILL BE SPENT
GROPING THROUGH THE DARKNESS.
SO OFTEN UNABLE TO DISCERN GOD'S
HEAVENLY PLANS.
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING WE CAN BE
SURE OF.
AND THAT IS THE LOVE THAT WE
HAVE.
FOR OUR CHILDREN, FOR OUR
FAMILIES, FOR EACH OTHER.
THE WARMTH OF A SMALL CHILD'S
EMBRACE, THAT IS TRUE.
THE MEMORIES WE HAVE OF THEM,
THE JOY THAT THEY BRING, THE
WONDER WE SEE THROUGH THEIR
EYES, THAT FIERCE AND BOUNDLESS
LOVE WE FEEL FOR THEM, A LOVE
THAT TAKES US OUT OF OURSELVES
AND BINDS US TO SOMETHING
LARGER, WE KNOW THAT'S WHAT
MATTERS.
WE KNOW WE'RE ALWAYS DOING RIGHT
WHEN WE'RE TAKING CARE OF THEM.
WHEN WE'RE TEACHING THEM WELL.
WHEN WE'RE SHOWING ACTS OF
KINDNESS.
WE DON'T GO WRONG WHEN WE DO
THAT.
THAT'S WHAT WE CAN BE SURE OF.
AND THAT'S WHAT YOU, THE PEOPLE
OF NEWTOWN, HAVE REMINDED US.
THAT'S HOW YOU'VE INSPIRED US.
YOU REMIND US WHAT MATTERS.
THAT'S WHAT SHOULD DRIVE US
FORWARD IN EVERYTHING WE DO.
FOR AS LONG AS GOD SEES FIT TO
KEEP US ON THIS EARTH.
LET THE LITTLE CHILDREN COME TO
ME, JESUS SAID, AND DO NOT
HINDER THEM.
FOR TO SUCH BELONGS THE KINGDOM
OF HEAVEN.
CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANA, DYLAN,
MADELEINE, CATHERINE, CHASE,
JESSE, JAMES, GRACE, EMILIE,
JACK, NOAH, CAROLINE, JESSICA,
BENJAMIN, AVIELLE, ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
FOR THOSE OF US WHO REMAIN, LET
US FIND THE STRENGTH TO CARRY ON
AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY WORTHY OF
THEIR MEMORY.
MAY GOD BLESS AND KEEP THOSE
WE'VE LOST IN HIS HEAVENLY
PLACE.
MAY HE GRACE THOSE WE STILL HAVE
WITH HIS HOLY COMFORT, AND MAY
HE BLESS AND WATCH OVER THIS
COMMUNITY AND THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA.
>> CONCLUDING HIS SPEECH,
CLEARLY EMOTIONAL PRESIDENT
OBAMA ADDRESSING THE ANWISHED
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, STARTING OUT BY
TALKING OF THEIR GRIEF, SAYING
DO NOT LOSE HEART, QUOTING THE
SCRIPTURE, YOU ARE NOT GRIEVING
ALONE.
BUT THEN TURNING TO THE HARD
QUESTIONS.
HE SAID WE WILL HAVE TO CHANGE,
THIS CANNOT BE TOLERATED
ANYMORE.
>> THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME AS
PRESIDENT HE'S HAD TO COMFORT A
COMMUNITY AFTER A MASS SHOOTING.
HE SAID WE HAVE TO MAKE A
COUNTRY WORTHY OF A MEMORY OF
ALL THE CHILDREN'S NAMES HE READ
AT THE CLOSE OF THAT PRAYER.
YOU TALK ABOUT EMOTION.
YOU COULD HEAR THOSE SOBS IN THE
CROWD TODAY AS THE PRESIDENT
TALKED ABOUT THE HEROISM OF THE
ADULTS IN THAT SCHOOL AS WELL.
>> SOME OF THE LITTLE BABIES IN
THE ROOM CRIED AS WELL,
REMINDING EVERYONE OF THE
INCREDIBLE SMALL CHILDREN WHO
WERE LOST.
WE THANK YOU FOR JOINING US
RIGHT NOW AND WE RETURN YOU TO
YOUR REGULAR PROGRAMMING, BUT WE
WANT YOU TO KNOW THAT ALL WEEK
LONG HERE AT ABC NEWS, WE'LL BE
ASKING TOUGH QUESTIONS ABOUT HOW
WE MOVE FORWARD, THE TRAGEDY AT
SANDY HOOK, THE SEARCH FOR
SOLUTIONS, ALL WEEK HERE AT ABC
NEWS.
>> BEGINNING TOMORROW MORNING
WITH A SPECIAL EDITION OF "GOOD
MORNING AMERICA."
>> UNTIL THEN, FROM ALL OF US AT
ABS NEWS, THANK YOU FOR JOINING
US AND TO YOU AND YOUR FAMILIES,
GOODNIGHT.
♪
>> THIS HAS BEEN A SPECIAL
REPORT FROM ABC NEWS.
♪
>> AND THAT IS "WORLD NEWS" FOR
THIS SUNDAY NIGHT.
ALL THIS WEEK, A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION RIGHT HERE ON ABC
NEWS ABOUT GUNS, ABOUT MENTAL
ILLNESS, IS IT TIME THAT WE CAN
DO SOMETHING AS A NATION
TOGETHER?
POLITICS ASIDE.
TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK, THE
SEARCH FOR SOLUTIONS.
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA"
BROADCASTING FROM NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
FOR ALL OF US HERE AT ABC NEWS.
I'M DAVID MUIR.
THANK YOU FOR WATCHING.
HAVE A GOOD EVENING.
GOODNIGHT.
♪
>> Ama: NEXT AT 6:00, AN
EMOTIONAL GARETH TONIGHT AS
THOUSANDS GATHERED TO MOURN THE
VICTIMS
VICTIMS OF FRIDAY'S MASSACRE.
WE'RE LIVE IN CONNECTICUT
TONIGHT WHERE WE SPEAK WITH
FRIENDS OF THE VICTIMS.
>>> A FIERY ACCIDENT NEAR THE
CALDECOTT TUNNEL IS AFFECTING
TRAFFIC RIGHT NOW.
ABC-7 NEWS AT 6:00 BEGINS NOW.
>>> I AM VERY MINDFUL THAT MERE
WORDS CANNOT MATCH THE DEPTH OF
YOUR SORROW.
>> Ama: THE PRESIDENT PAYS
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS AND
HEROES TONIGHT IN CONNECTICUT.
I'M AMA DAETZ.
WE BEGIN WITH AN EMOTIONAL
PUBLIC MEMORIAL SERVICE IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THESE ARE PICTURE US OF THAT
SERVICE.
THIS IS A LIVE LOOK RIGHT NOW.
MEMBERS OF THE COMMUNITY STUNNED
BY THE SHOCKING DEATH OFFICE 20
CHILDREN AND SEVEN ADULTS,
PACKED THE HIGH SCHOOL.
[APPLAUSE]
>> EARLIER, GROPE -- GROWN MEN
CRIED AS THEY EMBRACED THE FIRST
RESPONDERS.
SHORTLY BEFORE THE SERVICE BEGAN
PRESIDENT OBAMA SLIPPED INTO THE
HIGH SCHOOL AND HE ASKED IF THE
NATION HAS DONE ENOUGH TO
PROTECT THE CHILDREN.
>> ARE YOU REALLY PREPARED TO
SAY WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
THAT THE POLITICS ARE TOO HARD?
>> Ama: THE PRESIDENT DID NOT
SPEAK ABOUT GU