AND IS SAFER THAN ANY COOKTOP.
BEST OF ALL, THE NUWAVE
IS THE ONLY PORTABLE COOKTOP
THAT GIVES YOU PRECISE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL WITH THE
SIMPLE PRESS OF A BUTTON.
PROFESSIONAL CHEFS CREATE
GREAT-TASTING MEALS BY
MAINTAINING THE PRECISE
TEMPERATURE FOR THE PERFECT
AMOUNT OF TIME.
WELL, NOW YOU CAN GET
PROFESSIONAL RESULTS TOO,
WITH THE NUWAVE PRECISION
INDUCTION COOKTOP.
>> THE KEY TO GREAT FOOD IS
KNOWING HOW TO CONTROL THE
TEMPERATURES OF WHAT
YOU'RE COOKING.
>> NOW THE P.I.C. IS ALLOWING
PEOPLE AT HOME TO COOK LIKE YOU
CAN IN A RESTAURANT.
>> I KNOW THAT WHEN I TURN IT ON
THAT TEMPERATURE, IT'S GOING TO
BE THAT TEMPERATURE.
THERE'S NO GUESSING.
>> Announcer: NOT ONLY DOES THE
NUWAVE GIVE YOU PRECISE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL, IT HEATS
UP TWICE AS FAST AS AN
ELECTRIC COOKTOP.
>> I PUT THE WATER IN THE PAN
AND TURNED AROUND AND THE NEXT
THING I KNEW, IT WAS BOILING.
>> WHAT AMAZES ME ABOUT P.I.C.
IS HOW QUICKLY IT WILL HEAT UP.
INDUCTION TECHNOLOGY IS JUST
UNBELIEVABLE.
>> Announcer: AND BECAUSE
THERE'S NO FLAME TO CATCH FIRE,
NO HOT COILS TO BURN YOU,
THE NUWAVE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP IS THE SAFEST COOKTOP
EVER INVENTED.
LOOK WHAT HAPPENS WITH THIS EGG:
THE PAN IS HOT, BUT THE COOKTOP
IS NOT.
THAT'S THE MAGIC OF
INDUCTION COOKING.
MAKE PASTA IN HALF THE TIME.
MELT BUTTER WITH NO CHANCE
OF IT BURNING.
MELT CHOCOLATE TO
CREAMY PERFECTION.
MAKE SAUCES WITH PERFECT
TEMPERATURE CONTROL.
>> IT'S SMALL, IT'S EFFICIENT,
IT'S CLEAN AND IT'S SAFE.
>> Announcer: AND BECAUSE
IT'S PORTABLE, YOU CAN
TAKE IT ANYWHERE, SO IT'S
PERFECT FOR BUFFETS AND
OUTDOOR PARTIES.
TO TELL YOU MORE, LET'S JOIN BOB
WARDEN AND JENNY REPKO AT THE
NUWAVE TEST KITCHEN IN CHICAGO.
>> LET ME ASK YOU, DO YOU HATE
BOIL-OVERS AND THE MESS THEY
MAKE IN THE KITCHEN?
DO YOU HATE BURNT GRILLED
CHEESE SANDWICHES OR
SHRIVELED-UP BACON?
>> WHAT ABOUT OVER-FRIED CHICKEN
THAT'S ALL GREASY, OR DRIED-OUT
OATMEAL, OVERDONE PORK CHOPS
OR CHARRED STEAK?
>> WELL, WHAT IF I WAS TO TELL
YOU THAT INSTEAD, YOU COULD NOW
HAVE PERFECT GRILLED CHEESE
SANDWICHES, PERFECTLY BROWNED
EVENLY EVERY SINGLE TIME?
>> ALL THAT CHEESE IS MELTED IN
THERE, SO DELICIOUS.
>> PERFECTLY MELTED.
AND I COULD HAVE PERFECTLY
GRILLED STEAKS SET AT
350 DEGREES THAT GIVE ME A
PERFECT MEDIUM RARE STEAK OR
HOWEVER YOU LIKE IT AND IT'S
NEVER GOING TO BURN.
PERFECT PORK CHOPS, AND NOT ONLY
PORK CHOPS...
>> RIGHT, SALMON,
GRILLED VEGETABLES, SAUSAGE,
PERFECT EVERY TIME.
>> WHAT IF I TOLD YOU, WHEN YOU
FRIED YOUR CHICKEN, IT WAS GOING
TO BE FRIED AT THE PERFECT
TEMPERATURE OF 375, GENTLY,
PERFECTLY, CRISPY, NEVER SOAKING
UP TOO MUCH OIL.
>> THAT'S HARD TO DO.
>> IN FACT, THAT'S THE PROBLEM
WITH THE OLD STOVETOPS,
WHETHER IT'S GAS OR ELECTRIC--
YOU CAN TURN IT UP AND DOWN,
BUT BECAUSE YOU DON'T HAVE
PRECISE CONTROL, YOU'RE GOING
TO GET BOIL-OVERS.
BECAUSE YOU DON'T HAVE PRECISE
CONTROL, YOU'RE GOING TO BURN
THE CEREAL ON THE BOTTOM FROM
TIME TO TIME.
AND BECAUSE YOU DON'T HAVE
PRECISE TEMPERATURE CONTROL,
YOU CAN'T HELP BUT BURN A STEAK
OR A PORK CHOP ON YOUR STOVE.
YOU SEE, YOU'RE NOT THE BAD COOK
IN THE KITCHEN.
THE STOVETOP IS THE BAD COOK IN
THE KITCHEN.
>> THAT'S RIGHT, AND THOSE DAYS
OF BAD COOKING ARE OVER,
THANKS TO THE FINE FOLKS HERE AT
NUWAVE, MAKERS OF THE
NUMBER-ONE-SELLING COUNTERTOP
OVEN IN THE WORLD.
>> WELL, THEY'VE DONE IT AGAIN.
YOU'RE LOOKING AT THE NEW WAVE
IN STOVETOP COOKING.
NOW, THIS INGENIOUS INVENTION
WILL MAKE YOUR LIFE A WHOLE LOT
EASIER IN THE KITCHEN AND A
WHOLE LOT SHORTER AND A LOT
MORE FUN.
WE'RE GOING TO SHOW YOU HOW AND
WHY EVERY MEAL-- BREAKFAST,
SNACKS, LUNCH, DINNER, GRILLED
STEAKS, FONDUES AND BUFFETS--
WILL BE MADE PERFECTLY
EVERY TIME.
BECAUSE NOW, FOR THE FIRST TIME,
YOU CAN PRECISELY CONTROL THE
COOKING TEMPERATURE.
>> Announcer: NOW YOU CAN LIVE
WELL FOR LESS WITH THE NUWAVE
PRECISION INDUCTION COOKTOP.
IT'S THE MOST ENERGY-EFFICIENT
WAY TO COOK.
THE NUWAVE P.I.C. USES
INDUCTION TECHNOLOGY.
THE SECRET IS AN INTERNAL SERIES
OF COPPER COILS.
THESE COILS GENERATE A MAGNETIC
FIELD WITHIN YOUR METAL POTS
AND PANS.
THE MAGNETIC FIELD CAUSES
INVISIBLE MOLECULES TO BEGIN
VIBRATING RAPIDLY, CREATING
HEAT, SO THE COOKWARE ITSELF
HEATS THE FOOD.
>> ONE OF MY PASSIONS
ARE BUTTER SAUCES.
AND ONE OF THE CHALLENGES OF
COOKING A BUTTER SAUCE IS THAT
IF YOU GET IT TOO HOT,
YOU KNOW, OVER 135 DEGREES,
IT BREAKS DOWN.
IF YOU GET IT TOO COOL,
IT CONGEALS.
THE BEAUTY OF THE NUWAVE P.I.C.
IS THAT I CAN CONTROL THE
TEMPERATURE EXACTLY AND KEEP
THE SAUCE FOR AN EXTENDED
PERIOD OF TIME.
THAT'S SUCH AN ADDED BONUS
FOR A PROFESSIONAL COOK
AND A HOME COOK.
>> LET ME SHOW YOU THIS
UNUSUAL PAN.
BOB, WHAT DID WE DO HERE?
>> WELL, WE ACTUALLY CUT A PAN
AND CUT A SECTION OUT,
BECAUSE IN HERE YOU CAN SEE WE
HAVE CEREAL RAPIDLY BOILING,
RIGHT? >> BOILING AWAY.
>> I CAN PUT MY HAND
RIGHT THERE.
>> IT'S AMAZING.
MOVE YOUR HAND.
I'M GOING TO PUT AN ICE CUBE
RIGHT THERE.
IT'S NOT MELTING.
>> BECAUSE ALL OF THE ENERGY IS
GOING INTO COOKING YOUR FOOD.
THERE'S NOTHING WASTED ANYWHERE
OUTSIDE OF THE PAN, SO THIS IS
PERFECTLY COOL.
SO WIPE THAT ICE CUBE OFF THERE.
>> O.K., I'VE GOT A CLOTH
RIGHT HERE.
WATCH THIS, I'LL TAKE THIS
ICE CUBE, WIPE IT UP.
I'M USING A PAPER TOWEL
ON A BURNER.
THERE'S NO FIRE, THERE'S NO
FLAME, SO IT'S SO SAFE.
>> AND THE MINUTE YOU PUT THE
PAN BACK ON IT STARTS BOILING
RIGHT AGAIN. >> WOW.
>> NOW, BECAUSE WE'RE COOKING
WITHOUT FIRE, JENNY,
I'M GOING TO TAKE A SHEET OF
PLAY MONEY AND PUT IT BETWEEN
THE P.I.C. AND THE PAN.
INSTANTLY IT STARTS
BOILING AGAIN.
>> HAVE YOU EVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE THAT?
COOKING THROUGH PAPER?
>> SO NOW WE'RE COOKING FAR MORE
EFFICIENTLY, WE'RE SAVING 40- TO
50% OF THE ENERGY. >> RIGHT.
>> ISN'T THAT AMAZING?
>> Announcer: SEEING
IS BELIEVING.
LOOK WHAT HAPPENED
WHEN THE NUWAVE P.I.C.
WAS PUT TO THE TEST ON THE
STREETS OF SAN FRANCISCO.
>> ALL RIGHT, THIS IS GONNA
BLOW YOUR MIND.
THIS IS THE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP, AND IT IS PORTABLE,
ECO-FRIENDLY AND IT SAVES YOU
A LOT OF MONEY, SAVES YOU
A LOT OF TIME. >> WOW.
>> COOKING TIME IS CUT IN HALF.
YOU SEE THAT THE WATER'S
BOILING NOW? >> YEAH.
>> THE GREAT THING ABOUT
INDUCTION COOKING IS IT ONLY
HEATS THE PART OF THE POT THAT
IS MAGNETIC, SO EVERYTHING ELSE
STAYS COOL, SO WATCH THIS.
AH!
[GROUP EXCLAIMS]
OKAY, EVERYBODY, PUT YOUR HANDS
ON IT. >> ISN'T IT HOT?
>> NO, IT JUST HEATS THE
MAGNETIC PART OF THE POT.
THIS IS AT 110.
YOU CAN LEAVE IT AT 110 AND IT
WON'T GET GLOPPY, IT WON'T GET
STALE, IT WON'T HARDEN.
>> AND YOU DON'T HAVE TO BE A
BIG CHEF TO COOK.
LIKE, I DON'T HAVE TIME TO COOK.
THIS WOULD BE GREAT.
>> EXACTLY-- THIS MAKES YOU LOOK
LIKE AN ACTUAL GOOD CHEF.
IT'S TEMPERATURE-CONTROLLED, SO
I POP MY FRIED CHICKEN RIGHT IN
THERE AND I KNOW EXACTLY WHAT
TEMPERATURE IT'S AT, AND YOU
KNOW IF YOU GO DOWN ONE,
10 DEGREES, BOOM, DROPS
JUST LIKE THAT.
CAN YOU DO THAT ON A GAS RANGE?
>> ABSOLUTELY NOT. >> NO.
>> NOT AT ALL. >> THIS IS
TEMPERATURE-CONTROLLED SO
YOU DON'T OVERCOOK IT,
YOU DON'T UNDERCOOK IT.
>> I LOVE THE TEMPERATURE
CONTROL-- THAT CAN COOK MEAT
WITHOUT DRYING IT OUT.
>> Man: MMM! >> THAT'S AMAZING!
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK?
>> NICE AND CRISPY.
>> YOU CAN FRY, YOU CAN SIMMER,
YOU CAN STEAM, YOU CAN FONDUE,
YOU CAN DO EVERYTHING WITH
THIS-- I LOVE IT.
>> IT'S AMAZING-- I'VE NEVER
SEEN ANYTHING LIKE IT.
>> I LOVE THAT IF YOU TAKE
THE TOP... THE POT OFF OF
THE TOP, IT STOPS AND THAT
THE HANDLES WERE COOL.
THAT'S REALLY AMAZING.
>> AND YOU KNOW WHAT THE GREAT
THING IS, YOU GUYS?
IT'S PORTABLE.
YOU CAN TAKE THIS WHOLE THING
OVER TO THE TABLE, PLOP IT DOWN
AND IT WILL STAY AT 110 RIGHT
IN THE MIDDLE OF YOUR GUESTS
AND YOU CAN DIP ALL DAY.
DIP, DIP, DIP, EVERYBODY DIP.
AND THE BEST PART ABOUT IT?
YOU CAN GRILL ON THE TABLE.
>> Man: OH...
>> WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT THAT?
>> MMM...
>> SO IT'S RAINING OUTSIDE,
IT'S THE MIDDLE OF WINTER,
YOU STILL GET GRILLED FOOD.
WILL IT CHANGE THE WAY YOU COOK
AT HOME? >> Group: YES.
>> THE P.I.C. MAKES EVERYTHING
SO SIMPLE. >> IT LOOKS LIKE YOU
ORDERED IT FROM A RESTAURANT.
>> IT DOES LOOK LIKE I ORDERED
IT FROM A RESTAURANT.
THAT'S BECAUSE I'M A GOOD COOK
NOW WITH THE P.I.C. [LAUGHTER]
>> Announcer: INTRODUCING
THE REVOLUTIONARY PRECISION
INDUCTION COOKTOP FROM NUWAVE,
THE LEADER IN PORTABLE
INDUCTION COOKING TECHNOLOGY.
THE NUWAVE HEATS UP TWICE AS
FAST, USES UP TO 70% LESS ENERGY
AND IS SAFER THAN ANY COOKTOP.
BEST OF ALL, THE NUWAVE
IS THE ONLY PORTABLE COOKTOP
THAT GIVES YOU PRECISE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL WITH THE
SIMPLE PRESS OF A BUTTON.
>> IT TAKES THE HUMAN ERROR
OUT OF COOKING.
THERE'S NO MORE GUESSWORK
IN WHAT TEMPERATURE
YOU'RE COOKING AT.
>> Announcer: MAKE PASTA
IN HALF THE TIME.
MELT BUTTER WITH NO CHANCE
OF IT BURNING.
MELT CHOCOLATE TO
CREAMY PERFECTION.
MAKE SAUCES WITH PERFECT
TEMPERATURE CONTROL.
GAS AND ELECTRIC STOVES
HAVE HOT COILS AND OPEN
FLAMES WHICH CAN BURN YOU.
THE NUWAVE P.I.C. TRANSFERS
HEAT ONLY TO YOUR COOKWARE,
SO IT'S 100% SAFE.
LOOK WHAT HAPPENS WITH THIS
EGG: THE PAN IS HOT, BUT THE
COOKTOP IS NOT.
THAT'S THE MAGIC OF
INDUCTION COOKING.
>> IT GETS HOT WITHIN FIVE
SECONDS, BUT THEN YOU TAKE THE
PAN OFF AND PUT YOUR HAND ON THE
DEVICE AND IT'S COLD.
>> Announcer: WHY CROWD YOUR
KITCHEN WITH EXPENSIVE,
BULKY APPLIANCES?
THE NUWAVE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP IS A COMPLETE KITCHEN
ALL IN ONE.
IT'S YOUR PORTABLE INDOOR GRILL,
TEMPERATURE-CONTROLLED DEEP
FRYER, FESTIVE FONDUE MAKER,
TIMED RICE COOKER,
HEALTHY VEGETABLE STEAMER,
PROGRAMMABLE SLOW COOKER.
>> IT'S SMALL, IT'S EFFICIENT,
IT'S CLEAN AND IT'S SAFE.
>> Announcer: THE OVERSIZED
12-INCH TEMPERED GLASS SURFACE
CAN HANDLE EVEN LARGE POTS
AND PANS.
THE NUWAVE P.I.C. WORKS
WITH MOST COOKWARE--
JUST CHECK FOR THE "INDUCTION
COOKING READY" SYMBOL.
ITS COMPACT SIZE MAKES IT THE
IDEAL SOLUTION FOR R.V.s, SMALL
APARTMENTS, AND DORM ROOMS TOO.
AND BECAUSE IT'S PORTABLE,
YOU CAN TAKE IT ANYWHERE,
SO IT'S PERFECT FOR BUFFETS
AND OUTDOOR PARTIES.
INDUCTION COOKING CAN COST
THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS, BUT THE
NUWAVE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP IS A BARGAIN AT JUST
FOUR EASY PAYMENTS OF
ONLY $33.33.
YOUR NUWAVE COMES WITH THE
QUICK START GUIDE, GOURMET DVD
AND THE NUWAVE RECIPE BOOK
GIVING YOU THE PRECISE
TEMPERATURE SETTINGS TO MAKE
ALL YOUR FAVORITE MEALS COME
OUT PERFECT EVERY TIME.
AND GET THIS: WHEN YOU CALL NOW
AND ORDER DIRECT, WE'LL DROP
A PAYMENT!
YOU PAY ONLY THREE PAYMENTS
OF $33.33.
THAT'S A 25% SAVINGS.
BUT WE'RE NOT DONE.
YOU ALSO GET THE NUWAVE
STAINLESS STEEL 3-1/2 QUART
POT WITH PREMIUM TEMPERED
GLASS LID.
ALONE, IT'S WORTH MORE THAN
$100, BUT CALL TODAY AND IT'S
YOURS FREE.
PLUS WE'LL ALSO INCLUDE THIS
STAINLESS STEEL STEAMER BASKET.
WAIT, THERE'S MORE GOOD NEWS.
WE'LL ALSO SEND YOU THE
NUWAVE PERFECT GREEN NON-STICK
COOKWARE SET, INCLUDING A
NINE-INCH OMELET PAN, PLUS A
10-1/2-INCH SAUCE PAN THAT CAN
BE USED WITH YOUR GLASS LID TOO.
THE NON-STICK SURFACE IS COATED
WITH DURALON DIAMOND-INFUSED
NANO-CERAMIC COATING.
IT HELPS YOU MAKE GREAT-TASTING
LOW-FAT MEALS.
WE'LL ALSO SEND YOU THE
NINE-PIECE DELUXE FONDUE KIT,
PERFECT FOR MAKING YOUR
FAVORITE FONDUES.
HOLD ON.
ARE YOU READY FOR
AN AMAZING DEAL?
ACT NOW AND WE'LL SEND YOU
A SECOND NUWAVE P.I.C.
ABSOLUTELY FREE!
YOU'LL GET A FREE NUWAVE WITH
ALL THE FREE BONUSES-- ALL YOU
PAY IS THE S&P FOR EACH SET.
KEEP IT FOR YOURSELF OR SEND IT
AS AN UNFORGETTABLE GIFT
FROM YOU.
THIS BUY ONE, GET ONE FREE
SPECIAL PROMOTION
WON'T LAST LONG.
AND LISTEN TO THIS: WE'LL LET
YOU TRY THE NUWAVE P.I.C.
RISK-FREE, NOT FOR 30 DAYS,
NOT FOR 60 DAYS, BUT 90 DAYS.
IF YOU'RE NOT HAPPY, RETURN
THEM, BUT KEEP BOTH SETS OF
BONUS COOKWARE AS YOUR
FREE GIFTS.
ALL YOU PAY IS THE SHIPPING AND
PROCESSING FOR EACH OF THEM.
THIS SPECIAL TELEVISION OFFER,
WORTH OVER $600, IS NOT
AVAILABLE AT STORES AND WON'T
LAST LONG, SO ACT FAST.
DON'T FORGET TO ASK ABOUT
SPECIAL SAVINGS ON THE NUWAVE
CAST-IRON BARBECUE GRILL AND
GRIDDLE, THE 10-PIECE PERFECT
GREEN COOKWARE SET, THE NUWAVE
PRESSURE COOKER, PLUS THE
COMPLETE LINE OF NUWAVE OVENS.
CALL OR GO ONLINE NOW.
[♪...]
>> ONE OF MY MOST POPULAR
DESSERT DISHES IS CALLED THE
CHOCOLATE THREE WAYS.
IT'S MADE WITH A TRIPLE
CHOCOLATE BROWNIE, DONE WITH
A CHOCOLATE ESPRESSO SAUCE
THAT I DO, AND ALSO WHITE
CHOCOLATE GELATO WITH A LITTLE
BIT OF ROCK SALT AND OLIVE OIL,
AND THE P.I.C. INDUCTION BURNER,
I CAN KEEP IT WARM AND ADJUST IT
IN 10-DEGREE INCREMENTS AND
SPOON THE SAUCE RIGHT ON--
IT'S PERFECT TEMPERATURE
ALL NIGHT LONG... OPPOSED TO MY
DOUBLE BOILER THAT I HAD BEFORE,
RISKING TO GET WATER IN THE
CHOCOLATE-- WOULD ACTUALLY
MAKE IT SEPARATE.
SO I LOVE THE P.I.C.
WHEN IT COMES DOWN TO KEEPING
THINGS WARM, AND THAT
CHOCOLATE SAUCE CAN GET OUT
FAST AND I CAN MOVE THAT DISH
OUT OF THE KITCHEN QUICK.
NOW THE P.I.C. IS ALLOWING
PEOPLE AT HOME TO COOK
LIKE YOU CAN IN A RESTAURANT.
>> WELL, SO FAR WE'VE BEEN
SHOWING YOU WHAT YOU CAN DO WHEN
YOU CAN PRECISELY CONTROL
LOW TEMPERATURES, LIKE FOR
PERFECTLY MELTING CHOCOLATE
OR FOR SIMMERING CEREAL.
>> BUT, EVERYBODY LOVES A GREAT
STEAK AND EVERYONE HATES IT
WHEN THEIR STEAK DOES NOT COME
OUT JUST THE WAY THEY LIKE IT.
BUT WITH THE NUWAVE P.I.C.,
BECAUSE IT COMES WITH PRECISION
TEMPERATURE CONTROL, YOU WON'T
EVER UNDERCOOK OR OVERCOOK
THAT STEAK.
>> FOR GRILLING, USE THIS GREAT
CAST IRON BARBECUE GRILL PAN
THAT CAN COME WITH YOUR P.I.C.
NOW, IF YOU LIKE YOUR STEAK
RARE, CHECK THIS OUT.
IT'S GOING TO BE RED AND JUICY
ON THE INSIDE, BUT PERFECTLY
BROWN ON THE OUTSIDE.
IF YOU LIKE IT WELL DONE,
IT'S NOT GOING TO BE BURNED ON
THE OUTSIDE, BUT IT'S GOING TO
BE PERFECTLY WELL DONE ON
THE INSIDE. HOW?
BECAUSE THE P.I.C. GIVES YOU
PERFECT TEMPERATURE CONTROL.
LOOK AT THIS, FIRST I SEARED IT
TO 575, NOW I'VE REDUCED THE
P.I.C. TO 375 AND CHECK OUT THIS
LASER THERMOMETER--
EXACTLY 375 DEGREES.
>> CHECK OUT HOW 375 DEGREES
GIVES US THOSE GREAT GRILL MARKS
WITHOUT BURNING OR CHARRING.
>> AND YOU KNOW WHAT I LIKE WITH
MY STEAK? >> I KNOW.
>> A PERFECTLY BAKED POTATO,
WHICH I CAN DO RIGHT HERE IN MY
NUWAVE OVEN IN MINUTES.
>> OR IF YOU LIKE MY FAVORITE
THING, SWEET POTATO FRIES.
WHATEVER YOU MAKE IN THE NUWAVE,
IT COMES OUT PERFECT
EVERY TIME. [CHUCKLES]
>> Announcer: ACCORDING TO THE
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY,
50 CENTS OF EVERY DOLLAR YOU
SPEND HEATING UP YOUR GAS OR
ELECTRIC STOVE IS WASTED.
BUT NOT SO WITH YOUR NUWAVE
P.I.C., BECAUSE IT USES
INDUCTION TECHNOLOGY.
THIS INFRARED CAMERA SHOWS HOW
A TRADITIONAL COOKTOP HEATS THE
AREA ALL AROUND THE POT.
BUT LOOK HOW THE NUWAVE P.I.C.
HEATS UP ONLY THE POT.
THIS MEANS NO MORE
WASTED ENERGY.
>> I LOVE THAT I'M SAVING
ENERGY, THAT I'M ONLY HEATING UP
THE BOTTOM SURFACE OF THE POT
WHERE I NEED THE HEAT TO BE,
AND I REALLY THINK WE'RE SEEING
A DIFFERENCE IN OUR ELECTRIC
BILLS AND I LOVE THAT.
>> I FEEL REALLY GOOD WHEN I'M
USING THE P.I.C. 'CAUSE I'M
USING LESS ENERGY TO COOK
WHATEVER IT IS I'M COOKING, AND
I FEEL LIKE IN MY LITTLE WAY I'M
DOING SOMETHING FOR THE PLANET.
>> ONE OF THE BEST THINGS ABOUT
THE NUWAVE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP IS IT'S PORTABLE.
I CAN TAKE IT ANYWHERE, I DON'T
HAVE TO LEAVE IT IN THE KITCHEN.
SO I'LL TAKE IT INTO MY DINING
ROOM AND I'LL SET UP MY OWN EGG
STATION, SO WHEN I HAVE
VISITORS-- ESPECIALLY MY
FAMILY-- I CAN COOK MY OWN
OMELETS, THEY CAN COOK THEIR OWN
OMELETS, THEY CAN COOK THEIR
EGGS, THEY CAN COOK PANCAKES AND
IT'S JUST THIS SIMPLE BECAUSE
I'VE GOT PRECISE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL.
AND LOOK HOW BEAUTIFULLY
NON-STICK THIS IS.
ALL I HAVE TO DO TO MAKE THE
OMELET IS TIP IT, THE OMELET
RUNS BACK.
I TIP IT AGAIN, IT RUNS BACK.
I'M GOING TO BE ABLE
TO FILL THIS UP.
SO EVERYBODY CAN HAVE WHATEVER
FILLING THEY LIKE.
I ALWAYS LIKE TO HAVE SOME
MUSHROOMS, SOME CHEESE,
SOME PEPPERS... >> AND YOU KNOW
I LIKE THE HEALTHY SPINACH, BOB.
>> OHH... >> I JUST RUINED
HIS OMELET. >> [LAUGHS]
WELL, WITH THE PERFECT GREEN FRY
PAN, WE JUST SIMPLY FOLD THAT
OVER, IT'S GOING TO CONTINUE TO
COOK WHILE IT'S IN THE PAN.
I FOLD THAT OUT AND LOOK AT
THIS: MY PAN IS CLEAN, I'M READY
TO COOK ANOTHER OMELET AGAIN.
>> THE HEATING IS CONSISTENT,
SO I CAN SET UP A BUFFET WITH
FOUR OR FIVE OF THESE AND HAVE
DIFFERENT TEMPERATURES THAT ARE
GOING TO MAINTAIN.
I THINK ONE OF THE BIGGEST
COMPLAINTS IS THAT SOMETIMES
THE LAST PEOPLE THAT GO THROUGH
THE BUFFET, THEY GET THE COLD
FOOD, AND WITH THE P.I.C.,
THE FOOD STAYS WARM THROUGH
THE ENTIRE EVENT AND THE GUESTS
REALLY APPRECIATE THAT,
AS DOES THE HOST AND HOSTESS.
>> MY HUSBAND LOVES THE NUWAVE
P.I.C. BECAUSE HE CAN GRILL
INDOORS INSTEAD OF HAVING
TO GO OUTSIDE.
HE CAN ACTUALLY JOIN US AS A
FAMILY AND WE CAN ALL BE
TOGETHER AND COOK.
>> Announcer: INTRODUCING
THE REVOLUTIONARY PRECISION
INDUCTION COOKTOP FROM NUWAVE,
THE LEADER IN PORTABLE
INDUCTION COOKING TECHNOLOGY.
THE NUWAVE HEATS UP TWICE AS
FAST, USES UP TO 70% LESS ENERGY
AND IS SAFER THAN ANY COOKTOP.
BEST OF ALL, THE NUWAVE
IS THE ONLY PORTABLE COOKTOP
THAT GIVES YOU PRECISE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL WITH THE
SIMPLE PRESS OF A BUTTON.
>> I LOVE THE TEMPERATURE
CONTROL. >> AS YOU PRESS THE
BUTTONS, YOU CAN SEE EXACTLY
WHAT THE TEMPERATURE IS-- YOU
CAN WATCH THE WATER BOIL CHANGE.
>> MM-HMM. >> THAT'S INCREDIBLE.
>> ANYTHING YOU BOIL WATER
FOR... [SNAPS FINGERS]
IT'S THAT QUICK.
>> Announcer: MAKE PASTA
IN HALF THE TIME.
MELT BUTTER WITH NO CHANCE
OF IT BURNING.
MELT CHOCOLATE TO
CREAMY PERFECTION.
MAKE SAUCES WITH PERFECT
TEMPERATURE CONTROL.
GAS AND ELECTRIC STOVES
HAVE HOT COILS AND OPEN
FLAMES WHICH CAN BURN YOU.
THE NUWAVE P.I.C. TRANSFERS
HEAT ONLY TO YOUR COOKWARE,
SO IT'S 100% SAFE.
LOOK WHAT HAPPENS WITH THIS
EGG: THE PAN IS HOT, BUT THE
COOKTOP IS NOT.
THAT'S THE MAGIC OF
INDUCTION COOKING.
>> Group: WOW!
>> Woman: IT'S NOT EVEN HOT.
>> WILL IT CHANGE THE WAY YOU
COOK AT HOME? >> Group: YES.
>> Announcer: WHY CROWD YOUR
KITCHEN WITH EXPENSIVE,
BULKY APPLIANCES?
THE NUWAVE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP IS A COMPLETE KITCHEN
ALL IN ONE.
IT'S YOUR PORTABLE INDOOR GRILL,
TEMPERATURE-CONTROLLED DEEP
FRYER, FESTIVE FONDUE MAKER,
TIMED RICE COOKER,
HEALTHY VEGETABLE STEAMER,
PROGRAMMABLE SLOW COOKER.
>> IF I HAD THIS, I WOULD FRY
ALL DAY, EVERY DAY. [LAUGHTER]
>> SO I CAN STEAM MY VEGETABLES
ON TOP, I'VE GOT MY COUSCOUS,
MY RICE, MY PASTA UNDERNEATH,
EVERYTHING IS DONE, YOU COME
HOME FROM A HARD DAY AT WORK,
10 MINUTES, YOU GOT FOOD
FOR THE WHOLE FAMILY.
>> Announcer: THE OVERSIZED
12-INCH TEMPERED GLASS SURFACE
CAN HANDLE EVEN LARGE POTS
AND PANS.
THE NUWAVE P.I.C. WORKS
WITH MOST COOKWARE--
JUST CHECK FOR THE "INDUCTION
COOKING READY" SYMBOL.
ITS COMPACT SIZE MAKES IT THE
IDEAL SOLUTION FOR R.V.s, SMALL
APARTMENTS, AND DORM ROOMS TOO.
AND BECAUSE IT'S PORTABLE,
YOU CAN TAKE IT ANYWHERE,
SO IT'S PERFECT FOR BUFFETS
AND OUTDOOR PARTIES.
INDUCTION COOKING CAN COST
THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS, BUT THE
NUWAVE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP IS A BARGAIN AT JUST
FOUR EASY PAYMENTS OF
ONLY $33.33.
YOUR NUWAVE COMES WITH THE
QUICK START GUIDE, GOURMET DVD
AND THE NUWAVE RECIPE BOOK
GIVING YOU THE PRECISE
TEMPERATURE SETTINGS TO MAKE
ALL YOUR FAVORITE MEALS COME
OUT PERFECT EVERY TIME.
AND GET THIS: WHEN YOU CALL NOW
AND ORDER DIRECT, WE'LL DROP
A PAYMENT!
YOU PAY ONLY THREE PAYMENTS
OF $33.33.
THAT'S A 25% SAVINGS.
BUT WE'RE NOT DONE.
YOU ALSO GET THE NUWAVE
STAINLESS STEEL 3-1/2 QUART
POT WITH PREMIUM TEMPERED
GLASS LID.
ALONE, IT'S WORTH MORE THAN
$100, BUT CALL TODAY AND IT'S
YOURS FREE.
PLUS WE'LL ALSO INCLUDE THIS
STAINLESS STEEL STEAMER BASKET.
WAIT, THERE'S MORE GOOD NEWS.
WE'LL ALSO SEND YOU THE
NUWAVE PERFECT GREEN NON-STICK
COOKWARE SET, INCLUDING A
NINE-INCH OMELET PAN, PLUS A
10-1/2-INCH SAUCE PAN THAT CAN
BE USED WITH YOUR GLASS LID TOO.
THE NON-STICK SURFACE IS COATED
WITH DURALON DIAMOND-INFUSED
NANO-CERAMIC COATING.
IT HELPS YOU MAKE GREAT-TASTING
LOW-FAT MEALS.
WE'LL ALSO SEND YOU THE
NINE-PIECE DELUXE FONDUE KIT,
PERFECT FOR MAKING YOUR
FAVORITE FONDUES.
HOLD ON.
ARE YOU READY FOR
AN AMAZING DEAL?
ACT NOW AND WE'LL SEND YOU
A SECOND NUWAVE P.I.C.
ABSOLUTELY FREE!
YOU'LL GET A FREE NUWAVE WITH
ALL THE FREE BONUSES-- ALL YOU
PAY IS THE S&P FOR EACH SET.
KEEP IT FOR YOURSELF OR SEND IT
AS AN UNFORGETTABLE GIFT
FROM YOU.
THIS BUY ONE, GET ONE FREE
SPECIAL PROMOTION
WON'T LAST LONG.
AND LISTEN TO THIS: WE'LL LET
YOU TRY THE NUWAVE P.I.C.
RISK-FREE, NOT FOR 30 DAYS,
NOT FOR 60 DAYS, BUT 90 DAYS.
IF YOU'RE NOT HAPPY, RETURN
THEM, BUT KEEP BOTH SETS OF
BONUS COOKWARE AS YOUR
FREE GIFTS.
ALL YOU PAY IS THE SHIPPING AND
PROCESSING FOR EACH OF THEM.
THIS SPECIAL TELEVISION OFFER,
WORTH OVER $600, IS NOT
AVAILABLE AT STORES AND WON'T
LAST LONG, SO ACT FAST.
DON'T FORGET TO ASK ABOUT
SPECIAL SAVINGS ON THE NUWAVE
CAST-IRON BARBECUE GRILL AND
GRIDDLE, THE 10-PIECE PERFECT
GREEN COOKWARE SET, THE NUWAVE
PRESSURE COOKER, PLUS THE
COMPLETE LINE OF NUWAVE OVENS.
CALL OR GO ONLINE NOW.
[♪...]
>> Announcer: THE NUWAVE
PRECISION INDUCTION COOKTOP IS
THE MOST CONVENIENT AND
EFFICIENT WAY TO COOK.
YOU GET THE CONVENIENCE OF
TRADITIONAL STOVETOP SETTINGS
PLUS THE FLEXIBILITY TO
CONTROL THE TEMPERATURE
IN 10-DEGREE INCREMENTS.
SEAR A STEAK TO PERFECTION OR
MELT CHOCOLATE OR BUTTER WITHOUT
A DOUBLE BOILER.
YOU CAN DO IT ALL WITH THE
NUWAVE P.I.C.
THE SMART SENSORS INSIDE ENSURE
YOU'LL CREATE DELICIOUS MEALS
EVERY TIME BY MAINTAINING THE
CONSTANT CORRECT TEMPERATURE.
IT'S LIKE HAVING A PROFESSIONAL
CHEF COOKING FOR YOU.
THE RESULT: NO MORE MISTAKES,
NO MORE BURNING.
>> IT TAKES THE HUMAN ERROR
OUT OF COOKING.
THERE'S NO MORE GUESSWORK
IN WHAT TEMPERATURE
YOU'RE COOKING AT.
IT'S VERY EASY TO JUST SET
THE TEMPERATURE AT THE TOUCH
OF YOUR FINGERTIPS.
YOU CAN GO UP 10 DEGREES,
20 DEGREES, 30 DEGREES.
IN A MATTER OF SECONDS,
YOU'RE AT THAT TEMPERATURE.
IT'S GOING TO BE PERFECT
EVERY TIME.
>> NOW WE'D LIKE TO TALK ABOUT
THE PERFECT TEMPERATURE
TO FRY CHICKEN.
NOW, UP TO NOW WE'VE BEEN
TALKING ABOUT WHAT YOU CAN DO
WHEN YOU HAVE PRECISE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL ON LOW
TEMPERATURES, LIKE WITH
CHOCOLATE, RIGHT?
LOOK AT THAT, JENNY.
THAT'S BEEN IN THERE FOR HOURS,
IT'S STILL NOT STICKING,
IT'S STILL THE PERFECT,
PERFECT CREAMY TEXTURE.
>> DID YOU TASTE IT?
>> I KNOW, IT'S ALMOST
UNBELIEVABLE, ISN'T IT?
>> DELICIOUS.
OH, AND THEN WE WENT TO
HIGH-TEMPERATURE SEARING.
SO WITH THE PUSH OF A BUTTON,
WE GOT THIS TO 575 DEGREES,
SEARED THE STEAKS, THEN WE
BROUGHT IT DOWN TO 350 AND WE
HAVE BEAUTIFUL GRILLED SAUSAGES,
PORK CHOPS, SALMON, EVEN THOSE
GRILLED VEGETABLES-- THEY WERE
GOOD TOO.
>> WELL, FRYING TEMPERATURE IS
375 DEGREES, ESPECIALLY WHEN
YOU'RE USING VEGETABLE OIL.
WE WANT TO HOLD THAT PERFECT
TEMPERATURE, SO LOOKIT HERE.
WE HAVE A PROBE IN HERE, WE SET
THIS TO 375 DEGREES.
IT SAYS 375 DEGREES.
OUR CHICKEN IS FRYING GENTLY,
IT'S NOT GOING TO BURN.
>> HERE ON MY BURNER-- IT'S A
TYPICAL ELECTRIC COIL
UNDER HERE...
>> I CAN SEE JENNY'S BEEN
COOKING OVER HERE.
>> THIS IS WHAT HAPPENS.
IT'S NOT SAFE.
AND NOT ONLY IS IT NOT SAFE,
I HAVE NO IDEA WHAT THE
TEMPERATURE IS--
I'M JUST GUESSING.
>> WHEN YOU GET THAT REALLY GOOD
FRIED CHICKEN AT ONE OF THOSE
FAST FOOD CHICKEN PLACES,
IT'S BECAUSE THEY HAVE A VERY
EXPENSIVE DEEP FRYER,
THEY'VE SET IT AT 375 DEGREES,
THEY CAN USE THAT OIL ALL DAY
LONG WITHOUT IT BURNING.
WELL, NOW YOU HAVE THAT PRECISE
CONTROL AT HOME WITH THE
PRECISION INDUCTION COOKER.
LET ME GIVE YOU AN EXAMPLE.
IN THE TEST KITCHEN, WE COOKED
OVER 200 PIECES OF CHICKEN,
AND THIS IS WHAT THE OIL
LOOKED LIKE. >> IT LOOKS LIKE
IT JUST CAME OUT OF THE BOTTLE.
>> AND THIS IS BREADED
CHICKEN, RIGHT?
HERE WE COOKED JUST 20 PIECES OF
CHICKEN ON A GAS STOVE,
SAME RESULTS WOULD HAVE BEEN ON
AN ELECTRIC STOVE-- YOU'D GUESS.
YOU SET IT SOMEPLACE BETWEEN
MEDIUM AND MEDIUM-HIGH,
YOU DON'T KNOW.
THE MINUTE IT SMOKES, IT'S GONE,
IT'S RUINED.
THAT'S TYPICALLY WHAT HAPPENS.
YOU HAVE TO THROW THE OIL AWAY.
>> YEAH.
WELL, THAT GETS EXPENSIVE.
>> Announcer: THIRD-PARTY
ANALYSIS SHOWS THE ADVANTAGE
OF NUWAVE'S PRECISE TEMPERATURE
CONTROL VERSUS CONVENTIONAL
STOVE TOPS.
OIL COOKED WITH AN ELECTRIC
STOVE CONTAINED 45% MORE
SATURATED FAT.
OIL COOKED WITH A GAS STOVE
CONTAINED 10 TIMES MORE
TRANSFATTY ACIDS.
OIL COOKED WITH AN ELECTRIC
STOVE CONTAINED OVER 90% MORE
CHOLESTEROL THAN OIL COOKED WITH
THE PRECISION INDUCTION COOKTOP.
NOW SOME OF YOUR FAVORITE FOODS
CAN BE HEALTHIER WITH THE NUWAVE
PRECISION INDUCTION COOKTOP.
>> WHEN YOU'RE COOKING WITH
FRYING FOODS, YOU'RE, UM,
YOU'RE TRYING TO KEEP THAT
TEMPERATURE HIGH SO THE GREASE
DOESN'T GET IN THE FOOD,
WHERE YOU'RE NOT ENDING UP WITH
GREASY CHICKEN OR GREASY FISH.
AND WITH THE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP, I WAS ABLE TO MASTER
FRYING THAT CHICKEN PERFECTLY.
>> Announcer: THE NUWAVE P.I.C.
HAS BEEN TESTED AND RECOMMENDED
BY THE COOKING CLUB OF AMERICA
AND IS THE SAFEST COOKTOP
EVER INVENTED.
DID YOU KNOW THAT EVERY 85
SECONDS, A FIRE STRIKES A HOME
IN AMERICA?
AND MOST OFTEN, THAT FIRE STARTS
IN THE KITCHEN.
>> MY VERY, VERY FIRST FIRE WAS
A 16-YEAR-OLD KID WHO WAS
COOKING FRENCH FRIES ON
THE STOVE AND HE FORGOT ABOUT
THEM AND HE BURNED HIS PARENTS'
ENTIRE HOUSE DOWN.
>> Announcer: WELL, THAT WILL
NEVER HAPPEN WITH THE NUWAVE
P.I.C.
THERE IS NO OPEN FLAME,
NO RED-HOT ELECTRIC COIL TO
CATCH FIRE AND AS SOON AS A POT
IS REMOVED FROM THE NUWAVE,
THE CONDUCTION OF HEAT STOPS.
>> THE SAFETY FEATURES OF THE
P.I.C. IMPRESSED ME SO MUCH
THAT I'M GOING TO SEND ONE
TO MY MOTHER.
SHE'S GETTING A BIT ELDERLY AND
FORGETFUL AND I'M ALWAYS A BIT
WORRIED THAT SHE MIGHT START
A FIRE AND THE P.I.C.'S GOING
TO ELIMINATE THAT PROBLEM.
IT'S A GREAT THING FOR THE
ELDERLY TO HAVE AND IT'S GOING
TO BE A NICE PRESENT.
>> DURING OUR SHOW, WE'VE SHOWED
YOU WHAT A DIFFERENCE THE NUWAVE
PRECISION INDUCTION COOKTOP CAN
MAKE IN YOUR COOKING.
WHETHER YOU'RE COOKING BREAKFAST
OR SNACKS.
>> LUNCH, DINNER,
HORS D'OEUVRES.
>> WHETHER YOU'RE GRILLING OR
GRIDDLING, WHEN YOU HAVE PRECISE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL, IT CAN MAKE
ALL THE DIFFERENCE.
>> WHETHER YOU'RE SEARING AT
HIGH TEMPERATURES...
>> OR WHETHER YOU'RE HAVING
PRECISE TEMPERATURE CONTROL AT
ONLY 110 OR 20 DEGREES FOR
PERFECT CHOCOLATE,
YOU HAVE GOT IT.
IN 10 DEGREES INTERVALS YOU CAN
GO FROM 120 TO 130 TO 140, ALL
THE WAY UP TO 575 DEGREES,
WHICH YOU CAN NEVER GET WITH
YOUR STOVETOP-- YOU'RE ALWAYS
JUST GUESSING.
SO TO SUM IT UP,
WHAT DO YOU GET WITH THE
NUWAVE PRECISION COOKTOP?
YOU GET, FIRST OF ALL, SPEED--
IT HEATS UP REALLY FAST.
>> AND SAFETY.
THERE'S NO RED-HOT COIL
OR OPEN FLAME.
>> AND YOU GET PRECISE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL THAT YOU CAN
NEVER GET WITH YOUR OLD ELECTRIC
BURNER OR GAS STOVE.
AND YOU SAVE... >> Both: MONEY.
>> SO, HERE'S HOW YOU CAN GET
YOUR NUWAVE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP RIGHT NOW.
>> Announcer: INTRODUCING
THE REVOLUTIONARY PRECISION
INDUCTION COOKTOP FROM NUWAVE,
THE LEADER IN PORTABLE
INDUCTION COOKING TECHNOLOGY.
THE NUWAVE HEATS UP TWICE AS
FAST, USES UP TO 70% LESS ENERGY
AND IS SAFER THAN ANY COOKTOP.
BEST OF ALL, THE NUWAVE
IS THE ONLY PORTABLE COOKTOP
THAT GIVES YOU PRECISE
TEMPERATURE CONTROL WITH THE
SIMPLE PRESS OF A BUTTON.
INDUCTION COOKING CAN COST
THOUSANDS OF DOLLARS, BUT THE
NUWAVE PRECISION INDUCTION
COOKTOP IS A BARGAIN AT JUST
FOUR EASY PAYMENTS OF
ONLY $33.33.
YOUR NUWAVE COMES WITH THE
QUICK START GUIDE, GOURMET DVD
AND THE NUWAVE RECIPE BOOK
GIVING YOU THE PRECISE
TEMPERATURE SETTINGS TO MAKE
ALL YOUR FAVORITE MEALS COME
OUT PERFECT EVERY TIME.
AND GET THIS: WHEN YOU CALL NOW
AND ORDER DIRECT, WE'LL DROP
A PAYMENT!
YOU PAY ONLY THREE PAYMENTS
OF $33.33.
THAT'S A 25% SAVINGS.
BUT WE'RE NOT DONE.
YOU ALSO GET THE NUWAVE
STAINLESS STEEL 3-1/2 QUART
POT WITH PREMIUM TEMPERED
GLASS LID.
ALONE, IT'S WORTH MORE THAN
$100, BUT CALL TODAY AND IT'S
YOURS FREE.
PLUS WE'LL ALSO INCLUDE THIS
STAINLESS STEEL STEAMER BASKET.
WAIT, THERE'S MORE GOOD NEWS.
WE'LL ALSO SEND YOU THE
NUWAVE PERFECT GREEN NON-STICK
COOKWARE SET, INCLUDING A
NINE-INCH OMELET PAN, PLUS A
10-1/2-INCH SAUCE PAN THAT CAN
BE USED WITH YOUR GLASS LID TOO.
WE'LL ALSO SEND YOU THE
NINE-PIECE DELUXE FONDUE KIT,
PERFECT FOR MAKING YOUR
FAVORITE FONDUES.
HOLD ON.
ARE YOU READY FOR
AN AMAZING DEAL?
ACT NOW AND WE'LL SEND YOU
A SECOND NUWAVE P.I.C.
ABSOLUTELY FREE!
YOU'LL GET A FREE NUWAVE WITH
ALL THE FREE BONUSES-- ALL YOU
PAY IS THE S&P FOR EACH SET.
KEEP IT FOR YOURSELF OR SEND IT
AS AN UNFORGETTABLE GIFT
FROM YOU.
THIS BUY ONE, GET ONE FREE
SPECIAL PROMOTION
WON'T LAST LONG.
AND LISTEN TO THIS: WE'LL LET
YOU TRY THE NUWAVE P.I.C.
RISK-FREE, NOT FOR 30 DAYS,
NOT FOR 60 DAYS, BUT 90 DAYS.
IF YOU'RE NOT HAPPY, RETURN
THEM, BUT KEEP BOTH SETS OF
BONUS COOKWARE AS YOUR
FREE GIFTS.
ALL YOU PAY IS THE SHIPPING AND
PROCESSING FOR EACH OF THEM.
THIS SPECIAL TELEVISION OFFER,
WORTH OVER $600, IS NOT
AVAILABLE AT STORES AND WON'T
LAST LONG, SO ACT FAST.
DON'T FORGET TO ASK ABOUT
SPECIAL SAVINGS ON THE NUWAVE
CAST-IRON BARBECUE GRILL AND
GRIDDLE, THE 10-PIECE PERFECT
GREEN COOKWARE SET, THE NUWAVE
PRESSURE COOKER, PLUS THE
COMPLETE LINE OF NUWAVE OVENS.
CALL OR GO ONLINE NOW.
[♪...]
>> Woman: THIS HAS BEEN A PAID
PRESENTATION FOR THE NUWAVE
PRECISION INDUCTION COOKTOP.
♪
>> NOW A PAID PRESENTATION
FOR MEANINGFUL BEAUTY ADVANCED
BY CINDY CRAWFORD.
>> WITH SPECIAL APPEARANCES
BY DEBRA MESSING.
>> VALERIE BERTINELLI.
>> CHRISTA MILLER.
>> AND STARS FROM TV'S NCIS.
>> ROYAL PAINS.
>> AND THE MENTALIST.
>> HOSTED BY NETWORK TV
CORRESPONDENT, KATRINA SZISH.
>> BROUGHT TO YOU
BY GUTHY RENKER.
>> HI, EVERYONE,
I'M BEAUTY AND STYLE
JOURNALIST, KATRINA SZISH
ON LOCATION IN BEVERLY HILLS.
IN JUST A FEW MINUTES
WE'LL MEET ONE OF THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL WOMEN IN THE WORLD,
SUPER MODEL, CINDY CRAWFORD.
AT AGE 45, CINDY STILL LOOKS
IMPOSSIBLY YOUNG AND GORGEOUS.
>> OH, MY GOSH,