INVESTIGATION.
>> THE DETECTIVES WILL CERTAINLY
ANALYZE EVERYTHING AND PUT A
COMPLETE PICTURE TOGETHER.
>> OFFICIALS SAY THEY RECOVERED
VERY GOOD EVIDENCE THAT MAY
PROVIDE ANSWERS ABOUT WHAT
TRIGGERED THE CHAIN OF EVENTS.
>> WHEN 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA
SHOT TO DEATH HIS MOTHER, NANCY,
IN THEIR HOME, AND THEN HEADED
TO THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL,
WEARING A BULLETPROOF VEST AND
ARMED WITH WEAPONS LIKE THESE,
HIGH-POWERED PISTOLS AND A
SEMI-AUTOMATIC SULT RIFLE.
>> I THOUGHT WE WOULD ALL DAY.
>> THE MEDICAL CAPPER COMPLETED
THE TASK OF IDENTIFYING ALL THE
VICTIMS, INCLUDING 27-YEAR-OLD
HERO TEACHER, VICTORIA SOTO, WHO
THREW HERSELF IN FRONT OF THE
GUNMAN TO SHIELD HER STUNTS, AND
THE PRINCIPAL, DAWN HOCHSPRUNG,
WHO TRIED TO STOP THE SHOOTER
AND PAID WITH HER LIFE.
EMILY PARKER WAS REMEMBERED BY
HER FATHER.
>> WE WANT EVERYBODY TO KNOW --
THIS INCLUDES THE FAMILY OF THE
SHOOTER.
REPORTER: WE KNOW THAT ALL OF
THE CHIRP WHO LOST THEIR LIVES
WERE JUST SIX OR SEVEN YEARS
OLD.
ALL FIRST-GRADERS, JUST BARELY
BEGINNING THEIR LIVES.
>> Ama: 27-YEAR-OLD VICKY SOTO
WAS A SUBSTITUTE TEACHER.
FAMILY MEMBERS SAY THEY SPENT
AGONIZE HOURS AFTER THE SHOOTING
WONDERING WHAT HAPPENED TO HER.
>> AT THAT POINT WAS THE HARDEST
FOR THE WHOLE FAMILY, THE
WAITING GAME, TO RECEIVE WORD ON
WHAT HAPPENED TO VICKI'S CLASS.
>> VICKI HAD HER STUDENTS HIDE
BEHIND HER IN A CLOSET,
PROTECTING THEM FROM THE GUNMAN
WHEN SHE WAS SHOT AND KILLED.
>>> OTHER VICTIMS INCLUDE
30-YEAR-OLD LAUREN REDUCE SAW, A
TEACHER, MARY SHER SHERLACH WAS
THE EXCUSE ME EXPOIRN TOAD TO
STOP THE KILLER, AND NANCY
LANZA, THE MOTHER OF THE KILLER,
WAS KILLED EARLIER IN THE DAY.
VICKI SEW TOTAL WILL NEVER BE
FORGOTTEN BY ONE OF HER STUDENTS
WHO DOESN'T KNOW HER FATE RIGHT
NOW.
>> WE ARE HOPING SHE IS GOING TO
BE OKAY.
HE REALLY -- SHE REALLY LOVED
THAT CLASS, AND HE KEEPS SAYING
I REALLY HOPE SHE IS OKAY.
I HOPE IT'S NOT HER.
HE KNOWS SHE HAS BEEN HURT BUT
DOESN'T KNOW THE END RESULT.
>> THEY'RE ONE OF THE LUCKY
FAMILIES.
BOTH THEIR CHILDREN ATTEND THE
SCHOOL AND BOTH SURVIVE.
>> THE FATHER OF THE GUNMAN
RELEASED A STATEMENT SAYING HIS
FAMILY IS GRIEVING ALONG WITH
ALL OF THOSE WHO HAVE BEEN
AFFECTED BY THIS ENORMOUS
TRAGEDY.
PETER LANZA SAYS NO WORDS CAN
TRULY EXPECT HOW HEARTBROKEN WE
ARE.
THE CONNECTICUT TRAGEDY HAS
TOUCHED A NERVE ACROSS THE
COUNTRY AND, VIGILS ARE
SPRINGING UP EVERYWHERE IN
ALAMEDA, A VIGIL WAS HELD AT AN
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
ONE OF SHE PEEKERS HAS TWO
COUSINS WHO ATTEND SANDY HOOK.
BOTH SIR INDIVIDUAL.
>>> IN SAN FRANCISCO, CITY
SUPERVISOR ORGANIZED A VIGIL.
THIS WAS AT THE CORN ORE OF
SILVER AVENUE AND MISSION
STREET.
SPEAKERS TALKED ABOUT WORKING
TOGETHER TO BRING PEACE AND THE
IMPORTANCE OF ADDRESSING THE
ISSUE OF PEOPLE WITH MENTAL
HEALTH NEEDS.
>>> WE ARE LIVE TONIGHT AT GRACE
CATHEDRAL WHERE A SPECIAL
SERVICE IS BEING HELD TO
REMEMBER THE VICTIMS.
CORNELL?
>> FOR DECADES, HOLIDAY CONCERTS
HAVE BEEN A TRADITION HERE AT
GRACE CATHEDRAL ON KNOB HULL BUT
TONIGHT SOMETHING DIFFERENT,
PAUSING TO REMEMBER THE SHOOTING
VICTIMS IN CONNECTICUT.
♪.
REPORTER: THE CATHEDRAL'S CHOIR
MASTER WAS SO MOVED BY THE
TRAGEDY HE WROTE A SPECIAL
ARRANGEMENTS OF SILENT NIGHT FOR
TODAY'S CONCERT, A MOVING
TRIBUTE TO LIVES LOST.
THE BISHOP SAYS NOW I THE TIME
TO REFLECT YEAR.
>> WE GATHER AS THINGS ARE
SHADOWY AND GLOOMY AND DARK AND
TRY TO LIFT THE SPIRITS OF
PEOPLE.
YOU ALSO HAVE TO SAY SOMETHING.
YOU CAN'T JUST SMILE, YOU CAN'T
JUST SING GOOD HAPPY SONGS AT
CHRISTMAS AND NOT ACKNOWLEDGE
THE HEARTBREAK OF CHRISTMAS AS
WELL.
>> BISHOP ANDREWS SPOKE WITH
CONNECTICUT'S BISHOP TODAY WHO
WAS OFFERING COMFORT TO GRIEVING
FAMILIES IN NEWTOWN, BISHOP
ANDREWS OFFERED HIS SPOWR FROM
SAN FRANCISCO.
OTHER MEMORIALS ARE HAPPENING
ACROSS THE CITY AND ACROSS THE
BAY AREA.
WE'LL HAVE THOSE FOR YOU LIVE AT
11:00.
>> Ama: YOU CAN EXPRESS YOUR
SYMPATHY BY POSTING THIS BADGE
TO YOUR FACEBOOK WALL.
A SILENT SHOW OF SUPPORT FOR
EVERYONE IN CONNECTICUT.
AS THE TRAGEDY UNFOLDS, STAY
WITH US FOR CONTINUING COVERAGE.
LAURA ANTHONY WILL HAVE LIVE
REPORTS FROM CONNECTICUT
BEGINNING TOMORROW AND YOU CAN
GET UPDATES ANYTIME AT
ABC7NEWS.COM.
>>> WE DO HAVE BREAKING NEWS OUT
OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA.
POLICE HAVE ONE PERSON IN
CUSTODY AFTER REPORTS OF SHOTS
FIRED AT THE UPSCALE FASHION
ISLAND MALL IN NEWPORT BEACH,
WITNESSES REPORT THEY HEARD A
GUNSHOT IN THE MACY'S PARKING
LOT.
THERE ARE NO REPORTS OF
INJURIES.
>>> IT HAS BEEN A SOGGY
SATURDAY.
AND TAKE A LOOK AT THIS VIDEO
SHOT A SHORT TIME AGO AS THE
RAIN CAME DOWN IN SAN FRANCISCO.
YOU CAN SEE PEOPLE WITH THEIR
UMBRELLAS HURRYING THROUGH THE
RAIN.
LET'S HEAD RIGHT TO LEIGH GLASER
WITH A CHECK ON THE WEATHER.
>> Leigh: IT HAS BEEN WET,
ESPECIALLY THE NORTH BAY AND
DOWNRIGHT COLD.
HIGHS IN THE UPPER 40s.
HERE'S A LIVE LOOK FROM LIVE
DOPPLER 7HDY YOU CAN SEE THE
MOISTURE STARTING TO EVAPORATE.
WE HAD SOME EARLIER MODERATE
RAIN IN THE NORTH BAY, BUT YOU
CAN SEE AS THIS COLD FRONT
SLIDES SOUTH, THINGS JUST START
TO FALL APART A LITTLE BIT.
PETALUMA, A LITTLE LIGHT RAIN.
SOME IN HAYWARD, FREMONT, AND
MODERATE RAIN BETWEEN MORGAN
HILL AND GILROY.
THIS SYSTEM MOVES OUT BUT WE
HAVE A SERIES OF STORMS BACKED
UP IN THE PACIFIC.
WE'LL LOOK AT THE TIMING OF
THOSE COMING UP.
>> Ama: STILL TO COME, GETTING
GUNSES OFF THE STREET.
HUNDREDS TURN OUT FOR A BAY AREA
GUN BUYBACK PROGRAM.
>>> A MESS AFTER A DEADLY
ACCIDENT ON A BAY AREA ROAD.
WE'LL TELL YOU HOW TRAFFIC IS
MOVING TONIGHT.
>>> A DIFFERENT KIND OF MESS ON
HIGHWAY 1.
WHY A CLOSED HIGHWAY COULD STAY
CLOSED
>> Ama: ONE PERSON IS DEAD AFTER
A MULTIVEHICLE CRASH IN SOUTH
FRAN SEASONS ON SOUTHBOUND 280.
THE ROAD HAS BEEN CLEARED AND
TRAFFIC IS MOVING IN THE AREA
AGAIN TONIGHT.
NO WORD ON THE CAUSE OF THE
ACCIDENT.
>>> NEW DETAILS TONIGHT ON A
FATAL ACCIDENT INVOLVING AN
OFF-DUTY CHP OFFICER.
HAPPENED LAST NIGHT ON HIGHWAY
12 IN FAIRFIELD.
THE OFFICER JUST FINISHED HIS
SHIFT AND WAS LEAVING WORK WHEN
HE PIT A PICKUP TURNING LEFT IN
FRONT OF HIM.
THE CHP HAD NOT RELEASED THE
OFFICER'S NAME.
>>> A SECTION OF HIGHWAY 1
THROUGH SONOMA COUNTY WILL
REMAIN CLOSED INDEFINITELY.
THE HIGHWAY -- A SMALL SECTION
OF THE ROAD COLLAPSED THIS MONTH
WHEN STORMS HILT THE AREA.
CALTRANS HOPES TO HAVE THE ROAD
OPEN BY NOON TOP.
OFFICIALS INITIALLY HOPED TO
OPEN THE HIGHWAY THIS WEEK BUT
ENGINEERS DETERMINED THE WORK
WILL TAKE LONGER THAN EXPECTED.
>> JUST AHEAD, HUNDREDS OF GUNS
NOW OFF THE STREET IN THE BAY
AREA.
HOW AN ANONYMOUS DONOR IS MAKING
A DIFFERENCE.
>> A WET SATURDAY.
WHAT'S AHEAD FOR TOMORROW?
LEIGH GLASER IS UP NEXT WITH THE
FORECAST.
>> Mike: THE WARRIORS ARE ON
FIRE.
I'M MIKE SHUMANN.
A SEVEN-DAY SWING ENDING IN TWO
DAYS, AND WITH THE WIN THE
WARRIORS COME HOME WITH A RECORD
OF 6-1 FOR THE FIRST TIME
You know how much Grandma
wanted to be here
for your fist Christmas?
You see
Grandma lives waaaay down here,
and you live way up here.
Brian, your cousin, he's
a little bit older than you,
he lives here, in Chicago.
And your Aunt Lisa lives here,
in Baltimore.
Uncle Earnie?
Waaay out in Hawaii.
But don't you worry,
we will always be together
for Christmas.
[ Male Announcer ]
Being together
is the best part
of the holidays
and Cheerios is happy
to be part of the family.
You just ate Dallas!
>> Ama: A PREVIOUSLY SCHEDULED
GUN BUYBACK PROGRAM FOR OAKLAND
AND SAN FRANCISCO GOT A BOOST
TODAY.
HUNDREDS OF GUNS WERE BOUGHT BY
THE OAKLAND AND SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
THEM TO MASS ROMAN HAS THE
STORY.
>> I JUST DECIDED TO GET RID OF
THE GUNS.
>> MICHELLE, WHO DID NOT WANT TO
GIVE HER LAST NAME, WAS ONE OF
MORE THAN 200 PEOPLE SELLING
THEIR GUNS TO THE POLICE.
MANY WHO WAITED IN THIS LONG
LINE WERE BROUGHT HERE BY THE
SAME TRAGEDY.
THE MASS MURDER OF 27 CHILDREN
IN CONNECTICUT.
>> IT HIT ME STRONG.
I NEVER THOUGHT ABOUT GETTING
RID OF THEM BEFORE.
>> DANA IS A VIETNAM VET AND
SAYS HE AND HIS WIFE SOBBED
WHILE WATCHING THE NEWS.
JAN WAS TURNING IN HER GUN SO IT
COULD NEVER BE USED TO TAKE A
LIFE.
>> THIS IS SOMETHING THAT MIGHT
HURT SOMEBODY SOME DAY.
THEN I WOULD FEEL TERRIBLE ABOUT
THAT.
REPORTER: THE GUN BUYBACK WAS
FUNDED BY AN ANONYMOUS DOOR NOR
WHO CONTACTED THE YOUTH PROGRAM,
WHO CONTACTED THE BOYS C CLUB IN
SAN FRANCISCO.
THE TURNOUT SHOWS BOTH
COMMUNITIES CARE ABOUT GUN
VIOLENCE.
>> WHEN A COMMUNITY SAYS ENOUGH
IS ENOUGH, YOU GOT A GOOD
CHANCE.
>> IN OAKLAND, PEOPLE LINED UP
IN DOORS TURN IN GUNS OUT
ST. BENEDICT'S CHURCH.
THIS IS WHERE THE OAKLAND POLICE
WERE BUYING THE GUNS.
>> EVERY ANTICIPATION WILL'LL BE
EXCEED OUR WILDEST EXPECTATION.
>> THE INITIAL TARGET WAS 3500
GUNS.
A FINANCIAL INCENTIVE HELPED
BRING THESE PEOPLE OUT.
>> WELL, THE MONEY.
>> MONEY.
MONEY.
>> $200 WAS PAID FOR EACH
HANDGUN OR RIFLE.
A LIMIT OF THREE WEAPONS FOR
EACH RESIDENT.
AND PEOPLE HAD TO PROVE THEY
RESIDED IN THE CITY BUYING THE
GUNS.
>> OAKLAND AND SAN FRANCISCO
POLICE DEPARTMENTS ARE GOING TO
BE ASKING THE GOVERNOR TO SEE IF
HE CAN MAKE THIS KIND OF GUN
BUYBACK A STATE PROGRAM.
IN SAN FRANCISCO, TOMAS ROMAN,
ABC-7 NEWS.
>> Ama: THOUSANDS OF NURSES WILL
BE WALKING OFF THE JOB ON
CHRISTMAS EVE, SPOKESMAN SAYS
RNs FROM NINE BAY AREA
HOSPITALS OPERATED BY BETTER
HEALTH AND THE HOSPITAL
CORPORATION OF AMERICA.
THE STRIKE IS THE EIGHT SINCE
LAST SEPTEMBER OVER CONTRACT
ISSUES.
>> SOME SPRINKLES AROUND THE BAY
TODAY.
>> Leigh: GLOOMY, COLD,
MT. HAMILTON, TRACE AMOUNTS OF
SNOW, AND WE'RE CAUGHT IN A COLD
AIR SCENARIO.
THE COLD IRIS TRAPPED CLOSE TO
THE SURFACE, AND I WAS COLD
TODAY WITH THE RAIN COMING
THROUGH AS WELL.
HIGH DEFINITION EAST BAY CAM
RIGHT NOW, LOOKING TOWARDS THE
WEST.
KIND OF MERCKY TOWARDS SAN
FRANCISCO AS WELL.
TRYING TO DEAL WITH LOW CLOUDS
AND ALSO FOG MOVING IN.
FOLKS, HERE'S A LOOK AT LIVE
DOPPLER 7HD.
YOU CAN SEE THAT MUCH OF WHAT IS
FALLING SOUTH OF SAN JOSE ON THE
LIGHT SIDE.
EARLIER TODAY AS THIS VERY WEAK
FRONTAL SYSTEM HIT THE COAST,
BROUGHT THE NORTH BAY A QUARTER
INCH OF RAIN, AND THEN AS IT
PUSHED SOUTH, JUST KIND OF
STARTED TO DISSIPATE.
DISINTEGRATE.
RIGHT NOW WE'LL TAKE YOU OVER TO
MILPITAS WHERE WE'RE PICKING UP
LIGHT RAIN.
AND SAN JOSE, SUNNY VAIL, FROM
WHAT -- IN YOUR NEIGHBORHOOD AND
MODERATE RAIN MOVING TO THE
EAST, GILROY, HOLLISTER, WET
PAVEMENT, SOME MORE SHOWERS
STARTING TO MOVE INTO THE AREA.
SO SCATTERS SHOWERS OVERNIGHT,
AND WHERE SOME OF THOSE LOW SNOW
LEVELS, HIGHER PEAKS, MAY SEE
MORE THAN A LIGHT DUSTING OF
SNOW BY EARLY TOMORROW MORNING.
COLD TODAY.
CURRENT READINGS MID-TO-UPPER
40s ACROSS MUCH OF THE BAY
AREA, AND A FORECAST, COLD
SHOWERS OVERNIGHT, AND SNOW
POSSIBLE IN THE HIGHER PEAKS.
WE GATE WINDOW OF CLEARING
TOMORROW BEFORE ANOTHER COLD
FRONT MOVES IN TO BRING US MORE
RAIN.
SUNDAY NIGHT INTO EARLY MONDAY
MORNING, HERE'S THE LOWS.
NORTH BAY IN THE 30s.
UP TOWARDS LAKE-ON COUNTY,
EXPECT SNOW AT THE HIGHER PEAKS,
SAN FRANCISCO, 46 AND 42
EXPECTED LOW FOR SAN JOSE.
HERE'S A LOOK AT THE COLD FRONT.
HITS THE COAST AND FALLS APART
BUT WILL CONTINUE TO BRING US
SOME SCATTERED SHOWERS
OVERNIGHT, AND A FEW SNOW FLAKES
AT HIGHER PEAKS.
OVERNIGHT, BY 10:00 WE SHOULD
SEE SOME OF THIS THIN OUT.
WE GROL WITH TOUCH-AND-GO
SCATTERED SHOWERS THROUGHOUT THE
COURSE OF THE DAY, ON SUNDAY,
AND THEN BY SUNDAY NIGHT,
ANOTHER BATCH OF SHOWERS START
TO DEVELOP WELL THE NORTH OF THE
BAY AREA, THIS ILLS 9:00 SIZ
NIGHT AND THIS IS GOING TO BRING
US RAINs NIGHT, AND THROUGHOUT
THE MORNING HOURS ON MONDAY.
REAL QUICKLY.
WINTER ADVISORY UP FOR THE LAKE
COUNTY AREA UNTIL 4:00 A.M.
TOMORROW.
TWO TO FOUR INCHES-HIGHER EL --
ELEVATION OVERNIGHT.
HIGHS FOR SUNDAY, CHILLY,
MID-TO-LOW 50s.
WE'LL KEEP CHANCE OF SCATTERED
SHOWERS ACROSS THE BAY AREA FOR
YOUR SUNDAY AFTERNOON.
THEN WE GATE SLIGHT BREAK
TOMORROW AND THEN WE'LL BRING IN
ANOTHER BATCH OF RAIN, OVERNIGHT
SUNDAY NIGHT, AND THOUGHT THE
THE D THROUGHOUT THE DAY ON
MONDAY, AND A MUCH LARGER STORM
SYSTEM WILL HIT US THURSDAY
NIGHT AND FRIDAY.
PERIODS OF HEAVY RAIN AND GUSTY
WINDS.
>> Ama: THANK YOU SO MUCH.
MIKE SHUMANN IS HERE WITH
SPORTS, AND THE ROAD IS KIND TO
THE WARRIORS.
>> Mike: DON'T WANT TO COME
HOME.
THE WARRIORS SEVEN-GAME, 11-DAY
ROAD TRIP ENDED TODAY IN
ATLANTA.
THEY'D WON FIVE STRAIGHT,
KNOCKING OFF THE MIAMI HEAT, BUT
ORLANDO HASN'T THEM THEIR FIRST
LOSS.
WARRIORS OFF TO BEST STAR SINCE
THE 1991-1992 SEASON.
ROCKIE BARNES, 19 IN THE GAME.
LANDRY, SOLID OFF THE BENCH.
THE ONE-HANDED JAM.
HE HAD 19.
62-49 WARRIORS AT THE HALF.
EVERYONE ON THE WARRIORS GETTING
IN THE HIGHLIGHTS.
DAVID LEE, 20 POINTS, 11 BOARDS,
AVERAGING 20 AND 10 EVERY GAME
ON THIS TRIP.
PLAYING WELL.
STEPH CURRY.
THE STEAL HERE AND THE SLAM.
18 POINTS FOR STEPH.
WARRIORS 6-1 ON THE ROAD FOR THE
FIRST TIME IN FRANCE
CHARACTERIZE HISTORY.
115-93 YOUR FINAL.
>>> NOW TO COLLEGE HOOPS.
STANFORD MEN FACING UC DAVIS IN
A NONCONFERENCE MATCHUP AFTER
EXAMS.
FIRST GAME IN 13 DAYS FOR THE
CARDINAL.
THE ONLY AGGIE PLAYER TO SHOW
UP.
HE HAD 23 OF THE TEAM'S 52.
ONLY TWO DAVIS PLAYERS HIT
DOUBLE DIGITS.
HUESTIS, THE JUMPER AND THE
FOUL.
CARDINAL UP AT THE HALF.
DWIGHT PAUL LED ALL CARDINAL
WITH 20.
THE MONSTER JAM, CARDINAL
IMPROVE 2073-WITH THE 75-52
VICTORY.
>> OUR DEFENSE AND OFFENSE RIGHT
NOW AND I BELIEVE IN OUR GUYS, I
KNOW WE HAVE GOOD SHOOTERS.
WE KEEP DEFENDING LIKE WE ARE
NOW, I'LL TAKE IT.
THE WAY WE'RE DEFENDING, GIVES
OURSELVES A CHANCE TO WIN
AGAINST EVERYBODY, EVERY NIGHT.
IF WE STAY CONFIDENT AND BELIEVE
IN OURSELVES WE'RE GOING TO
SHOOT THE BALL WELL.
>> Mike: HE TOP RANKED INDIANA
AND BUTLER.
HOOSIERS DOWN THREE.
TEN TO PLAY.
DURRELL DRAINS THE THREE.
WE GO TO OVERTIME BUT THE
BULLDOGS HAD IDEAS.
ALEX BARLOW, SIX POINTS BUT GETS
IT TO GO WITH TWO SECONDS
REMAINING.
INDIANA'S FIRST LOSS OF THE
SEASON, BUTLER, 88-86 THE FINAL.
>> COLLEGE FOOTBALL BOWL SEASON
KICKED OFF IN ALBUQUERQUE,
ARIZONA AND NEVADA IN THE NEW
MEXICO BOWL.
FIRST OF 35 BOWL GAMES IN THE
NEXT 22 DAYS.
THIRD QUARTER, THE NEVADA
QUARTERBACK FAKES.
WOLFPACK UP 10.
ARIZONA BACK IN THE FOURTH.
46 SECONDS TO PLAY.
SCOTT, QUICK PASS, 4842 EVIDENCE
IN DAMP.
ENSUING KICKOFF, WILDCATS ONSIDE
KICK.
THEY GET IT.
MARCH DOWN THE FIELD AND THROWS
HIS THIRD T.D. OF THE GAME.
THIS ONE TO TERRENCE MILLER.
WILDCATS HOLD OFF NEVADA TO WIN
THEFUL BOWL, 49-48.
PAC-12 IS 1-0 IN BOWL GAMES SO
FAR.
>> UTAH STATE FACING TOLEDO IN
THE IDAHO POTATO BOWL IN BOISE
ON THE SMURF TURF.
THE OPTION.
SEE YA LATER.
62 YARDS, 227 YARDS IN THE AIR.
89 ON THE GROUND.
UTAH STATE WINS THE ALWAYS POP
ALREADY IDAHO POTATO BOWL, 41-15
THE FINAL.
>> DIVISION II CHAMPIONSHIP,
VALDOSTA AND SALEM.
UP THE MIDDLE.
96 YARDS LATER, 7-0 VALDOSTA
BEFORE THEY EVEN SAT DOWN.
STILL IN THE FIRST.
O'NEILL, FOURTH AND ONE.
GOES 4 YARDS, O'NEILL, 141 YARDS
ON 24 CARRIES.
VALDOSTA STATE WINS THEIR THIRD
NATIONAL CHAMPIONSHIP, 35-7 YOUR
FINAL, ENDING THEIR SEASON 12-2.
>> HIGH SCHOOL FOOTBALL, MARIN
CATHOLIC FACING MADISON HIGH
SCHOOL FROM SAN DIEGO NOR THE
CIF CHAMPIONSHIP.
COURT FARTHER, THE QUARTERBACK,
HEADED TO CAL, THROUGH FOUR
T.D.ES ON THE DAY.
TIPPED INTO THE HANDS OF HANLEY,
WILDCATS UP 35-31.
MADDISON ANSWERS.
CORMIER, RAN FOR 272 YARDS.
THIS KID HAS SOME SPEED.
79 YARDS.
MAD DISSIN YOUR CIF DIVISION
III CHAMPIONS WITH A 38-35
VICTORY.
>>> De La SALLE LOOKING FOR
ANOTHER CHAMPIONSHIP GAME.
WE'LL HAVE THE HIGHLIGHTS FOR
YOU AND A PREVIEW OF THE GAME
HOFF THE DAY, 49ers AND
PATRIOTS.
>> Ama: STILL TO COME, A HELPING
HAND FOR THE OHIO.
ONE GROUP IS HELP THING
>> Ama: JOIN ME AT 9:00 ON CABLE
13.
WE'LL FIND OUT WHAT SCIENTISTS
BELIEVE CAUSED THOUSANDS SQUIDS
TO WASH UP THIS WEEK.
THEN AT 11:00, POLICE NAMED THE
SUSPECT WANTED IN THE SHOOTING
IN SAN RAFAEL.
THE SUSPECT AND WHAT HAPPENED
TONIGHT.
AT 9:00 AND 11:00.
>>> THE ACT OF GIVING BACK AND
SHARING THE WEALTH IS VERY MUCH
ALIVE FOR THE HOLIDAYS.
IN SAN FRANCISCO, GLIDE WAS
PACKED WITH PEOPLE TODAY.
EACH ONE RECEIVED A BLANKET
DONATED BY THE BAY AREA'S SIKH
COMMUNITY.
THIS IS THE 16th YEAR THE
GROUP PASSED OUT BLANKETS TO
THOSE IN NEED.
>>> ANOTHER ACT OF GIVING WAS ON
DISPLAY IN OAKLAND ELM THE
ANNUAL HOLIDAY PARTY AND TOY
G.I.WAY AT THE ALLEN TEMPLE
FAMILY LIFE CENTER.
THE CENTER HAD A FREE GIFT FOR
EVERY ONE OF THE 900 KIDS THAT
WERE EXPECTED TO COME THROUGH
THE DOOR.
A GESTURE THAT MAKES A HUGE
DIFFERENCE THIS HOLIDAY SEASON.
>> THAT IS IT FOR US AT 6:00.
I'M AMA DAETZ.
FOR LEIGH GLASER AND MIKE
Captioned by Closed Captioning
Services Inc.
>> Announcer: THE FOLLOWING
PRESENTATION IS PROUDLY BROUGHT
TO YOU BY LIGHT RELIEF.
>> HI, I'M ROBERT WAGNER.
WHEN IT COMES TO PAIN, WHAT DO
WE ALL WANT?
WE WANT A WAY TO GET OUT OF PAIN
THAT'S EASY, FEELS GOOD AND HAS
NO SIDE EFFECTS.
50 MILLION AMERICANS AGREE
BECAUSE THEY SUFFER FROM PAIN
JUST LIKE YOU.
TODAY, THERE'S A THERAPEUTIC
PROVEN FORM OF PAIN RELIEF THAT
MAY BE MORE EFFECTIVE THAN
ANYTHING YOU HAVE EVER TRIED.
IT'S CALLED LIGHT RELIEF.
IT USES LIGHT AND WARMTH
TO SOOTHE AND RELIEVE PAIN.
SOUNDS LIKE SCIENCE FICTION?
WELL, TODAY IT'S SCIENCE FACT.
JOIN ME ON A JOURNEY THAT IS
LIGHT