YOU SEE HOW LATE IT IS ON
DOPPLER RADAR AND BLUES AND FEW
GREENS OUT THERE.
GREEN HEADING THROUGH THE SUNOL
GRADE.
TOWN TOWARD MISSION BOULEVARD.
AS YOU COME ACROSS THE SAN MATEO
BRIDGE YOU WILL RUN IN LIGHT
RAIN AROUND FOSTER CITY
BOULEVARD AND RIDE INTO SAN
MATEO RIGHT NOW.
BEST RADAR RETURNS ARE OVER THE
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS.
AS FAR AS THE RAIN, YOU CAN SEE
IT COMING IN WAVES OF MIST AND
LIGHT RAIN.
AS WE HEAD PAST NOON, ALL OF US
HAVE AN ISOLATED AFTERNOON
SHOWER AT LEAST A CHANCE.
TEMPERATURES IN THE LOW TO MID
50s.
>> EAST SHORE FREEWAY, RICHMOND
ON TO UNIVERSITY AND ONTO ALBANY
AND BERKELEY, SERVICING CROWDED
BUT IT'S FUNNELING INTO BAY
BRIDGE TOLL PLAZA.
TROUBLE SPOT NORTH 101
SUNNYVALE.
TWO LANES BLOCKED.
SLOW TRAFFIC BACKING TOWARDS THE
LAWRENCE EXPRESSWAY.
THE WAZE APP THAT SHOWS THE
NORTHBOUND STANDSTILL ALL THE
WAY BACK TOWARDS THE LAWRENCE
EXPRESSWAY.
THIS IS FREE APP YOU CAN
DOWNLOAD ON APPLE APP STORE OR
GOOGLE PLAY.
>>>.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, PRESIDENT
OBAMA IS BACK AT THE WHITE HOUSE
AFTER VISITING NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
HE WALKED OUT OF MARINE ONE
AFTER DELIVERING AN EMOTIONAL
TRIBUTE TO THE VICTIMS OF THE
TRAGEDY.
HE CALLED ON THE NATION TO
CHANGE SO ANOTHER MASS SHOOTING
LIKE THIS ONE NEVER HAPPENS
AGAIN.
>> OLIVIA, JOSEPHINE.
>> MORE THAN 900 MOURNERS THAT
PACKED THE HIGH SCHOOL HEARD
EMOTIONAL OBAMA ADMIT THE
COUNTRY HAS FAILD HIM.
>> THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME WE
HAVE COME TOGETHER TO COMFORT A
GRIEVING COMMUNITY TORN APART BY
MASS SHOOTING.
>> HE WILL USE THE POWER OF
PRESIDENCY LIKE THE MASSACRE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
TO END THEM WE MUST CHANGE.
>> OUTSIDE AN EMOTIONAL REACTION
FROM THE SHATTERED COMMUNITY TO
THE PRESIDENT'S VISIT.
>> IT WAS VERY TOUCHING, IT DID
MEAN A LOT.
>> WE HAVE SIX KIDS.
THAT IS HOW WE WILL BE JUDGED.
>> NEW AND CHILLING DETAILS
ABOUT ADAM LANZA'S PAST HAVE
EMERGED.
ACCORDING TO THE GOVERNOR THE
RAMPAGE ENDED TEN MINUTES AFTER
IT BEGAN WHEN LANZA WHERE HE
OPENED FIRE HEARD WAILING SIRENS
FROM LAW ENFORCEMENT APPROACHING
AND SHOT HIMSELF ONCE IN THE
HEAD.
>> WE SURMISE IT WAS DURING THE
SECOND CLASSROOM EPISODE THAT HE
HEARD RESPONDERS COMING AND
APPARENTLY DECIDED TO TAKE HIS
OWN LIFE.
>> ALSO THIS MORNING, NEW CLUES
ABOUT THE 20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER.
COMPUTERS AND VIDEOS WERE
REMOVED FROM THE LANZA FAMILY
HOME THAT COULD PROVIDE CLUES
INTO HIS MOTIVE.
FRIENDS OF ADAM LANZA'S MURDERED
MOTHER NANCY BECAME CONCERNED
OVER THE LAST FEW MONTHS ABOUT
HER SON'S BEHAVIORAL ISSUES.
>> I THINK IT WAS DIFFICULT FOR
HER TO TRY TO GET HIM IN REGULAR
LIFE.
>> ALL OF THE SCHOOLS IN THE
AREA ARE CLOSED TODAY.
STUDENTS FROM SANDY HOOK WILL
RESUME CLASSES AT AN UNUSED
SCHOOL IN MATTER OF DAYS.
>>> STAY WITH US FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY
IN CONNECTICUT.
AT 6:15 WE'LL HEAR FROM THE
CLASSMATES OF ADAM LANZA.
COMING UP AT 6:30, A NEW STORY
OF SURVIVAL EMERGING FROM SANDY
HOOK.
AT 7:00 TUNE INTO A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA."
ENTIRE SHOW WILL BE DEVOTED TO
THE TRAGEDY.
REPORTER LAURA ANTHONY IS ALSO
IN CONNECTICUT AND SHE WILL HAVE
LIVE REPORTS.
>>> NOW BACK TO OUR STORM WATCH
COVERAGE.
NEW STORM MOVED INTO THE BAY
AREA OVERNIGHT IN THE SANTA CRUZ
MOUNTAINS ARE GETTING HIT WITH
SHOWERS THIS MORNING.
REPORTER TERRY McSWEENEY JOINS
US LIVE, HOW HEAVY ARE THEY?
>> IT'S PRETTY LIGHT SHOWERS BUT
IT DOESN'T STOP.
IT'S BEEN GOING FOR AT LEAST
THREE HOURS UP HERE, PROBABLY
LONGER THAN THAT.
TAKE A LOOK AT PICTURES, AT THE
SUMMIT GIVE YOU AN IDEA WHAT IS
GOING ON.
YOU CAN SEE SOME CARS AND TRUCKS
GOING THROUGH.
AGAIN, NOTHING HEAVY, BUT IT
JUST DOESN'T QUIT.
NOW WITH THE TRAFFIC GETTING A
LITTLE HEAVIER, PROBABLY A GOOD
TIME TO KEEP THAT IN MIND.
ALSO, IN THE NORTH BAY, LOOK AT
PICTURES WE HAVE FROM THE GOLDEN
GATE BRIDGE.
SHOWERS THIS MORNING AND VIDEO
THIS MORNING AROUND 2:30 THIS
MORNING.
I CAME ACROSS THE GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE AROUND 3:00, A LITTLE BIT
BEFORE, IT WAS LIGHT SHOWERS AT
THAT TIME.
IT WAS COMING DOWN HEAVIER DOWN
THERE THAN IT HAS SINCE I GOT
HERE TO THE SANTA CRUZ
MOUNTAINS.
IT WAS EARLY IN THE GOING.
WE'VE GOT A FUEL MORNING IN
FRONT OF US AND FULL MORNING
COMMUTE TO DEAL WITH THIS RAIN.
NOTHING IN THE WAY OF A
DOWNPOUR.
HAVEN'T SEEN ANYTHING
APPROACHING A WEATHER CAUSED
ACCIDENT BUT AGAIN, IT IS EARLY
IN THE GOING.
TERRY McSWEENEY, "ABC 7 NEWS."
>> LIGHT BEHIND HIM MAKES IT
LOOKS LIKE IT IS RAINING HARDER
THAN IT IS.
>> WE DO HAVE TRAFFIC AND
WEATHER GO TO THE NEXT ON ABC
MORNING NEWS.
A LIVE LOOK ON THE EMBARCADERO.
YOU CAN SEE SAN FRANCISCO
STREETS ARE WET.
MIKE NICCO WILL HAVE THE FULL
FORECAST AND SUE HALL WILL HAVE
THE LATEST FROM THE TRAFFIC
CENTER WITH A FEW ACCIDENTS
INCLUDING A BIG PROBLEM
NORTHBOUND 101 IN SUNNYVALE.
>> AND MILESTONE SOUTHWEST MADE
THE MERGER
>>> WE'RE GOING TO START WITH
LIVE DOPPLER.
UP IN THE NORTH BAY, RADAR
RETURNS UP AROUND NAPA.
MORE AROUND THE AMERICAN CANYON
AND DOWN TO VALLEJO.
AS YOU HEAD TOWARD FAIRFIELD AND
ACROSS THE SAN MATEO BRIDGE
HEADING OVER TO EAST TAYLOR
STREET AND GRANT AVENUE.
SUNOL GRADE A LITTLE LIGHT RAIN
SHOWING UP ON THE RADAR RIGHT
NOW.
AS FAR AS VISIBILITY.
THREE MILES IN NAPA SO IT'S VERY
LIGHT RAIN FOR YOU THIS MORNING.
>> HEAVY TRAFFIC 80 WESTBOUND,
WE HAD A CAR INTO A WALL ON
GILLMAN.
BUT TRAFFIC REMAINS HEAVY ALL
THE WAY INTO THE MacARTHUR MAZE.
BETWEEN STONE CREST AND HAGEN,
DOWNED POWER LINE BLOCKING THAT
AREA THERE.
TO THE PENINSULA, SUNNYVALE,
SOUTH BAY, NORTH 101 AN ACCIDENT
AT MATILDA AND THAT IS BACKING
THINGS TOWARDS LAWRENCE
EXPRESSWAY.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, PILOTS FOR
UNITED AIRLINES AGREED TO A NEW
CONTRACT OVER THE WEEKEND.
IT COVERS PILOTS WHO CAME FROM
UNITED ALONG THOSE THAT WORK
WITH CONTINENTAL.
THE DEAL INCLUDES A 43% PAY
RAISE OVER FOUR YEARS PLUS
LARGER RETIREMENT COMPENSATION.
THEY MERGED BACK IN 2010 BUT THE
CONTRACT DISPUTE WITH PILOTS HAD
BEEN A LONGSTANDING ISSUE.
>> OUR COVERAGE OF THE SCHOOL
TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT CONTINUES
NEXT ON ABC7 MORNING NEWS.
AHEAD.
PHOTOS RELEASED BY THE FAMILIES
GETTING READY TO SAY GOODBYE TO
THEIR LITTLE LOVED ONES TODAY.
HOW ONE N.F.L. STAR PAID TRIBUTE
TO A VICTIM WHO SAW THE PLAYER
AS A HERO.
>> LIGHT RAPE IS THE BIG STORY
AS WE LOOK AT RADAR THIS MORNING
OVER THE LAST THREE HOUSE, WAVES
OF LIGHT RAIN THAT WILL CONTINUE
THROUGH 7:00.
FEW SHOWERS HANGING AROUND BY
NOON.
TAPER THOSE SHOWERS TO ISOLATED
AND SEE SOME SUNSHINE BUT
TEMPERATURES IN THE LOW TO MID
50s THROUGH THE BETTER PART OF
TODAY.
AS WE HEAD THROUGH 7:00,
TEMPERATURES IN THE MID 50s.
BEST CHANCE OF SHOWERS OVER THE
OCEAN.
WE'LL HAVE FROST IN A LOT OF
PLACES WEDNESDAY MORNING AND
BIGGER STORM COMES IN THURSDAY.
>>> CONTINUING COVERAGE ON THE
SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN CONNECTICUT.
HERE IS THE LATEST INFORMATION.
THIS MORNING FUNERALS WILL TAKE
PLACE OF TWO OF THE 20 CHILDREN
THAT WERE KILL IN THE ATTACK.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WILL
REMAIN CLOSED INDEFINITELY.
THEY ARE EXPECTED TO RESUME
CLASSES AT NEIGHBORING SCHOOL ON
WEDNESDAY.
THE INVESTIGATION INTO ADAM
LANZA CONTINUES.
AUTHORITIES REMOVED COMPUTERS
AND VIDEOS FROM THE FAMILY HOME
OVER THE WEEKEND.
>> ONE OF FUNERALS WILL BE OF
NOAH POSNER.
IT WILL TAKE PLACE AT FAIRFIELD
CONNECTICUT AND BURIAL WILL
FOLLOW IN A NEIGHBORING TOWN.
THEY SAY HE LOVED PLAYING WITH
HIS TWIN SISTER.
FAMILY MEMBERS SAY THEY HAVE YET
TO TELL THE SIBLINGS WHAT
HAPPENED.
>> THE OTHER FUNERAL TODAY WILL
BE FOR JACK PIN WHO IS ALSO SIX
YEARS OLD.
HE LOVED BASEBALL, WRESTLING AND
SKIING.
THEY SAY FOOTBALL WAS HIS FIRST
LOVE.
HE IDOLIZED VICTOR CRUZ.
HE PAID TRIBUTE TO HIM, JACK
OPINION TO MY HERO IN ONE OF HIS
TWEETS.
>>> OUT OF THE TRAGEDY, THERE IS
REMARKABLE STORY OF SURVIVAL.
A LITTLE GIRL WHOSE INSTINCTS
TOLD HER TO PLAY DEAD.
SHE WAS THE ONLY STUDENT IN THE
FIRST GRADE CLASS TO MAKE IT OUT
ALIVE.
>> SHE WAS THE FIRST STUDENT
THAT RAN OUT OF THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL.
SHE RAN OUT OF THE SCHOOL
BUILDING COVERED IN BLOOD FROM
HEAD TO TOE.
SHE SAID WHETHER SHE GOT OUTSIDE
MOMMY, I'M OKAY BUT ALL MY
FRIENDS ARE DEAD.
>> PASTOR ADDED THE LITTLE
GIRL'S FAMILY IS SUFFERING
SURVIVORS GUILTY.
>> FORMER CLASSMATES THEY DIDN'T
SEE ANY WARNING SIGNS OF TROUBLE
BEFORE FRIDAY'S RAMPAGE.
AS WE MENTIONED, THEY REMOVED
COMPUTERS AND VIDEOS THAT COULD
PROVIDE IMPORTANT CLUES INTO THE
MOTIVE BEHIND THE SHOOTING.
BY ALL ACCOUNTS, LANZA DIDN'T
CONFIDE HIS PLANS WITH ANYONE.
>> I WOULD THINK ANYONE, A LOT
OF PEOPLE JUST SAW HIM AS
SOMEONE --
>> THEY HAVE SAID THEY RECOVERED
THE EVIDENCE TO HELP WITH THE
MOTIVE BUT THEY ARE NOT SHARING
ANY OF THE DETAILS WITH THE
PUBLIC.
>> WE'RE SEEING SOME ACCIDENTS
OUT THERE THIS MORNING ON
ROADWAYS.
DON'T KNOW IF IT IS RELATED TO
THE LIGHT RAIN BUT CERTAINLY
THAT IS WHAT WE HAVE IN STORE
FOR YOU IN THE BAY AREA.
>> LIGHT LANE AND MILD
TEMPERATURES.
THAT IS GOING TO CHANGE AS WE
HEAD TOWARDS TOMORROW MORNING.
WE'LL TALK ABOUT THE FOG AND
REAL STRONG STORM IS COMING IN
FOR THURSDAY.
HERE IS A LOOK FROM SANTA CRUZ
MOUNTAINS.
HIGHWAY 17 WHERE TERRY McSWEENEY
IS RIGHT NOW.
RAIN IS LIGHT.
I BELIEVE BECAUSE HE IS SITTING
OUT THERE IN IT.
WHAT YOU ARE SEEING BECAUSE
SMASHING A THREE DIMENSIONAL
IMAGE INTO 2-D THE RAIN LOOKS A
LOT HEAVIER BUT IT IS FALLING
SIDEWAYS.
YOU CAN SEE THE BRANCHES IN THE
TREES THERE.
IT IS A LITTLE GUSTY THIS
MORNING.
LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD, YOU CAN SEE
WE HAVE RADAR RETURNS ALL OVER
THE BAY AREA WITH SOME OF THE
BETTER ONES RIGHT OVER FAIRFIELD
AROUND TRAVIS BOULEVARD ALL THE
WAY BACK DOWN 80 INTO AMERICAN
CANYON AND HEADING TOWARDS
VALLEJO.
COMING OVER TOWARDS HAYWARD FROM
THE SAN MATEO BRIDGE.
YOU CAN SEE RIGHT THERE, HARDER
ROAD, TEN ANY SON ROAD, CASTRO
VALLEY GETTING LIGHT RAIN ALSO
AND BIGGER PICTURE SHOWS MORE
RAIN UP TO THE NORTH.
COLD FRONT IS SPARKING THAT IS
GOING TO GIVE US A CHANCE OF
SHOWER DURING THE AFTERNOON
HOURS.
RAIN TOTALS SINCE SIX HOURS AGO,
YOU NOTICE IT'S BEEN VERY LIGHT
IN THE SOUTH BAY.
NOTHING IN HAYWARD BUT FALLING
RIGHT NOW, .15 IN SAN RAFAEL.
LOW TO MID 50s.
FROM ANTIOCH AT 51.
TO SAN FRANCISCO AT ABOUT 56.
WE HAVE 55 IN SAN JOSE AND
OAKLAND ONE OF COOLER SPOTS
ALONG WITH CONCORD AT 52.
MONTEREY AT 58.
MORNING RAIN, STEADY, PRETTY
LIGHT AND THEN JUST A SHOWER
DURING THE AFTERNOON HOURS.
FROSTY TONIGHT AND LOOKS LIKE
WE'LL HAVE A WIDESPREAD FROST
FOR WEDNESDAY.
THEN THE STRONGEST OF THE STORMS
WILL COME IN THURSDAY WITH GUSTY
WINDS AND HEAVY RAIN.
HERE IS A LOOK AT THE SYSTEM.
THE GATEWAY TO COLDER AIR.
FRECKLED NATURE OF THE CLOUDS.
YOU CAN SEE STEADIER RAIN STAY
AROUND NOON AND NOON INTO THE
AFTERNOON HOURS A STRAY SHOWER
IS POSSIBLE.
OVERNIGHT WE SEE CLEARING AND
FROST DEVELOPING AROUND INLAND
VALLEYS AS WE HEAD TOWARD
SATURDAY MORNING AND AFTERNOON,
NEXT SYSTEM SLIDES IN.
IT REINFORCES THE COLD AIR,
TUESDAY NIGHT INTO WEDNESDAY
MORNING, WE COULD EVEN HAVE
FROST AROUND THE BAY AREA AND
SOME 20s INLAND.
BY WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON, MID 50s
AND THEN WE'LL HAVE THE STRONGER
STORM MOVE IN THURSDAY.
PERIODS OF RAIN FOR FRIDAY AND
THEN ANOTHER STORMY SYSTEM FOR
SATURDAY.
>> GOOD MORNING.
WE HAVE RAIN AT THE SAN MATEO
BRIDGE, YOU CAN SEE THE
TAILLIGHTS DISAPPEARING INTO THE
HEAVY RAIN AND CLOUDS -- I DON'T
KNOW IF IT IS FOG BUT SOME OF
THE RAIN KICKING OFF THE
ROADWAY.
SLOW TRAFFIC EASTBOUND AS YOU
MAKE YOUR WAY TOWARDS HAYWARD.
20 MINUTE DRIVE BETWEEN EAST BAY
AND PENINSULA.
METERING LIGHTS ARE ON BAY
BRIDGE.
TRAFFIC IS SLUGGISH INTO SAN
FRANCISCO.
BACK TO SUNNYVALE, THAT ACCIDENT
CLEARED TO THE SHOULDER.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU WAZE APP,
BUMPER-TO-BUMPER ALL THE WAY
TOWARDS THE EXPRESSWAY DUE TO
THE EARLIER ACCIDENT.
IT'S SLOW TRAFFIC REALLY REMAINS
HERE ALL THE WAY FROM SAN JOSE
TOWARDS SUNNYVALE.
>>> AHEAD, FOOD FROM YOUR
FREEZER, MICHAEL FINNEY FINDS
OUT IF FROZEN APPETIZERS PASS
THE TASTE TEST.
>> AND LIVE LOOK AT DOPPLER 7-HD
BLUE REPRESENTING RAIN.
MICHAEL WILL TELL US WHERE IT IS
HITTING THE GROUND.
SUE WILL TELL US AGAIN WHERE THE
TROUBLE SPOTS ARE.
>> TODAY AT 3:00, ON ABC7, WE
WANT TO LET YOU KNOW A BADGE ON
FACEBOOK AND WE HAVE A SPECIAL
EDITION OF KATIE ON THE MASS
SHOOTING ELEMENTARY IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT TODAY AT
>>> TIME TO LOOK FOR LIVE
DOPPLER.
LIGHT RAIN FOR THE MORNING
COMMUTE.
YOU CAN SEE BLUE AND GREEN AND
IT'S JUST ABOUT EVERYWHERE.
MAYBE UP TO LIGHT RAIN BEFORE
YOU KNOW IT.
MOST OF THE RAIN ABOVE IS
DIPPING AROUND MODESTO.
ANYWHERE NORTH OF FRESNO, VALLEY
RAIN AND MOUNTAIN SNOW.
SOUTH PARTS OF THE STATE, MID TO
UPPER 60s WITH PARTLY SUNNY
CONDITIONS.
THIS IS FOR THE WESTERN SLOPES,
THAT IS WHY YOU NEED CHAINS
BECAUSE FOUR TO EIGHT INCHES
WILL FALL.
>>> READY MADE APPETIZERS FROM
YOUR FREEZER CAN SAVE YOU TIME
ESPECIALLY IF YOU ARE THROWING A
HOLIDAY PARTY BUT HOW DO THEY
TASTE.
HERE ARE THE RESULTS OF A
BRAND-NEW CONSUMER REPORTS TASTE
TEST.
>> GOOD MORNING, TIS THE SEASON
TO CELEBRATE WITH FAMILY AND
FOOD.
CONSUMER REPORTS FINDS CERTAIN
READY MADE APPETIZERS CAN SAVE
YOU TIME AND MONEY.
>> WANT TO BE THE HOSTESS
WITHOUT THE MOSTESS LOOK NO
FURTHER THAN THE SUPERMARKET
FREEZER.
THEY TESTED APPETIZERS AND TACOS
AND SPINACH PIE.
>> SOME WERE REALLY GOOD.
>> THESE LEAK LEAVING A LOT OF
CHEESE ON THE TRAY.
OF THE SIX CHEESE STICKS TESTED
ONLY ONE TURNED OUT TO BE VERY
GOOD.
FARM RIDGE WERE BIG AND TASTY.
>> THE OTHER SIDE WERE MEDIOCRE.
>> MEXICAN APPETIZERS CAN BE
HIGH IN FAT AND CALORIES.
LOWEST RATED IN THE TEXT, DELI
MIX CHICKEN.
FROZEN APRIL TIDESERS WERE GREEK
INSPIRED SPINACH PIES, ALL SIX
TASTED VERY GOOD.
COSTCO'S CUISINE ADVENTURE WERE
FRESH.
ANOTHER GOOD CHOICE SPINACH PIE.
CRISPY WAS FRESH TASTING
SPINACH.
>> IT'S NOT AN EASY THING TO
MAKE AT HOME SO IT'S A GOOD
THING TO BUY AT HOME.
>> AND REMEMBER, LIGHT SNACK
BEFORE A PARTY CAN HELP YOU
AVOID OVERINDULGING.
>> WHEN ORGANIZING A COCKTAIL
PARTY, PLAN ON SERVING EIGHT
APPETIZERS PER PERSON AND FIVE
FOR THE REST OF THE PARTY.
FIGURE THREE TO FOUR APPETIZERS
A PERSON.
>>> STILL AHEAD.
THE BAY AREA WAKING UP TO
SHOWERS.
LET'S GIVE YOU A LIVE LOOK
METEOROLOGIST MIKE NICCO IS
AHEAD WITH THE COMMUTERS FACING
THE WET DRIVE TO WORK RIGHT NOW.
>> ALSO AHEAD, THIS MAN SPEAKS
OUT.
CALIFORNIA MAN WHO BABY SAT
NEWTOWN SCHOOL GUNMAN ADAM LANZA
REVEALS WHAT HE WAS LIKE AS A
KID.
>> STUDENTS HEADING BACK TO
SCHOOL FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
THE MASS SHOOTING IN
CONNECTICUT.
THEY HAVE A LOT OF QUESTIONS AND
CONCERNS.
IN SAN FRANCISCO, TEACHERS WILL
HAVE A LITTLE HELP
WITH MY KEURIG VUE
BREWER,
I CAN BREW MY COFFEE
JUST THE WAY I LOVE IT.
HOW DO YOU DO THAT?
INSIDE THE BREWER,
THERE'S THIS TRAIN
THAT MAKES COFFEE
STRONGER, BIGGER, AND HOTTER!
ACTUALLY, I JUST PRESS
THIS BUTTON.
BREW WHAT YOU LOVE
WITH THE KEURIG VUE.
>>> GOOD MORNING, IT IS 6:29.
YOU ARE LOOKING AT LIVE PICTURE
AT THE SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS,
RAIN IS LIGHT.
TERRY McSWEENEY IS UP THERE AND
WILL TELL YOU MORE ABOUT THAT
COMING UP.
I'M ERIC THOMAS.
>> Kristen: I'M KRISTEN SZE.
THE QUESTION FOR YOU RIGHT NOW
BEFORE YOU HEAD TO WORK, IS IT
OFF OR ON FOR YOU.
>> GOOD MORNING.
STEADY RAIN DOWN IN THE SANTA
CRUZ MOUNTAINS, STEADY RAIN WAS
UP IN THE NORTH BAY, YOU CAN SEE
A LOT OF BLUE AND A LITTLE BIT
OF GREEN.
WE HAVE SOME DRIZZLE AND LIGHT
RAIN.
WE ARE PICKING UP LIGHT RAIN
AROUND TENNISON BOULEVARD AROUND
HAYWARD AND THEN OVER TO DUBLIN.
YOU CAN SEE MILPITAS.
ANCHOR ROAD AND HEADING OVER TO
CUPERTINO AND FEW MORE HEADING
TOWARD SAN FRANCISCO, DALY CITY
AND COLMA AND HALF MOON BAY.
THIS IS ALL MOVING FROM WEST TO
EAST.
IT WILL BE MOST PREVALENT DURING
THE MORNING HOURS.
BY NOON, TEMPERATURES WILL HOLD
STEADY IN THE LOW TO MID 50s.
>> LIVE LOOK DID HE GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE, ROADS ARE WET.
TRAFFIC IS MOVING NICELY HEADING
INTO SAN FRANCISCO FROM THE
WALDO GRADE IN MARIN COUNTY.
680, INJURY ACCIDENT BLOCKING AN
OFF-RAMP, BACK TO TRAFFIC APP
SHOWING 101 NORTHBOUND JAMMED
FROM THE EXPRESSWAY, FROM SANTA
CLARA UP TO SUNNYVALE.
AN EARLIER ACCIDENT AT MADA VERY
HEAVY TRAFFIC REMAINS.
TO NAVIGATE YOUR COMMUTE, FREE
APP AT APPLE APP STORE OR GOOGLE
PLAY.
>>> FIRST OF 28 FUNERALS WILL
TAKE PLACE TODAY IN CONNECTICUT.
TWO YOUNG BOYS KILLED AT SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY WILL BE BURIED.
THIS MORNING WE ARE HEARING A
NEW STORY OF SURVIVAL.
NEWS REPORTER JOINS US LIVE FROM
THE NEWSROOM.
>> SIX-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO AND
NOAH POS NEVER WILL BE LAID TO
REST.
JACK PINTO WILL BE LAID IN
VICTOR CRUZ'S JERSEY BECAUSE
THAT WAS HIS HERO.
HE WILL TAKE HIS CLEATS AND
GLOVES TO PINTO'S FAMILY.
SANDY HOOK NURSE SALLY COX IS
TALKING FOR THE FIRST TIME WHEN
SHE KNEW SOMETHING IT WAS
TERRIBLE HAPPENING.
SHE HEARD LOUD POPPING SOUNDS.
SHE HID UNDER HER COMPUTER DESK
AND GUNMAN ENTERED HER OFFICE.
>> I HEARD THE DOOR CLOSE.
HE PROBABLY WALKED IN AND I
COULD SEE HIM FROM THE KNEES
DOWN.
>> RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU.
>> 20 FEET AWAY, FACING HIS
BOOTS WERE FACING MY DESK.
>> THEN HE TURNED AND WALKED
AWAY.
>> IT WAS SECONDS AND TURNED AND
WALKED OUT AND I HEARD THE DOOR
CLOSED.
>> WHAT DO YOU DO NEXT?
>> AFTER THE DOOR CLOSED, I
DON'T KNOW HOW THE SECRETARY HAD
THE COURAGE, BUT HE RACED INTO
MY OFFICE AND PULLED THE DOOR
CLOSED AND RACED BEHIND MY DESK.
WE PULLED THE PHONE OFF MY DESK.
I HELD THE PHONE WHILE SHE
DIALED 911.
>> OVER THE WEEKEND, GOVERNOR OF
CONNECTICUT BECAUSE THE NURSE
AND SECRETARY CALLED 911 SO FAST
EMERGENCY RESPONDERS WERE ABLE
TO GET TO THE SCHOOL QUICKLY AND
PREVENT MORE KILLINGS.
OF COURSE WE KNOW THE SHOOTER
TURNED ON HIMSELF WHEN HE HEARD
POLICE CLOSING IN.
AFTER THAT, THE NURSE AND
SECRETARY STAYED HIDDEN FOR
ALMOST FOUR HOURS.
THEY WERE PETRIFIED AND DIDN'T
KNOW HOW MANY SHOOTERS THERE
COULD HAVE BEEN.
YOU CAN SEE SALLY'S INTERVIEW
AND INCREDIBLE STORY OF SURVIVAL
WITH GEORGE STEPHANOPOLOUS
COMING UP AFTER THE NEWSCAST.
>>> TIME IS 6:33.
>> THEY ARE HOLDING A NEWS
CONFERENCE, LET'S LISTEN IN.
>> WE WILL NOT STOP UNTIL WE
INTERVIEW EVERY LAST ONE OF
THEM.
WE ARE HOLDING BOTH CRIME SCENES
THE SCHOOL AND SECONDARY CRIME
SCENE INDEFINITELY.
WE SEIZED IT UNDER SEARCH
WARRANTS AND HOLD THOSE
LOCATIONS UNTIL WE HAVE
COMPLETED OUR WORK AND WE FEEL
IT IS APPROPRIATE TO LET THEM
GO.
SO NOT TO READ ANYTHING INTO
THAT.
IT IS COMMON PRACTICE TO DO
TO HOLD ON TO THE CRIME SCENE AS
LONG AS IT IS NEEDED FOR
INVESTIGATIVE PURPOSES.
WE HAVE THE GUN PROCESSING THE
EVIDENCE AND ANALYZING THE
EVIDENCE.
AS I STATED YESTERDAY, TO USE AN
EXAMPLE, WEAPONRY, EVERY SINGLE
FACET OF THE WEAPONS WILL BE
ANALYZED.
EVERY SINGLE ROUND OF AMMUNITION
WILL BE LOOKED AT AND EXAMINED
FOR ANY KIND OF PHYSICAL
EVIDENCE.
I ALLUDED YESTERDAY TO THE
VOLUME OF ROUNDS THAT WERE
SEIZED OR RECOVERED.
EACH IMAGE IS GHRAR ROUND WILL
BE EXAMINED TO GIVE YOU AN IDEA
OF THE PROCESS.
ALL THE EVIDENCE THAT WILL BE
PROCESSED AND ANALYZE EVERY
SINGLE PIECE.
I CAN'T DETAIL ANY EVIDENCE OR
EVEN WHAT THAT EVIDENCE IS FOR
PUBLIC CONSUMPTION.
I WANT TO RESTATE AGAIN, THANK
YOU FOR HELPING US IN THIS --
ANY THREATS, ANY INFORMATION
INTENDED TO MISLEAD
INVESTIGATORS IN THIS CASE WILL
IN FACT BE COMPLETELY AND
THOROUGHLY INVESTIGATED AND IF
APPROPRIATE PROSECUTED IF ANYONE
ATTEMPTS TO THREATEN OR MISLEAD
PEOPLE.
IRRESPECTIVE --
>> WE WILL ALSO TELL YOU HERE IN
THE BAY AREA, SCHOOL DISTRICTS
ARE REVIEWING THEIR SAFETY PLANS
IN THE WAKE OF THE TRAGEDY IN
CONNECTICUT.
"ABC 7 NEWS" REPORTER AMY
HOLLYFIELD IS LIVE IN SAN
FRANCISCO WITH MORE ON THAT PART
OF THE STORY.
>> IF YOU KNOW -- SPEAK ONE
TEACHER SAID IT WAS THE 9/11 FOR
TEACHERS.
TEACHERS SAY THEY DID SPEND THE
WEEKEND, HOW THEY COULD CALM
STUDENTS TODAY.
WHAT THEY WILL SAY.
TEACHERS' UNION HERE IN SAN
FRANCISCO SENT OUT AN E-MAIL
WITH A GUIDE TO HELP THEM STEER
THE CONVERSATIONS.
PRESIDENT OF THE UNION SAYS --
>> SCHOOL SHOULD BE A SAFE
PLACE.
IT SHOULD BE A PLACE OF REFUGE
IN ADDITION TO BE A PLACE OF
LEARNING.
WHEN A SCHOOL IS VIOLATED LIKE
THIS, IT GOES TO HEART OF ALL US
EDUCATORS.
>> Reporter: CALIFORNIA
EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY
OFFERS STEPS.
SOME OF THOSE INCLUDE YOUR
SCHOOL'S EMERGENCY ACTION PLAN,
ALSO KNOW YOUR SCHOOL'S ALERT
SYSTEM FOR PARENTS AND CREATE OR
REVIEW YOUR FAMILY'S ACTION
PLAN.
IF YOU ARE FAMILIAR WITH PLANS,
TODAY IS GOOD DAY TO START
ASKING QUESTIONS, THERE WILL BE
A LOT OF QUESTIONS TODAY.
>>> STAY WITH US FOR CONTINUING
COVERAGE OF THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL TRAGEDY.
"GOOD MORNING AMERICA" IS
DEVOTING TWO HOURS TO THE
TRAGEDY.
GEORGE STEPHANOPOLOUS, JOSH
ELLIOT WILL BE LIVE.
COVERAGE STARTS AT 7:00.
>> WE ARE KEEPING TRACK OF LIGHT
RAIN IN THE BAY AREA RIGHT NOW.
TRAFFIC AND WEATHER TOGETHER.
HERE IS A LIVE LOOK OUTSIDE AT
THE GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE.
YOU CAN SEE RAIN IS COMING DOWN
THERE.
MIKE NICCO WILL HAVE THE FULL
ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST.
THERE HAVE BEEN SOME ACCIDENTS
AND WE'LL CHECK IN WITH SUE HALL
IN THE TRAFFIC CENTER.
>> ALSO AHEAD, HE WASN'T SANTA
BUT HE WAS TRYING TO COME DOWN
THE CHIMNEY WHEN HE GOT STUCK.
>>> WE'VE GOT SLOW TRAFFIC BY
WAZE APP, THIS 101 NORTHBOUND,
IN SANTA CLARA-SUNNYVALE AREA
AROUND MATILDA.
THAT HAS BEEN CLEARED OUT OF THE
LANES JUST BEFORE 237 BUT
TRAFFIC IS JAMMED NORTHBOUND.
WE'RE GOING TO TAKE 85 OR
PERHAPS 280 TO GET AROUND THIS
UNTIL TRAFFIC RECOVERS BUT 101
NORTH IS JAMMED.
>> GOOD MORNING.
A LITTLE WET OUT THIS MORNING.
LIGHT RAIN AND DRIZZLE.
EVEN IN AREAS YOU DO NOT SEE
BLUE AND GREEN THIS MORNING.
WE ARE STILL GETTING SOME WET
WEATHER AND THAT WILL HANG
AROUND UNTIL THIS MORNING.
TAPERING DOWN AROUND 4:00.
TEMPERATURES WILL HANG OUT LOW
TO MID-50s.
GRAB A HEAVY COAT.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT THE WET
WEATHER GEAR.
AS WE HEAD TUESDAY, SHOWER BEST
CHANCE OVER THE OCEAN.
COLDER MORNING ON WEDNESDAY AND
BIGGER STORM AND HEAVY FLOODING
RAIN ON THURSDAY.
>>> NEW THIS MORNING, IN SAN
FRANCISCO WHERE FIREFIGHTERS
RESCUED A MAN WHO WAS STUCK IN A
CHIMNEY OVERNIGHT.
IT HAPPENED AROUND MIDNIGHT AT A
SIX STORY APARTMENT BUILDING
NEAR CLUE STREET IN THE LAUREL
HEIGHTS NEIGHBORHOOD.
IT CAUSED QUITE A XEOGS FOR
PEOPLE THAT LIVE THERE.
INVESTIGATORS DON'T KNOW WHY THE
MAN WAS IN THE CHIMNEY BUT THEY
SAY HE WAS NOT TREASURY PASSING.
FIREFIGHTERS GOT HIM OUT AND MAN
IS EXPECTED TO BE OKAY.
>>> AHEAD, TEDDY BEARS FOR SANDY
HOOK.
THOUSANDS OF STUFFED ANIMALS NOW
ON THE WAY TORN APART BY
TRAGEDY.
>> AND TRADING IS UNDER WAY ON
WALL STREET.
LIVE LOOK AND DOW IS UP 42
POINTS.
ALL EYES WILL BE ON APPLE STOCK
THIS MORNING, DIPPING BELOW 500
A SHARE FOR THE FIRST TIME SINCE
FEBRUARY.
WE'RE GOING LIVE T
>>> THIS IS DOPPLER RADAR THIS
MORNING, YOU CAN SEE THE RADAR
RETURNS WEST TO EAST AS WE HAVE
A MOIST FLOW COMING OFF THE
OCEAN.
RAINFALL IS MAKING IT SOUTH OF
80 AND SOUTH OF SAN JOSE RIGHT
NOW.
WATCH OUT FOR LIGHT RAIN IF YOU
ARE TRAVELING THERE AND HIGH
ELEVATION SNOW TODAY ALL THE WAY
DOWN TO FRESNO AND YOSEMITE.
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA, MID TO
UPPER 50s WITH PARTLY SUNNY SKY.
WINTER STORM WARNING FOR WESTERN
SLOPE UNTIL MIDNIGHT.
CHAINS REQUIRED ON ALL HIGHWAYS
HEADING UP TO THE SIERRA.
FOUR TO EIGHT INCHES OF
ADDITIONAL SNOW ABOVE 4500 FEET.
>> WE HAVE DEVELOPING NEWS FROM
SAN FRANCISCO WHERE POLICE ARE
INVESTIGATING A HOME INVASION
THIS MORNING.
IT TOOK PLACE AROUND 2:00 THIS
MORNING ON SLOAT BOULEVARD
ACROSS FROM THE LAKESHORE
SHOPPING CENTER.
THREE MEN WEARING MASKS STORMED
INTO THE HOME AND TIED UP THE
PEOPLE INSIDE.
INVESTIGATORS DON'T KNOW WHY
THAT HOME WAS TARGETED OR WHAT
WAS TAKEN, THEY DO KNOW THAT
NOBODY WAS HURT.
>> Kristen: "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA" WILL HAVE MUCH MORE ON
THE SCHOOL TRAGEDY IN NEWTOWN
COMING UP AT 7:00.
HERE IS PAULA WITH A PREVIEW.
>> COMING UP WE WILL BRING YOU A
SPECIAL EDITION, TRAGEDY AT
SANDY HOOK THE SEARCH FOR
SOLUTIONS, WE HAVE BREAKING KNEW
DETAILS ABOUT THE GUNMAN, WE
WILL BE LIVE WITH THE LATEST ON
THE INVESTIGATION, ALL NEXT ON
GMA.
>> FOR A MEMORIAL IN NEWTOWN
CONTINUES TO GROW.
THIS IS HOW THE MEMORIAL LOOKED
LAST NIGHT.
HOLIDAY LIGHTS ARE MIXED IN WITH
FLOWERS AND TEDDY BEARS.
ONE FAMILY DONATED 3,000 TEDDY
BEARS.
MEMORIAL IS ALSO BRINGS IN
VISITORS FROM NEIGHBORING TOWNS
TO STOPPING BY TO PAY RESPECTS.
>> BY ALL ACCOUNTS THE SHOOTER
ADAM LANZA WAS A LONER THAT KEPT
MOSTLY TO HIMSELF.
THEY SAW NO REASON TO FEAR HIM
BEFORE FRIDAY'S SHOOTING.
A NEIGHBOR WHO BABY SAT HIM WHEN
HE WAS TEN HE WAS QUIET KID,
RYAN CRAFT NOW LIVES IN SOUTHERN
CALIFORNIA AND HE SAYS HE NEVER
SAW ANY RED FLAGS.
>> I REMEMBER WHEN WE WERE DOING
SOMETHING, BUILD LEGOS HE WAS
REALLY FOCUSED ON IT.
HE WAS LIKE IN HIS OWN WORLD.
>> COMING UP ON "GOOD MORNING
AMERICA," THE MAN WHO MENTORED
ADAM LANZA ADVISING HIM WILL
GIVE HIS MEMORIES.
YOU CAN EXPRESS YOUR SYMPATHY
THIS BADGE A SHOW OF SUPPORT.
>> A QUICK CHECK HOW GUN MAKERS
ARE FARING FOLLOWING THE
SHOOTING.
>> INVESTORS CONTINUE TO EYE
FISCAL CLIFF TALKS.
JANE KING IS LIVE WITH THESE
STORIES AND MORE.
>> GUN CONTROL ADVOCATES
INCLUDING DEMOCRATIC SENATOR
DIANNE FEINSTEIN HAVE GUN MAKERS
IN THEIR EYE.
THEY ARE DOWN AND SMITH AND
WESSON ARE LOWER AS BOTH OF
STOCKS LOST MORE THAN 4% AS
EVENTS UNFOLDED WE DO HAVE A
HIGHER OPEN OVERALL FOR MARKETS
THIS MORNING.
IN SPITE OF WEAK NUMBERS ON
MANUFACTURING HERE IN THE
NEW YORK AREA.
OPTIMISM MIGHT BE BECAUSE
PRESIDENT OBAMA AND HOUSE
SPEAKER APPEAR TO BE GETTING
CLOSER ON FISCAL CLIFF TALKS.
BLOOMBERG INDEX IS TRADING UP.
WE CONTINUE TO WATCH APPLE
SHARES.
THEY DID SLIP BELOW 500 EARLY
THIS MORNING IN THE PRE-MARKET.
CITIGROUP SAYS APPLE'S ASIAN
SUPPLIERS HAVE BEEN POSTING
LOWER ORDERS FOR THE iPHONE 5.
CAN YOU SEE SEE AND TOUCH BUT
HEAR AND TASTE AND SMELL THINGS
OFF THE DEVICES.
THIS IS YOUR SUIT OF ARTIFICIAL
INTELLIGENCE HAS BEEN ONGOING
FOR YEARS.
THEY ARE TAKING A COGNITIVE
COMPUTING MORE SERIOUSLY THESE
DAYS.
I'M JANE KING, BLOOMBERG NEWS.
>> WE HAVE A STORM, NOT A VERY
COLD ONE.
>> VERY MILD OUT THIS MORNING.
TEMPERATURES IN THE 50s.
THAT IS WHERE THEY ARE GOING TO
STAY THE BETTER PART OF THE DAY.
STEADY RAIN IN THE SANTA CRUZ
MOUNTAINS, WHERE THE RAIN IS
FALLING, LIGHT RAIN, MORE
IMPRESSIVE, WE HAVE LIGHTS
SHINING ON AND THREE DIMENSIONAL
IMAGE AND SMASHING IT INTO TWO
DIMENSIONAL IMAGE.
IT LOOKS HEAVIER THAN IT IS AND
CAUSING SLICKNESS ON 35 AND 17?
IN THE SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS.
DOPPLER RADAR AND SATELLITE,
BEST RADAR RETURNS DOWN IN THE
SOUTH AND OVER TOWARDS THE EAST.
IN FACT AROUND DUBLIN HEADING
OVER TO LIVERMORE, HACIENDA,
EVEN STONE RIDGE, ALL THOSE
AREAS SHOWING RAIN RIGHT NOW.
84, NILES BOULEVARD FREMONT
TOWARDS NEWARK.
HEADING OVER TO SAN FRANCISCO,
DALY CITY, SOUTH SAN FRANCISCO,
COLMA, PACIFICA AND BRISBANE
GETTING A LITTLE BIT OF LIGHT
RAIN.
WE HAVE MORE SHOWERS UP TO THE
NORTH.
THOSE ARE GOING TO SLIDE DOWN
WITH THE COLD FRONT AND BRING US
SCATTERED SHOWER IN THE
AFTERNOON.
RAINFALL AMOUNTS MOST IMPRESSIVE
UP IN THE NORTH BAY.
HALF AN INCH IN SANTA ROSA TO
NEARLY TENTH AROUND SAN
FRANCISCO AND OAKLAND TO NOTHING
MEASURABLE YET IN SAN JOSE.
MILD TEMPERATURES, 51 IN ANTIOCH
TO 57 IN SAN RAFAEL.
52 IN GILROY TO 58 IN MONTEREY.
MORNING STEADY RAIN AND
SCATTERED SHOWERS THIS
AFTERNOON.
IT'S GOING TO BE FROSTY AND
BETTER CHANCE OF WIDESPREAD
FROST WEDNESDAY.
HEAVY RAIN AND GUSTY WINDS AND
GUSTY WINDS FOR THURSDAY.
BEHIND THIS SYSTEM WE HAVE REAL
COLD AIR COMING IN FOR THE NEXT
COUPLE NIGHTS.
STEAD ZI RAIN HANGING AROUND SAY
NOON.
THEN DURING THE AFTERNOON HOURS,
YOU SEE IT GETS QUIETER WITH
ISOLATED SHOWER POSSIBLE.
WITH THE CLEARING OVERNIGHT,
FROST IN THE INLAND VALLEYS,
MAINLY 30s AND 40s AROUND THE
BAY.
AS WE HEAD TOWARDS TUESDAY
AFTERNOON, WEAK PULSE OF ENERGY
ACROSS THE OCEAN AND THEN
TUESDAY NIGHT INTO WEDNESDAY
MORNING, WE COULD HAVE FROST
JUST ABOUT ANYWHERE AS IT WILL
BE ONE OF COLDEST MORNINGS WE'VE
HAD THIS SEASON.
WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON, PARTLY
SUNNY AND MID 50s, STRONG STORM
COMES IN THURSDAY, ANOTHER
STRONG STORM COMING IF FOR
SATURDAY WITH MORE RAIN ON
SUNDAY.
>>> GOOD MORNING EVERYONE.
A STALL WITH HEADLIGHTS HEADED
SOUTHBOUND 101 PAST LUCAS VALLEY
ROAD HEADED IN THE SOUTHBOUND
DIRECTION TOWARDS THE CIVIC
CENTER AND UP OVER TO SAN
RAFAEL.
NO PROBLEMS WITH IT.
680 BLOCKING SOUTH MAIN
OFF-RAMP.
IT'S AN OVERTURN.
SLOWING PAST THE SCENE, BACK TO
SUNNYVALE, WE HAD AN EARLIER
ACCIDENT ON MATILDA.
HIGHWAY 87 WAS JAMMED ALL THE
WAY TOWARD THE EARLIER SCENE.
UNTIL IT BEGINS TO RECOVER, YOU
WANT TO TAKE 85 OR 280.
>>> AHEAD, FIVE THINGS TO KNOW
BEFORE YOU GO.
>> THE MORNING NEWS
>>> WELCOME BACK.
LIVE LOOK AT GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE,
IT'S RAINING THERE.
WET BRIDGE DECK AS THE CARS
STREAM INTO SAN FRANCISCO.
RAIN IN MANY PARTS OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO.
MIKE WILL TELL YOU EXACTLY WHERE
COMING UP IN THE FORECAST.
>> RAIN IS GOING TO BE THE FIRST
OF THE FIVE THINGS TO KNOW
BEFORE WE GO.
NUMBER ONE, NEW STORM BROUGHT
WET WEATHER AND WINDS THROUGHOUT
THE BAY AREA.
WE HAVE SEEN HEAVY DOWNPOURS IN
SANTA CRUZ MOUNTAINS.
LIGHT RAIN AT GOLDEN GATE
BRIDGE.
IT'S EXPECTED TO REMAIN WET FOR
THE MORNING COMMUTE.
>> NUMBER TWO, CONNECTICUT
POLICE HELD A NEWS CONFERENCE
ABOUT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
SHOOTING THAT CLAIMED 26 LIVES,
20 OF THEM CHILDREN, LITTLE
INFORMATION WAS RELEASED AT THE
BRIEFING EXCEPT THAT THE
INVESTIGATION CONTINUES AND THEY
ARE NARROWING THE FOCUS ON THE
MOTIVE.
>> NUMBER THREE, FIRST FINALS
FOR TWO OF THE SIX-YEAR-OLD
VICTIMS TODAY.
ONE WILL BE BURIED IN JERSEY OF
FOOTBALL HERO VICTOR CRUZ.
MEANTIME, OTHER STUDENTS IN THE
GRIEVING COMMUNITY RETURNED TO
THEIR CLASSROOM,000 MORNING
WHERE THERE IS EXTRA SECURITY
AND COUNSELORS ON HAND.
>> NUMBER FOUR, A NEW CHALLENGE
FACING SCHOOL TEACHERS AS THEY
FACE NERVOUS STUDENTS LOOKING
FOR ANSWERS FOLLOWING FRIDAY'S
TRAGEDY.
IN SAN FRANCISCO SCHOOLS,
STUDENTS WILL SEE TIGHTENED
SECURITY MEASURES ON SOME
CAMPUSES.
>> MEMORIALS CONTINUE TONIGHT IN
THE BAY AREA.
ON THE PENINSULA, A SERVICE OF
REMEMBRANCE WILL GET UNDERWAY AT
7:00 P.M.
IT WILL TAKE PLACE AT FIRST
PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH OF
BURLINGAME.
>> FINAL CHECK OF YOUR
ACCU-WEATHER FORECAST.
>> WE'LL START WITH FINAL LOOK
AT LIVE DOPPLER 7-HD.
RADAR IS SHOWING BEST RADAR
RETURN IN SOLANO COUNTY HEADING
DOWN, A LITTLE BIT OF LIGHT RAIN
TOWARDS COLMA AND BRISBANE AND
SOUTHERN SECTIONS HAVE SAN
FRANCISCO, POSSIBLY NEAR MISSION
AND AROUND SAN JOSE WHERE WE ARE
GETTING SOME BETTER RADAR
RETURNS.
RAIN IS TAPERING TO DRIZZLE AND
RAMPING BACK UP TO LIGHT RAIN.
THAT IS WHAT WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
THROUGH THE BETTER PART OF THIS
MORNING.
BY THE AFTERNOON HOURS, AN
ISOLATED SHOWER IS POSSIBLE, A
LITTLE POCKET OF SUNSHINE AND
TEMPERATURES JUST LIKE THEY ARE
RIGHT NOW, LOW TO MID 50s.
BE PREPARED FOR THURSDAY BECAUSE
A BIG STORM ON THE WAY.
>> BACK TO THE BAY BRIDGE,
METERING LIGHTS ARE ON, CARPOOL
LANES ARE GETTING BY WITH NO
PROBLEM, TRAFFIC IS BACK TOWARD
THE WEST GRAND OVERCROSSING AND
MacARTHUR MAZE AND SLUGGISH ON
THE UPPER DECK.
GOLDEN GATE BRIDGE WET AS WELL,
TRAFFIC MOVING OUT OF MARIN
COUNTY BUT WET CONDITIONS REMAIN
THERE.
FINAL LOOK AT OUR ABC7 WAZE APP
SHOWING YOU NORTH 101 JAMMED IN
SAN JOSE, UP TOWARDS SUNNYVALE
TO 237 DUE TO AN EARLIER
ACCIDENT.
THIS IS FREE APP FOR YOU AT THE
APPLE APP STORE TO HELP YOU MOVE
AROUND THE COMMUTE.
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
MORNING NEWS CONTINUES IN 25
MINUTES WITH NEWS, WEATHER AND
TRAFFIC DURING A SPECIAL EDITION
OF "GOOD MORNING AMERICA."
>> BYE-BYE.
>>> GOOD MORNING, AMERICA,
FROM NEWTOWN.
THIS MORNING, HARD QUESTIONS
FROM THE PRESIDENT.
>> ARE WE REALLY PREPARED TO SAY
THAT WE'RE POWERLESS IN THE FACE
OF SUCH CARNAGE?
>> HIS DRAMATIC CALL FOR CHANGE
AFTER THE DEADLIEST GRADE SCHOOL
SHOOTING IN HISTORY.
>> LET US FIND THE STRENGTH TO
CARRY ON AND MAKE OUR COUNTRY
WORTHY OF THEIR MEMORY.
>> THIS MORNING, INDELIBLE
IMAGES OF THE YOUNGEST VICTIMS.
>> READY, NOW, GO.