THE BODY DOESN'T KNOW
THE DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN NERVES AND EXCITEMENT,
PANIC AND DOUBT,
THE BEGINNING,
AND THE END.
THE BODY JUST TELLS YOU
TO GET THE HELL OUT.
♪
SOMETIMES YOU IGNORE IT.
THAT'S THE REASONABLE THING
TO DO.
(speaking inaudibly)
BUT SOMETIMES YOU LISTEN.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO TRUST
YOUR GUT, RIGHT?
WHEN YOUR BODY SAYS RUN...
♪
RUN.
UH, ONCE AGAIN,
SOME THREE HOURS AGO,
PRESIDENT GRANT WAS SHOT.
PREVIOUSLY ON "SCANDAL"...
THE FBI IS ISSUING A HIGH ALERT,
AND THEY--THEY DO HAVE
A DESCRIPTION OF A SUSPECT.
MS. POPE?
YES.
ARE YOU--
BACK? YES.
I'M BACK,
FOR AS LONG AS YOU NEED ME.
The vice president is
making a play.
SHE SPENT THE LAST TWO HOURS
LOBBYING CABINET MEMBERS
ABOUT SIGNING OVER
THE PRESIDENCY TO HER.
SHE WHAT?
(Reed) PRESIDENT SALLY LANGSTON
MAKES HISTORY TODAY
AS THE FIRST FEMALE
COMMANDER IN CHIEF.
GOOD MORNING.
FIRST, LET ME SAY
THAT ALL THAT I HAVE
I WOULD GIVE
NOT TO BE HERE TODAY.
LIKE ALL OF YOU,
MY THOUGHTS AND PRAYERS
ARE WITH THE PRESIDENT
AND HIS WIFE AND CHILDREN.
THE DOCTORS AT JAMES MADISON
HOSPITAL HAVE INFORMED ME
THAT PRESIDENT GRANT'S
CONDITION REMAINS CRITICAL.
THE DOCTORS HAVE BEEN CANDID,
AND I WILL BE, TOO.
THEY HOPE THE PRESIDENT WILL
WAKE UP WITHIN A FEW DAYS.
IF AND WHEN HE DOES,
THEY MAY NOT KNOW
THE EXTENT OF THE DAMAGE
TO HIS BRAIN
FOR AT LEAST A COUPLE OF WEEKS,
MAYBE LONGER.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WE HAVE EXTENDED THE MANHUNT
FOR THE PERSON
OR PERSONS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE ATTACK
ON THE PRESIDENT.
I HAVE DIRECTED THE LEADERS
OF THE FBI, HOMELAND SECURITY,
AND THE CIA TO PURSUE
EVERY AVENUE,
RUN EVERY THREAT TO GROUND,
UNTIL WE HAVE CAPTURED
WHOEVER IS RESPONSIBLE
FOR THIS EVIL ACT.
(breaths heavily)
THE PERSON THEY'RE LOOKING FOR,
THE ONE THEY THINK
SHOT THE PRESIDENT--
THAT'S ME.
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
-- Captions by VITAC --
I'M GONNA NEED TO TALK TO
COLONEL JESSUP OVER AT M.D.W.
HE'S THE CHIEF OF CEREMONIES
AND SPECIAL EVENTS.
CALL D.H.S. AND JUSTICE.
(cell phone ringing)
TELL THEM TO BE HERE
AT 1:00 P.M. FOR A BRIEFING.
HOLD ON. WHAT?
YOU NEED TO GET BACK HERE.
I can't.
IN FACT, I'M STAYING ON
FOR A WHILE LONGER.
I'M NOT ASKING.
WHATEVER IT IS, DEAL WITH IT.
WHAT IS IT?
CAN'T SAY. OPEN LINE.
HARRISON, I'M IN THE MIDDLE
OF SOMETHING.
I will call you--
GET YOUR ASS BACK HERE NOW.
(cell phone beeps)
I'LL BE BACK IN AN HOUR.
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
HUCK.
I THINK SHE RELAPSED.
WE NEED TO FIND HER.
YOU HAVE TO HELP ME.
(voice echoing) I MESSED UP.
I'M IN TROUBLE, HUCK.
I MEAN, YOU HAVE TO COME.
SHE'S IN
A LOT OF TROUBLE.
WHEN DID BECKY CALL YOU?
OH. YESTERDAY OR THE DAY BEFORE.
I WAS TALKING TO QUINN.
IT WAS REGISTERED
TO VERNA THORNTON.
THE SUPREME COURT JUSTICE?
SHE'S ONE OF OLIVIA'S CLIENTS,
RIGHT?
(cell phone rings)
(ring)
(beep)
BECKY? WHAT'S WRONG?
SHE WAS CRYING, SCARED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO DO.
CAN YOU COME GET ME, PLEASE?
SHE GAVE ME A ROOM NUMBER,
AND I WENT.
TO THE STANWORTH.
ROOM 807.
UH, THE DOOR WAS OPEN.
(knock on door)
BECKY?
BUT SHE WASN'T THERE.
(beeps and whirs)
(multiple gunshots)
(crowd screaming)
I'M NEW TO THE FIELD OF
REMOTE-CONTROLLED SNIPER RIFLES.
IS THERE A TRADE MAGAZINE
THEY SEND OUT TO ENTHUSIASTS,
PSYCHOPATHS, ASSASSINS?
THERE'S A CAMERA
IN THE SCOPE.
THE MOVEMENT OPERATES
ON A RADIO SIGNAL.
IT'S THE SAME TECHNOLOGY YOU USE
TO FLY MODEL AIRPLANES.
YOU CAN FIND IT AT ANY
TOY STORE, ELECTRONICS STORE.
IT'S UNTRACEABLE.
WHAT'S ITS RANGE?
DEPENDS ON
IF THEY BOUNCE THE SIGNAL.
IT COULD BE 50 FEET.
IT COULD BE 2 STATES AWAY.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
WHAT I'M TRAINED TO DO.
I COULDN'T FIND
THE FIFTH CARTRIDGE,
BUT I COULDN'T SPARE
ANOTHER SECOND,
SO I RAN DOWN THE STAIRS
AND SNUCK OUT
OF THE SERVICE ENTRANCE.
(alarm blaring)
WHY DISABLE THE GUN?
WHY TAKE IT?
IF SOMEONE FOUND YOU WITH IT--
IT COULD HELP US FIND WHO DID
THIS AND WHO TOOK BECKY.
EVERY GUN HAS A STORY.
WHAT DID YOU DO WITH IT?
SO THAT'S THE...
THAT'S THE GUN
THAT SHOT THE PRESIDENT.
(Intel Mnemonic)
DJ'ing is all about connecting.
♪
To people.
To rhythms.
I'm deaf.
But I've always been
able to feel the bass.
Now, I can feel it in
a whole new way.
It doesn't matter that
I can't hear the music.
Touch...it matters.
The HP Envy 4 Touchsmart
Ultrabook...
with Intel Core i3 processor.
Ultrabook. Inspired by Intel.
Only at Best Buy. Only from HP.
♪ Target REDcard...
♪ Save 5% and get...
♪ free shipping!
♪ It's On. Hit the sale.
♪ Hallelujah.
Grab Your REDcard. ♪
♪ Hallelujah!
♪
IT'S FINALLY HERE...
...THE PETSMART
COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS SALE.
SAVE UP TO 50% ON
ALL PETHOLIDAY® PRODUCTS,
DECEMBER 13TH
THROUGH THE 24TH.
AND HELP HOMELESS PETS
WHEN YOU PURCHASE
CHANCE & LUCKY GIFT CARDS!
AT PETSMART®.
YOUR MOUTH HAS BEEN
SIPPING, SNACKING, YELLOWING.
NUTCRACKING, GIFT STACKING,
YELLOWING.
MISTLETOE'ING, HO HO HO'ING,
AND EVERY HOLIDAY SEASON,
YOUR TEETH HAVE BEEN YELLOWING.
FACT IS IF YOU'RE NOT
WHITENING, YOU'RE YELLOWING.
CREST 3D WHITE WHITESTRIPS
REMOVE OVER 10 YEARS OF STAINS,
AND WHITEN 25 TIMES BETTER
THAN A LEADING
WHITENING TOOTHPASTE.
CREST.
LIFE OPENS UP WHEN YOU DO.
IN A HURRY?
TRY 2 HOUR EXPRESS WHITESTRIPS,
JUST IN TIME
FOR A WHITE HOLIDAY.
♪ One for You.
♪ And one for me.
♪ You, you, you, you, you...
♪ TV for Jack.
♪ Sweaters for Nancy.
♪ I'm blown away...
I'm freaking out... ♪
♪ Deals, deals, deals!
♪ It's On, it's on, it's on,
♪ The Finish Your List Sale.
REBECCA FLYNN--
BORN JANUARY 17, 1982.
FREELANCE GRAPHIC DESIGNER.
WORKS OUT OF A SHARED SPACE
ON 9th STREET.
ATTENDS A.A. MEETINGS
AT A CHURCH ON FLORIDA AVENUE.
IT'S WHERE WE MET.
SHE'S AN ALCOHOLIC?
COCAINE.
YOU'RE AN ALCOHOLIC?
I HAVE AN ADDICTION,
BUT NOT TO DRUGS OR ALCOHOL.
(Olivia) WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU SAW HER?
THURSDAY MORNING.
YOU'VE KNOWN HER FOR HOW LONG?
THREE MONTHS.
HUCK, I KNOW YOU LOVE THIS GIRL,
BUT I HAVE TO ASK--
IS THERE ANY CHANCE SHE WAS
INVOLVED IN SETTING YOU UP?
NO.
I'M TRAINED TO DETECT LYING,
AND ALL THAT ASIDE, I KNOW HER.
I KNOW SHE WOULD
NEVER DO THAT TO ME.
NEVER. SHE'S IN TROUBLE.
SOMEONE GRABBED HER
TO LURE HER TO THAT HOTEL.
THEY KNEW I WOULD COME FOR HER.
SOMEONE HAS HER.
SOMEONE PROFESSIONAL
WHO KILLS FOR A LIVING,
WHO'S GOOD ENOUGH TO DO IT
WITH A REMOTE SNIPER RIFLE.
SOMEONE LIKE YOU?
THAT'S WHAT YOU MEAN, RIGHT?
SOMEONE LIKE YOU.
QUINN.
I NEED TO FIND BECKY BEFORE
THEY DECIDE SHE'S DISPOSABLE.
AND...
SHE'S A NICE PERSON.
I NEED TO FIND HER.
OKAY. SO WE FIND HER,
CONNECT THE DOTS,
FIND OUT WHO SHE TALKED TO,
WHERE SHE WENT.
I'M GOING, TOO.
NO. YOU STAY HERE.
THERE'S NO WAY IN HELL.
YOU'RE THE MOST WANTED MAN
IN AMERICA.
THE FBI HAS SKETCHES OF YOU
EVERYWHERE. YOU STAY HERE.
YOU DO NOT MOVE.
YOU DO NOT LEAVE THIS OFFICE.
HUCK, LOOK AT ME.
LOOK AT ME.
DO NOT LEAVE THIS OFFICE.
THE FBI SKETCH IS BASED
ON ONE INDIVIDUAL'S DESCRIPTION
ON WHAT IS BEING DESCRIBED
THUS FAR
AS A PERSON OF INTEREST
IN THE EVENTS SURROUNDING
THE SHOOTING OF PRESIDENT GRANT
AND BRITTA KAGEN.
FOR FURTHER DETAILS
ON THE INVESTIGATION,
I'D LIKE TO TURN THE PODIUM OVER
TO THE ATTORNEY GENERAL
AND HER TEAM OF INVESTIGATORS.
(camera shutters clicking)
DAVID.
THE SKETCH IS THE RESULT
OF AN EYEWITNESS
WHO SAW THE SUSPECT
WITH A RED HOODIE
PULL THE FIRE ALARM
ON THE EIGHTH FLOOR.
WE ARE GOING THROUGH
HOTEL SECURITY FOOTAGE NOW
TO LOOK FOR LEADS.
FACIAL RECOGNITION SOFTWARE IS
BEING USED
TO SEEK A MATCH
WITH EVERY RECORD AVAILABLE.
I'M LEAVING
THE CABINET BRIEFINGS
AND THE WHITE HOUSE SCHEDULE
ON YOUR DESK.
ALSO THE MINUTES FROM
YESTERDAY'S N.S.A. MEETINGS.
I FIGURE I WOULD PATCH YOU
INTO THE WHITE HOUSE
FOR ANY INTEL UPDATES.
DON'T BOTHER.
JUST BECAUSE
PRESIDENT LANGSTON--I'M SORRY.
JUST BECAUSE THAT WOMAN
KICKED YOU OUT OF YOUR OFFICE,
DOESN'T MEAN YOU CAN'T MOVE
TO ANOTHER OFFICE
IN THE WHITE HOUSE.
I HAVE ANOTHER OFFICE, MARY.
YOU'RE STANDING IN IT.
AND I'M NOT LEAVING HERE
UNTIL PRESIDENT GRANT--
THE ONLY PRESIDENT
OF THIS GREAT NATION--
LEAVES HIS HOSPITAL BED.
(telephone ringing)
(woman) ...THAT THE SHOOTER
MOST LIKELY HAS...
ARE YOU GETTING THAT?
NO.
MARY.
THAT'S YOUR HOME PHONE.
I DON'T ANSWER YOUR HOME PHONE.
BECAUSE UNLIKE YOU,
I STILL WORK AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
(door opens)
(ring)
OKAY. (mutters)
HELLO?
MRS. NOVAK?
NO. I'M NOT AT WORK.
(coughs)
YES, I... (sighs)
YES, I KNOW
WITH EVERYTHING THAT'S GOING ON,
YOU WOULD THINK THEY NEED ME,
BUT THEY DON'T.
SO I HAVE TIME TO TALK TO
MY VERY FAVORITE MOTHER-IN-LAW.
YES, I HOPE THE PRESIDENT
PULLS THROUGH, TOO.
NO. JAMES ISN'T HERE RIGHT NOW.
HE'S AT WORK.
YEAH. THEY NEED HIM AT WORK.
DID YOU WANT ME
TO GIVE HIM A MESSAGE?
HIS NEXT VISIT? I DON'T KNOW.
PROBABLY NOT FOR A WHILE.
BECAUSE HE WAS JUST UP THERE
LAST WEEKEND.
JAMES DID NOT COME AND VISIT YOU
AND HIS DAD THIS PAST WEEKEND?
NO.
I GUESS THAT'S MY MISTAKE.
YES.
I'LL HAVE HIM CALL AS SOON
AS HE GETS BACK HOME.
I'M STANDING IN YOUR CUBICLE.
WHERE ARE YOU?
OH, MY DAD'S HAVING
ONE OF THOSE DAYS
WHERE HE THINKS
I'M HIS UNCLE KRYSTOF.
I'M SORRY TO HEAR THAT.
ANYTHING I CAN DO?
NO. IF IT'S OKAY WITH YOU,
THOUGH,
I THINK I'LL SPEND
THE NIGHT HERE.
NO. NO. OF COURSE.
YEAH. WHATEVER YOU NEED.
THANKS.
BYE.
(beep)
JAMES.
DAVID, HEY.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
YOU TOLD ME LAST NIGHT YOU FOUND
SOMETHING IN OHIO, BUT YOU
DIDN'T SAY WHAT IT WAS, AND NOW
YOU'RE NOT RETURNING MY CALLS.
IS IT SOMETHING ABOUT CYTRON?
LOOK, I-I REALLY CAN'T TALK
ABOUT THIS RIGHT NOW.
WHY?
BECAUSE IT'S COMPLICATED,
ESPECIALLY--
ESPECIALLY IN LIGHT OF THIS.
THE ASSASSINATION ATTEMPT?
I KNOW THAT IT SOUNDS VAGUE,
BUT YOU JUST HAVE TO TRUST ME.
FINE. BUT IF IT HAS
ANYTHING TO DO
WITH THE PRESIDENT GETTING SHOT,
ANYTHING AT ALL--
YOU'LL BE THE FIRST TO KNOW.
MADAM PRESIDENT,
I AM HUMBLED
AND TRULY HONORED
TO STAND BEFORE
THE FIRST FEMALE PRESIDENT
OF THESE UNITED STATES.
VERY KIND.
MA'AM, I'M NOT ONE TO
SPEAK OUT OF SCHOOL, BUT--
OH, WELL, HELL--
EXCUSE MY FRENCH.
WE BOTH KNOW IF I'M BREATHING,
I'M SPEAKING OUT OF SCHOOL,
BUT IT'S MY PURE BELIEF
YOU DIDN'T GET YOUR PROPER DUE
AS V.P.
THERE. SAID.
WELL, MY POSITION HAS HAD
ITS, UH, CHALLENGES.
NOW CAN WE GET
TO YOUR BUSINESS, HOLLIS?
WHATEVER STRETCH
THE ALMIGHTY HAS IN MIND
FOR YOU TO NOW LEAD
THIS GREAT LAND--
BE IT A WEEK, A MONTH,
OR LONGER--
YOU WERE PUT HERE
FOR A PURPOSE,
SURE AS HE MADE THE WORLD.
AND THAT PURPOSE IS TO MAKE
YOURSELF SOME HISTORY.
THAT IS,
IF YOU'RE SO INCLINED.
MIGHT BE TIME TO PAY A VISIT
TO VERNA THORNTON.
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
NOTHING KNOCKED OVER
OR EVEN ASKEW.
IF BECKY WAS ABDUCTED,
IT WASN'T FROM HERE.
STILL HOLDING?
THE PRESIDENT WAS SHOT. THEY'RE
A LITTLE BUSY AT JUSTICE.
BUT DON'T WORRY. MY GUY'S SOLID.
OWES ME BIG-TIME.
YEAH, JIM. LISTEN, THAT SECURITY
FOOTAGE AT THE STANWORTH HOTEL
BEFORE AND AFTER THE SHOOTING--
I'M GONNA NEED A COPY.
SO I'M GONNA HAVE TO CALL IN
THAT FAVOR.
DUDE, I MADE THAT D.U.I.
GO AWAY. I SAVED YOU 12 GRAND.
NO, THIS IS EXACTLY
THE KIND OF THING
PEOPLE MEAN WHEN THEY SAY,
"I OWE YOU."
WAIT. WAIT.
(beep)
HE HUNG UP.
WOW. MR. BIG TIME.
THEY'RE ON LOCKDOWN.
THEY'RE NOT RELEASING ANYTHING
TO ANYONE FOR ANY REASON.
I MAY HAVE SOMEONE
I CAN CALL.
(keyboard keys clicking)
ANY LUCK WITH
THE HOTEL SECURITY FEED?
UH, THE FBI PULLED IT. I'M
SEEING IF THEY HAVE IT CACHED.
(sighs) SO I GUESS
WE'RE BOTH PATSIES THEN.
ME FOR THE CYTRON EXPLOSION,
YOU FOR SHOOTING THE PRESIDENT.
MAKES YOU WONDER
IF THEY'RE RELATED.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I MEAN, WHOEVER SET ME UP
FOR THE CYTRON EXPLOSION
MUST'VE BEEN PRETTY UNHAPPY
I SLIPPED THROUGH THEIR FINGERS.
IF THEY KNEW YOU WERE THE GUY
WHO TOOK ME,
FIRST OF ALL, THEY'D BE PISSED,
BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
IF THEY DID THEIR HOMEWORK,
THEY'D KNOW YOU WERE EX-CIA,
AND WHO BETTER TO PIN
AN ASSASSINATION ON
THAN SOMEONE WHO'S BEEN TOSSED
ASIDE BY THE GOVERNMENT?
SO WHO WERE THEY, HUCK?
WHO SET ME UP?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU DON'T KNOW
BECAUSE YOU NEVER ASKED
OR YOU DON'T KNOW
BECAUSE YOU'RE STILL
PRETENDING IT WASN'T YOU
WHO FLEW ME CROSS-COUNTRY
IN VERNA THORNTON'S JET
AND DUMPED ME IN A D.C. HOTEL
ROOM WITH A BRAND-NEW IDENTITY?
I NEVER ASKED.
(computer beeping)
A WOMAN TELLS YOU TO KIDNAP
SOMEONE AND YOU DON'T ASK WHY?
IS OLIVIA POPE REALLY WORTH
THAT KIND OF LOYALTY?
MY GIRLFRIEND IS MISSING,
AND I'M TRYING TO FIND HER.
ARE YOU GONNA HELP ME OR NOT?
(typing on keyboard)
HEY.
HOTEL SECURITY FOOTAGE
FOR THE LAST 72 HOURS.
(sets flash drive down)
THANKS.
(door opens and closes)
I MEAN, BECKY'S ONLY BEEN
AT HER JOB FOR THREE MONTHS.
HER CREDIT CARDS--
ALL OPENED THREE MONTHS AGO.
AND GET THIS, SHE'S BEEN
DATING HUCK FOR EXACTLY...
THREE MONTHS.
ABBY, WHAT IS IT?
SHE WENT INTO THE HOTEL
ALONE.
WELL, SHE COULD HAVE BEEN
MEETING HER DEALER UPSTAIRS.
NO WAY TO TELL.
SECURITY CAMERAS ON THE EIGHTH
FLOOR WERE ALL MESSED WITH.
HUCK, I CHECKED HER PHONE.
NO CALLS TO OR FROM ANY DEALERS
OR ANYONE, FOR THAT MATTER.
ONLY YOU, HUCK.
FOR THE ENTIRE THREE MONTHS
SHE HAD THAT PHONE,
SHE ONLY CALLED YOU.
THAT DOESN'T PROVE ANYTHING.
SHE WAS GETTING SOBER.
SHE LEFT HER WHOLE LIFE BEHIND
AND MOVED HERE TO GET SOBER.
SHE DOESN'T HAVE
A LOT OF FRIENDS.
WE CHECKED HER BANK STATEMENTS.
SHE KEPT EXACTLY THE AMOUNT SHE
NEEDED TO PAY RENT AND UTILITIES
IN THAT ACCOUNT.
NEVER WROTE ANY OTHER CHECKS.
HUCK...
BECKY DOESN'T EXIST.
YES, SHE DOES.
SHE SET YOU UP, HUCK.
NO, SHE'D NEVER DO THAT.
I'M SORRY.
YOU MADE A MISTAKE.
I'M GONNA FIND HER.
OLIVIA SAID
YOU DON'T LEAVE HERE.
WHO'S GONNA STOP ME?
I AM A TRAINED KILLER.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND THAT?
YOU LEAVE HERE,
YOU GOTTA GO THROUGH ME.
YOU MISSED SOMETHING.
YOU ARE WRONG ABOUT BECKY,
SO YOU ARE OF NO HELP TO ME.
NONE OF YOU.
I'M TAKING CARE OF THIS
MYSELF.
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(thudding)
(hollow thud)
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(projector clicks)
(click)
AND EDDY SAID THE TOYS
NIMIGHT NOT BE READY!MAS
EDDY?
THE ELF!
♪
[ Radio Announcer ]
TODAY'S FORECAST:
IT'S SNOWING SNOWBALLS
AND SNOW BRICKS OUT THERE...
SEVEN MORE DAYS
AND IT'S SNOWING SNOW BRICKS!
OH, WELL, BE CAREFUL!
[ Radio Announcer ]
ONLY TWO DAYS TO GO,
AND SEVERAL OF THE ELVES
WERE TOSSED AROUND
WHEN THEY TRIED TO WRAP A PONY.
[ Female Announcer ] THE
Keepsake Countdown ORNAMENT.
BUILD ANTICIPATION EVERY DAY
TILL CHRISTMAS.
ELVES TRIED TO WRAP
A PONY!
Well, it's that time of year
again.
You know, picture-taking season.
And with Photo Stream,
You can share all the photos you
want,
With just the people you want.
It's as easy as pie.
Mmmm .. pie.
♪
THANK YOU.
FOR WHAT?
WHEN THINGS WERE TOUGH,
YOU KEPT BELIEVING IN ME...
YOU HELPED
MAKE THIS HAPPEN.
THANK YOU.
[ Jane ] BEHIND EVERY OPEN HEART
IS A STORY.
TELL YOURS WITH MY OPEN HEART
COLLECTION AT KAY JEWELERS,
THE NUMBER ONE JEWELRY STORE
IN AMERICA.
THERE ARE MILLIONS OF REASONS
TO GIVE ONE,
BUT THE MESSAGE
IS ALWAYS THE SAME.
KEEP YOUR HEART OPEN...
AND LOVE WILL ALWAYS
FIND ITS WAY IN.
YOU DID IT, DADDY.
WE DID IT.
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
AND WITH MY BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CREDIT CARD,
I LOVE 'EM EVEN MORE.
I EARN 1% CASH BACK EVERYWHERE,
EVERY TIME.
2% ON GROCERIES.
3% ON GAS.
AUTOMATICALLY.
NO HOOPS TO JUMP THROUGH.
THAT'S 1% BACK ON...
[ toy robot sounds ]
2% ON PUMPKIN PIE.
AND APPLE.
3% BACK ON 4 TRIPS
TO THE AIRPORT.
IT'S AS EASY AS...
-[ man ] 1...
-[ woman ] 2...
[ woman ] 3.
[ Male Announcer ]
THE BANKAMERICARD
CASH REWARDS CARD.
APPLY ONLINE OR AT
A BANK OF AMERICA NEAR YOU.
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
MADAM PRESIDENT.
HELLO, JUSTICE THORNTON.
I HEARD YOU WERE FEELING
UNDER THE WEATHER.
THOUGH "UNDER THE WEATHER"
REALLY DOESN'T QUITE COVER IT,
DOES IT?
IS THERE SOMETHING
I CAN DO FOR YOU?
YOU CAN TAKE CARE
OF YOURSELF,
FOR YOUR OWN GOOD,
FOR THE GOOD OF THE COUNTRY.
YOU CAN FOCUS ON YOUR HEALTH,
CONCENTRATE YOUR ENERGIES
ON GETTING BETTER.
SUCH A STRESSFUL JOB
CAN'T BE GOOD FOR YOU
AT A TIME LIKE THIS.
I AM NOT STEPPING DOWN
FROM THE BENCH.
JUSTICE THORNTON, YOUR PRESIDENT
IS MAKING A REQUEST OF YOU.
WOULDN'T BE PATRIOTIC
NOT TO ACQUIESCE.
YOU'RE GONNA BE PRESIDENT
FOR ABOUT THE NEXT 15 MINUTES
AND THEN YOUR TIME
WILL BE DONE,
AND I WILL BE STILL BE
ON THE BENCH.
IF I HAVE TO RULE FROM
THE CONFINES OF AN IRON LUNG,
I WILL BE ON THE BENCH.
THE SEAT YOUR BUTT IS FILLING
ON THE SUPREME COURT
BELONGS TO ME TO FILL
AS I SEE FIT.
IT WAS PROMISED TO ME
DURING THE CAMPAIGN.
IT IS MINE,
AND I MEAN TO HAVE IT,
AND FOR SOMEONE OTHER THAN
A LEFT-WING, BABY-KILLING,
HOMOSEXUAL LOVING, GODLESS
CREATURE SUCH AS YOURSELF.
I WANT IT NOW,
AND YOU WILL GIVE IT TO ME,
BECAUSE IF YOU DON'T,
I WILL LEAK TO ONE OF
YOUR LIBERAL MEDIA PAPERS
THAT YOU HAVE TERMINAL CANCER,
THAT YOU HAD TERMINAL CANCER
DURING
THE CONFIRMATION HEARINGS,
THAT YOU LIED BY OMISSION
ABOUT HAVING TERMINAL CANCER
TO THE AMERICAN PEOPLE,
THAT THE DRUGS COURSING
THROUGH YOUR SYSTEM--
INCLUDING THE MEDICAL MARIJUANA
PILLS YOU TAKE AT NIGHT--
MAY POSSIBLY HAVE CLOUDED
YOUR JUDICIAL JUDGMENT.
I WILL CALL INTO QUESTION EVERY
DECISION YOU HAVE EVER MADE
FROM THE BENCH OF
THE HIGHEST COURT IN THE LAND.
I WILL DISGRACE YOU
IN THE EYES OF YOUR PEERS
AND IN THE ANNALS OF HISTORY.
I WILL RUIN WHAT LITTLE TIME
YOU HAVE LEFT ON THIS EARTH,
AND I WILL BE RIGHT TO DO SO
BECAUSE IT IS
THE GOD'S HONEST TRUTH.
STEP DOWN FROM THE BENCH,
VERNA.
I'M ASKING YOU NICELY.
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
IT'S NICE THAT YOU CAME HOME
FOR LUNCH.
WELL, I HAVE TO ADMIT,
I WAS A LITTLE WORRIED
ABOUT WHAT I MIGHT FIND
WHEN I CAME HOME.
I MEAN, IT'S BEEN FOUR HOURS
WITHOUT A POLITICAL HIT
IN YOUR VEINS.
THOUGHT YOU MIGHT BE HUDDLED
IN THE CORNER,
MAINLINING C-SPAN AND TRYING
TO SNORT SHREDDED PIECES
OF THE CONGRESSIONAL RECORD
UP YOUR NOSE.
BUT YOU'RE FINE.
OH, I'M GOOD. I'M VERY GOOD.
A LITTLE TIME OFF WAS
JUST WHAT I NEEDED.
SO...
H-HOW DID YOU SAY
YOUR DAD WAS DOING?
HMM?
YOUR DAD.
YOU HAD TO SPEND THAT NIGHT
AT HIS HOUSE THE OTHER DAY.
AND WE NEVER HAD A CHANCE
TO TALK ABOUT IT,
BECAUSE, WELL,
ALL HELL BROKE LOOSE
WITH FITZ AND THE SHOOTING,
SO I WAS WONDERING, HOW IS
YOUR FATHER DOING? BETTER?
WORSE?
OH, ABOUT THE SAME, I GUESS.
THIS COULD REALLY USE
SOME MUSTARD. YOU WANT?
NO, I'M GOOD.
THERE. THAT'S HIM.
SAME RED SWEATSHIRT AS THE MAN
SEEN PULLING THE FIRE ALARM.
AND HE'S HEADING UP
TO THE EIGHTH FLOOR,
WHICH IS WHERE THE SHOTS
WERE FIRED FROM.
BUT NO CLEAR ANGLE
ON HIS FACE?
NO CLEAR ANGLE ON HIS FACE,
AND THE CAMERAS ON THE EIGHTH
FLOOR WERE TAMPERED WITH,
SO WE DON'T HAVE ANY FOOTAGE OF
HIM FROM THERE. HOWEVER, MA'AM,
IF YOU'LL FOCUS YOUR ATTENTION
BACK ON THE MONITOR...
THERE. SEE? HE PICKS UP
THAT WOMAN'S CELL PHONE.
AND PRESUMABLY LEFT
HIS FINGERPRINTS ON IT.
HAVE YOU LOCATED
THE WOMAN YET?
WE'RE LOOKING FOR HER NOW.
HUCK'S FINGERPRINTS--
FIND OUT IF THEY'RE
IN ANY GOVERNMENT DATABASES.
OKAY, BUT FIRST--
The FBI has
SECURITY FOOTAGE OF HUCK
PICKING UP SOMEONE'S PHONE
IN THE HOTEL ELEVATOR.
OKAY, BUT--
If they find the phone,
they'll have
HIS PRINTS,
SO WE NEED TO KNOW
IF THEY'LL BE ABLE
TO MATCH THEM.
If that's the case, we track
down this woman and take
HER PHONE BEFORE THE FBI
CAN GET THEIR HANDS ON IT.
LIV, HUCK'S GONE.
WHAT?
(girls speaking indistinctly)
(girls laugh)
SUNDAYS IS PASTA
AND MONDAYS IS SANDWICHES,
BUT TONIGHT--
TONIGHT'S MY FAVORITE NIGHT.
THEY EAT PIZZA
AND THEY PLAY GAMES.
THAT'S THE BEST PART.
IT'S GAME NIGHT.
SHE'S CAROL, 34,
NOT A NATURAL BLONDE,
BUT THAT'S OKAY.
SHE TEACHES MATH
AT THE JUNIOR HIGH.
AND HE'S BILLY.
HE SELLS SPORTING GOODS,
WHICH IS AN ACTUAL THING--
SPORTING GOODS.
(chuckles)
AND THE LITTLE GIRLS
ARE LUCY--SHE'S 8,
AND SARAH BETH--SHE'S 10.
SO WHAT ABOUT YOU?
WHAT DO YOU LIKE TO DO?
(Billy chuckles)
LET ME GET THAT.
(rustling)
(gun cocks)
HI, HUCK.
♪
McDonald's TENDER,
JUICY Chicken McNuggets
IN SPICY BUFFALO
AND CREAMY RANCH SAUCE.
JUST $4.99 FOR 20 OF YOUR
FAVORITE Chicken McNuggets.
MORE WAYS TO LOVE McNuggets.
♪
NESPRESSO.
WHERE I NEVER HAVE TO COMPROMISE
ON ANYTHING.
♪
WHERE JUST ONE TOUCH
CREATES THE PERFECT COFFEE.
WHERE EVERY CAPPUCCINO AND LATTE
IS ONLY MADE WITH FRESH MILK.
AND WHERE THE STAFF
IS EXCEPTIONALLY FRIENDLY.
♪
NESPRESSO. WHAT ELSE?
WHAT, YOU'RE NOT SPEAKING
TO ME NOW?
YOU SET ME UP.
YEAH, I SET YOU UP.
WHO HIRED YOU?
YOU KNOW I CAN'T
TELL YOU THAT.
PROFESSIONAL ETHICS.
GAL'S GOTTA HAVE STANDARDS.
WHO ARE YOU?
I'M BECKY,
LIKE
"REBECCA OF SUNNYBROOK FARM."
NICE TO MEET YOU,
HUCK OF "HUCKLEBERRY FINN."
IS TODAY THE DAY
I'M GONNA DIE?
BECAUSE I'D LIKE TO KNOW
AHEAD OF TIME.
I'M NOT HERE TO KILL YOU.
WHY WOULD I KILL YOU?
WE'RE THE SAME, YOU AND ME.
EXCEPT THAT I SHOT
THE PRESIDENT. THAT'S A BIG JOB.
YOU WANT ME TO GO DOWN
FOR THIS.
COME ON. DON'T YOU THINK IF I
WANTED YOU TO GO DOWN FOR THIS,
YOU'D BE IN LOCKDOWN
IN THE DEEPEST, DARKEST HOLE
IN GITMO BY NOW?
SWEETIE, I COULD'VE PAID
FOR THAT HOTEL ROOM
WITH YOUR CREDIT CARD.
I COULD'VE SPREAD YOUR D.N.A.
ALL OVER THAT PLACE.
I COULD'VE KILLED YOU,
MADE IT LOOK LIKE
YOU SHOT THE PRESIDENT
AND THEN YOURSELF. BUT I DIDN'T.
I WAS SUPPOSED TO,
BUT I DIDN'T.
HOW COME?
BECAUSE I LIKE YOU, HUCK.
YOU SHOT THE PRESIDENT.
SO?
BECKY--
YOU WERE IN B613.
YOU KILLED THREE WORLD LEADERS.
MADE 'EM LOOK LIKE
HEART ATTACKS,
BUT STILL, THREE.
I SHOOT ONE A FEW TIMES,
AND YOU'RE SUDDENLY
BETTER THAN ME?
WHAT,
I THOUGHT YOU WERE IN A.A.
BECAUSE YOU LIKE
TO COLLECT CHIPS?
YOU LIKE TO KILL PEOPLE.
IT'S WHAT YOU DO.
IT'S WHO YOU ARE.
LOOK, YOU'RE MAD RIGHT NOW
BECAUSE I HAD YOU,
BECAUSE YOU LET YOUR GUARD DOWN,
AND I FOOLED YOU.
BUT, HUCK,
YOU'RE MISSING THE POINT.
WE'RE ALIKE. YOU'RE LIKE ME.
WE'RE THE SAME.
WE'RE BUILT FOR EACH OTHER.
SO YOU CAN SIT HERE EVERY NIGHT
AND WATCH YOUR LITTLE FAMILY
EAT THEIR SANDWICHES,
OR YOU CAN COME WITH ME.
COME WITH ME.
I'M LEAVING TOWN.
WE COULD GO ON THE RUN,
DO THE WHOLE
BONNIE-AND-CLYDE-FOR-HIRE THING.
JUST YOU AND ME.
THINK ABOUT IT, HUCK.
(kisses)
YOU KNOW WHERE TO FIND ME.
(car door opens)
(car door closes)
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(doorbell rings)
'94 du BELLAY
CHATEAUNEUF du PAPE.
WOW. WHAT'S THE OCCASION?
MY HUSBAND IS
CHEATING ON ME.
WHAT DID HE SAY?
I'M NOT ASKING HIM.
HE'S LYING TO ME
ABOUT VISITING HIS PARENTS.
HE LOVES YOU.
HE'S MUCH YOUNGER THAN ME
AND VERY HANDSOME
AND A BIT OF A SLUT.
(laughs) CYRUS.
BEFORE HE MET ME,
HE WAS A BIT OF A SLUT,
WHICH I FOUND VERY SEXY,
AND I SHOULDN'T HAVE,
BECAUSE NOW MY YOUNG,
HANDSOME, SLUTTY HUSBAND
IS CHEATING ON ME, AND I AM
GOING TO GROW OLD ALONE.
YOU DON'T KNOW FOR SURE
HE'S CHEATING.
(chuckles)
I WILL KNOW FOR SURE
AS SOON AS MY PRIVATE
INVESTIGATOR GETS BACK TO ME.
YOU HIRED A P.I. ON HIM?
WOULDN'T YOU?
YEAH.
I AM GOING TO GROW OLD
ALONE.
I'M MAKING LISTS--
OF FITZ'S FAVORITE SONGS,
BANDS HE LOVES,
POEMS HE'S QUOTED,
BIBLE VERSES THAT SEEM TO FIT
HIS PERSONALITY,
HYMNS HE LIKES.
SALLY HAS ME
PLANNING HIS FUNERAL.
MELLIE'S LET ME VISIT HIM
EXACTLY ONCE,
THEN SHE REVOKED
MY PRIVILEGES.
I MAY NOT EVEN
GET TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
I'M GONNA SAY THIS ONCE,
AND I BETTER NOT EVER
HAVE TO SAY IT AGAIN...
DON'T YOU EVER AGAIN
SUGGEST TO ME
THAT FITZGERALD THOMAS GRANT III
IS GOING TO DIE.
THAT IS UNACCEPTABLE
COMING FROM YOU.
HE CALLS YOU
THE LOVE OF HIS LIFE.
DON'T YOU DARE
GIVE UP ON HIM.
(whispers) YEAH.
W--
DO YOU WANNA WATCH
THE NEWS?
YES.
MM-HMM.
SURE.
(man speaking indistinctly)
YOU ARE NOT GOING
TO GROW OLD ALONE.
YOU'RE NEVER ALONE.
I'M HERE.
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
IT'S BLACKMAIL.
THAT BIBLE-THUMPING BITCH IS
BLACKMAILING ME,
AND I DON'T WANT
TO GIVE IN TO HER. I WON'T.
BUT I HAVE EVERY INTENTION
OF LIVING LONG ENOUGH TO RESIGN
WHEN THERE'S A LEGITIMATE
PRESIDENT IN OFFICE.
FITZ IS A LEGITIMATE PRESIDENT.
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN.
I'M TALKING ABOUT--
HE'S LYING IN A HOSPITAL ROOM,
FIGHTING FOR HIS LIFE,
AND HE HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH HOW HE GOT ELECTED.
HE'S A PATRIOT
AND HE'S LEGITIMATE.
WE'RE BOTH IN HOSPITAL ROOMS.
(sighs)
KARMA'S A FUNNY THING.
WE'RE PAYING THE PRICE
FOR WHAT WE DID.
LIV, IS THERE ANY WAY
OUT OF THIS WITH SALLY?
ANYTHING I CAN DO TO KEEP HER
FROM BLACKMAILING ME?
YOU CAN RESIGN.
STEP DOWN FROM THE BENCH.
LIV--
IT'S THE ONLY WAY IF YOU WANT
TO KEEP YOUR LEGACY INTACT.
YOU SPEND THE TIME
YOU HAVE LEFT
WITH YOUR FAMILY,
YOUR GRANDKIDS.
OH, THAT SOUNDS NICE.
I'VE BEEN SEEING PICTURES
OF THAT FELLOW WEARING
THE RED HOODIE ALL DAY.
HE LOOKS A LOT LIKE HUCK.
HUH.
LIKE I SAID,
KARMA'S A FUNNY THING.
(keys jangle)
♪
(keys jangle and thud)
(sighs)
I'LL LEAVE WITH YOU.
REALLY?
YEAH, WE'RE THE SAME.
WE'RE BUILT THE SAME.
I LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
WHAT'S YOUR REAL NAME?
DOES IT MATTER?
NO, IT DOESN'T.
JUST GIVE ME AN HOUR
TO GET MY STUFF.
I'LL MEET YOU AT OUR SPOT?
OKAY.
♪
IT'S FINALLY HERE...
...THE PETSMART
COUNTDOWN TO CHRISTMAS SALE.
SAVE UP TO 50% ON
ALL PETHOLIDAY® PRODUCTS,
DECEMBER 13TH
THROUGH THE 24TH.
AND HELP HOMELESS PETS
WHEN YOU PURCHASE
CHANCE & LUCKY GIFT CARDS!
AT PETSMART®.
Online Outfit
Piccolo
Headphones
Buy Now
Broadway Show
Megapixels
Place to Sleep
Little Roadster
War and Peace
Deep Sea Diving
Ninja App
Hipster Glasses
5% cash back
Sign up to get 5% everywhere
online through December. Only
from Discover.
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
JUST TELL ME.
DON'T SUGARCOAT IT. HOW LONG
HAS IT BEEN? IS IT SERIOUS?
DID YOU TAKE PICTURES?
I LOOKED INTO IT. YOUR HUSBAND'S
NOT SEEING ANYONE ON THE SIDE.
(exhales)
OH, THANK GOD.
THE NUMBER ON YOUR PHONE BELONGS
TO A GUY NAMED DAVID ROSEN.
DAVID ROSEN?
HE'S AN ASSISTANT
U.S. ATTORNEY,
WHO, BY THE WAY,
IS STRAIGHT.
JUST GOT DUMPED BY SOME REDHEAD.
HE'S TAKING IT REALLY HARD.
ANYWAY, HE'S BEEN CALLING JAMES
FOR SOME KIND OF INFORMATION,
AND AS FAR AS I CAN TELL,
JAMES HASN'T GIVEN HIM ANYTHING.
LOOK, I DON'T MEAN TO BE RUDE,
BUT I'M AN ARTIST.
I'M AN INNOVATOR
IN MY FIELD.
THE RETAINER YOU'RE PAYING ME
IS GENEROUS,
BUT MAYBE DON'T CALL ME UP
EVERY TIME YOUR HUSBAND
TAKES A BUSINESS TRIP TO SOME
TINY LITTLE TOWN IN OHIO.
WHAT TOWN...
IN OHIO?
WHICH TINY LITTLE TOWN
DID HE VISIT?
DEFIANCE, NEAR TOLEDO.
AND HE CHARGED IT TO HIS EXPENSE
ACCOUNT--WORK, NOT PERSONAL.
(exhales deeply)
KEEP WATCHING HIM.
I'LL PAY YOU
WHATEVER YOU WANT.
(tires peal)
I TRACKED DOWN THE WOMAN
FROM THE HOTEL ELEVATOR.
THAT'S GOOD NEWS.
UNFORTUNATELY,
SO DID THE FBI.
THEY GOT HER
AND THE PHONE HE PICKED UP.
WE WERE TOO LATE. I'M SORRY.
So not-so-good news.
(cell phone beeps)
(rings and beeps)
HUCK, WHERE ARE YOU?
(indistinct conversations)
ARE YOU INSANE?
GO BACK TO THE OFFICE.
IT'S NOT SAFE FOR YOU HERE.
I PROMISED I'D SAY GOOD-BYE.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
I WAS IN THE HOTEL ROOM.
PEOPLE SAW ME.
I DON'T CARE.
YOU DIDN'T DO IT.
DOESN'T MATTER.
PEOPLE SAW ME.
IF THEY WANT TO HANG ME
FOR THIS, THEY WILL.
WHAT?
SHE GOT TO YOU, DIDN'T SHE?
NO.
SHE DID.
YOU FOUND HER,
AND SHE GOT TO YOU.
HUCK, SHE SHOT THE PRESIDENT.
NOT JUST THAT,
SHE SHOT THE PRESIDENT,
AND SHE FRAMED YOU FOR IT.
SHE WAS DOING HER JOB.
HER JOB? HUCK, THIS ISN'T
JUST ABOUT YOU ANYMORE.
IT'S ABOUT A MAN
LYING IN A HOSPITAL BED
BECAUSE YOUR GIRLFRIEND
SHOT HIM IN THE HEAD,
A WOMAN WHO'S CLEARLY USING YOU
TO PROTECT HERSELF.
AND IF YOU CAN'T SEE THAT,
YOU'RE BLIND. HUCK--
DON'T TOUCH ME.
DO I TELL YOU WHO TO LOVE?
NO.
SO DON'T TELL ME.
(indistinct conversations
continue)
...UP INDEPENDENCE AVENUE,
SWINGING BACK ON PENNSYLVANIA.
MS. POPE.
WE'RE JUST DISCUSSING
POSSIBLE ROUTES
FOR THE FUNERAL PROCESSION.
WE'RE OPERATING
ON THE ASSUMPTION
THAT THE BODY WOULD LIE IN STATE
IN THE CAPITOL ROTUNDA.
TRADITION CALLS FOR 24 HOURS
FOR PUBLIC VISITATION.
YES, OF COURSE.
THEN THERE IS THE QUESTION
OF OPEN CASKET OR CLOSED.
I'LL TAKE THAT QUESTION
TO THE FIRST LADY.
AS FAR AS MILITARY PRESENCE
AND PROTOCOL AT THE SITE,
IF YOU'LL TURN TO PAGE SEVEN,
YOU'LL SEE WE'VE ARRANGED
A 21-GUN SALUTE,
AS WELL AS SIX HONOR GUARDS
TO FOLD THE CASKET'S FLAG
BEFORE PRESENTING IT
TO THE FIRST LADY.
(volume fades)
WE'VE ALSO CONFIRMED
A MISSING MAN AERIAL FLYOVER
BY THE U.S. AIR FORCE.
(speaking inaudibly)
HAVE YOU THOUGHT ABOUT PUTTING
THE CASKET OUTDOORS?
HE LOVES BEING OUTDOORS.
BECKY'S MEETING ME IN AN HOUR.
AS SOON AS SHE LEAVES
HER APARTMENT,
WAIT TEN MINUTES,
THEN GO IN, AND PLANT THE GUN.
COPY THAT. HUCK?
YES?
YOU'RE DOING THE RIGHT THING.
DON'T GO IN BEFORE
THE TEN MINUTES ARE UP.
HALF THE TIME PEOPLE THINK
they've forgotten something
and come back.
(beep)
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(door closes)
I'M HOME.
CYRUS?
WHAT ARE YOU--
DID YOU COOK ALL THIS?
I ORDERED IT
FROM A RESTAURANT.
WELL,
YOU SET THE TABLE AND--
AMALIA SET THE TABLE.
SHE'S OFF TODAY,
BUT I MADE HER COME IN
AND SET THE TABLE,
WHICH IS--I'M A REPUBLICAN
OVERLORD, I KNOW, BUT--
CYRUS BEENE.
BUT THERE'S A REASON.
MM.
WHAT DID YOU DO?
A BABY WAS BORN
AT COUNTY GENERAL THIS EVENING
AT 5:42 P.M--
A GIRL.
5 POUNDS, 11 OUNCES.
WE CAN BRING HER HOME
IN A WEEK, IF...
YOU SAY YES.
YOU STOLE A BABY?
I DID NOT--
YOU BOUGHT A BABY?
I PULLED SOME STRINGS
AND GOT US
TO THE FRONT OF THE LINE,
WHICH IS WRONG, VERY WRONG.
BUT LIKE I SAID,
I'M A REPUBLICAN OVERLORD,
AND YOUR DREAM IS A BABY,
SO...
(chuckles)
AND NOW YOU'RE THINKING
"WHY NOW?"
WHEN I DIDN'T WANT A BABY
BEFORE, WHY NOW?
SOMEONE SH--
SHOT MY BEST FRIEND.
HE'S LYING IN A HOSPITAL BED
DYING,
WHICH MAKES ME DENYING US
A CHANCE TO START A FAMILY
SEEM LUDICROUS.
SO THERE'S A BABY GIRL
IN COUNTY GENERAL,
AND IF YOU SAY YES, IN ONE WEEK,
SHE COULD BE OUR DAUGHTER.
WE CAN--
YES.
YOU KNOW
I'LL GO BACK TO WORK SOON.
YES. THIS IS OUR BABY.
WHICH MEANS
YOU'LL NEED TO STAY HOME.
YES.
YOU'LL HAVE TO QUIT YOUR JOB
BECAUSE ONE PARENT
SHOULD BE AT HOME.
I'M NOT GONNA STOP
SAYING YES.
HEY.
YES?
YES.
YES. YES.
YES. (kisses)
OKAY. COME HERE.
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(crickets chirping)
(dog barking in distance)
(beeps)
(error tone)
(woman) THE NUMBER
YOU HAVE REACHED--
202-555-0186--
HAS BEEN DISCONNECTED.
(barking)
(Huck) Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
(Harrison) Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
Becky's meeting me
in an hour.
As soon as she leaves
her apartment,
wait ten minutes,
then go in, and plant the gun.
Copy that.
HE IS A GOOD LITTLE MONKEY
AND ALWAYS VERY CURIOUS.
ONE DAY GEORGE GOT
AN IMPORTANT LETTER.
HE'S BUILT A ROCKET SHIP
TO TRAVEL INTO SPACE."
GOOGLE, HOW FAR IS EARTH
TO THE MOON?
THE MOON IS 238,900 MILES...
"THE GREAT MOMENT HAD COME."
3, 2, 1...
[ GIGGLING ]
SURE. CAKE OR PIE?
PIE.
APPLE OR CHERRY?
CHERRY.
OIL OR CREAM?
CREAM.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] THE SOUND OF
REDDI-WIP IS THE SOUND OF JOY.
♪
she doesn't
Even though our really get us.
And she'll never know
who we are, or what...
No way,
Madden Girls??
Nike!
Who's your mommy now?
Famous brands. Famously easy.
Famous Footwear.
Victory is Yours.
PRESIDENT GRANT'S
FUNERAL PLANS,
PENDING
THE FIRST LADY'S APPROVAL.
HMM.
WHY A RIDERLESS HORSE
DURING THE FUNERAL PROCESSION?
IT SYMBOLIZES A WARRIOR
WHO RIDES NO MORE.
AND THE BOOTS REVERSED
IN THE STIRRUPS?
THEY REPRESENT A FALLEN LEADER
LOOKING BACK ON HIS TROOPS
FOR THE LAST TIME.
NICE JOB.
HOPEFULLY,
WE WON'T HAVE TO USE IT.
BY THE WAY, DID THE FBI
MANAGE TO GET
A PRINT
OFF THAT WOMAN'S CELL PHONE?
THEY DID.
BUT IT WAS ONLY A PARTIAL,
WHICH IS AS GOOD AS NOTHING
WITHOUT A SUSPECT IN CUSTODY.
ANYTHING ELSE?
NO. GOOD NIGHT,
MADAM PRESIDENT.
GOOD NIGHT.
OLIVIA.
SO YOU FINALLY GOT
A PRESIDENT THAT'LL DO
YOUR BIDDING.
DIDN'T YOUR MAMA EVER TEACH YOU
TO SHARE?
WE'RE SUPPOSED TO BE
IN THIS TOGETHER. WE HAD A DEAL.
AM I THE POT OR THIS KETTLE
IN THIS HERE DEALIO?
YOU TOOK DOWN VERNA.
YOU DREW FIRST BLOOD.
YOU AND VERNA TURNED ON ME
WHEN YOU CONSPIRED TO SAVE
LINDSAY DWYER BEHIND MY BACK.
I BELIEVE EVERYTHING
THAT COMES AFTER NOW,
WELL, THAT'S JUST WHAT THEY
CALL... (whispers) FAIR GAME.
YOUR BOY REALLY WENT CRAZY
TONIGHT.
HE STOPPED BY TWO BABY STORES.
AT THE FIRST PLACE,
HE MADE THE CLERK EXPLAIN
HOW TO PUT IN A CAR SEAT.
IT WAS... THRILLING.
WHERE IS HE NOW?
PROBABLY STILL AT THE BABY
STORE. YOU WANT ME TO GO BACK?
THAT'S OKAY.
YOU CAN STOP WATCHING HIM.
AT LEAST FOR NOW.
THE SLOW NIPPLES WORK
FOR MOST NEWBORNS.
IS IT A BOY OR A GIRL?
A GIRL.
CONGRATULATIONS.
THANKS.
IF YOU HAVE ANY QUESTIONS,
I'LL BE RIGHT AROUND THE CORNER.
THANK YOU.
OKAY. WHERE WERE WE?
SOMETHING ABOUT THE NATIONAL
ELECTION BEING RIGGED,
WHICH YOU SAY YOU CAN PROVE.
YES, WHAT I CAN'T PROVE IS WHO
ON THE GRANT TEAM KNEW ABOUT IT.
DOES YOUR HUSBAND KNOW
YOU'RE LOOKING INTO THIS?
HE OFFERED ME A BABY.
HE HATES BABIES.
SO HE KNOWS.
HE'LL BE WATCHING YOU.
WHICH IS WHY I NEED YOU
TO TAKE THIS.
AND THIS IS?
THE MEMORY CARD I STOLE FROM
THE VOTING MACHINE IN DEFIANCE.
LOSE IT AND WE BUNGLE
THE BIGGEST STORY
SINCE WATERGATE.
KEEP IT...
AND WE BRING DOWN AN ENTIRE
ADMINISTRATION TOGETHER.
I NEED TO GO.
YEAH.
SEE YOU.
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(keys jangle)
(sets glasses down)
(unzips zipper)
(panting)
(door closes)
(projector and camera shutter
clicking)
MADAM PRESIDENT, SUPREME COURT
JUSTICE VERNA THORNTON
IS HERE TO SEE YOU.
YOU'RE LOOKING WELL.
YES, I AM.
ARE YOU HERE TO DELIVER
YOUR LETTER OF RESIGNATION?
I DO HAVE IT, HOWEVER...
HOWEVER?
HOWEVER, I WOULD LIKE TO OFFER
YOU SOMETHING ELSE INSTEAD.
I'M NOT SURE THERE IS
ANYTHING I WANT FROM YOU,
OTHER THAN YOUR SEAT
ON THE BENCH, SO--
NOT EVEN THE NAME
OF THE MAN IN THE RED HOODIE?
I COULD GIVE YOU
MY LETTER OF RESIGNATION
OR I COULD GIVE YOU THE NAME
OF THE MAN WHO TRIED TO KILL
THE PRESIDENT.
THE MOST WANTED MAN
IN THE WORLD,
YOUR OSAMA bin LADEN.
ONE PILL MAKES YOU LARGER.
ONE PILL MAKES YOU SMALL.
YOU NEED TO COME HERE.
HUCK NEEDS YOU.
HE KEEPS SAYING THAT SHE KILLED
HIS FAMILY.
Do you know what that means?
What family?
HUCK, YOU NEED TO LISTEN TO ME
RIGHT NOW.
SHE WILL NOT GET AWAY WITH THIS.
WE WILL FIND HER.
I DON'T KNOW WHY WE'RE NOT
TELLING THE FBI ABOUT BECKY.
WON'T DO ANY GOOD.
SHE'S IN THE WIND.
SO? THEY COULD MOBILIZE
THOUSANDS OF AGENTS
TO LOOK FOR HER.
THEY COULD GET THE WHOLE COUNTRY
LOOKING FOR HER.
IT TOOK THE WHOLE COUNTRY
TWO YEARS TO FIND YOU,
AND YOU WEREN'T EVEN
A SUPERSPY.
ALSO, IF THEY START
LOOKING INTO BECKY,
THEY'LL EVENTUALLY FIND
A HUCK CONNECTION.
THE FBI ONLY HAS
A PARTIAL PRINT.
AS LONG AS THEY CAN'T MATCH IT
TO HIM, HE'S SAFE.
I CAN'T WATCH THIS.
(gasps)
SHH.
WHERE IS HE?
(thud)
(man) GET ON THE FLOOR!
GET ON THE FLOOR NOW!
(Olivia) WHAT ARE YOU--
(man speaking indistinctly)
(man) DO NOT MOVE!
(handcuffs click)
WHAT'S THE CHARGE?
THIS MAN IS BEING HELD
UNDER THE P.A.T.R.I.O.T. ACT.
(projector and camera shutter
clicks)
♪
[Spider-Man]
WE GOT THIS.
♪
[Mom]
THIS HERO STUFF IS EASY!
.
>> DEVOURED BY FLAMES.  COME UP
NEXT.  EAST BAY BUSINESS GUTTED
BY MASSIVE FLIER.  WE TAKE YOU
LIVE TO THE SCENE.
>> MASSIVE SABER ATTACK MAY
COMING SOON.  WHAT YOU
CONDITION DID TO PROTECT YOUR
BANK ACCOUNTS.  STAY WITH US.
7 NEWS BEGI