>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS "WORLD
NEWS NOW."
>>> ISN'T IT FUNNY WE LEFT HERE
FRIDAY THINKING THE BIGGEST
STORY HAD TO DO WITH TAX CUTS
AND SPENDING CUTS AND FISCAL
CLIFFS.
NO LONGER SEEMS TO BE THE CASE.
WHAT A DIFFERENCE 72 HOURS
MAKES.
A DIFFERENT COUNTRY ON THIS
MONDAY MORNING.
GOOD MORNING, EVERYONE, I'M ROB
NELSON.
>> AND I'M SUNNY HOSTIN.
PAULA FARIS IS ON ASSIGNMENT.
AFTER THE INITIAL SHOCK AND THE
WEEKEND VIGILS, IT'S TIME FOR
PARENTS TO SEND THEIR CHILDREN
BACK TO SCHOOL.
WHAT DO YOU TELL YOUNG CHILDREN
ABOUT THEIR SAFETY AND CONFRONT
THEIR FEARS?
WE'LL GET SOME EXPERT ADVICE
RIGHT HERE IN JUST A MOMENT.
>>> ALSO THIS MORNING, AFTER SO
MANY MASS SHOOTINGS IN THE
RECENT YEARS, THERE'S A RENEWED
CALL FOR TIGHTER GUN CONTROL,
EVEN THOUGH THE VAST MAJORITY OF
GUN OWNERS ARE LAW ABIDING.
>> I THINK NOW WE'RE GOING TO
REALLY BE FOCUSED, I THINK, ON
GUN -- JUST REFORM.
IT'S SORT OF FRONT OF MIND FOR
EVERYONE NOW.
>> A TIPPING POINT EVENT.
ABSOLUTELY.
>>> LATER THIS HALF HOUR, HOW DO
YOU CELEBRATE CHRISTMAS AFTER A
MASSACRE AT AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
PUT YOUR SMALL TOWN ON THE MAP?
WE'LL SEE HOW NEWTOWN IS TRYING
TO HEAL.
>>> BUT FIRST, NEWTOWN BEGINS
SAYING GOODBYE TO THE VICTIMS
TODAY WITH FUNERALS FOR TWO
6-YEAR-OLDS.
JACK PINTO AND NOAH POZNER.
>> PRESIDENT OBAMA REMEMBERED
THOSE LITTLE BOYS ALONG WITH ALL
THE OTHERS WHO DIED DURING AN
EMOTIONAL SPEECH LAST NIGHT.
ABC'S MARK GREENBLATT IS IN
NEWTOWN WITH MORE FROM THAT
VIGIL.
GOOD MORNING, MARK.
>> Reporter: WELL, GOOD MORNING.
THE PRESIDENT CAME HERE TO
NEWTOWN TO GRIEVE WITH A
COMMUNITY THAT HAS LOST SO MUCH.
AND TELL THE REST OF AMERICA
THAT HE HOPES THAT WE CAN ALL
LEARN FROM WHAT HAPPENED HERE.
>> SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT,
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME WE'VE
COME TOGETHER TO COMFORT A
GRIEVING COMMUNITY TORN APART BY
MASS SHOOTINGS.
>> Reporter: MORE THAN 900
PEOPLE PACKED INTO NEWTOWN HIGH
SCHOOL FOR AN EMOTIONAL
INTERFAITH SERVICE.
THEY CAME TO REMEMBER LOVED ONES
LOST IN THE SHOOTINGS AND LEFT
WITH THE MESSAGE THAT THOSE WHO
DIED MAY HELP LEAD AMERICA TO
BECOME BETTER AND SAFER FOR
OTHERS.
>> THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
AND TO END THEM, WE MUST CHANGE.
IN THE COMING WEEKS I'LL USE
WHATEVER POWER THIS OFFICE HOLDS
IN AN EFFORT AIMED AT PREVENTING
MORE TRAGEDIES LIKE.
THIS>> Reporter: THE ENTIRE
COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN HAS
TRANSFORMED INTO ONE GIANT
MEMORIAL, WITH FLOWERS, TEDDY
BEARS AND CANDLES NOW PILING UP
AT A CONTINUOUS PACE SEEMINGLY
EVERYWHERE HERE.
>> THERE'S NO WAY YOU CAN BE
LIVING AND THIS DOESN'T AFFECT
YOU.
>> Reporter: INVESTIGATORS ARE
STILL TRYING TO FIND OUT WHAT
PROMPTED 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA
TO SHOOT HIS OWN MOTHER MULTIPLE
TIMES IN THE FACE BEFORE
CONTINUING HIS KILLING SPREE AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
WHILE THIS TOWN TRIES TO BEGIN
HEALING, ONE MAJOR FOCUS IS ON
HELPING ITS YOUNGEST SURVIVORS
FIND HOPE AGAIN, SO THEIR LIVES
DO NOT BECOME DEFINED BY ONE
MOMENT OF TERROR.
AND THE PRESIDENT SAYS TONIGHT
THAT HE BELIEVES THAT OUR
SOCIETY WILL BE JUDGED BASED ON
HOW WELL WE PROTECT OUR CHILDREN
AND SAYS HE'LL USE ALL THE
POWERS OF THE PRESIDENCY IN
ORDER TO MAKE SURE AMERICA DOES
A BETTER JOB IN THE FUTURE.
LIVE IN CONNECTICUT, MARK
GREENBLATT, BACK TO YOU.
>> ANYTHING ANYONE CAN IMAGINE
THE ANGUISH THAT TOWN IS
EXPERIENCING AND THINGS WILL
ONLY GET WORSE THROUGHOUT THIS
WEEK.
27 FUNERALS TO GO THROUGH IN
THIS TRAGEDY.
WHAT DO WE KNOW ABOUT WHEN THEY
BEGIN?
>> Reporter: IT'S REALLY SUCH A
GRIM TASK AND IT BEGINS IN A FEW
HOURS.
THE FIRST TWO FUNERALS SCHEDULED
TO BEGIN LATER TODAY.
>> MARK, IT'S THE HOLIDAYS TOO.
SO HOW IS THE MOOD IN NEWTOWN?
>> Reporter: CLEARLY HERE, THE
HOLIDAYS HAVE REALLY JUST
CHANGED REMARKABLY.
IF YOU GO INTO TOWN, NOT TOO FAR
FROM WHERE WE'RE STANDING,
YOU'LL SEE CANDLES, YOU'LL SEE
PEOPLE COMING OUT.
IT'S A GIGANTIC MEMORIAL THIS
TOWN SEEMS TO BE TURNING INTO.
KIND OF A BEAUTIFUL THING TO
WATCH A COMMUNITY COME TOGETHER
DURING A DIFFICULT TIME.
>> AND MARK, I THINK EVERYONE
HAS HAD AN EMOTIONAL REACTION TO
THIS, INCLUDING THE PRESIDENT.
VERY WAS EMOTIONAL DURING THAT
NEWS CONFERENCE ON FRIDAY, WE
SAW SOME EMOTION DURING HIS
SPEECH LAST NIGHT.
HE SAID HE'S GOING TO FIGHT NOW
TO MAKE SOME KIND OF POLITICAL
CHANGE IN LIGHT OF WHAT'S
HAPPENED HERE.
ANY SENSE OF WHEN THAT'S COMING
OR WHAT THOSE CHANGES MAY BE?
>> Reporter: WELL, HE'S TALKING
ABOUT HE REALLY WANTS TO ENGAGE
THE NATION IN AN ONGOING
DIALOGUE.
NOT A LOT OF DETAILS IN EXACTLY
WHAT HE'S GOING TO BE DOING.
BUT IF YOU LISTEN TO ALL OF THE
POLITICIANS THAT HAVE BEEN
TALKING, FIRST ON THE SUNDAY
MORNING SHOWS OVER THE WEEKEND,
IT SEEMS EVERYONE IS SAYING
SOMETHING HAS TO GIVE HERE.
ANYBODY THAT'S BEEN AGAINST
REFORMING SOME OF THE GUN
CONTROL DEBATES THAT HAVE BEEN
GOING ON, THEY SEEM TO BE QUIET
RIGHT NOW.
>> MANY THANKS TO ABC'S MARK
GREENBLATT, LIVE FOR US IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
THANKS A LOT, MARK.
>>> AND TWO COMMUNITIES THAT
KNOW FIRST HAND THE HEARTBREAK
OF A MASS SHOOTING ARE OFFERING
SUPPORT FOR CONNECTICUT.
FAMILIES AND VICTIMS OF THE
VIRGINIA TECH MASSACRE IN 2007
RELEASED A STATEMENT OFFERING
CONDOLENCES TO THE TOWN.
AND THE SIKH TEMPLE IN WISCONSIN
OPENED ITS DOORS TO ANYONE
WANTING TO JOIN A PRAYER
SERVICE AND CANDLE LIT VIGIL
HONORING THE LATEST VICTIMS.
SIX PEOPLE WERE KILLED WHEN A
GUNMAN BURST INTO THAT TEMPLE
AND OPENED FIRE BACK IN AUGUST.
>>> AND IN WASHINGTON, ADVOCATES
FOR GUN CONTROL HELD A VIGIL
OUTSIDE THE WHITE HOUSE.
THE GROUP IS DEMANDING TOUGHER
LAWS RESTRICTING ACCESS TO GUNS
AND WHO CAN OWN THEM.
WHITE HOUSE OFFICIALS SAY THAT
DISCUSSION IS COMING, AS
EVIDENCED BY PRESIDENT OBAMA'S
COMMENTS DURING LAST NIGHT'S
SERVICE THERE IN NEWTOWN.
>>> THIS IS THE FOURTH MASS
SHOOTING SINCE PRESIDENT OBAMA
TOOK OFFICE.
LAST NIGHT HE MADE IT CLEAR GUN
CONTROL IS ABOUT TO BECOME A TOP
PRIORITY OF HIS ADMINISTRATION.
BUT DESPITE NATIONAL OUTRAGE
AFTER EACH TRAGEDY, THE NUMBER
OF GUNS IN AMERICA IS SOARING.
HERE'S ABC'S CORRESPONDENT
PIERRE THOMAS.
>> Reporter: ON BLACK FRIDAY,
U.S. SHOPPERS WERE NOT JUST
BUYING TOYS AND ELECTRONICS,
THEY WERE ALSO BUYING GUNS IN
RECORD NUMBERS.
ON THAT SINGLE DAY, THE FBI DID
COMPUTERIZED BACKGROUND CHECKS
ON MORE THAN 154,000 PURCHASES
OF FIREARMS.
AND IN NOVEMBER ALONE, AMERICANS
TRIED TO BUY A WHOPPING 2
MILLION GUNS.
HERE ARE SOME FACTS THAT MIGHT
SURPRISE YOU.
THERE ARE MORE REGISTERED GUN
DEALERS AND STORES THAN MAJOR
SUPERMARKETS.
MORE GUN SELLERS THAN McDONALD'S
RESTAURANTS.
THE OVERWHELMING MAJORITY OF GUN
USERS ARE LAW ABIDING CITIZENS.
BUT AUTHORITIES TELL ABC NEWS
THE MILLIONS OF GUNS ALREADY IN
CIRCULATION GUARANTEE THAT
DISTURBED PEOPLE WILL BE ABLE TO
OBTAIN THEM.
EVEN IN QUIET COMMUNITIES LIKE
NEWTOWN.
WE SPOKE TO THE ATF ON-SCENE
COMMANDER.
ROUGHLY HOW MANY GUN DEALERS ARE
IN THERE AREA?
>> THERE ARE ABOUT 400 GUN
DEALERS IN A FOUR-COUNTY AREA.
JUST WITHIN TEN MILES OF THE
INCIDENT, THERE ARE 36 GUN
DEALERS.
>> Reporter: POLICE BELIEVE THE
GUNS ADAM LANZA USED WERE BOUGHT
LEGALLY.
>> IN AMERICA, UNLESS YOU HAVE A
FELONY CONVICTION OR YOU'RE
ADJUDICATED BY A COURT TO BE
MENTALLY INCOMPETENT, YOU HAVE
ACCESS TO FIREARMS.
>> Reporter: LANZA JOINS THE
RANKS OF MASS SHOOTERS.
SO HOW DO YOU KEEP WEAPONS FROM
MEN LIKE THESE, WHEN THERE ARE
AN ESTIMATED 200 MILLION PLUS
GUNS ALREADY IN CIRCULATION?
PIERRE THOMAS, ABC NEWS.
>>> LAWMAKERS AND ADVOCATES FOR
GUN CONTROL HAVE WASTED NO TIME
FOR SPEAKING OUT.
BUT FOR NOW, THE NATIONAL RIFLE
ASSOCIATION SEEMS TO BE SILENT
THE SOCIAL MEDIA SAVVY GROUP HAS
NOT TWEETED OR POSTED ANYTHING
ON ITS FACEBOOK PAGE SINCE THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTINGS.
IN FACT, THE NRA'S FACEBOOK PAGE
WAS TAKEN DOWN A DAY AFTER IT
BOASTED REACHING 1.7 MILLION
LIKES.
>> I WAS WATCHING SOME OF THE
SUNDAY SHOWS AND THERE WAS ONE
PROGRAM WHERE THEY SAID THEY
INVITED 31 PRO-GUN RIGHT
SENATORS ON THE SHOW TO BE PART
OF THE PANEL DISCUSSION AND NOT
A SINGLE ONE ACCEPTED THE
INVITATION.
>> THAT'S REMARKABLE TO ME.
>> IT IS.
>> TYPICALLY, THE REACTION WHEN
SOMETHING LIKE THIS HAPPENS IS
WELL, IF THERE WERE MORE GUNS,
THEN THIS TYPE OF THING WOULDN'T
HAPPEN.
SO FOR EXAMPLE, IF THE SECURITY
GUARD AT THE SCHOOL HAD A GUN,
THIS WOULDN'T HAVE HAPPENED.
IF THE TEACHERS HAD GUNS, THIS
WOULDN'T HAVE HAPPENED.
SO I'M SURPRISED THE NRA HAS
BEEN SO SILENT.
THESE GUN ENTHUSIASENTHUSIASTS,
SURPRISED THEY HAVE BEEN SILENT.
>> I THINK THEY KNOW ALL THE PRO
GUN RIGHTS THAT OBVIOUSLY FOR
CLEAR REASONS, EMOTIONS ARE RAW
RIGHT NOW.
TEMPERS ARE HIGH, FRUSTRATION IS
HIGH.
AND SO THEY'RE LAYING LOW.
BUT THE THING IS, THE PRESIDENT
MADE IT VERY CLEAR.
SOME LEGISLATION IS COMING.
WHETHER IT SUCCEEDS OR NOT IS A
DIFFERENT STORY.
>> SENATOR DIANNE FEINSTEIN
INTENDS TO INTRODUCE AN ASSAULT
WEAPONS BAN ON THE FIRST DAY OF
THE NEXT CONGRESS.
THIS IS GOING TO HAPPEN VERY
QUICKLY.
>> IT IS HAPPENING.
>>> IN OTHER NEWS THIS MORNING,
IN THE WAKE OF THE NEWTOWN
TRAGEDY, THE PREMIERE OF THE TOM
CRUISE MOVIE HAS BEEN POSTPONED.
THE FILM IS ABOUT A GUNMAN ON A
DEADLY SHOOTING SPREE.
THE PREMIERE WAS SCHEDULED TO
TAKE PLACE SATURDAY IN
PITTSBURGH WHERE IT WAS SHOT,
BUT IT WAS CALLED OFF OUT OF
HONOR AND RESPECT FOR THE FAMILY
OF THE VICTIMS.
"JACK REACHER" IS SCHEDULED TO
OPEN THIS FRIDAY.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, OUR COVERAGE
OF THE NEWTOWN TRAGEDY DOES NOT
END HERE.
WE'LL HEAR ABOUT ONE CLASSROOM'S
LONE SURVIVOR AND HOW SHE MADE
IT OUT ALIVE.
>> REMARKABLE STORY.
>>> HOLIDAY HEARTACHE.
THE ATTEMPT TO OBSERVE CHRISTMAS
IN A TOWN FILLED WITH SO MANY
EMOTIONS.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
MANY EMOTIONS.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
3Q
Lysol believes no toilet
is complete,
until it's completely clean.
Lysol Toilet Bowl Cleaner
gives you maximum coverage
from the rim down to
the water line
to kill 99.9% of germs.
And removes stains better
than Clorox Toilet Bowl Cleaner
with Bleach.
So if you want to do
the whole job,
Lysol's got you covered.
Lysol.
Mission for Health.
And for an incredibly clean
and fresh bowl with every flush,
try the No Mess Automatic
Toilet Bowl Cleaner.
>>> ONE FIRST GRADER WHO
SURVIVED THE MASSACRE FACES AN
UNIMAGINABLE BURDEN.
>> THE GUNMAN ENTERED THE
CLASSROOM AND KILLED EVERYONE IN
IT EXCEPT HER.
ABC'S LARA SPENCER SPOKE WITH
HER FAMILY'S PASTOR.
>> Reporter: YOU HAVE ONE
PARISHIONER WHO WAS RIGHT THERE,
A LITTLE GIRL.
A FIRST GRADER.
>> SHE WAS THE FIRST STUDENT WHO
RAN OUT OF THE SANDY HOOK
SCHOOL, 6 1/2 YEARS OLD.
SHE RAN OUT OF THE SCHOOL
BUILDING COVERED IN BLOOD AND
THE FIRST WORDS SHE SAID TO HER
MOM WHEN SHE GOT OUTSIDE, MOMMY,
I'M OKAY, BUT ALL OF MY FRIENDS
ARE DEAD.
>> Reporter: WAS SHE THE ONLY
CHILD IN THAT CLASSROOM WHO
SURVIVED?
>> YES.
OF THOSE WHO WERE LEFT IN THE
CLASSROOM OF FIRST GRADERS, SHE
WAS THE LONE SURVIVOR.
>> Reporter: WHAT DID SHE TELL
HER MOM, WHAT DID SHE SEE IN
THERE?
>> SHE SAW SOMEONE WHO SHE FELT
WAS ANGRY AND SOMEBODY WHO SHE
THOUGHT WAS VERY MAD.
>> Reporter: HOW AT 6 1/2 YEARS
OLD CAN YOU BE THAT SMART AND
BRAVE?
>> I THINK IT'S IMPOSSIBLE
OUTSIDE OF DIVINE INTERVENTION.
SHE HAS WISDOM BEYOND HER YEARS.
>> Reporter: HOW ARE THE MOM AND
DAD DOING?
>> I THINK AS WELL AS YOU CAN
EXPECT THEM TO DO.
>> Reporter: AND THEY MUST BE
RELIEVED TO HAVE THEIR CHILD.
BUT ON THE OTHER HAND --
>> YES, THE MOM TOLD ME, AND I
THOUGHT THIS WAS VERY
INSIGHTFUL, THAT SHE WAS
SUFFERING FROM WHAT SHE CALLED
SURVIVOR'S GUILT.
BECAUSE SO MANY OF HER FRIENDS
NO LONGER HAVE THEIR CHILDREN
LONGER HAVE TRS.
HILDREN
BUT SHE HAS HERS.
>>> MANY STUDENTS MAY BE ANXIOUS
GOING BACK TO SCHOOL.
SO WHAT SHOULD PARENTS SAY AND
DO TO CALM THOSE FEARS?
JOINING US IS DR. HAROLD
KOPLEWICZ, DIRECTOR OF THE CHILD
MIND INSTITUTE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING US
THIS MORNING.
>> IT'S MY PLEASURE TO BE HERE.
>> WE HAVE SO MANY QUESTIONS, OF
COURSE.
I'M A PARENT.
I HAVE A FIRST GRADER AND A
FIFTH GRADER.
I STRUGGLED WITH WHETHER OR NOT
TO SPEAK TO BOTH OF THEM.
CAN YOU TELL OUR VIEWERS WHAT
AGE IS APPROPRIATE TO DISCUSS
THIS TERRIBLE TRAGEDY?
>> I THINK IT'S GOING TO DEPEND
ON THE PARTICULAR CHILD, BUT AT
LEAST 5 YEARS OF AGE IS THE
FIRST TIME YOU TALK TO THEM.
ONE OF THE THINGS WE LIKE IS FOR
PARENTS TO BREAK THE NEWS TO THE
KIDS.
SAY SOMETHING TERRIBLE HAPPENED
IN A SCHOOL, VERY FAR AWAY, NOT
SO FAR AWAY, AND BECAUSE THIS
TERRIBLE THING HAPPENED WHERE
KIDS WERE VERY BADLY HURT,
SCHOOL IS GOING TO BE SAFER NOW,
WHERE THERE ARE GOING TO BE MORE
PRECAUTIONS AT SCHOOL.
BUT TAKE THE CUE FROM THE CHILD,
SO YOUR INDIVIDUAL CHILD MIGHT
WANT TO KNOW MORE OR LESS, BUT
WHATEVER YOU DO, DON'T FORCE
THIS.
IT'S NICE FOR THEM TO KNOW YOU
TOLD THEM ABOUT IT, AND THEY
KNOW THAT THEY CAN KEEP COMING
BACK TO ASK MORE QUESTIONS.
>> WHAT ABOUT THE CHILD THAT IS
AFRAID TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL ON
MONDAY MORNING?
>> I THINK IT'S VERY IMPORTANT
TO GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
THAT MEANS YOU'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO REASSURE THEM AND TELL THEM
ABOUT THE SAFETY OF YOUR SCHOOL,
HOW RARE THESE KIND OF EVENTS
ARE.
AND IF NECESSARY, YOU'RE GOING
TO CHANGE YOUR SCHEDULE AROUND
AND DRIVE YOUR CHILD TO SCHOOL
OR WALK YOUR CHILD TO SCHOOL,
OR WALK YOUR CHILD TO SCHOOL
BECAUSE IT'S REALLY IMPORTANT
THAT WE WANT TO MODEL RESILIENCE
AND WE WANT OUR CHILDREN TO BE
RESILIENT.
WE DON'T WANT THIS TERRIBLE
EVENT TO HAVE MORE NEGATIVE
EVENTS ON CHILDREN WHO WON'T GO
BACK TO SCHOOL, BECAUSE GETTING
BACK INTO A ROUTINE IS ONE OF
THE BEST THINGS WE CAN DO FOR
CHILDREN.
>> WHAT IF YOU SEE, OR WHAT ARE
THE SIGNS OF TRAUMA IN A CHILD?
ALTHOUGH PARENTS I BELIEVE
CERTAINLY KNOW THEIR CHILDREN,
WE MAY NOT BE FAMILIAR WITH THE
SIGNS OF TRAUMA.
SO WHAT SHOULD WE BE LOOKING
FOR?
>> I THINK YOU'RE ABSOLUTELY
RIGHT.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO BE LISTENING
TO YOUR CHILD EVEN WHEN THEY'RE
NOT TALKING.
IF YOU HAVE A GREAT SLEEPER,
THEN THEY WANT TO SLEEP IN YOUR
BED OR THEY ARE VERY IRRITABLE
OR THEIR APITUTE HAS CHANGED OR
YOUR CHILD HAS MANY WORRIES THEY
NEVER HAD BEFORE THESE ARE THE
BEGINNING SIGNS OF AN ANXIETY
REACTION AND WE SHOULD WATCH
THAT.
BECAUSE IN A FEW WEEKS FROM NOW,
IF THESE THINGS DON'T DISAPPEAR,
THAT'S WHEN WE CALL IT TRAUMATIC
STRESS DISORDER.
>> LET'S SAY WE SEE THAT.
WHERE DO WE GET HELP FOR OUR
CHILDREN?
>> I THINK EVERY PARENT HAS TO
KNOW THEY COULD REACH OUT TO
THEIR PEDIATRICIAN.
THEY SHOULD REACH OUT TO
WEBSITES LIKE CHILDSMIND.ORG
WHERE THEY CAN GET
SCIENTIFICALLY SOUND
INFORMATION.
AND IF THEY STILL HAVE WORRIES,
THAT'S WHEN YOU MAKE AN
APPOINTMENT WITH YOUR DOCTOR AND
ASK THEM TWO WEEKS, THREE WEEKS
FROM NOW WHETHER OR NOT YOUR
CHILD YOU WOULD SEE A MENTAL
HEALTH PROFESSIONAL.
ONE OF THE TRAGEDIES OF THIS
EVENT IS THAT THIS WAS SOMEONE
WITH TERRIBLE SYMPTOMS THAT
WENT IGNORED AND DIDN'T GET THE
HELP THEY SO NEED AND WE DON'T
WANT CHILDREN SUFFERING BECAUSE
OF THIS EVENT UNNECESSARILY.
>> AND PERHAPS THIS WILL OPEN UP
THE DISCUSSION ABOUT MENTAL
HEALTH IN OUR CHILDREN.
>> CERTAINLY TIME FOR THAT
NATIONAL DISCUSSION.
>> I WOULD SAY SO.
FINDING DIRECTOR OF THE CHILD
MIND INSTITUTE, THANK YOU FOR
THAT ADVICE.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
♪
[ Male Announcer ]
SPONGES TAKE YOUR MARK.
[ Female Announcer ]
ONE DROP OF ULTRA DAWN
HAS TWICE THE EVERYDAY
GREASE CLEANING INGREDIENTS
OF ONE DROP OF THE LEADING
NON-CONCENTRATED BRAND...
TO CLEAN 2X MORE GREASY DISHES.
DAWN DOES MORE.
SO IT'S NOT A CHORE.
♪
>>> WELCOME BACK.
A SPONTANEOUS ROUND OF APPLAUSE
BROKE OUT BEFORE THE PROGRAM
NEWTOWN HIGH SCHOOL LAST NIGHT.
IT WAS THE TOWN'S FIRST
RESPONDERS ARRIVING.
>> FAMILY MEMBERS IN THAT ROOM
RUSHED TO GIVE THEM HUGS.
THEY WERE THE FIRST PEOPLE TO
SEE THE DEVASTATION INSIDE SANDY
HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
YOU CAN IMAGINE THE SCENE THEY
FOUND INSIDE.
>> FINALLY, THE SHOOTING AT
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
COMES AS THE HOLIDAYS ARE
APPROACHING.
THE TOWN STRUNG WITH LIGHTS AND
DECORATED WITH WREATHS.
>> AND NOW THE PEOPLE WHO LIVE
THERE ARE DETERMINED THAT THE
GUNMAN WHO TOOK SO MANY LIVES
DOES NOT TAKE THE SPIRIT OF
CHRISTMAS, AS WELL.
HERE'S ABC'S DAVID MUIR.
>> Reporter: AS YOU DRIVE
THROUGH THIS COMMUNITY, THEY'RE
EVERYWHERE.
THE SIGNS, HUG A TEACHER.
LOVE WILL GET US THROUGH.
THIS BENCH FULL OF ROSES.
THE SMALL CHURCH ON MAIN STREET,
TALKING WITH THE PASTOR.
BUT WHAT WE ALSO NOTICED WERE
THE MINIVANS, THE STATION WAGONS
CARRYING HOME CHRISTMAS TREES.
FAMILIES DETERMINED TO KEEP THIS
TRAGEDY FROM STEALING THE
HOLIDAY, TOO.
>> MORE THAN 40 YEARS YOU'VE
BEEN SELLING CHRISTMAS TREES
HERE.
JULIE SAYS THIS IS THE TOUGHEST
CHRISTMAS EVER.
SHE GOT A CALL FROM A FATHER ON
THE WAY TO HER TREE FARM.
>> I WANT TO PICK A TREE WITH
HER.
IT WILL BE A BITTER SWEET
CHRISTMAS.
I THINK FOR MANY, MANY PEOPLE.
>> AND FOR YOU, I CAN TELL.
INSIDE THE PHOTOS OF THE
FAMILIES WHO COME EVERY YEAR.
AND OUTSIDE, RIGHT THERE AT HER
FARM, THE COUNSELOR, THAT FIRST
RESPONDER WE MET WHO HELPED THE
PARENTS INSIDE THAT FIREHOUSE.
SHE'S TRYING TO KEEP HER
CHRISTMAS.
SO YOU'VE GOT THE SAW IN YOUR
HAND AND THE TREE ON THE TRUCK.
>> TREE ON THE TRUCK.
>> THERE THEY ARE.
>> Reporter: THE TREE ON THE
ROOF, THEIR FOUR DOGS INSIDE.
THEIR FAMILY DETERMINED TO KEEP
CHRISTMAS.
DAVID MUIR, ABC NEWS, NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> AND THIS CONVERSATION WILL
CONTINUE ALL THIS WEEK HERE AT
ABC NEWS ON EVERY ONE OF OUR
PROGRAMS AND AT ABCNEWS.COM.
>> THIS IS A NATIONAL
CONVERSATION.
WE WANT TO HELP FURTHER THINGS
ALONG, SO WE'LL OPEN UP A
DIALOGUE ABOUT GUNS, MENTAL
ILLNESS AND FINDING AN AGREEMENT
TO STOP THIS KIND OF VIOLENCE.
TRAGEDY AT SANDY HOOK, THE
SEARCH FOR SOLUTIONS ALL THIS
WEEK ON ABC NEWS.
CERTAINLY EVERYONE HAS A OPINION
AND A GUT REACTION.
HOPEFULLY THE DISCUSSION WILL
FURTHER AND GET SOME ANSWERS TO
WHAT'S BECOME A NATIONAL
EPIDEMIC OF VIOLENCE.
WE'LL HAVE MORE FROM ABC AFTER
THE BREAK.
I'M ONLY IN MY 60's...
I'VE GOT A NICE LONG LIFE AHEAD.
BIG PLANS.
SO WHEN I FOUND OUT
Medicare DOESN'T PAY
ALL MY MEDICAL EXPENSES,
I GOT A Medicare
SUPPLEMENT INSURANCE PLAN.
[ Male Announcer ] IF YOU'RE
ELIGIBLE FOR Medicare,
YOU MAY KNOW
IT ONLY COVERS ABOUT 80%
OF YOUR Part B
MEDICAL EXPENSES.
THE REST IS UP TO YOU.
CALL AND FIND OUT
ABOUT AN AARP Medicare
Supplement Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED Medicare
SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
IT COULD SAVE YOU THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
CALL NOW TO REQUEST
YOUR FREE DECISION GUIDE.
I'VE BEEN WITH MY DOCTOR
FOR 12 YEARS.
NOW I KNOW I'LL BE ABLE
TO STICK WITH HIM.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO VISIT
ANY DOCTOR OR HOSPITAL
THAT ACCEPTS Medicare PATIENTS.
PLUS, THERE ARE NO NETWORKS,
AND YOU NEVER NEED A REFERRAL.
SEE WHY MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
HAVE ALREADY ENROLLED
IN THE ONLY Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plans
ENDORSED BY AARP.
DON'T WAIT. CALL NOW.
>>> THIS MORNING ON THIS SPECIAL
EDITION OF "WORLD NEWS NOW,"
HEALING WORDS.
THE PRESIDENT LEADS A MEMORIAL
VIGIL IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> WE GATHER HERE IN MEMORY OF
20 BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN AND SIX
REMARKABLE ADULTS.
>> AS THE PRESIDENT, NATION AND
THE WORLD SEARCH FOR ANSWERS.
IT'S MONDAY, DECEMBER 17.
>> FROM ABC NEWS, THIS IS "WORLD
NEWS NOW."
>> GOOD MORNING.
I'M SUNNY HOSTIN IN FOR PAULA
FARIS.
>> AND I'M ROB NELSON.
WE WILL HEAR MORE ABOUT WHAT THE
PRESIDENT HAD TO SAY IN
CONNECTICUT LAST NIGHT.
SOME MOVING WORDS THERE IN THAT
SPEECH, PARTICULARLY TOWARDS THE
END WHERE HE RAMBLED OFF THE
NAMES OF THE 20 YOUNG LIVES.
YOU COULD HEAR THE CRIES IN THE
BACKGROUND, EVEN SEE HIM CHOKE
UP.
IT WAS A REMARKABLE SCENE LAST
NIGHT.
AS THE LONG HEALING PROCESS
BEGINS IN THAT NEW ENGLAND TOWN.
>>> ALSO, WE'LL TAKE A LOOK
INSIDE THAT CONNECTICUT SCHOOL
WHERE THIS MASSACRE TOOK PLACE
AND LET YOU KNOW WHY IT ACTUALLY
COULD HAVE BEEN EVEN WORSE.
EVEN THOUGH THE SCHOOL DISTRICT
PUT A REMARKABLE EMERGENCY PLAN
IN PLACE.
>>> ALSO THIS MORNING, TAKING
ACTION TO GET GUNS OFF THE
STREET.
THE FIREARM BUYBACK PROGRAMS IN
SEVERAL CITIES, WHY GUN OWNERS
WERE SO ANXIOUS TO GET THEIR
WEAPONS OFF THEIR HANDS.
>>> ON LATER THIS HALF HOUR, IT
WAS NO ORDINARY CHRISTMAS CAROL
TO SAY THE LEAST.
HOW A FUNNY SHOW PUT HUMOR ASIDE
WITH AN EXTREMELY TOUCHING
RENDITION OF "SILENT NIGHT."
A LOT OF ATTENTION ON FACEBOOK
AND TWITTER HOW "SATURDAY NIGHT
LIVE" BEGAN THEIR PROGRAM.
A MOVING AND FITTING TRIBUTE
THERE TO THE VICTIMS OF THIS
TRAGEDY.
>> SO RARE FOR "SATURDAY NIGHT
LIVE."
>> I HAVEN'T SEEN ANYTHING LIKE
THAT -- I DON'T THINK WE'VE SEEN
THIS NATIONAL OUTPOURING OF
EMOTION SINCE MAYBE 9/11.
IT'S RISING TO THAT LEVEL IN A
LOT OF WAYS.
>>> BUT FIRST, PRESIDENT OBAMA
IS BACK AT THE WHITE HOUSE THIS
MORNING AFTER DELIVERING A
POWERFUL MESSAGE DURING A
MEMORIAL SERVICE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> THERE WERE HUGS, TEARS IN A
ROOM FILLED WITH APPLAUSE AS
FIRST RESPONDERS ENTER THE HIGH
SCHOOL AUDITORIUM FOR LAST
NIGHT'S INTERFAITH SERVICE.
HUNDREDS TURNED OUT TO REMEMBER
THE 20 CHILDREN AND 6 ADULTS
KILLED IN LAST FRIDAY'S
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL MASSACRE.
AND IN A VERY EMOTIONAL ADDRESS,
THE PRESIDENT SAID SIMPLY THE
COUNTRY HAS HAD ENOUGH OF THIS
KIND OF BLOODSHED.
>> SINCE I'VE BEEN PRESIDENT,
THIS IS THE FOURTH TIME WE'VE
COME TOGETHER TO COMFORT A
GRIEVING COMMUNITY TORN APART BY
MASS SHOOTINGS.
FOURTH TIME WE'VE HUGGED
SURVIVORS.
THE FOURTH TIME WE'VE CONSOLED
THE FAMILIES OF VICTIMS.
AND IN BETWEEN, THERE HAVE BEEN
AN ENDLESS SERIES OF DEADLY
SHOOTINGS ACROSS THE COUNTRY
ALMOST DAILY REPORTS OF VICTIMS,
MANY OF THEM CHILDREN, IN SMALL
TOWNS AND BIG CITIES ACROSS
AMERICA.
VICTIMS WHO MUCH OF THE TIME
THEIR ONLY FAULT WAS BEING IN
THE WRONG PLACE AT THE WRONG
TIME.
WE CAN'T TOLERATE THIS ANYMORE.
>> THOSE IN ATTENDANCE COULD BE
HEARD CRYING IN THE BACKGROUND
DURING THE MOST POIGNANT MOMENT
OF THE NIGHT WHEN PRESIDENT
OBAMA SPOKE THE NAMES OF THE 20
YOUNG CHILDREN TAKEN FROM THEIR
FAMILIES.
>> CHARLOTTE, DANIEL, OLIVIA,
JOSEPHINE, ANA, DYLAN, MADELYNE,
CATHERINE, CHASE, JESSE, JAMES,
GRACE, EMILIE, JACK, NOAH,
CAROLINE, JESSICA, BENJAMIN,
AVIELLE, ALLISON.
GOD HAS CALLED THEM ALL HOME.
>> ALL SCHOOLS IN NEWTOWN WILL
REMAIN CLOSED TODAY.
SOME SCHOOLS ELSEWHERE IN
CONNECTICUT PLAN TO HAVE
COUNSELORS AVAILABLE WHEN
STUDENTS ARRIVE FOR CLASS LATER
THIS MORNING.
YOU WONDER HOW LONG IT WILL TAKE
FOR ANY SENSE OF NORMALCY TO GET
BACK TO THAT TOWN.
IN CASE YOU'RE WONDERING ABOUT
THE FACILITY ITSELF, OBVIOUSLY,
SANDY HOOK IS NOT GOING TO BE
OPEN FOR A WHILE.
IT'S STILL A CRIME SCENE HERE.
THOSE KIDS WILL GO BACK TO
SCHOOL ON TUESDAY, BUT IN A
DIFFERENT CAMPUS AS PART OF THAT
SCHOOL DISTRICT.
WHO KNOWS FOR HOW LONG?
THOSE KIDS WILL NOT BE RETURNING
THERE ON TUESDAY.
THEY'RE GOING TO MAKE SOME OTHER
PLANS.
>> THERE'S NO WAY.
THEY COULDN'T POSSIBLY.
I THINK WHAT'S FASCINATING IS
THAT IT HAS AFFECTED, AS YOU
MENTIONED EARLIER, EVERYONE IN
OUR COUNTRY.
OUTSIDE OF OUR COUNTRY, IN A WAY
THAT I HAVEN'T SEEN SINCE 9/11.
EVERYONE FELT THIS TRAGEDY SO
PERSONALLY IN SO MANY WAYS.
EVEN MY -- THE SCHOOL MY
CHILDREN GO TO, WE GOT SO MANY
E-MAILS FROM THE PRINCIPAL, FROM
THE FIRST GRADE TEACHERS, THE
FIFTH GRADE TEACHERS, ASKING US
HOW WE WERE, WHAT WE WERE GOING
TO BE TALKING TO OUR CHILDREN
ABOUT, WHAT THEY WERE GOING TO
BE DOING ON MONDAY.
BECAUSE IT HAS AFFECTED EVERY
SINGLE FAMILY IN THE COUNTRY.
>> YOU CAN'T IMAGINE THAT EVERY
SINGLE SCHOOL IN THE COUNTRY IS
NOT GOING TO ADDRESS THIS IN
SOME WAY WITH THEIR STUDENTS
COMING BACK TO CLASS TODAY AND
MAYBE LOOK AT THEIR OWN SECURITY
PROCEDURES.
THE RIPPLE EFFECTS ARE
BOUNDLESS.
>> UNBELIEVABLE.
>>> THE GUNMAN ADAM LANZA HAD
HUNDREDS OF ROUNDS AND USED
MULTIPLE HIGH CAPACITY MAGAZINES
WHEN HE WENT TO THE SCHOOL
ACCORDING TO POLICE.
ABC'S DAN HARRIS HAS NEW DETAILS
ABOUT THE DEADLY PATH LANZA TOOK
INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
>> Reporter: AFTER ADAM LANZA
SHOT HIS WAY THROUGH THE GLASS
NEAR THE FRONT ENTRANCE OF THE
SCHOOL ON FRIDAY AT AROUND 9:40
A.M., HE HAD CHOICES.
LANZA COULD HAVE GONE TO THE
RIGHT, TO THE CAFETERIA, WHERE,
ACCORDING TO THE HARTFORD
NEWSPAPER, STUDENTS WERE
REHEARSING A PLAY.
STRAIGHT AHEAD TO THE
PRINCIPAL'S OFFICE OR LEFT
TOWARD THE FIRST GRADE
CLASSROOMS.
HE WENT LEFT AND ENCOUNTERED THE
PRINCIPAL AND A SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST, WHO, AS WE KNOW,
LOCAL OFFICIALS SAY DIED TRYING
TO STOP LANZA.
IN THE FIRST CLASSROOM LANZA
ENTERED HE SHOT AND KILLED
LAUREN RUSSEAU, A SUBSTITUTE
TEACHER, AND 15 FIRST GRADERS,
ALL BUT ONE OF THE STUDENTS.
THEN HE WENT TO THE CLASSROOM OF
VICTORIA SOTO WHO WAS HIDING THE
STUDENTS.
SOTO TRIED TO CONVINCE LANZA THE
KIDS WERE ON THE OTHER SIDE OF
THE BUILDING, BUT WHEN A GROUP
OF STUDENTS TRIED TO GET AWAY,
LANZA SHOT THEM, SOTO, AND A
SPECIAL ED TEACHER.
IT WAS ONLY AFTER POLICE ARRIVED
THAT THEY FOUND OTHER STUDENTS.
THE PAPER SAYS THEY WERE HIDDEN
IN A CLOSET.
THE GOVERNOR OF CONNECTICUT TOLD
ABC'S GEORGE STEPHANOPOULOS THE
RAMPAGE ONLY ENDED AROUND 9:50,
ABOUT TEN MINUTES AFTER IT BEGAN
WHEN LANZA HEARD THE SIRENS
APPROACHING AND KILLED HIMSELF
WITH ONE BULLET TO THE HEAD.
>> WE SURMISE THAT IT WAS DURING
THE SECOND CLASSROOM EPISODE
THAT HE HEARD RESPONDERS COMING
AND APPARENTLY DECIDED TO TAKE
HIS OWN LIFE.
>> Reporter: SCHOOL OFFICIALS
ANNOUNCED THE SURVIVING STUDENTS
FROM SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WILL
IN A MATTER OF DAYS START
ATTENDING CLASSES AT AN UNUSED
SCHOOL IN A NEIGHBORING TOWN.
AFTER THAT, THOUGH, THERE'S A
WRENCHING DECISION TO BE MADE --
DO THEY EVER REOPEN SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY?
DAN HARRIS, ABC NEWS IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> NO EASY ANSWER ON THAT ONE.
SCHOOLS AROUND THE COUNTRY ARE
NOW REVIEWING SECURITY IN LIGHT
OF THE TRAGEDY.
ADMINISTRATORS HAVE PLEDGED TO
HAVE EXTRA POLICE AND GUIDANCE
COUNSELORS ON HAND AS STUDENTS
RETURN TO THE CLASSROOM FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE THE SHOOTING.
THE NEWTOWN SCHOOL DISTRICT
DECIDED TO SPEND TEN TIMES MORE
ON SECURITY TRAINING FOR STAFF
MEMBERS THIS YEAR, TRAINING THAT
MAY HAVE LIMITED THE DAMAGE.
>> YOU HAVE TO HAVE A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF FIRE DRILLS AND
EVACUTION DRILLS AND LOCKDOWN
DRILLS SO THE KIDS KNOW THE
ROUTINE AND THE TEACHERS KNOW
THE ROUTINE AND EVERYONE HAS A
SPOT WHERE THEY'RE SUPPOSED TO
GO TO.
>> THE POLICE CHIEF SAYS HE
PLANS TO STEP UP PATROL OF THE
CITY'S ELEMENTARY AND MIDDLE
SCHOOLS BY ASSIGNING OFFICERS TO
VISIT THEM AT LEAST ONCE A DAY.
AGAIN, THOSE ARE THE RIPPLE
EFFECTS WE'RE TALKING ABOUT.
HOW YOU AS A SCHOOL DISTRICT OR
PRINCIPAL, HOW CAN YOU LOOK AT
THIS TRAGEDY AND NOT PERHAPS
REVIEW YOUR OWN SECURITY
PROCEDURES.
>> THAT'S RIGHT.
I MEAN, I REMEMBER DOING FIRE
DRILLS.
I'M SURE YOU REMEMBER THE SAME
THING.
BUT THESE LOCKDOWNS, I DON'T --
I NEVER PARTICIPATED IN THAT.
>> BUT THEY DID IT AT SCHOOL.
TEACHERS SAID THANK GOD WE DID
THIS, BECAUSE THEY KNEW WHERE TO
HIDE AND WHERE TO GO.
AND THIS DETAIL TOO IS CHILLING
TO THINK ABOUT.
APPARENTLY THE GUNMAN FIRST
ENTERED A KINDERGARTEN CLASSROOM
AND IT WAS EMPTY.
HE THOUGHT IT WAS EMPTY, BUT THE
KIDS WERE IN A BATHROOM AREA
WHERE THE TEACHER HAD TAKEN
THEM.
I GUESS IT WAS A BATHROOM BREAK
OR WHAT HAVE YOU.
AFTER THINKING THAT ROOM WAS
EMPTY, HE WENT INTO THAT FIRST
GRADE CLASSROOM WHERE HE
PROCEEDED TO KILL 15 OF THE 16
STUDENTS.
BUT HAD THOSE KINDERGARTEN KIDS
BEEN IN THAT ROOM, THE DEATH
TOLL COULD HAVE BEEN HIGHER AND
THE VICTIMS EVEN YOUNGER THAN
THE 6 AND 7-YEAR-OLDS.
>> I CAN'T WRAP MY BRAIN AROUND
IT.
>> NO ONE CAN.
IT'S A LEVEL OF EVIL AND
SICKNESS YOU CAN'T PROCESS.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
>>> NOW TO MORE GUN VIOLENCE
THIS MORNING IN TOPEKA, KANSAS.
THE POLICE FORCE IS IN SHOCK
AFTER TWO OF ITS OFFICERS WERE
SHOT AND KILLED.
BOTH THE MEN WERE SHOT IN THE
HEAD WHEN THEY RESPONDED TO A
REPORT OF A SUSPICIOUS VEHICLE
OUTSIDE A GROCERY STORE.
NOW THERE'S A MANHUNT FOR THE
PERSON WHO PULLED THE TRIGGER.
>>> IN SUBURBAN CHICAGO, POLICE
SURROUNDED A HOME DEPOT LAST
NIGHT AS THEY SEARCHED FOR TWO
MEN WHO HAD ROBBED ANOTHER STORE
EARLIER.
THEY SAY THE ARMED ROBBERS WORE
SKI MASKS WHEN THEY ENTERED A
NEARBY RADIOSHACK AND TOOK CASH
AND EQUIPMENT.
A POLICE DOG FOLLOWED THEIR
TRAIL TO THE HOME DEPOT.
>>> AND IT DOES NOT END THERE.
AN OKLAHOMA STUDENT IS IN
CUSTODY, CHARGED WITH PLOTTING
TO SHOOT UP HIS HIGH SCHOOL.
18-YEAR-OLD SAMMY CHAVEZ WAS
ARRESTED LATE LAST WEEK.
POLICE SAY CHAVEZ WANTED TO GET
ALL STUDENTS INTO THE AUDITORIUM
AND THEN START SHOOTING THEM
AFTER THE DOORS WERE CHAINED
SHUT.
ON HIS FACEBOOK PAGE, HE LISTED
KILLING PEOPLE AS A FAVORITE.
>>> THE GUN BUYBACK PROGRAMS
ACROSS THE COUNTRY ARE SEEING A
HUGE SPIKE IN THE AFTERMATH OF
FRIDAY'S SCHOOL SHOOTING
RAMPAGE.
PREVIOUSLY SCHEDULED BUYBACK
EVENTS IN SAN FRANCISCO AND
OAKLAND, CALIFORNIA DREW
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE.
MANY OF THEM SAID THEY TURNED
OVER THEIR WEAPONS BECAUSE THEY
WERE MOVED BY THE CONNECTICUT
TRAGEDY.
>> I FEEL THIS IS SOMETHING THAT
MIGHT HURT SOMEBODY SOME DAY,
YOU KNOW, THEN I WOULD FEEL
TERRIBLE ABOUT THAT.
>> WHEN THE COMMUNITY SAYS
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH, I THINK YOU'VE
GOT A GOOD CHANCE OF SOMETHING
LIKE THIS.
>> THE GUN OWNERS RECEIVED $200
FOR EACH WEAPON THEY BROUGHT IN.
THERE WERE SIMILAR BUYBACKS IN
BROOKLYN, NEW YORK AND
WASHINGTON, D.C. AND IN PRINCE
GEORGE'S COUNTY, MARYLAND.
>> YOU THINK ABOUT THE
STAGGERING NUMBER.
THERE ARE MORE THAN 200 MILLION
GUNS ALREADY ON THE STREETS OF
AMERICA.
SO ONE, THAT QUESTIONS HOW
EFFECTIVE ANY GUN CONTROL COULD
BE.
IT SEEMS LIKE THE GENIE IS WAY
OUT OF THE BOTTLE.
I GUESS EVERY LITTLE BIT HELPS,
SO SOME OF THOSE BUYBACK
PROGRAMS HAVE BEEN SUCCESSFUL IN
SOME CITIES.
>>> COMING UP NEXT, SOME OF THE
OTHER MAJOR HEADLINES THIS
MORNING, INCLUDING THAT HEALTH
SCARE FOR HILLARY CLINTON.
>> WHAT THE SECRETARY OF STATE'S
ILLNESS AND INJURY MEANS TO A
MAJOR INVESTIGATION IN
WASHINGTON.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
and harshness of bleach.
And free ourselves from worrying
about the ones we love.
New Lysol Power & Free has more
cleaning power than bleach.
How?
The secret
is the hydrogen peroxide
formula.
It attacks tough stains
and kills 99.9% of germs.
New Lysol Power & Free.
Powerful cleaning that's
family friendly.
Another step forward
in our Mission for Health.
>>> HERE'S A QUICK LOOK AT YOUR
MONDAY WEATHER.
RAIN FROM SEATTLE TO SAN
FRANCISCO.
UP TO TWO FEET OF MOUNTAIN SNOW
IN THE CASCADES AND SIERRA
NEVADA.
LIGHT SNOW IN THE ROCKIES.
SHOWERS IN THE NORTHEAST.
SEVERE STORMS FROM THE OHIO
VALLEY ALL THE WAY DOWN TO THE
FLORIDA PANHANDLE.
>> 82 IN MIAMI.
50s FROM BOSTON TO BALTIMORE.
MOSTLY 40s ACROSS THE MIDWEST.
30s IN THE NORTHERN ROCKIES AND
PACIFIC NORTHWEST.
>>> AND NOW TO HEALTH CONCERNS
FOR OUTGOING SECRETARY OF STATE
HILLARY CLINTON.
SHE'S BEEN BATTLING A STOMACH
VIRUS THAT'S LED TO OTHER
COMPLICATIONS.
WITH MORE ON THIS, HERE'S ABC'S
DAVID KERLEY.
>> Reporter: HILLARY CLINTON IS
AT HOME, RECOVERING FROM A
CONCUSSION, AS WELL AS A STOMACH
VIRUS.
IN FACT, THE TWO ARE RELATED.
THE STATE DEPARTMENT SAYS THE
SECRETARY RETURNED FROM HER
LATEST TRIP WITH A STOMACH BUG.
BUT LAST WEEK, CLINTON BECAME
DEHYDRATED AND FAINTED AT HER
HOME.
SHE APPARENTLY HIT HER HEAD,
BECAUSE OFFICIALS SAY SHE
SUFFERED A CONCUSSION.
IT'S THE SECOND TIME IN EIGHT
YEARS SHE'S FAINTED BECAUSE OF A
STOMACH BUG.
BUT SHE'S GENERALLY HEALTHY, AS
SHE TOLD BARBARA WALTERS WHO
ASKED ABOUT A POSSIBLE
PRESIDENTIAL RUN IN 2016.
>> IS YOUR AGE A CONCERN TO YOU?
>> IT REALLY ISN'T.
I AM, THANKFULLY, KNOCK ON WOOD,
NOT ONLY HEALTHY, BUT HAVE
INCREDIBLE STAMINA AND ENERGY.
>> Reporter: BUT STAYING HOME
THIS WEEK MEANS THE SECRETARY
WILL NOT TESTIFY ABOUT THE
TERRORIST ATTACKS IN BENGHAZI,
LIBYA.
>> LOOK, I'VE SAID IT AND I'LL
SAY IT ONE MORE TIME, NO ONE
WANTS TO FIND OUT WHAT HAPPENED
MORE THAN I DO.
>> Reporter: THE STATE
DEPARTMENT REPORT THAT LED TO
THE ATTACK, THE DEATH OF THE
AMBASSADOR CHRIS STEVENS AND
THREE OTHERS WILL COME OUT IN
THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS.
CLINTON WAS SET TO TESTIFY
BEFORE BOTH HOUSES ON THURSDAY.
NOW SHE WILL STAY HOME AND TWO
DEPUTIES WILL FILL IN.
NOT GOOD ENOUGH SAID THE
REPUBLICAN CHAIR OF THE HOUSE
COMMITTEE, WHO SAID THIS
REQUIRES A PUBLIC APPEARANCE BY
THE SECRETARY OF STATE HERSELF.
BUT THAT MAY NEVER HAPPEN.
ABC NEWS LEARNED THE PRESIDENT
WILL NOMINATE JOHN KERRY AS
SECRETARY OF STATE.
AS SOON AS HE IS CONFIRMED,
CLINTON WILL RETIRE AND MAY
NEVER TESTIFY ABOUT BENGHAZI.
DAVID KERLEY, ABC NEWS,
WASHINGTON.
>>> IN A MOMENT, WE RETURN TO
OUR TOP STORY, THE TRAGEDY AT
SANDY HOOK.
>> HOW A SIMPLE CHRISTMAS CAROL
CAN MEAN SO MUCH TO A NATION IN
DISBELIEF.
YOU'RE WATCHING "WORLD NEWS
NOW."
>>> COMEDIOFTE
>>> COMEDIANS OFTEN ASK HOW SOON
AFTER A TRAGEDY IS IT OKAY TO
LAUGH?
IS THE DAY AFTER A TRAGEDY TOO
SOON?
>> THE WRITERS AND PRODUCERS OF
"SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE" DECIDED TO
EASE INTO THE COMEDY ON THIS
WEEKEND'S SHOW WITH A VERY
POIGNANT OPENING SCENE.
♪ SILENT NIGHT, HOLY NIGHT
♪ ALL IS CALM, ALL IS BRIGHT
♪ ROUND YON VIRGIN MOTHER AND
CHILD ♪
♪ HOLY INFANT SO TENDER AND
MILD ♪
♪ SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE, SLEEP
IN HEAVENLY PEACE ♪
♪ SILENT NIGHT, HOLY NIGHT
♪ HALLELUJAH TO OUR KING
♪ SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE, SLEEP
IN HEAVENLY PEACE ♪
>> LIVE FROM NEW YORK, IT'S
SATURDAY NIGHT.
>> TRYING TO STRIKE THE RIGHT
TONE.
BEAUTIFUL VOICES.
THAT WAS THE NEW YORK CHILDREN'S
CHORUS, APPROPRIATELY.
>> AND SLEEP IN HEAVENLY PEACE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
REMEMBER, 9/11 THAT FAMOUS SCENE
WITH THE MAYOR AND TRYING TO
EASE BACK INTO NORMALCY AND
LAUGHTER.
WE'RE NOT THERE YET, BUT A
BEAUTIFUL I THINK MESSAGE TO SEE
THOSE KIDS.
>> WELL DONE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
WE'LL BE BACK WITH MORE AFTER
THIS.
HAVE TO COME OVER!
ACTUALLY, HONEY,
I THINK I DID...
OH? YOU DID?
WHOA, LADIES, EASY.
HI.
CASCADE KITCHEN COUNSELOR.
WE CAN HELP AVOID THIS
WITH CASCADE COMPLETE PACS.
SEE, OVER TIME,
CASCADE COMPLETE PACS
FIGHT FILM BUILDUP TWO TIMES
BETTER THAN FINISH QUANTUM.
TO HELP LEAVE GLASSES SPARKLING
SHINY!
TOO BAD IT DOESN'T WORK
ON WINDOWS.
OKAY, I'M OUTTA HERE.
CASCADE. THE CLEAR CHOICE.
♪
>>> FINALLY, IT TOOK CONNECTICUT
STATE POLICE UNTIL SATURDAY TO
RELEASE THE NAMES OF ALL THOSE
WHO DIED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> WE GOT THE E-MAIL HERE AT ABC
NEWS FROM ONE OF OUR VICE
PRESIDENTS AND SAID THIS MAY BE
THE SADDEST PIECE OF PAPER EVER
WRITTEN WITH THOSE 20 NAMES ON
IT.
READING OF THE NAMES MADE THEM
THAT MUCH MORE REAL AND SEEING
HOW YOUNG MOST OF THEM WERE WAS
HEARTBREAKING.
♪
>> ALL OF THE YOUNG VICTIMS, 5
OR 6 YEARS OLD.
ALL OF THEM FIRST GRADERS.
12 GIRLS, 8 BOYS, AND NINE OF
THE DECEASED CHILDREN HAVE
SIBLINGS WHO ALSO ATTENDED THE
SCHOOL.
>> JUST UNFATHOMABLE.
WE'VE BEEN TALKING ABOUT IT
SINCE FRIDAY AND I STILL CAN'T
BELIEVE THIS.
>> NO ONE CAN REALLY GET THEIR
HEAD AROUND THIS.
THERE'S JUST ALWAYS I THINK A
GUT VISCERAL REACTION TO
ANYTHING INVOLVING KIDS, LET
ALONE THIS KIND OF MAD MAN WHO
COMES INTO AN ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> THEY'RE BABIES.
>> AND OPENS FIRE.
>> A WRITER FOR "THE NEW YORK
TIMES" SAID ALL THE VICTIMS OF
>>> THIS MORNING, REMEMBERING
THE VICTIMS.
>> HUNDREDS COME TOGETHER FOR AN
EMOTIONAL VIGIL TO HONOR THOSE
KILLED IN FRIDAY'S SCHOOL
MASSACRE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ASKING A TOUGH
QUESTION.
>> CAN WE HONESTLY SAY WE'RE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM, SAFE FROM
HARM?
>> THE COMMUNITY OF NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, TRANSFORMED.
ITS RESIDENTS AT A LOSS.
>> I SEE THE SCHOOL I WENT TO.
AND I JUST DON'T BELIEVE THAT'S
WHERE I WAS FROM, THAT'S WHERE I
CAME FROM.