GOOD.
KATIE: I LOVE MY JOB.
DID I MENTION HOW MUCH I LOVE MY
JOB?
ANNOUNCER: THE SEXY, CHARMING,
JACK OF ALL TRADES ACTOR LEADS
EVERYONE BLUSHING.
>> BOND.
JAMES BOND.
KATIE: THAT'S LIKE THROWING RAW
MEAT TO THE AUDIENCE.
ANNOUNCER: HUGH HITS ALL OF THE
RIGHT NOTES.
>> ♪
EVERYTHING'S GOING KATIE'S WAY.
ANNOUNCER: FROM STUDIO ONE IN
NEW YORK, IT'S KATIE.
[APPLAUSE]
-- "KATIE."
KATIE: THANK YOU.
HI.
HI, EVERYONE.
WELCOME.
HAVE A SEAT.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR COMING.
YOU ARE SO LUCKY.
YOU PICKED A FANTASTIC SHOW TO
COME TO TODAY.
AND I AM SO EXCITED.
NOW, I COULD WASTE A LOT OF TIME
RECITING SUPERLATIVES ABOUT MY
GUEST TODAY.
I COULD SAY HE'S A TRIPLE
THREAT.
HE COULD SING, HE COULD DANCE,
HE COULD ACT.
I COULD SAY HE STARRED IN A FILM
FRANCHISE THAT HAS MADE $1
BILLION.
I COULD TELL YOU HE'S A 6'2"
HUNK OF BURNING LOVE AND WAS
VOTED SEXIEST MAN ALIVE IN 2008.
OR I COULD SIMPLY SHOW YOU THIS.
>> AAAAAAAHHHHHH!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
KATIE: ALL THAT AND HONESTLY, HE
HAPPENS TO BE ONE OF THE NICEST
PEOPLE I HAVE EVER MET.
SO PLEASE WELCOME HUGH JACKMAN.
[APPLAUSE]
♪
>> HI, GUYS.
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
YOU LOOK SO GOOD.
KATIE: THANK YOU.
I WAS GOING TO SAY IS THIS YOUR
DREAM COME TRUE OR YOUR BIGGEST
NIGHTMARE?
A ROOM FULL OF ADORING SCREAMING
WOMEN.
WE'VE GOT SOME GUMMI BEARS FOR
YOU.
>> YEAH, THIS IS WHAT I HAD
BEFORE I GO ON STAGE.
YOUR INCREDIBLE CREW WHO WORKED
WITH ME ON MY BROADWAY SHOW AND
THIS IS WHAT I WOULD EAT
BACKSTAGE.
KATIE: THAT'S SO CUTE.
ARE THEY LIKE SOUR PATCH?
>> LIKE I LITTLE DR GET A LITTL
IN THE THEATER, THEY HAVE THE
SMOKE AND THAT SORT OF DRY ICE
THING?
AND SO THIS IS WHAT I WOULD HAVE
BEFORE.
KATIE: OH, THAT'S SO
>> HERE.
PASS ONE AROUND.
KATIE: YEAH, YOU'VE GOT TO TAKE
A SOUR PATCH KID FROM HUGH
JACKMAN.
>> THIS IS THE HIGHLIGHT OF MY
TRIP, YOU KNOW THAT.
I LOVE IT.
KATIE: SO LET'S TALK ABOUT THIS
BECAUSE I AM SO EXCITED ABOUT
THIS MOVIE AND SO THRILLED FOR
YOU.
I KNOW YOU CALL IT THE ROLE OF A
LIFETIME.
>> YEAH.
KATIE: AND WHY IS THAT?
IS THIS SOMETHING YOU'VE ALWAYS
WANTED TO PLAY IT?
>> SLIGHTLY REGRETTING EATING
THAT CANDY RIGHT NOW.
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: TAKE YOUR TIME.
YOU WANT ME TO MAKE THE QUESTION
A LITTLE LONGER?
BECAUSE I'M A HUGE FAN OF "LES
MIS."
KATIE: BORN IN 1968.
KATIE: DO YOU WANT SOME WATER?
>> I'M GOOD.
JOHN IS A LITTLE BIT LIKE
HAMLET.
THE BOOK IS THE MOST FAMOUS
LITERARY CHARACTERS BUT IN
MUSICAL THEATER TERMS, IT'S A
DIFFICULT VOCAL ROLE.
EMOTIONALLY, YOU HAVE TO GO
PLACES IN A WAY, I'VE NEVER BEEN
ASKED BEFORE AND PHYSICALLY,
IT'S VERY DIFFICULT AS WELL.
IT'S ABOUT AS DIFFICULT AS A
"WOLVERINE" MOVIE SO SORT OF IN
A WAY, EVERYTHING THAT I'VE HAD
TO DO IN THE PAST ALL KIND OF
COMING TOGETHER IN ONE MOVIE IN
A ROLE, AS YOU SAID, ROLE OF A
LIFETIME.
KATIE: NOW, WERE YOU A BIGAMIST
MIST FAN?
>> YES.
KATIE: I SAW IT AT THE KENNEDY
CENTER BEFORE IT CAME TO
BROADWAY AND THEN I SAW IT ON
BROADWAY THREE TIMES.
I KNOW.
I'M ONE OF THOSE WEIRD PEOPLE
WHO WATCH THE SHOW OVER AND
OVER.
>> THERE'S A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO
WATCH THE SHOW HUNDREDS OF
TIMES.
KATIE: YOU MOTHER SHARE MUCH
ABOUT THE COMPOSER AND THE
LYRICIST, RIGHT?
>> YEAH.
KATIE: I LOVE THAT.
>> VICTOR HUGO'S NOVEL IS ONE OF
THE GREATEST POOKS BOOKS OF ALL
TIME.
IMAGINE GETTING THAT ON YOUR
DESK.
IT'S PRETTY INCREDIBLE THAT THEY
DID AND THE FACT THAT THEY'VE
MADE THE MUSIC AS BEAUTIFUL AND
AS TIMELESS AS THE STORY IS ONE
OF THE GREATEST ACHIEVEMENTS OF
ALL TIME.
EVERY SONG WAS ALL GREAT UNTIL
SUSAN BOYLE DID "I DREAM A
DREAM."
EVERY SONG IS A WINNER.
KATIE: IT'S FUNNY BECAUSE
IRONICALLY, ONE OF YOUR FIRST
AUDITIONS, I READ THAT YOU SANG
"STARS" FOR THAT WHICH WAS A
SONG THAT'S SUNG BY THE
INSPECTOR IN THE MUSICAL.
HOW DID YOU HAPPEN TO SING
>> WELL, THAT?
>> WELL, I WENT FOR AN AUDITION
FOR "BEAUTY AND THE BEAST."
AND THEY SAID WHY DID YOU SING
THAT SONG FOR "BEAUTY AND THE
BEAST?"
AND THEY SAID PUT THAT AWAY.
YOU'LL NEVER BE IN THAT SHOW.
I WAS LIKE WHERE ARE THEY?
YEAH.
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: WHERE IS THAT GUY?
>> BUT ANYWAY, IT'S BEEN A GOOD
OPENING FOR ME.
I'M GRATEFUL FOR IT.
KATIE: AND THE MAN WHO SINGS
THAT PART IS RUSSELL CROWE.
WE HAVE A SCENE EARLY IN THE
MOVIE WHERE YOU AND RUSSELL ARE
SINGING AFTER YOU'VE BEEN
RELEASED ON PO PA ROLE AFTER 19
YEARS OF SOME HARD TIME.
LET'S TAKE A LOOK.
>> ♪
FOLLOW THE LETTER OF YOUR
ITINERARY.
IT WANTS -- WARNS YOUR A
DANGEROUS MAN.
>> ♪
MY SISTER'S CHILD WAS CLOSE TO
DEATH.
WE WERE STARVING.
>> ♪
YOU'LL STARVE AGAIN UNLESS YOU
LEARN THE MEANING OF THE LAW.
>> ♪
YOU'RE THE MEANING OF THOSE 19
YEARS, A SLAVE OF THE LAW ♪
[APPLAUSE]
>> LOOKING LIKE HELL, RIGHT?
KATIE: YEAH.
THAT'S VERY OBVIOUSLY, THAT'S
VERY HAIRY, REALLY AT THE
BEGINNING OF THE MOVIE AND I'VE
GOT TO SAY, HUGH, YOU LOOK VERY
GNARLY IN THAT SCENE.
TELL US WHAT YOU WENT THROUGH.
YOU WENT THROUGH A MAJOR
PHYSICAL TRANSFORMATION TO BE IN
THIS MOVIE.
>> IT FELT LIKE 11 YEARS SINCE
I'VE HAD CARBOHYDRATES.  HOURS A
DAY.
KATIE: AND YOU LOST SOMETHING
LIKE 20 POUNDS?
>> I'VE LOST LIKE 20 POUNDS AND
THEN I DID THIS CRAZY THING JUST
BEFORE THAT SCENE, ACTUALLY,
WHICH WE SHOT WHICH IS A BODY
BUILDER TRICK OF NOT DRINKING
ANY LIQUID FOR 30 HOURS OR 36
HOURS.
AND WHAT THAT DOES, DO NOT TRY
THIS, BY THE WAY.
RECOMMEND IT.
YOU LOSE ABOUT 10 POUNDS OF
WEIGHT, REALLY, ON THE
EXTREMITIES LIKE ALL THE WATER
JUST DRAINS OUT.
YOU GET VERY SUNKEN CHEEKS,
SUNKEN EYES AND A MASSIVE
HEADACHE.
MASSIVE HEADACHE.
KATIE: AND YOU DO THIS AND THEN
YOU HAVE TO SING THIS PRETTY
IMPORTANT SONG, THE FIRST,
REALLY, SONG OF THE MUSICAL.
WAS THAT HARD?
DID YOU FEEL LIKE YOU WERE GOING
TO PASS OUT?
>> WELL, YOU CAN SEE HOW GRUMPY
I LOOKED.
THERE WAS NO ACTING REQUIRED.
EVEN RUSSELL WAS SCARED OF ME
THAT DAY.
KATIE: AND YOUR TEETH, THEY WERE
ALL YELLOW.
>> THOSE WERE FAKE TEETH.
KATIE: AND THEN THERE'S A
WORM-TYPE SCAR.
>> IT'S NOT MY BEST LOOK.
KATIE: NO.
>> WE HAD TO WEAR THE FAKE TEETH
FOR THREE WEEKS ALL DAY LONG.
BECAUSE WHEN I FIRST WAS SINGING
♪
WHO AM I'M JEAN -- ♪
NO, THIS IS NOT ICONIC.
IT TOOK ABOUT TWO OR THREE WEEKS
TO GET USED TO IT.
KATIE: I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU HAD
TO AUDITION FOR THIS MOVIE.
>> YEAH.
KATIE: WHO ELSE WOULD THEY USE
FOR THIS MOVIE, HUGH, REALLY?
>> WELL, I SUPPOSE IT WAS -- I
WAS THRILLED TO AUDITION.
I NEVER MINDED AUDITIONING.
I ACTUALLY RANG TOM HOOPER, THE
DIRECTOR, BEFORE HE HAD EVEN
SIGNED ON FOR THIS.
I WANTED THIS SO BAD.
I PRETTY MUCH STALKED HIM AND HE
LITERALLY M CHAIR LIKE
WAY CLOSER THAN WE ARE AND HE
GOES OK, JUST --
KATIE: YOU CAN DO THAT IF YOU
N
TO.LL
>> ALL RIGHT.
GOOD.
[LAUGHTER]
[APPLAUSE]
>> YEAH.
SORRY, HE DIDN'T DO THAT.
SORRY.
AND HE GOES DON'T WORRY ABOUT
ME.
OK.
I'M THE CAMERA.
KATIE: I LOVE MY JOB.
DID I MENTION HOW MUCH I LOVE MY
JOB?
YEAH.
SO HE JUST -- WHY?
WHY DID HE DO THAT?
>> HE SAID NOW I NEED TO WATCH
YOUR PERFORMANCE FROM HERE
BECAUSE THIS IS GOING TO BE LIKE
WHAT IT IS FOR THE AUDIENCE.
THE CAMERA, WE'RE GOING TO GET
INSIDE YOUR HEAD AND THAT'S THE
BEAUTY OF THIS.
WE WERE SINGING LIVE ON THE SET
BUT UNLIKE THE STAGE WHERE
YOU'RE ALWAYS HAVING TO TAKE
CARE OF EVERYBODY, INCLUDING THE
BACK ROW, HERE, THE AUDIENCE IS
PRETTY MUCH SITTING ON YOUR LAP.
ANNOUNCER: UP NEXT, HUGH'S
SECRET TO A SUCCESSFUL MARRIAGE.
KATIE: HOW DOES SHE PUT UP YOUR
SEX SYMBOL STATUS?
>> I REMIND HER MOST DAYS.
I REMIND HER IN THE MORNING AND
GO HMM, RIGHT?
AND SHE GOES UH-HUH.
ANNOUNCER: THAT'S NEXT.
>> ♪
WHO AM I
WHOM AM I I'M JEAN VALJEAN ♪
KATIE: AND WE'RE BACK WITH THE
AMAZING HUGH JACKMAN AND LET'S
TALK ABOUT SOME OF THE OTHER
MEMBERS OF THE CAST BECAUSE THIS
IS AN EXTRAORDINARY CAST.
>> WHAT ABOUT THAT ANNE
HATHAWAY?
KATIE: OH, SHE ALSO LOST A TON
OF WEIGHT FOR THAT ROLE,
SOMETHING LIKE 25 POUNDS.
SOMEBODY TOLD ME LIKE SHE ATE
TWO PEANUT BUTTER CRACKERS A DAY
OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
I SAID I SHOULD TRY THAT DIET.
>> SHE SAID IT'S FOOD TIME AND
THAT WOULD COME LIKE GREEN APPLE
LIKE THAT.
AND ONCE I -- AND SHE GOES NO, I
DIDN'T GRAB IT AND SHE WAS
LITERALLY --
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: CAN YOU IMAGINE?
>> I DID.
AT ONE POINT, SHE GOT SOME BAKED
POTATO LIKE THIS.
AND I WAS LIKE REALLY, ANNE?
BAKED POTATO?
COME ON.
YOU'RE REALLY NOT COMMITTING.
I MEAN, BAKED POTATO.
WAY TOO MANY CARBOHYDRATES.
KATIE: BUT THE CAST WAS AMAZING.
SO OBVIOUSLY, YOU LOVED WORKING
WITH ANNE.
DID SHE DID THAT NUMBER WITH THE
OSCARS, BUT YOU'VE NEVER REALLY
WORKED TOGETHER, RIGHT?
>> NO.
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED TO WORK WITH
HER.
I THINK SHE'S ONE OF THE REAL
TALENTS AND TO SEE HER DO THIS
WAS SUCH A THRILL.
AS A FRIEND OF HERS, YOU KNOW,
HER MUM PLAYED THE ROLE.
KATIE: RIGHT.
SHE WAS THE UNDERSTUDY RIGHT?
>> AND AT AGE 8 OR SOMETHING
WATCHED HER MOM PLAY FANTINE.
AND FROM DAY ONE OF FILMING, SHE
CAME TO SAY WITH THIS "LES MIS"
JACKET AND ALL OF A SUDDEN, SHE
POINTED AND IT HAD "KATE" WHICH
WAS HER MUM'S NAME.
IT WAS A ORIGINAL WHICH HER MUM
GAVE HER AS GIFT TO STAR.
SHE'S THE SECOND GENERATION "LES
MIS" AND IT WAS AMAZING.
I WAS SO PROUD OF HER.
I'M HAPPY WITH HER.
KATIE: SHE BLEW ME AWAY WITH HER
PERFORMANCE.
SHE WAS AMAZING.
RUSSELL CROWE SAYS JAVERT.
HE SCARES ME A LITTLE.
IS HE NICE?
>> HE NICEST.
NO, DON'T BE SCARED BY RUSSELL.
TRUST ME.
ONE OF THE NICEST MOST LOYAL
PEOPLE I KNOW.
AND IF YOU GO TO RUSSELL'S
HOUSE, IT IS THE BEST PARTY
YOU'VE EVER BEEN TO.
EVERYONE'S UP SINGING.
YOU WOULD BE SINGING.
HE GETS THE GUITAR OUT.
HE'S VERY RELAXED.
HE'S BEEN A GREAT FRIEND TO ME.
I'VE CALLED ON HIM ABOUT THREE
OR FOUR TIMES, I CAN REMEMBER,
FOR ADVICE ON THINGS, PRIVATELY
AND HE'S AN INCREDIBLE FRIEND, A
VERY WISE AND HE, YOU KNOW, WAS
A BIG PART OF THIS MOVIE, YOU
KNOW, THE EXPERIENCE BEING AS
GREAT AS IT WAS.
KATIE: AMANDA SIGFRIED PLAYS
COSETTE AND SHE'S WONDERFUL.
>> BUTTER MELT IN YOUR MOUTH.
SHE'S THE CHEEKIEST GIRL THAT
YOU'VE EVER MET.
KATIE: WHY HER?
YOU HAD SOME VERY SORT OF A VERY
INAPPROPRIATE SENSE OF HUMOR
WITH DURING THE FILMING AND YOU
WOULD MAKE ALL THESE JOKES THAT
WERE SEXUAL INNUENDOS BUT YOU'RE
FATHER-DAUGHTER, YOU WEIRDO.
WHAT KIND OF THINGS WOULD YOU
>> I D
[LAUGHTER]
>> I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE
OFFICIAL TERM IS IS WHEN YOU
HAVE THE QUALITY AND YOU JUST
PUT IT ON SOMEONE ELSE.
KATIE: I THINK IT'S CALLED
TRANSFERRING.
>> THANK YOU.
CHEEKY.
SHE IS VERY CHEEKY.
AND MANY TIMES, TOM WOULD GET
UPSET WITH THIS BECAUSE WE WERE
LAUGHING SO MUCH BECAUSE SHE
WOULD BE LOOKING FOR ME.
AND I SAID WE'RE
FATHER-DAUGHTER.
WE'RE TOTALLY INAPPROPRIATE.
KATIE: WITH A DO YOU THINK OF
ALL THE OSCAR BUZZ?
PEOPLE ARE SAYING HUGH JACKMAN'S
GOING WIN BEST ACTOR.
>> WHENEVER I HEAR OSCAR, HAIR
WHAT'S MY SON DONE?
WHERE IS HE?
HE'S ABOUT TO TURN 13.
TO GIVE YOU SOME PERSPECTIVE,
YOU KNOW THIS.
YOU GUYS MAY NOT.
MY FATHER WORKED FOR PRICE
WATERHOUSE, THE ACCOUNTANCY
FIRM.
IN THE OSCARS, THEY ALWAYS BRING
THE ACCOUNTANTS ON WITH THEIR
THREE BRIEFCASES.
I USED TO CHEER WHEN THE
ACCOUNTANTS CAME ON AT THE
OSCARS, RIGHT?
I'M THE KID FROM THE NORTHERN
SUBURB OF OSCARS, I TOOK PHOTOS
ON THE RED CARPET.
I TOOK PHOTO OFFENSE THE
ACCOUNTANTS AND SEND IT TO MY
DAD.
TO ME, THAT WAS ABOUT AS GOOD AS
IT GOT.
KATIE: WOULD IT BE NICE?
>> OF COURSE.
SOME ACTORS WERE LIKE I'M NOT
GOO IT.
I WOULD BE INTO IT.
[LAUGHTER]
JUST FOR THE RECORD.
[APPLAUSE]
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE
GOING TO TALK YOUR DAD AND YOUR
KID AND OF COURSE, YOUR LOVELY
WIFE, DEB.
WE'LL BE RIGHT BACK.
ANNOUNCER: STILL TO COME --
>> ♪
WHEN MICHAEL FEINSTEIN AND KATIE
AND THIS GREAT AUDIENCE, WHAT
MORE CAN ANYONE WANT ♪
[APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: THAT'S LATER.
♪
THAT WAS 20 LONG YEARS AGO, MY
WIFE WAS A WAR THAT COULD NEVER
BE GONE THEY GAVE ME A NUMBER
AND THEY MURDER VALUE-JEAN AND
THEY LEFT ME FOR DEAD ♪
KATIE: THAT WAS A SNEAK PEEK OF
THE ALL-STAR ADAPTATION OF "LES
MISéRABLES" WHICH OPENS ON
CHRISTMAS DAY.
LET'S TALK A LITTLE BIT ABOUT
YOUR PERSONAL LIFE BECAUSE I
KNOW PEOPLE ARE INTERESTED IN
KIND OF YOUR FAMILY AND ALL
THAT.
AND YOU AND DEB HAVE BEEN
MARRIED FOR 16 YEARS.
>> YES.
KATIE: AND YOU GUYS MET ON THE
SET OF AN AUSTRALIAN COP SHOW.
>> YOU REALIZE I TOOK MY RING
OFF -- OH, I'M IN TROUBLE.
KATIE: HEY!
I UNDERSTAND.
>> YES.
KATIE: MY HUSBAND USED TO CALL
THE WORLD'S SMALLEST HANDCUFFS.
[LAUGHTER]
THAT'S NOT VERY NICE.
>> BUT I'M SO IN TROUBLE BECAUSE
I HAVE LOST THREE WEDDING RINGS,
ALL OF THEM IN BODIES OF WATER
ALL AROUND THE WORLD.
I GO IN AND I GO THE LAST TIME I
WAS LITERALLY TELL THE STORY HOW
I WAS LOSING HOW I WOULD GET
BACK ON THE BOAT AND ANYWAY -- I
DON'T BELIEVE IT.
[LAUGHTER]
SO A
KATIE: BUT DEB IS FANTASTIC.
>> SHE'S THE BEST.
KATIE: SHE WAS QUITE AN
ACCOMPLISHED ACTRESS WHEN YOU
ALL MET.
SHE HAD DONE 20 MOVIES OR
SOMETHING?
>> 20 OR 25 MOVIES.
WE MET ON A TV SERIES AND SHE
WAS THE STAR OF THE SHOW,
"CORRELLI."
IT WAS MY FIRST JOB AND CLICHES,
FELL IN LOVE WITH MY LEADING
LADY.
I DIDN'T TALK TO HER FOR A WEEK.
I WAS LIKE I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I'M THAT GUY.
THIS IS EMBARRASSING.
KATIE: AND I SHOULD MENTION THAT
SHE WAS A COUGAR WHEN COUGARS
WERE COOL.
DEB IS EIGHT YEARS OLDER THAN
YOU, RIGHT?
[APPLAUSE]
GO FOR IT.
>> HANG ON.
ANYONE AS KATIE DOES KNOW,
ANYONE THAT DOES KNOW DEB,
LITERALLY, I AM THE OLD FUDDY
DADDY IN THE RELATIONSHIP.
I'M WAY MORE BORING.
SHE'S UP FIRST IN THE MORNING
AND SHE'S ALWAYS LIKE COME ON,
HUGH.
I'M LIKE COME ON, DEB.
CAN WE GO HOME?
SHE LITERALLY LIGHTS UP A ROOM.
KATIE: HOW DOES SHE PUT UP YOUR
SEX SYMBOL STATUS IF DOES SHE
GET NERVOUS OR JUST LAUGHS IT
OFF?
>> NO, I REMIND HER MOST DAYS.
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: YOU SAY BABY IF I'M NOT
PICKING UP MY UNDERWEAR.
I'M HUGH JACKMAN.
>> I WALK IN IN THE MORNING, I
GO RIGHT?
AND SHE'S LIKE UH-HUH.
[LAUGHTER]
GARBAGE.
KATIE: REALLY?
[LAUGHTER]
LOT O LOT OF PEOPLE ASK
ME, YOU KNOW, WHAT'S IT LIKE FOR
DEB HAVING IF I WORKED WITH
HALLE BERRY OR MEG RYAN AND ALL
THESE BEAUTIFUL WOMEN I'M LUCKY
ENOUGH TO WORK WITH.
WHAT I DO ON EVERY FILM, WHEN WE
GET TOGETHER, WE'LL GO OUT AND
WE'LL ALL HAVE A DINNER TOGETHER
AND HONESTLY FROM THE MOMENT ANY
OF THEM MEET DEB, THEY ALL
PREFER HER TO ME.
MEG RYAN TOOK HER ON DATES THAT
THEY WON'T TELL ME ABOUT.
KATIE: WHAT DO YOU THINK MAKES
YOUR MARRIAGE WORK?
16 YEARS, THAT'S NOT THAT LONG
BUT STILL, THAT'S A NICE PERIOD
OF TIME, WHICH IS GREAT.
>> YOU KNOW, I'M AN INDECISIVE
PERSON.
I'M TERRIBLE TO GO TO A
RESTAURANT WITH.
I COULD SPEND 10 MINUTES ON
DECIDING WHAT TO EAT, WHAT TO
DRINK.
WHEN I'M WITH DEB, IT WAS THE
CLEAREST THING IN THE WORLD TO
ME.
I KNEW 100% AND I ALWAYS FEEL
FOR PEOPLE.
SOME PEOPLE COME TO ME AND GO
YOU KNOW, I REALLY LOVE HER, I'M
NOT SURE AND I'VE WRITTEN A LIST
AND I'M LIKE I CAN'T RELATE TO
THAT BECAUSE IT WAS BEYOND
WRITING A LIST.
THERE WAS NO PROS OR CONS.
IT WAS I'VE NEVER KNOWN ANYTHING
AS CONFIDENTLY OR SURE IN MY
LIFE THAT SHE WAS THE ONE I WAS
MEANT TO BE WITH AND I THINK FOR
ME, THAT'S WAS ONE OF THE GREAT
BLESSINGS BECAUSE IN ANY GREAT
MARRIAGES, GOOD TIMES, BAD
TIMES, HARD TIMES, AND GREAT
TIMES, IT'S JUST ALWAYS IN HERE.
WHATEVER HAPPENS TO DEB AND I,
WHATEVER THINGS COME IN OUR
PATH, I KNEW WE WERE MEANT TO BE
TOGETHER.
AND TRULY, SHE IS THE GREATEST
PERSON I HAVE EVER MET.
EVER.
KATIE: AWW, THAT'S SO NICE.
[APPLAUSE]
WELL, YOU'RE VERY LUCKY.
YOU'RE BOTH VERY LUCKY TO HAVE
EACH OTHER.
>> YEAH.
KATIE: AND SHE PRETTY MUCH GAVE
UP HER CAREER, HUGH SO, YOU
COULD PURSUE YOURS.
DOES IT EVER BOTHER HER THAT
SHE'S NOT REALLY ACTING ANYMORE?
>> I THINK AT TIMES.
I THINK AT TIMES, IT DOES.
I THINK FOR ME, SHE IS ONE OF
THE GREAT ACTORS I KNOW AND
SHE'S INCREDIBLE.
IN FACT, SHE HAD A TIME IN
HOLLYWOOD AND I RUN INTO PEOPLE,
YOU KNOW, NICOLE DAVID, REALLY
POWERFUL, BIG PEOPLE IN
HOLLYWOOD AND THEY'RE LIKE
CONGRATULATES TO YOU, BUT YOUR
WIFE IS REALLY RUN OF THE MOST
TALENTED AND EVERY TIME I HEAR
THAT, IT REMINDS ME OF SACRIFICE
SHE'S MADE, HER SELFLESSNESS,
HER LOVE AND WHAT SHE'S DONE FOR
THE KIDS.
AND, YOU KNOW, WE ALWAYS MADE
FAMILY A PRIORITY BUT I'M
ACUTELY AWARE EVERY DAY THAT
WHEN IT COMES TO SACRIFICES, DEB
HAS SHOULDERED MOST OF THOSE AND
SHE WILL COME TO WORK.
I'LL TELLING YOU RIGHT NOW.
YOU NEED TO GET BACK TO WORK
BECAUSE YOU'RE TOO GOOD TO WASTE
THAT TALENT.
EVERYONE NEEDS TO SEE IT.
KATIE: WHEN WE COME BACK, WE'RE
GOING TO TALK ABOUT YOUR
WONDERFUL CHILDREN, OSCAR AND
AVA.
>> GOOD.
I LOVE IT.
ANNOUNCER: STILL TO COME, HUGH'S
TAKING EVERYONE'S QUESTIONS.
>> HAVE YOU EVER SPENT ANY TIME
AS AN ADULT IN A COLA SUIT?
>> THANK YOU, ANNE FROM
BROOKLYN.
>> MY QUESTION TO YOU IS ARE YOU
REALLY A WOLF MAN ALL OVER?
♪
WHEN MY BABY SMILES AT ME, I GO
TO RIO DEGENTLEMAN NARROW, I GO
OUT AND THEN I HAVE TO DO THE
SAMBA AND LA BAM BA ♪
[LAUGHTER]
[APPLAUSE]
KATIE: THAT'S LIKE THROWING OUT
RAW MEAT TO THIS CROWD.
THAT BECAUSE THE SCENE FROM "THE
BOYS FROM OZ" CONSIDERED ONE OF
HUGH'S FINEST ROLE BUT HE WOULD
SAY HIS BEST WORK IS RAISING
OSCAR AND AVA.
YOU LOVE BEING A DAD, DON'T YOU?
YOU'RE THE YOUNGEST, RIGHT?
>> YES.
MY MUM AND DAD HAD FIVE AND MY
MUM HAD ANOTHER DAUGHTER.
SO I REALLY GREW UP IN TERMS OF
MY HOUSEHOLD, THE YOUNGEST OF
FIVE.
AND I LOVE THE CHAOS OF FAMILY.
HONESTLY, THE -- IT IS, THE
CALMER I GET.
KATIE: MY KIDS ARE OLDER NOW, 21
AND 16 AND I WISH I HAD MORE
KIDS.
I LIKE THE NOISE AND THE CHAOS
TOO.
>> HOW ARE YOUR KIDS?
KATIE: THEY'RE GREAT.
KERRY'S 16.
AND IN HER JUNIOR OF HIGH
SCHOOL.
AND LAST NIGHT --
>> KERRY'S COMING BACK HOME TO
LIVE?
KATIE: NO.
YOU MEAN ELLY?
KERRY IS THE YOUNGEST ONE.
STUDYING  STUDYING LAST
NIGHT AND SHE SAID PLEASE STAY
UP WITH ME.
SO I WAS LIKE OH, THE GUILTY.
-- GUILT.
>> YEAH, RIGHT.
KATIE: AND I SAID I WILL JUST
LIE HER.
AND AT 1:00, I'M SLEEPING VERY
HAPPY AND ALL OF A SUDDEN, I
HEAR THIS CRYING IN THE ROOM
NEXT DOOR AND I WOKE UP AND SHE
GOES I'M JUST REALLY STRESSED
OUT.
YEAH, I KNOW.
IT'S TERRIBLE.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THE KIDS
BECAUSE OSCAR IS ALMOST 13.
AVA IS 8, RIGHT?
>> ALMOST 8.
KATIE: AND I KNOW THEY HAVE
DIFFERENT VIEWS OF THE
PAPARAZZI.
SOMETIMES I SEE THERE'S HUGH
GOING RUNNING INTO THE SURF WITH
HIS KIDS.
OSCAR HATED IT, RIGHT?
>> HE ALWAYS HATED IT HE WAS
LIKE 2 1/2 AND HE CAMED HE
AND HE WOULD START CRYING JUST
WITH THE FLASH AND ALL OF THAT.
HE REALLY HATED IT.
AND LUCKILY NOW, ACTUALLY IN
AUSTRALIA, I GET A FAIR BIT OF
-- THEY'LL LEAVE US ALONE.
EVEN THE PHOTOGRAPHERS CAN TELL
IT'S A REAL DOWNER FOR HIM.
I'M ALWAYS TRYING TO PROTECT
HIM.
IT WAS MEG RYAN AGAIN -- I ASKED
WHAT DO YOU DO WITH YOUR SON?
AND SHE'S LIKE WHAT DO YOU --
YOU LOOK AT THEM FROM THEIR
VIEW.
ALL THE PEOPLE WILL ASK FOR
THEIR PHOTOGRAPH.
AND HE GOES THIS IS THEIR TIME
WITH YOU AND THEY'RE HOLDING
THEIR HAND AND SO IT'S RARE TO
GET TIME WITH YOU.
SO WHAT SHE DOES AND WHAT I NOW
DO IS I ALWAYS ASK THE KIDS IF
THEY MIND IF THEY TAKE A PHOTO?
AND PEOPLE SAY HANG ON.
I'VE GOT CHECK WITH MY KIDS.
AND SOMETIMES, THEY'LL SAY YES
AND SOMETIMES THEY'LL SAY NO.
BUT FOR A LONG TIME, I WOULD SAY
NO, I'M WITH MY KIDS AND
FINALLY, MY SON GOES DAD, WHY
CAN'T YOU JUST BE NICE?
THEY JUST WANT A PHOTOGRAPH.
[LAUGHTER]
KATIE: YOU CAN'T WIN, RIGHT?
>> NO.
BUT MY DAUGHTER ON THE OTHER
HAND, WE WILL GO OUT AND I'LL
SEE C.C. THE PAPARAZZI TO THE
RIGHT AND I WILL TURN LEFT AND
SHE GOES WHERE ARE WE GOING?
THE PAPARAZZI IS THIS WAY.
ALL MUGGING, WINK, WINK.
PULLING MY EARS AND DOING THE
WHOLE THING.
KATIE: THAT'S SO FUNNY.
>> I KNOW.
I'M MORE WORRIED ABOUT THAT.
KATIE: THEY'RE VERY CUTE KIDS.
YOU'VE ACTUALLY TALKED VERY
OPENLY ABOUT THE FACT THAT YOU
AND DEB HAD SOME FERTILITY
ISSUES AND THE CHILDREN ARE
ADOPTED.
AND THAT I THINK PEOPLE DON'T
REALIZE WHAT AN EXCRUCIATING
DIFFICULT TIME THAT IS WHEN
YOU'RE TRYING TO HAVE A CHILD
AND YOU'RE HAVING A LOT OF
DIFFICULTY.
>> IT IS.
YOU KNOW, IT'S INTERESTING UNTIL
YOU GO THROUGH IT, YOU REALIZE
WE DON'T TALK ABOUT IT A LOT.
DEB AND I ALWAYS WANTED TO HAVE
KIDS.
WE DIDN'T KNOW WHERE IN THE
PROCESS THAT WOULD HAPPEN.
BIOLOGICALLY, WE TRIED AND IT
WAS NOT HAPPENING FOR US AND IT
IS A DIFFICULT TIME.
WE DID AN I.V.F. AND DEB HAD A
COUPLE OF MISCARRIAGES AND THE
MISCARRIAGE THING IS ALSO -- AND
APPARENTLY, HAPPEN TO ONE IN
THREE PREGNANCY BUT IT'S VERY,
VERY RARELY TALKED ABOUT.
IT'S ALMOST SECRETIVE.
SO I HOPE DEB DOESN'T MINE ME
BRINGING IT UP NOW BUT IT'S A
GOOD THING TO TALK ABOUT.
IT'S MORE COMMON AND IT IS
TOUGH.
THERE'S A GRIEVING YOU HAVE TO
GO THROUGH.
THE MOMENT OSCAR WAS BORN, YOU
KNOW, ALL THE HEARTACHE JUST
MELTED AWAY AND IT'S ONE OF THE
GREAT -- WELL, YOU GUYS, MANY OF
YOU ARE PARENTS, YOU KNOW.
YOU CAN'T PREPARE FOR THAT
MOMENT.
NOTHING CAN PREPARE YOU.
YOU CAN'T EVEN EXPLAIN HOW
INCREDIBLE IT IS AND THAT
AVALANCHE OF EMOTIONS IT COMES
AND HOW IT OPENS UP YOUR HEART,
HOW IT FRUSTRATES YOU, HOW IT
ANGER YOU, HOW EVERYTHING IS ALL
OF A SUDDEN, ALIVE OF YOU AS A
APPARENT.
>> IT'S -- PARENT.
KATIE: IT'S SO HUMBLING BECAUSE
YOU'RE SURROUNDED WITH PEOPLE
WHO ARE DOING FOR YOU AND YOU'RE
OBVIOUSLY THE CELEBRATED PERSON
AND JUSTIFIABLY SO, BUT TO BE
ONE-ON-ONE WITH A CHILD WHO
REALLY HAS NO REASON TO LOVE YOU
EXCEPT THAT YOU'RE THERE IS, I
THINK, KIND OF BRINGS YOU BACK
TO A VERY IMPORTANT PLACE, DON'T
YOU THINK?
>> CONSTANTLY.
YOU KNOW, THERE'S NOT A DAY, YOU
KNOW, I SING EVERY DAY.
IT'S PART OF MY DAILY ROUTINE.
DAD, PLEASE, CAN YOU STOP IT?
I HATE IT WHEN YOU SING.
STOP.
[LAUGHTER]
THERE ARE SOME PEOPLE -- I DON'T
WANT TO HEAR OTHER PEOPLE.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR IT.
IT IS VERY HUMBLING.
KATIE: THE OTHER THING I THINK
PROBABLY PEOPLE DON'T KNOW ABOUT
YOU OR SOME PEOPLE IS THAT YOUR
DAD RAISED THE FIVE KIDS.
YOUR MOM LEFT WHEN YOU WERE 8
YEARS OLD.
SHE WENT TO ENGLAND AND I THINK
HER MOM WAS SICK, RIGHT?
>> YEAH.
I'M THE YOUNGEST.
SO MY OLDEST SISTER WAS 16.
SO MY MUM IS THERE FOR MANY,
MANY YEARS BUT OBVIOUSLY FROM
WHEN I WAS 8 THROUGH UNTIL 18,
MUM WAS LIVING IN ENGLAND.
AND IT WAS HARD.
I WAS IN AUSTRALIA AND HER MUM
WAS VERY, VERY ILL.
SO SHE WENT BACK -- I DON'T
THINK SHE EVER EXPECTED IT TO GO
ON THAT LONG, YOU KNOW.
KATIE: WHAT WAS THAT ABOUT?
I KNOW YOU WOULD SEE HER ONCE A
YEAR.
>> YEAH.
KATIE: SHE LEFT HER FIVE KIDS.
THAT SEEMS SO STRANGE.
>> YOU KNOW, LOOK, OBVIOUSLY,
MUM AND I HAVE COME TO PEACE
WITH IT.
WE'VE HAD A LOT OF TALKS AND MY
MOM IS A BEAUTIFUL, BEAUTIFUL
PERSON AND I LOVE HER VERY MUCH
AND WE SPEND A LOT OF TIME
TOGETHER.
AND SHE -- AGAIN, I DON'T THINK
SHE MINDS ME SAYING THIS BUT SHE
SUFFERED VERY SEVERELY FROM
PERSONAL SEVERE DEPRESSION.
SHE HAD A VERY TOUGH TIME AND
WITHOUT GETTING INTO SPECIFICS
TO GO THROUGH THAT, AND STILL
HAVE FIVE KIDS AND BE AWAY FROM
YOUR SUPPORT NETWORK.
BECAUSE THEY ALL CAME FROM
ENGLAND TO AUSTRALIA SO FEELING
VERY MUCH ON HER OWN, I THINK TO
SURMISE IT IN THE BEST WAY I CAN
TO SUPPORT MY MUM THAT SHE KIND
OF WOKE UP IN A WAY, A LITTLE
LATER AFTER IT ALL HAPPENED, YOU
KNOW, AND SHE SAID TO ME, SHE
FEELS LIKE OH, THAT WAS LIKE
ANOTHER PERSON WHEN I MADE ALL
THOSE DECISIONS.
YOU ALL ARE O YOU ALL ARE ON G
TERMS NOW
>> YEAH.
I NEVER FELT MY MUM DIDN'T LOVE
ME.
HONEST, I NEVER HAD THAT ANGER
OF BALTIMORE OR WHATEVER PEOPLE
OR -- ABANDONMENT OR WHATEVER
MIGHT HAPPEN.
I ALWAYS FELT GREAT LOVE FOR MY
MUM AND DAD.
WHAT MY DAD DID, THAT WAS A
DECADE OF HIS LIFE.
HE NEVER HAD A SECOND TO
HIMSELF.
EVER.
AND HE NEVER ONCE COMPLAINED.
AND ONE OF THE TIMES I'M MOST
ASHAMED ABOUT AS A KID WAS A
COUSIN CAME OVER AND FROM
ENGLAND.
I'VE NEVER MET HIM BEFORE.
MATTHEW.
AND HE PULLED ME AND MY BROTHER
ASIDE AND GOES YOU GUYS SHOULD
BE ASHAMED OF YOURSELF.
AND I GO WHAT ARE YOU TALKING
ABOUT?
YOUR FATHER, HE COMES HOME 7:00,
AFTER WORKING ALL DAY.
HE GOES STRAIGHT THE KITCHEN AND
COOKS YOU GUYS IN THE MEAL AND
THE ONLY THING I'VE HEARD YOU
GUYS SAY IS WHAT TIME IS DINNER,
DAD?
AND YOU NEVER CAME TO HELP.
AND I SAT THERE AND IT WAS LIKE
ALL OF A SUDDEN, THIS WAVE OF
OH, MY GOD.
IT REALLY HIT ME AT AGE 14, YOU
KNOW, WHAT MY FATHER HAD DONE.
KATIE: AND THE SUFFICE TO SEE HE
MADE FOR YOU -- SACRIFICE TO SEE
HE MADE FOR YOU GUYS.
>> NONSTOP.
I'VE NEVER HEARD HIM SAY A BAD
WORD ABOUT ANYONE.
I'VE NEVER HEARD HIM SAY DO YOU
KNOW WHAT I HAVE DONE FOR YOU?
WHERE'S THE GRATITUDE.
EVER.
HE JUST WENT ABOUT IT.
KATIE: WHEN YOU PLAYED AT
CARNEGIE HALL, THERE WAS A VERY
SPECIAL MOMENT ABOUT YOU AND
YOUR DAD.
>> SO MY DAD, ALL THE BEST
QUALITIES PROBABLY YOU MIGHT SAY
ABOUT ME, I'VE PICKED UP FROM MY
DAD.
MY DAD WORKED HARD, VERY
ETHICAL, NEVER MISSED A DAY OF
WORK IN HIS LIFE AND ALWAYS VERY
SWEET ABOUT THE WORK I'VE DONE,
EVEN WHEN IT WAS SOMETHING LIKE
"VAN HELSING" THAT HE HAD NO
INTEREST IN.
WONDERFUL, HUGH.
YOU WERE JUST WONDERFUL.
[LAUGHTER]
VAN HELSING IS JUST REALLY, YOU
KNOW?
THANKS, DAD.
TOLD HIM TOLD HIM I WAS GOING
TO PERFORM "CAROUSEL" AT
CARNEGIE HALL, HE COULDN'T HIDE
HIS ENTHUSIASM.
I'M GOING.
AND HE DID AND HE TOOK THREE
DAYS OFF WORK FOR THE FIRST DAY
OF HIS LIFE AND IT'S A 24-HOUR
FLIGHT FROM SYDNEY TO NEW YORK.
KATIE: DID YOU KNOW HE WAS
COMING?
>> YEAH.
AND HE WAS THERE FOR 24 HOURS,
LITERALLY GOT BACK, FLIED BACK
STRAIGHT TO THE OFFICE.
AND HE'S A STICKLER TO DETAILS,
MY DAD.
SO HE WANTED TO KNOW EVERYTHING
ABOUT THE ITINERARY, DRESS ROAD,
HOTEL, IT WAS BLACK TIE, THE
WHOLE THING.
AND THE DAY HE ARRIVED WAS THE
DAY OF THE PERFORMANCE AND I
FOUND OUT IT WAS NOT BLACK TIE.
IT WAS ACTUALLY BUSINESS CASUAL
AND I'M FREAKING OUT.
IT'S SUMMER.
I THOUGHT HE WAS ARRIVING IN
SHORTS AND THONGS.
FLIP-FLOPS OR SOMETHING.
SO I RANG HIM AND I SAID DAD,
IT'S NOT BLACK TIE, IT'S
BUSINESS CASUAL.
HE GOES I'VE GOT IT COVERED.
HE SAYS HUGH, PLEASE DO ME A
FAVOR.
I DON'T WANT TO BOTHER YOU.
I KNOW IT'S A BIG NIGHT FOR YOU.
DON'T WORRY, BUT I WOULD JUST
LOVE AND PICK YOU UP AT YOUR
HOTEL ROOM AND WALK YOU TO THE
STAGE BEFORE THE PERFORMANCE.
I WAS VERY TOUCHED BY THAT.
AND I SAID GREAT.
I SAID MAYBE AT 6 -- MEET ME AT
6:30.
KNOCK ON THE DOOR.
HE'S AN ACCOUNTANT.
6:30 AND THERE'S MY FATHER IN
FULL BLACK TIE STANDING.
AND I GO WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
NO ONE IS WEARING THE BLACK TIE
EXCEPT THE CHOIR.
AND HE LOOKED ME STRAIGHT IN THE
EYE AND HE SAID "HUGH, MY SON IS
SINGING AT CARNEGIE HALL.
IT IS BLACK TIE FOR ME."
KATIE: SO SWEET.
[APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: STILL HO COME, KATIE
AND HUGH IN A BROADWAY TUNE
SING-OFF.
>> ♪
WE'RE HERE ON "KATIE COURIC
SHOW" ♪
[APPLAUSE]
ANNOUNCER: THAT'S LATER.
KATIE: OK.
SO I'VE GOT TO ASK YOU A LOT OF
QUESTIONS.
WE'VE SOLICITED YES, SIR FROM
SOCIAL MEDIA AND MEMBERS FROM
OUR AUDIENCE.
ON TWITTER, ROB ASKS WHEN IS
HUGH JACKMAN SHOWING UP ON
"GLEE"?
WOULD YOU DO "GLEE"?
>> YEAH.
KATIE: YOU WOULD?
DO YOU LIKE THE SHOW?
>> I HAVE ONLY SEEN ONE EPISODE.
KATIE: DID YOU LIKE IT?
>> YEAH, I LIKED IT A LOT.
YEAH, HAVEN'T BEEN ASKED.
IT WOULD BE FUN TO DO.
KATIE: WE HAVE A QUESTION FROM
JAY IN THE AUDIENCE.
JAY, WHERE YOU?
HI, JAY.
>> YOU HAVE ONE OF THE
JOURNALISTS FROM COLUMBIA.
JAY.
KATIE: WHAT'S YOUR QUESTION.
>> EASY.
SOFTBALLS.
NICE EASY ONES.
>> SO THERE'S ONCE TALK THAT YOU
MIGHT PLAY JAMES BOND.
IS THAT STILL A POSSIBILITY IN
THE FUTURE?
[APPLAUSE]
>> JAY, I'LL CLEAR SOMETHING UP.
ABOUT 20 YEARS AGO.
NO ONE WAS LISTENING.
DANIEL IS A GREAT MIND AND AS
LONG AS DANIEL WANTS IT,
OBVIOUSLY IT'S HIS BUT THERE'S
NOT AN ACTOR ON THE PLANET WHO
DOESN'T SOMEWHERE IN THEIR MIND
THINK I COULD PLAY JAMES BOND.
KATIE: CAN YOU SAY "BOND, JAMES
BOND"?
>> BOND.
JAMES BOND.
[APPLAUSE]
KATIE: OK.
ALL RIGHT, NOW WE GOT SOME
QUESTIONS FROM PEOPLE ON THE
OUTSIDE.
>> OH.
KATIE: SO LET'S GO TO ANNE FROM
BROOKLYN, NEW YORK.
>> HUGH, HAVE YOU EVER SPENT ANY
TIME AS AN ADULT IN A KOALA
SUIT?
>> THANK YOU, ANNE, FROM
BROOKLYN, I REALLY APPRECIATE
THAT QUESTION, AND YOU LOOK
STUNNING BY THE WAY.
YES, I HAVE.
FAR TOO MUCH TIME.
I USED TO ACTUALLY BE RANGER
HUGH, RIGHT, PROMOTING THE
NATIONAL PARKS AND WILDLIFE AND
I WOULD GO WITH SUZY, WHO WOULD
DRESS UP IN A KOALA SUIT.
ONE DAY, SHE FAINTED AND IT WAS
CLEANING IT UP ON THE INSIDE ON
ABOUT A 100-DEGREE DAY.
YES, THAT WAS NOT WORTH $12 AN
HOUR.
BUT THANK YOU, ANNE.
KATIE: IT'S SOME OF YOUR FINEST
WORD.
NEXT, WE HAVE SASHA FROM LONDON.
>> HUGH, THIS IS SASHA CONE AND
I'VE SHARED THE STAGE AND SCREEN
WITH YOU AND MY QUESTION TO YOU
IS ARE YOU REALLY A WOLF MAN ALL
OVER?
OR JUST ON THE EXTERNAL?
KATIE: RAW WOLF MAN ALL OVER OR
JUST IN THE EXTREMITIES?
[LAUGHTER]
>> SASHA BARREN COHEN, HE'S AN
-- SACHA BARON COHEN, HE'S AN
INCREDIBLE STAGE ACTOR.
UM --
[APPLAUSE]
IN. D
IN.
GET OUT OF HERE.
NO, IT'S REALLY FAR TOO MUCH
HAIR.
BUT UNLIKE MY FATHER, THERE'S
NONE ON THE BACK, WHICH IS GOOD.
KATIE: GOOD.
BACK HAIR IS NOT A GOOD LOOK.
ALL RIGHT.
BEFORE WE GO, I DO WANT TO
MENTION HUGH IS VERY, VERY
PHILANTHROPIC AND GENEROUS WITH
HIS TIME FOR SO MANY DIFFERENT
CAUSES BUT YOU STARTED YOUR OWN
COFFEE COMPANY.
TELL ME ABOUT THAT.
>> YES.
I WAS SO INSPIRED BY PAUL NEWMAN
AND WHAT HE DID WITH PAUL
NEWMAN'S OWN AND I READ HIS BOOK
AND FOR A LONG TIME, I FIGURED
ONE OF THE GREAT WAYS AS A
CELEBRITY WAS STARTING A
BUSINESS.
I JUST LOVE COFFEE.
I LOVE IT AND ME AND MY FRIEND,
BARRY HAD BEEN IN THE COFFEE
BUSINESS HIS WHOLE LIFE.
WE STARTED AN EXERCISE WHERE WE
MAKE GREAT, GREAT COFFEE.
IT'S CALLED LAUGHING MAN COFFEE
AND TEA.
WE HAVE CHOCOLATES AS WELL.
AND PROFITS GO BACK TO
CHARITIES.
WHICH IS -- ONE OF WHICH IS THE
CHARITY THAT WE SUPPORT.
KATIE: A HARLEM SCHOOL IN NEW
YORK CITY.
I HAD MIRE HOW YOU GIVE BACK SO
MUCH TO SO MANY DIFFERENT
ORGANIZATIONS.
>> KELL, COMING FROM YOU, THAT
MEANS A LOT.
KATIE: COMING UP, HUGH TAKES ON
THE MOST CHALLENGING ROLE OF HIS
CAREER.
HE'S GOING HEAD-TO-HEAD WITH ME
IN A GAME CALLED "SING THAT SHOW
TUNE."
THAT'S RIGHT, BABY!
THAT'S RIGHT.
AFTER THIS.
I'VE GOT A NICE LONG LIFE AHEAD.
BIG PLANS.
SO WHEN I FOUND OUT
Medicare DOESN'T PAY
ALL MY MEDICAL EXPENSES,
I GOT A Medicare
SUPPLEMENT INSURANCE PLAN.
[ Male Announcer ] IF YOU'RE
ELIGIBLE FOR Medicare,
YOU MAY KNOW
IT ONLY COVERS ABOUT 80%
OF YOUR Part B
MEDICAL EXPENSES.
THE REST IS UP TO YOU.
CALL AND FIND OUT
ABOUT AN AARP Medicare
Supplement Insurance Plan,
INSURED BY UnitedHealthcare
Insurance Company.
LIKE ALL STANDARDIZED Medicare
SUPPLEMENT PLANS,
IT COULD SAVE YOU THOUSANDS
IN OUT-OF-POCKET COSTS.
CALL NOW TO REQUEST
YOUR FREE DECISION GUIDE.
I'VE BEEN WITH MY DOCTOR
FOR 12 YEARS.
NOW I KNOW I'LL BE ABLE
TO STICK WITH HIM.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO VISIT
ANY DOCTOR OR HOSPITAL
THAT ACCEPTS Medicare PATIENTS.
PLUS, THERE ARE NO NETWORKS,
AND YOU NEVER NEED A REFERRAL.
SEE WHY MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
HAVE ALREADY ENROLLED
IN THE ONLY Medicare Supplement
Insurance Plans
ENDORSED BY AARP.
DON'T WAIT. CALL NOW.
KATIE: OK, EVERYBODY, WE'RE
BACK.
YOU KNOW, HUGH THINKS HE'S MR.
MUSICAL THEATER BUT I'M NO
SLOUCH MYSELF IN THAT DEPARTMENT
SO IT'S TIME TO PLAY "SING THAT
SHOW TUNE."
WHOO.
ALL RIGHT.
CAN WE HAVE A LITTLE MORE
ENTHUSIASM?
I'VE ASKED THE LEGENDARY, BY THE
WAY, A BIG SURPRISE, MICHAEL
FEINSTEIN IS HERE, AUTHOR OF THE
NEW BOOK, "THE GERSHWINS AND
ME."
>> WHAT?
KATIE: TO ACCOMPANY US ON THE
PIANO.
[APPLAUSE]
HI, MICHAEL.
HOW SWEET IS THIS?
SO THE WAY THE GAME WORKS IS ON
THIS VIDEO SCREEN ON OUR RIGHT,
IT'S GOING TO COME UP AT RANDOM
FROM A SONG ON A BROADWAY SHOW.
IS --
>> HANG ON.
IS IT RAP DONOVAN DOM?
KATIE: OF COURSE IT IS, HUGH.
HERE'S THE FIRST SONG FOR HUGH
AND THE SONG IS --
>> MY GOD.
OH.
♪
JUNE IS BUSTING OUT ALL OVER
"THE KATIE COURIC SHOW" IS SO
FANTASTIC WHERE WITH MICHAEL
FEINSTEIN AND KATIE AND THIS
GREAT AUDIENCE WHAT MORE CAN
ANYONE WANT ♪
[APPLAUSE]
[BELL]
KATIE: WOW.
NICE JOB.
I LIKE THOSE LYRICS.
>> I LOVE HIS LYRICS.
>> FORGET IT.
KATIE: OK.
MY SONG IS --
>> OH.
KATIE: OH.
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
CAN I JUST MENTION I CAN'T SING
IF I AUDITIONED MY BROADWAY
MUSICAL AND THEY CAST ME AS A
DEATH MUTE.
AND THAT IS A TRUE STORY.
♪
GETTING TO KNOW YOU
GETTING TO KNOW ALL ABOUT YOU
SPEED IT UP, MICHAEL
GETTING TO LIKE YOU
GETTING TO HOPE YOU LIKE ME ♪
>> AWW, I DO LIKE YOU.
KATIE: ♪
GETTING TO KNOW YOU DOING
WAY IT MY
WAY BUT NICELY YOU ARE PRECISELY
MY CUP OF TEA ♪
>> AWW.
[BELL]
[APPLAUSE]
KATIE: ALL RIGHT.
>> SHE'S SO CHEATING.
YOU SO KNEW THAT WAS COMING UP.
KATIE: NO.
>> WHY DONE YOU SING THIS NEXT
ONE.
NO.
I DON'T MIND.
KATIE: I WAS GETTING BITTER AND
-- YOU'RE GETTING BITTER AND
ANGRY.
I LIKE THIS SIDE OF YOU, HUGH.
HUGH'S NEXT SONG IS --
>> AWW.
KATIE: OH, MY GOD.
HELLO, EASY PEACEY.
-- PEASY.
>> ♪
THERE'S A BRIGHT GOLDEN HAZE ON
THE MEADOW THERE'S A BRIGHT
GOLDEN HAZE ON THE MEADOW THE
CORN IS AS HIGH AS AN ELEPHANT'S
EYE AND IT LOOKS LIKE IT'S
CLIMBING CLEAR UP TO THE SKY ♪
♪
COME ON EVERYBODY, JOIN ME ♪
OH WHAT A BEAUTIFUL MORNING
VERY GOOD OH, WHAT A BEAUTIFUL
DAY
I GOT A BEAUTIFUL FEELING
EVERYTHING'S GOING KATIE'S WAY
♪
[APPLAUSE]
KATIE: OK.
CAN I JUST SAY --
>> THANK YOU VERY MUCH, MICHAEL.
KATIE: THAT WAS TOTALLY UNFAIR
BECAUSE -- THAT WAS TOTALLY
UNFAIR.
>> I PROBABLY SUNG THAT 400
TIMES.
KATIE: BECAUSE HUGH PLAYED CURLY
IN "OKLAHOMA."
MY NEXT SONG IS -- OH.
♪
I'M AS CORNY AS KANSAS IN AUGUST
TIME IS NORMAL -- I SOUND AWFUL
NO MORE A SMART LITTLE GIRL WITH
NO HEART I HAVE FOUND ME A
WONDERFUL GUY ♪
THAT'S ALL I KNOW.
THANK YOU.
[APPLAUSE]
[BELL]
AND FINALLY --
>> ALL THE TRASH TALKING YOU DID
IN THE COMMERCIAL BREAK AND NOW
YOU'RE BEING SO SWEET.
KATIE: FINALLY -- I THINK YOU'RE
SWEET, TOO.
>> OH, OK.
OH, WOW.
YEAH.
♪
I'M GOING TO STRUGGLE WITH THE
LYRICS ♪
CONSIDER YOURSELF AT HOME
CONSIDER YOURSELF ONE OF THE
FAMILY
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE SO MUCH FUN
♪
KATIE: TAKE IT TO YOU SO STRONG
>> ♪
WE'RE HERE ON "THE KATIE COURIC
SHOW" BECAUSE WHEN YOU'RE HERE
WITH MICHAEL FEINSTEIN AND KATIE
COURIC -- IS THAT HOW THE LYRICS
ARE?
>> THAT'S THE ORIGINAL.
>> I DON'T KNOW LYRICS.
THAT WAS TERRIBLE.
[APPLAUSE]
KATIE: THAT WAS GOOD.
NO, THAT WAS GOOD.
>> THANK YOU.
I LOVE THAT SONG.
KATIE: I KNOW YOU HAVE TO GO,
BUT MAYBE YOU CAN SING US OUT
WITH ONE OF THE SONGS FROM YOUR
SHOW. OW.
ONE OF YOUR FAVORITE SONGS.
>> OH, SURE.
KATIE: MICHAEL, YOU KNOW WHAT IT
IS.
SING THE INTRO.
♪
A, DAH, BA, DAH, BA, DA ♪
>> ♪
AND SINGING IN THE RAIN
JUST SINGING IN THE RAIN
WHAT A GLORIOUS FEELING I'M
HAPPY AGAIN OH
[LAUGHTER]
I'M LAUGHING OUT LOUD
WHEN CLOUDS ARE ABOVE -- STORM
ARE UP ABOVE I'M SINGING AND
DANCING IN THE RAIN ♪
[APPLAUSE]
KATIE: HUGH JACKMAN.
>> MATT RYAN MICHAEL FEINSTEIN!
[APPLAUSE]
KATIE: GOOD LUCK.
GOOD LUCK.
>> THANK YOU.
KATIE: WISHING YOU ALL THE BEST
IN "LES MIS."
I KNOW IT'S GOING TO BE A HUGE
HIT AND YOU'RE SO WONDERFUL IN
IT.
AND HUGH, THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> AWW, MY PLEASURE.
YOU'RE MY CUP OF TEA.
THANK YOU.
[CAPTIONED BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE
--WWW.NCICAP.ORG--]
>>> GOOD AFTERNOON, EVERYONE,
I'M LARRY BEIL.
>> NATIONAL RIFLE ASSOCIATION
IS BREAKING IT'S SILENCE FOUR
DAYS AFTER THE CONNECTICUT
SCHOOL SHOOTING, SAYING IT
WANTED TO GIVE FAMILIES TIME
TO MOURN BEFORE MAKING IT'S
STATEMENTS.
>> THE GROUP SAYS MEMBERS WERE
QUOTE, SHOCKED, SADDENED AND
HEART BROKEN BY THE NEWS.
THE GROUP ALSO PLEDGED TO
QUOTE HELP MAKE SURE THAT THIS
NEVER HAPPENS AGAIN.
THE NRA SCHEDULED A NEWS
CONFERENCE FOR FRIDAY.
>> RIGHT NOW IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT MORE VICTIMS OF
THE TRAGEDY BEING LAID TO
REST.
>> ABC NEWS REPORTER TJ WINNIK
IS THERE.
>> OFFICIALS SAY IT'S UNCLEAR
IF SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY WILL
EVER REOPEN.
IT WAS A SOMBER DAY FOR MANY
PARENTS HERE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT SENDING THEIR
THE FIRST TIME SINCE THE
SHOOTING.
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY REMAINS
CLOSED AND A SECOND SCHOOL
CLOSED TODAY FOR PRECAUTION
NAIRY REASON AUTOS A LOT OF
PEOPLE ARE NERVOUS TO BE BACK
TO SCHOOL.
A LOT PECHL DON'T WANT TO BE
HERE.
>> I THINK GETTING BACK INTO A
ROUTINE IS THE BEST THING.
>> THERE IS NO WORDS.
JUST TEAR AUTOS IN THIS
CATHOLIC CHURCH, BACK TO BACK
FUNERALS.
A SERVICE ENDS FOR A
6-YEAR-OLD JAMES, HIS CASKET
PLACED BACK IN THE HEARSE.Y,f&r
SEVERAL MINUTES LATER ANOTHER
TINY WHITE CASKET IS CARRIED
INSIDE OF THE CHURCH.
>> IT'S HARD TO GET YOUR MIND
AROUND IT.
YOU KNOW?
THAT SOMEONE SO YOUNG, WOULD
LEAVE NEWS SUCH A PEACEFUL
COMMUNITY OVER A?; HORRIFIC
EVENT.
>> THREE OTHER SHOOTINGNvKK
[g ALSO HAVE SES
TODAY.
THE BODY OF 6-YEAR-OLD EMILY
PARKER RETURNED TO HER FAMILY
TO HER HOME STATE OF UTAH.
IN MONROE, VOLUNTEERS CONTINUE
PREPARE A MIDDLE SCHOOL FOR
STUDENTS TO ATTEND.
>> WE'RE GOING TO WORK WITH
EVERYBODY THROUGHOUT THE
PROCESS IN ORDER TO PROVIDE
WHAT THEY NEED IN ORDER TO GET
THROUGH THIS.
THAT IS WHAT IS TRULY
IMPORTANT TO US.
>> THE CRIMINAL ZBAIGS
PROCEEDING AS AUTHORITIES COMB
THROUGH EVERY INCH OFmçm$Y GUNMN
ADAM LANZA'S LIVE, SEARCHING
FOR CLUES OF.