>> AND PRESIDENT OBAMA DECLARES.
>> THESE TRAGEDIES MUST END.
>> ASKING ALL AMERICAN IF WE ARE
DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN SAFE.
BUT IS WASHINGTON DOING ENOUGH?
>> FROM THE GLOBAL RESOURCES OF
ABC NEWS, THIS IS A SPECIAL
EDITION OF "NIGHTLINE," TRAGEDY
AT SANDY HOOK, THE SEARCH FOR
SOLUTIONS.
>> I'M CYNTHIA McFADDEN.
TODAY THE FIRST OF FAR TOO MANY
FUNERALS IN A SMALL COMMUNITY
CHANGED BY TRAGEDY.
THREE DAYS AGO 20 CHILDREN AND
SIX ADULTS WERE KILLED IN A
CONNECTICUT ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, A
MASS SHOOTING THAT SENT SHOCK
WAVES OF DEGREE ACROSS THE
COUNTRY.
ABC'S JUJU CHANG REPORTS FROM
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL IS CLOSED
TOMORROW.
AND WHEN THE CHILDREN RETURN IT
WILL BE TO A DIFFERENT CAMPUS.
THE TOWN IS COVERED WITH
MEMORIALS LIKE THIS ONE THAT
TAKE ON A FEELING OF A SACRED
SIGHT AS PEOPLE MAKE PILGRIMAGES
FROM ALL OVER.
UNDER A COLD STEADY RAIN, A WAVE
OF COMMUNAL GRIEF WASHES OVER
NEWTOWN.
MEMORIALS GROWING IN SETS OF 20
FOR THE CHILDREN.
20 CHRISTMAS TREES, 20
POINSETTIAS, 20 ANGELS.
TODAY THE FIRST FUNERALS IN A
FOUND WHOSE FAITH IS BEING
TESTED IN WAYS IT COULD NEVER
HAVE IMAGINED.
>>> FOR SIX-YEAR-OLD JACK PINTO
A HUGE NEW YORK GIANTS FAN.
AND NOAH POZNER WHOSE SISTER
SURVIVED IN ANOTHER CLASSROOM.
THE RABBI STRUGGLED FOR THE
RIGHT WORDS.
TODAY A MUCH TOUGHER TASK, A
EULOGY FOR A SIX-YEAR-OLD AS A
WOMAN COLLAPSED OUTSIDE IN
GRIEF, THE RABBI INSIDE TRIED TO
FIND WORDS TO COMFORT NOAH'S
GRIEVING MOTHER.
>> I LOOKED AT HER AND SAID I
PERSONALLY BELIEVE IN THE
ETERNITY OF THE SOUL.
>> AND DID NOAH'S FAMILY RESPOND
THE TO THAT?
>> YES.
THAT WAS HELPFUL TO HER.
IN THE END SHE RELEASED BLUE AND
WHITE BALLOONS INTO THE SKY
UNTIL WE COULDN'T SEE THEM ANY
MORE.
AND THAT WAS A GOOD SYMBOL, TO
LET IT GO.
SHE SAID GO, MY SON INTO THE
BLUE SKIES.
GO MY SON INTO THE GREEN
PASTURES.
>> CHRIS IS PLANNING HER
DAUGHTER'S FUNERAL TOMORROW.
JESSICA WAS DEVOTED TO HER TWO
YOUNGER SIBLINGS AND LEFT BEHIND
AN UNEXPECTED GIFT, A DIARY.
>> I JUST OPENED THE BOOK AND IT
SAYS I LOVE YOU SO MUCH, MAMA,
LOVE JESSICA, WITH A LITTLE
HEART.
IT IS LIKE SHE WAS, YOU KNOW,
SHE'S WATCHING US AND SHE KNOWS
HOW HARD THIS MUST BE FOR US.
AND SHE WANTS TO KNOW HOW MUCH
SHE LOVED US AND KNOWS HOW MUCH
SHE WAS LOVED.
>> Reporter: OTHERS ARE TELLING
HARROWING STORIES OF SURVIVAL.
>> THEY WERE SITTING THERE.
THEY WERE SITTING THERE.
I HAD NO IDEA WHY THEY WERE
THERE.
>> Reporter: A NEIGHBOR FOUND
SIX CHILDREN AT THE END OF HIS
DRIVEWAY AND TOOK THEM IN.
THEY WERE IN VICKY SOTO'S FIRST
GRADE CLASS.
>> THE BOYS WERE SAYING WE CAN'T
GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
WE CAN WANT GO BACK TO SCHOOL.
OUR TEACHER'S DEAD.
PL
MRS. SOTO.
WE DON'T HAVE A TEACHER.
>> Reporter: THE COUNSELLOR
CROUCHED UNDER HER DESK.
>> YOU SEE THE FEET OF THE
SHOOTER?
>> I COULD SEE HIM FROM THE
KNEES DOWN.
>> RIGHT IN FRONT OF YOU?
>> 20 FEET AWAY FACING HIS FEET.
HIS BOOTS WERE FACING MY DESK.
>> AND HE TURNED AND WALKED
AWAY.
>> SECONDS AND TURNED AND WALKED
OUT.
>> Reporter: SCHOOLS IN FIVE
STATES INCLUDING IN RIDGEFIELD,
CONNECTICUT ON LOCKDOWN DUE TO
HEIGHTENED SUSPICIONS AS
DISTRICTS FAST TRACK NEW
SECURITY PLANS.
>> IN LOCKDOWN MODE UNTIL YOU
HEAR AN ALL CLEAR ANNOUNCEMENT.
>> Reporter: SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL WAS CLOSED
TODAY.
NO ONE KNOWS WHEN STUDENTS WILL
RETURN.
BUT SOME PUT IT OUT OF THEIR
MINDS JUST FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
LACROSSE PLAYERS FROM NEW HAVEN
UNIVERSITY VOLUNTEERED TO LIFT
KIDS' SPIRITS.
>> KIND OF MAKES THEM FORGET
ABOUT IT FOR THREE OR FOUR HOURS
THEY WERE PLAYING AND HAVING FUN
AND BEING KIDS.
>> Reporter: A CHANCE FOR THE
KIDS TO ENJOY THE KINDNESS OF
STRANGERS.
>> ONCE WE ALL STARTED PLAYING
AND THE KIDS COULD SEE THEY LIT
UP, YOU KNOW.
>> THEY WANTED TO PLAY?
>> THEY WANTED TO PLAY.
YEAH.
IT WAS NICE TO SEE A SMILE ON
THEIR FACE.
>> THERE IS HOPE THAT THE SOUL
LIVES ON.
>> Reporter: FOR THE RABBI THE
TOUGH TASK OF EXPLAINING TO THE
FAITHFUL WHERE THE EVIL COMES
FROM.
>> I DON'T BELIEVE THAT GOD DID
THIS.
I BELIEVE A CRAZY MAN DID THIS.
THE MEANING IN IT IS NOT TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND WHY GOD DOES
SOMETHING.
SOMEHOW HE GOT HERE.
WE HAVE TO NOT NECESSARILY ALMS
LOOK TOWARD GOD.
BUT LOOK TOWARD HUMANITY AND SAY
WHAT IS IT THAT WE'VE DONE THAT
HAS CREATED THIS ENVIRONMENT.
>> Reporter: THE CLERGY OF THIS
SMALL NEW ENGLAND TOWN SAY THE
HOUR ROWS OF LAST WEEK HAVE
HELPED TO BOND PEOPLE TOGETHER
SPIRITUALLY.
THE RABBI'S WORDS WERE THE SAME
HE DELIVERED AT THE FUNERAL.
>> YOU HUG YOUR CHILDREN MORE.
YOU BECOME EVER PRESENT TO THE
FRAGILITY OF LIFE AND YOU LIVE
LIFE FULLER.
>> Reporter: FOR "NIGHTLINE" I'M
JUJU CHANG IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT.
>> JUST AHEAD, THE UNFOLDING
INVESTIGATION INTO WHAT COULD
HAVE LED TO THIS TERRIBLE CRIME.
♪
[ Male Announcer ] EVERY TIME
YOU SAY NO TO A CIGARETTE
YOU CELEBRATE A LITTLE WIN.
NICORETTE GUM HELPS CALM
YOUR CRAVINGS
AND MAKES YOU LESS IRRITABLE.
QUIT ONE CIGARETTE AT A TIME.
...so as you can see, GEICO's
customer satisfaction is at 97%.
Mmmm tasty.
And cut! Very good.
People are always asking me how
we make these GEICO adverts.
So we're taking you
behind the scenes.
This coffee cup, for example,
is computer animated.
It's not real.
GEICO's customer satisfaction
is quite real though.
This computer-animated
coffee tastes dreadful.
GEICO. 15 minutes could
save you 15 % or more
on car insurance.
Someone get me a latte will ya,
please?
>>> THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"NIGHTLINE," TRAGEDY AT SANDY
HOOK, THE SEARCH FOR SOLUTIONS,
CONTINUES FROM NEW YORK CITY
WITH CYNTHIA McFADDEN.
>> AS THE NATION STRUGGLES TO
COME TO TERMS WITH THE TRAGEDY
THAT STRUCK SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, NEW DETAILS
ARE EMERGING ABOUT THE
20-YEAR-OLD SHOOTER.
TONIGHT ABC NEWS CONFIRMED THAT
HIS PARENTS HAVE BEEN SEPARATED
SINCE 2001 AND HE HAD NOT SPOKEN
TO HIS FATHER OR OLDER BROTHER
IN THE LAST TWO YEARS.
ABC'S CHIEF INVESTIGATIVE
CORRESPONDENT BRIAN ROTH HAS THE
LATEST.
>> Reporter: IN THE LAST MONTH
OF ADAM LANZA'S LIFE FAMILY AND
FRIENDS SAY HE WOULD NOT LEAVE
THE HOUSE.
WITH HIS MOTHER NANCY, TELLING
THEM SHE WAS LOSING CONTROL OF
HER 20-YEAR-OLD SON.
>> IT WAS GETTING HARDER FOR HER
AS TIME WENT ON.
>> Reporter: NANCY LANZA WAS A
REGULAR AT NEWTOWN BAR AND
RESTAURANT, MY PLACE WHERE THE
OWNERS SAY SHE TOLD THEM ABOUT
HER STRUGGLES WITH ADAM'S
EMOTIONAL AND BEHAVIOR PROBLEMS
FOR YEARS.
>> SHE WAS HELPING HIM ALL THE
TIME.
SHE HOME SCHOOLED HIM AND
EVERYTHING.
SO SHE, YOU KNOW, I KNEW HE WAS
ON MEDICATION BUT THAT'S ALL I
KNOW.
>> Reporter: SINCE HER DIVORCE
FROM PETER THREE YEARS AGO, HER
FRIENDS SAY NANCY WAS LEFT TO
DEAL WITH ADAM BY HERSELF.
>> WE KNEW HE HAD A PROBLEM.
BUT SHE TOOK CARE OF IT THE BEST
SHE COULD.
SHE WAS A SINGLE MOM.
>> Reporter: SINCE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AT SANDY HOOK, THROUGH
HIGH SCHOOL, ADAM WAS KNOWN AS
STRANGE, SEVERELY SHY.
>> HE HATED AT LOOKLING AT YOUR
EYES FOR MORE THAN A COUPLE
SECONDS.
IT MADE HIM FEEL UNCOMFORTABLE
AND HE MADE YOU FEEL
UNCOMFORTABLE AS WELL.
>> Reporter: A FORMER BABYSITTER
SAID HE WAS TOLD NEVER TO LEAVE
HIM ALONE.
>> NANCY TOLD ME TO NEVER TURN
YOUR BACK ON HIM AT ANY TIME.
>> Reporter: THE FORMER SCHOOL
SECURITY DIRECTOR SAYS THAT HE
WAS SEEING THE SCHOOL
PSYCHOLOGIST.
>> IF HE CUT OR HURT HIMSELF HE
WOULD NOT KNOW IT OR FEEL IT.
WE WERE CAREFUL WITH HIM.
>> Reporter: ON FRIDAY, THE SHY
ADAM TURNED INTO A DIFFERENT
PERSON AND NOW THE MYSTERY OF
WHY IS AT THE CENTER OF THE
POLICE INVESTIGATION.
>> WE WILL ANSWER EVERY SINGLE
QUESTION, DETERMINING ANY KIND
OF MEDICAL CONDITION, ANY KIND
OF ISSUE WHATSOEVER THAT MAY
HAVE BEEN INVOLVED IN.
I'M NOT AT LIBERTY TO DISCUSS
MEDICAL CONTENT OR ANY OF THE
INFORMATION SO FAR UNCOVERED.
>> Reporter: ONE BIG QUESTION IS
WHY HIS MOTHER, KNOWING OF HIS
EMOTIONAL ISSUES INTRODUCED ADAM
TO THE WORLD OF HIGH-POWERED
GUNS INCLUDING THE SEMIAUTOMATIC
BUSHMASTER RIFLE THAT HE USED IN
HIS DEADLY RAMPAGE THAT SHE
BOUGHT LEGALLY IN MARCH 2010.
AGENTS SAY MOTHER AND SON WENT
TO THE FIRING RANGE TOGETHER IN
THE LAST SIX MONTHS.
>> YOU HAVE A CHILD THAT IS
TROUBLED AND DOESN'T BOND WITH
PEOPLE OR WITH HER, APPARENTLY
AND YOU INTRODUCE SOMETHING THAT
IS SO LETHAL AND VIOLENT IF
APPROPRIATELY USED IT'S AN
EXTREMELY POOR DECISION ON HER
PART.
>> Reporter: ESPECIALLY WITH THE
BUSHMASTER ONE OF THE MOST
POPULAR GUNS IN THE COUNTRY,
DEMONSTRATED IN A VIDEO POSTED
ON THE COMPANY YOUTUBE CHANNEL.
IT CAN FIRE 45 ROUNDS IN A
MINUTE AND MODIFIES SO IT IS
LEGAL EVEN UNDER THE CONNECTICUT
LAW MEANT TO BAN THE WEAPONS.
>> IF YOU GO TO THEIR WEBSITE
THEY HAVE A PAGE CALLED STATE
COMPLIANT.
BUT IT IS STILL JUST AS DEADLY.
IT MAKES IT DANGEROUS OF COURSE
IS THE ABILITY TO TAKE UNLIMITED
AMOUNTS OF AMMUNITION IN THE
PISTOL GRIP.
>> Reporter: ON FRIDAY ADAM
SHOWED UP AT THE SCHOOL WITH THE
BUSHMASTER AND TWO HANDGUNS AND
HUNDREDS OF BULLETS, ENOUGH TO
KILL EVERYONE, EVERY STUDENT AND
CHILDREN ONLY THE SOUND OF
APPROACHING POLICE STOPPED HIM.
>> THAT GUN EMPOWERED HIM.
ONCE HE DECIDED TO COMMIT THE
SHOOTING HE HAS NOW BEEN TRAINED
WITH A PIECE OF EQUIPMENT THAT
WILL ACCOMPLISH THAT.
>> Reporter: POLICE AND FEDERAL
AGENTS ARE WORKING ON ANOTHER
KEY PIECE OF EVIDENCE, A
COMPUTER HARD DRIVE FOUND IN THE
LANZA HOME.
SOMEONE TRIED TO DESTROY IT WITH
A HAMMER OR SCREWDRIVER.
AGENTS SAY IT WILL NOT STOP THEM
FROM RECOVERING WHAT WAS ON THE
HARD DRIVE, PERHAPS THE SECRET
THAT ADAM LANZA WANTED NO ONE TO
SEE.
>> THANK YOU, BRIAN.
>>> A VISIBLY MOVED PRESIDENT
OBAMA CALLS FOR NATIONAL
REFLECTION.
BUT WILL THIS TRAGEDY LEAD TO
REAL CHANGE?
YO, GIVE IT UP, DUDE!
UP HIGH!
OK. DON'T YOU HAVE
ANY USEFULL APPS ON THAT THING?
WHO DO YOU THINK I AM,
Quicken Loans?
♪
AT Quicken Loans,
OUR AMAZINGLY USEFUL
MORTGAGE CALCULATOR APP
ALLOWS YOU TO QUICKLY CALCULATE
YOUR MORTGAGE PAYMENT
BASED ON TODAY'S INCREDIBLY LOW
INTEREST RATES...
RIGHT FROM YOUR IPHONE
OR ANDROID SMARTPHONE.
ONE MORE WAY Quicken Loans
IS ENGINEERED TO AMAZE.
♪
>>> THE HORRIFIC EVENTS THAT
UNFOLDED AT SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY HAVE USHERED IN A
MOMENT OF NATIONAL RECKONING.
PRESIDENT OBAMA SAID THAT THE
VIOLATION MUST STOP.
BUT WILL WASHINGTON RESPOND WITH
MORE THAN WORDS?
HERE'S ABC'S JAKE TAPPER.
>> IT IS A TRIP HE NEVER WANTED
TO TAKE TO DELIVER A SPEECH HE
NEVER WANTED TO WRITE.
PRESIDENT OBAMA ARRIVED IN
NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT UNDER A
CLOUD OF COLD RAIN.
BUT INSIDE THE HIGH SCHOOL WHERE
HE MET WITH THE VICTIMS'
FAMILIES HE TRIED TO BRING SOME
WARMTH.
AND THE PRESIDENT TOLD NEWTOWN
THAT THE NATION GRIEVES WITH
THEM.
>> WHATEVER PORTION OF SADNESS
THAT WE CAN SHARE WITH YOU TO
EASE THIS HEAVY LOAD, WE WILL
GLADLY BEAR IT.
NEWTOWN, YOU ARE NOT ALONE.
>> Reporter: BUT THIS IS A
COMMUNITY CONSUMED BY GRIEF AND
THERE WERE NO WORDS TO COMFORT
THOSE WEEPING WHEN HE LISTED THE
NAMES OF THE SLAIN CHILDREN, THE
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS AS HE
REFED TO THEM ON FRIDAY.
>> AVIELLE, ALLISON.
>> Reporter: IT WAS HEART
WRENCHING TO SIT IN THAT ROOM TO
HEAR THE FIRST-HAND GRIEF NOT
JUST THE WEEPING THAT SO MANY OF
US AS AMERICANS AND PARENTS HAVE
EXPERIENCE BUD THE REAL ANGUISH
AND DEVASTATION.
>> BUT WE AS A NATION ARE LEFT
WITH HARD QUESTIONS.
>> Reporter: AND A PRESIDENT
STRUGGLING TO ARGUE THAT SOME
MEANING WILL COME TO IT ALL.
THOSE CLOSE TO THE PRESIDENT SAY
HE HAS BEEN HIT HARD BY THE
EMOTION OF THE TRAGEDY.
>> CAN WE HONESTLY SAY THAT
WE'RE DOING ENOUGH TO KEEP OUR
CHILDREN, ALL OF THEM, SAFE FROM
HARM?
AND IF WE'RE HONEST WITH
OURSELVES, THE ANSWER'S NO.
>> Reporter: BUT NOW, THE RUBBER
MEETS THE ROAD.
>> WHEN HE REFERRED TO OUR
FREEDOM WAS HE REFERRING TO GUN
RIGHTS?
>> WE OBVIOUSLY HAVE A SOCIETY
THAT IS ONE BASED ON LAWS BUT IT
IS A FREE SOCIETY THAT CREATES A
BALANCE BETWEEN THE LAWS THAT WE
MUST ABIDE AND THE FREEDOMS THAT
WE ENJOY.
>> Reporter: AND THE AMERICANS
TURNING TO WASHINGTON, D.C.
TODAY IN THEIR GRIEF OR FOR
ANSWERS FOR WHAT SOCIETY CAN DO,
THEY DID NOT HEAR ANY ANSWERS
FROM THE WHITE HOUSE TODAY.
>> CAN YOU NAME ONE THING THAT
THE WHITE HOUSE HAS DONE TO
REMOVE WEAPONS OF WAR FROM OUR
STREETS?
>> THERE'S NO QUESTION, JAKE,
THAT THE SCOURGE OF GUN
VIOLATION IS A PROBLEM THAT HAS
NOT SUFFICIENTLY BEEN ADDRESSED.
>> Reporter: IN OTHER WORDS, NO.
THOUGH THERE APPEARS RIGHT NOW
TO BE A MOMENT WITH GUN
STALWARTS SUCH AS JOE MANSION
WHO FIRED A GUN AT ENVIRONMENTAL
REGULATIONS IN A CAMPAIGN AD
SOUNDING MORE COMPROMISING.
>> I DON'T KNOW ANYONE WHO NEEDS
30 ROUNDS IN A CLIP TO GO
HUNTING.
>> Reporter: AND THE WHITE HOUSE
POINTS OUT THAT THE WHITE HOUSE
INCREASED ACCESS TO MENTAL
HEALTH CARE.
AND THE NATIONAL ALLIANCE ON
MENTAL ILLNESS REPORTS THAT
DURING THE RECESSION, STATES CUT
ALMOST $2 BILLION IN THEIR
BUDGETS FOR MENTAL HEALTH
TREATMENTS.
TEACHERS LEFT A MESSAGE ON THE
WHITE BOARD THANKING THE
PRESIDENT IN THIS PICTURE THEY
TWEETED YOU'RE IN OUR THOUGHTS
AND PRAYERS THE PRESIDENT WROTE
BACK AND FOR NOW THAT WILL HAVE
TO DO.
THIS IS JAKE TAPPER FOR
"NIGHTLINE" AT THE WHITE HOUSE.
>> THIS WEEK "NIGHTLINE" WILL BE
DEDICATING TO THE SEARCH OF
SOLUTIONS IN THE WAKE OF THE
TRAGEDY AS WE REMEMBER THE LIVES
LOST AT SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY.
GOOD NIGHT, AMERICA.
>>> UP NEXT ON AN ALL NEW "JIMMY
KIMMEL LIVE" LIVE.
>> HANUKKAH ENDED AT THEUNDOWN.
IT SEEMED LIKE IT WENT ON LONGER
THAN THOBBIT.
>> HUGH JACKMAN, JENNA FISCHER.
AND 2 CHAINZ.
>> MY NAME IS