>>> TONIGHT ON A SPECIAL EDITION
OF "20/20," TRAGEDY AT THE
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
HYSTERIA AND CHAOS AT THE
DEADLIEST SCHOOL SHOOTING IN
U.S. HISTORY.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> AT LEAST 27 DEAD, MOST OF
THEM CHILDREN.
>> WE HEAD GUNSHOTS.
>> EVERYBODY WAS CRYING.
>> FIRSTHAND REPORTS FROM
CHILDREN WHO SAW THEIR TEACHER
AND PRINCIPAL GUNNED DOWN BFSH
THE GUN WAS TURNED ON THE
CHILDREN THEMSELVES.
>> CHRIS CUOMO WITH THE LATEST
ON THE GUNMAN.
THE 20-YEAR-OLD WHO KILLED HIS
MOTHER AT HOME AND THEN HIMSELF.
>> HE STRIKES MES A SOMEONE WHO
WANTS TO HARM EVERYONE AROUND
HIM.
>> AND PLUS, THE TEACHER WHOSE
QUICK THINKING SAVED HER FIRST
GRADE CLASS.
>> I SAID, THERE ARE BAD GUYS
OUT THERE NOW, WE HAVE TO WAIT
FOR THE GOOD GUYS.
>> THE HOSM WHERE A SINGLE
SURVIVOR CLINGS TO LIFE.
A SENSE OF LOSS IN SMALL TOWN
AMERICA.
TRAGEDY AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
REREPORTING LIVE IN NEWTOWN,
CONNECTICUT, CHRIS CUOMO AND
DIANE SAWYER.
>> I'M DIANE SAWER WITH CHRIS
CUOMO IN NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT
WHERE TRAGEDY STRUCK IN A PLACE
WHERE PARENTS THOUGHT THEIR
CHILDREN WERE SAFE.
AT LEAST 27 DEAD, 20 CHILDREN, 7
ADULTS INCLUDING THE PRINCIPAL.
AND THE GUNMAN KILLED HIMSELF.
AND ALL OVER THIS TOWN IN
CHURCHES LIKE THE UNITED
METHODIST CHURCH, THE LIGHTS ARE
ON AND THEY ARE STILL OPEN FOR
PRAYER TONIGHT.
>> THEY WILL BE ALL NIGHT.
PEOPLE ARE GATHERING AND LEANING
ON A BELIEF BIGGER THAN
THEMSELVES TO GET THROUGH A
BELIEF THAT IS IMPOSSIBLE TO
BELIEVE.
AND A SENTIMENT YOU SEE NEAR THE
WASHINGTON MONUMENT IN D.C., THE
MEMBERS OF THE DELEGATION WERE
THERE.
BUT THIS IS A STORY ABOUT THEIR
HOME, NEWTOWN, CONNECTICUT, JUST
20,000 PEOPLE.
THIS IS A PLACE WHERE PEOPLE
KNOW EACH OTHER.
FAMILIES KNOW EACH OTHER.
AND WHAT HAPPENED TODAY IS KNOWN
BY ALL.
IT'S NOT ABOUT HOW MANY ARE
LOST.
IT'S THE AGE.
THE REALITY OF THESE BEING
TARGETED BY A MAD MAN.
WE NOW KNOW HIS NAME.
WE KNOW HE IS 20 YEARS OLD, ADAM
LANZA.
HE SHOT HIS MOTHER IN THE FACE,
KILLING HER AT HER HOME.
THE LOOMING QUESTION, WHY THIS
MAN DECIDED TO COME TO THIS
SCHOOL.
HE SHOWS UP AT A PLACE WHERE
THEY ARE MAKING JIRNG BRED
HOUSES IN PREPARATIONS FOR THE
HOLIDAYS AND CHRISTMAS PRESENTS.
JUST KIDS.
A PLAN IN BLACK ENTERS WITH A
VEST AND MULL PL WEAPONS AND
BEGINNING A MASSACRE.
IT WAS A CLEAR, CRISP AND
TROUBLE-FREE START TO THE
MORNING AT SANDY HOOK.
KIDS EAGER FOR THE WEEKEND AND
THE HOLIDAYS TO ARRIVE.
IT'S CHRISTMAS TIME, RIGHT?
WHERE ARE WE, IN TERMS OF
CHRISTMAS PLANNING?
>> SHOPPING, COOKIE MAKING.
WE DECK KATED THE CHRISTMAS
TREE.
>> IS THE CHRISTMAS LIST MADE?
>> YES.
>> SENT TO SANTA?
>> YEAH.
>> ELLA'S CLASS WAS PREPARING TO
MAKE GINGER BRED HOUSES.
>> WHEN YOU FIRST GOT THERE?
>> IT WAS A REGULAR DANCHTS BUT
AT 9:40 A.M., THE CHILDREN'S DAY
AND INNOCENCE IS SHATTERED.
>> SANDY HOOK SCHOOL, THERE IS
SOMEONE SHOOTING IN THE
BUILDING.
>> WE THOUGHT SOMETHING E FELL.
AND WE HERD ANOTHER BANG AND WE
THOUGHT THAT WAS A GUNSHOT.
>> WHAT DO YOU REMEMBER?
>> WE GOT TO SCHOOL.
WE DID EVERYTHING WE NEEDED TO
AND THEN WE HEARD ALL THIS
RACKET.
AND THEN WE HEARD SAY GO IN YOUR
CUBBIES.
WE THOUGHT SOMETHING BAD WAS
HAPPENING.
>> WHAT DID THE TICHER DO THEN?
>> SHE READ US BOOKS AND TALKED
ABOUT THINGS AND WE PLAYED
LITTLE GAMES IN THERE.
>> WHILE THAT WAS GOING ON, YOUR
TEACHER WAS READING YOU BOOKS
AND KEEPING YOU CALM?
>> YEAH.
>> SHE WAS KEPT YOU CALM AND
READ YOU A STORY.
>> SHE READ US THE "NUTCRACKER"
AND ANOTHER BOOK ABOUT
CHRISTMAS.
>> HOW DO YOU FIND OUT?
>> WE GOT A PHONE CALL FROM THE
SCHOOLS SAYING THE SCHOOL WAS ON
LOCK DOWN.
>> LOCK DOWN?
WHAT DID THAT MAKE YOU FEEL?
>> NOT VERY GOOD.
>> THE POLICE QUICKLY CONVERSGE
ON THE SCHOOL AND LOOK FOR THE
SHOOTER.
>> THE POLICE CAME IN.
HE IS LIKE S HE IN HERE?
HE RAN OUT.
>> THAT INCLUDED CHECKING EVERY
DOOR, CRACK, CREVICE FOR THE
SCHOOL.
THE MAIN OBJECTIVE WAS TO
EVACUATE AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE
ANY AND ALL STUDENTS IN THE
SCHOOL.
>> IT TACKS AN AGONIZING HOUR
BEFORE IT'S CLEAR WHAT HAS TAKEN
PLACE INSIDE THE SCHOOL.
NEXT, AMBULANCES ARE CALLED.
STRETCHERS SET UP.
BY 10:30 A.M., THEY ESCORT
STUDENTS OUT OF THE SCHOOL.
>> TEACH ESHS ARE CRYING.
AND THEY ARE ALL HUDDLING
TOGETHER AND THEY FELT SO SAD.
>> WE ALL PUT OUR HANDS ON OTHER
PEOPLE'S SHOULDERS AND THEN OUR
TEACHER HOLDS THE FIRST PERSON'S
HAND AND SHE LED US OUT.
>> DID YOU KEEP YOUR EYES CLOSED
IN.
>> YEAH.
>> WHEN YOU OPENED THEM, WHERE
WERE YOU?
>> WE WERE WALKING DOWN TO THE
FIRE STATION.
>> THE CHILDREN ARE TAKEN TO THE
FIRE DEPARTMENT WHERE PARENTS
SWARM, DESPERATE TO FIND OUT IF
THEIR CHILDREN ARE SAFE.
>> IT'S TERRIFYING.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
RUDD RUSHING OVER HERE AND YOU
CAN'T GET TO WHERE YOU NEED TO
GO.
AND YOU HAVE TO PARK DOWN HERE.
AND WALK.
>> WHEN A SON OR DAUGHTERER IS
FOUND, THE RELIEF IS IMMENSE.
>> I WAS SO HAPPY.
I JUST HUGGED HER.
>> WHAT GOES THERE YOUR MIND
WHEN YOU SEE HER?
>> OH, MY GOD, THIS IS THE BEST
DAY OF MY LIFE.
THE WORST DAY OF MY LIFE.
JUST GREAT FRL NSS.
GRATEFUL NSS.
THE TEARS COME TO YOUR EYES WHEN
YOU KNOW YOUR CHILD IS OKAY.
>> TOO MANY FAMILIES AREN'T AS
LUCKY.
MINUTES DRAG BY, NO ANSWERS IN
THE SCHOOL.
AND THE WORST IS OBVIOUS.
NOT ALL OF THE REUNIONS BETWEEN
PARENTS AND THE CHILD WILL BE
HAPPY ONES.
>> I NEED UNITS IN THE SCHOOL.
I GOT BODIES HERE.
>> BY 11:00 A.M., THE POLICE
GIVE INDICATIONS THERE ARE
MULTIPLE FATALITIES INSIDE.
BY 11:50 A.M., THEY ANNOUNCE
MOST OF THE FATALITIES ARE
CHILDREN.
IT IS ALMOST UNIMAGINE ABLE.
27 DEATHS, 20 CHILDREN.
NEWS OF THE SECOND WORST
SHOOTING IN U.S. HISTORY
SMOTHERS THE COUNTRY.
>> I KNOW THERE'S NOT A PARENT
IN AMERICA WHO DOESN'T FEEL THE
SAME OVERWHELMING GRIEF THAT I
DO.
THE MAJORITY OF THOSE WHO DIED
TODAY WERE CHILDREN.
BEAUTIFUL LITTLE KIDS BETWEEN
THE AGES OF 5 AND 10 YEARS OLD.
THEY HAD THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
AHEAD OF THEM.
BIRTHDAYS, GRADUATIONS,
WEDDINGS.
KIDS OF THEIR OWN.
>> THE MAN RESPONSIBLE FOR TAKES
THESE LIVES, 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM
LANZA.
HIS BODY FOUND IN A CLASSROOM
AFTER HE TOOK HIS OWN LIFE.
HE WAS ARMED FOR WAR, SAY
AUTHORITY, CARRYING TWO
SEMIAUTOMATIC HANDGUNS.
A SEM AUTOMATIC RIFLE FOUND IN
HIS CAR.
AUTHORITIES CONFUSED HIM WITH
HIS OLDER BROTHER, RYAN, BECAUSE
HE WAS CARRYING HIS I.D.
HE SHOT HIS OWN MOTHER IN THE
FACE BEFORE HEADING TO THE
SCHOOL.
PRINCIPAL DAWN HOUFSPRUNG, ONE
OF THOSE KILLED.
>> EVIL VISITED THIS COMMUNITY
TODAY.
>> OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN TODAY.
FOR THE PARENTS, AND
GRANDPARENTS, SISTERS AND
BROTHERS OF THESE LITTLE
CHILDREN AND FOR THE FAMILIES OF
THE ADULTS WHO WERE LOST, OUR
HEARTS ARE BROKEN FOR THE
PARENTS OF THE SURVIVORS AS
WELL.
FOR AS BLESSED AS THEY ARE TO
HAVE THEIR CHILDREN HOME
TONIGHT, THEY KNOW THEIR
CHILDREN'S INNOCENCE HAS BEEN
TORN AWAY FROM THEM TOO EARLY.
>> IT DOESN'T HAPPEN HERE.
AND THE SIX DEGREES OF
SEPARATIONS, WE KNOW THOSE
FAMILIES.
THERE WILL BE FAMILIES AND
FRIENDS WE KNOW.
>> YOU KNOW THAT PEOPLE GOT
HURT, RIGHT?
>> YES.
>> YOU KNOW THAT IT'S OVER?
>> I DON'T KNOW WHEN IT WAS
OVER.
AND I PROBABLY WOULD HAVE NEVER
KNOWN WHEN IT WAS OVER.
>> WELL, IT'S OVER.
OKAY?
YOU KNOW THAT NOW?
>> YES.
>> AND WHAT HAPPENED THERE TODAY
HAPPENED AND IT'S OVER.
OKAY?
AND YOU HAVE TO BE HAPPY THAT
YOU ARE OKAY.
OF COURSE, FOR THE SEAVERS, SO
MUCH WHY THEY WANTED TO COME
FORWARD, THEY FEEL FOR THE
FAMILIES WHO WERE NOT AS LUCKY
TO HAVE ELLA COME HOME.
THE COMMUNITY, THIS IS GOING TO
BE WITH THEM A LONG TIME.
>> THEY SHARE IN THAT GRIEF.
I KNOW THEY DO.
AND THE NEXT FEW DAY, WE ARE
GOING TO BE HEARING SO MANY MORE
STORIES OF COURAGE FROM LITTLE
CHILDREN AND ALSO FROM THESE
TEACHERS WHO HELD HANDS AND
PRAYED WITH THE CHILDREN AND
TRIED TO KEEP THE TRAGEDY FROM
BECOMING WORSE.
AND I SPENT THE DAY THIS
AFTERNOON, I SPENT TIME WITH ONE
YOUNG WOMAN WHO WANTED US TO
KNOW WHAT ALL THE TEACHERS DO IN
THE SCHOOL, AS SHE TOLD HER
STORY.
FIRST GRADE TEACHER KAITLIN ROIG
AND SHE SUR PRESSED HER OWN FEAR
FOR THE CHILDREN TO SAY THEY
WERE GOING HAVE A CHRISTMAS.
THEY WERE GOING HAVE A HANUKKAH
AND COME THROUGH IT TOLL.
IT WAS 9:25 IN THE MORNING WHEN
KATELIN ROIG BEGAN CLASS.
>> IT WAS IN THE MORNING MEANING
AND IT STARTED.
>> WHAT YOU DID HEAR?
>> THE SHOOTING, THE FIRST
CLASSROOM.
>> YOU DID KNOW IT WAS A
SHOOTING?
>> I KNEW IT WAS A SHOOTING,
IMMEDIATELY.
>> IT WAS A REPETITIVE SOUND?
>> YEAH, THE TYPE OF GUN THAT
SHOOTS OVER AND OVER AGAIN.
AND I HEARD THAT AND I KNEW THAT
SOMETHING WAS OBVIOUSLY VERY
WRONG.
AND I GOT UP AND I CLOSED OUR
DOOR.
IT WASN'T LOCK SBID TOLD THE
STUDENTS WE HAD TO GET IN THE
BACK.
IT WAS ALL I COULD THINK OF.
I KNEW WE HAD TO BE HIDING.
>> HOW MANY CHILDREN?
>> I HAVE 16 STUDENT, ONE WAS
ABSENT TODAY.
15.
>> 15 FRIGHTENED FIRST GRADERS.
ONE CRAMPED PLACE TO HIDE.
>> YOU GOT THEM IN THE BATHROOM?
>> I PUT THEM ON TOP OF THE
TOILET.
AND ONE ON TOP OF THE TOILET.
I KNEW WE HAD TO GET IN THERE.
>> WERE YOU LAYING ON TOP OF
THEM?
>> WE WERE ALL VERY, VERY CLOSE.
>> DID THEY CRY?
>> NO -- IF THEY STARTED CRYING,
I WOULD TAKE THEIR FACE AND SAY,
IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
SHOW ME YOUR SMILE.
I TRIED -- AND ONE OF MY
STUDENTS WAS SAYING THING, I
KNOW KARATE, IT'S OKAY.
I WILL LEAD THE WAY OUT.
TRYING TO BE COURAGEOUS AND TAKE
OVER.
AND I SAID, WE NEED TO STAY HERE
RIGHT NOW.
WE HAVE TO BE CALM AND STILL AND
QUIET.
>> IN THE FIRST GRADE, THEY
KNEW.
>> WE WERE RIGHT THERE.
I MEAN, WE'RE THE FIRST ROOM.
WE HEARD IT SO CLEARLY.
THEY KNEW SOMETHING WAS
OBVIOUSLY VERY WRONG.
>> MANY MEMBER OF THE EMERGENCY
UNITS FROM THIS TOWN --
>> DID YOU TELL THEM TO BE
QUIET?
>> YEAH.
>> DID YOU TELL THEM --
>> I TOLD THEM WE HAD TO BE
ABSOLUTELY QUIET.
I WAS AFRAID HE COULD HEAR US
AND JUST SHOOT THE DOOR.
I SAID, WE HAVE TO BE ABSOLUTELY
QUIET AND WE HAVE -- I SAID,
THERE IS A BAD GUY THROUGHOUT
NOW.
WE HAVE TO WAIT FOR THE GOOD
GUYS.
AS THE TEACHER, I'M THE
PROTECTOR.
FOR THEM TO SAY, I JUST WANT TO
GO HOME AND HAVE CHRISTMAS.
WAS TRYING TO TELL THEM, YOU
WILL.
WE WILL BE OKAY.
YOU HAVE TO THINK POSITIVE.
>> THEY SAID TO YOU, WE WANT TO
GO HOME FOR CHRISTMAS.
>> OH, YEAH.
YEAH.
M
MM-HMM.
I JUST WANT TO HUG MY MOM.
THINGS LIKE THAT.
THEY WERE JUST -- IT'S
HEARTBREAKING.
YOU KNOW?
AND YOU ARE HEARING -- I HAVE
NEVER BEEN A PART OF SOMETHING
OBVIOUSLY NEVER NEAR THIS
TRAUMATIC.
SO I'M HEARING THE GUN FIRE IN
THE HALLWAY AND I'M THINKING, IN
MY MIND, I'M THE FIRST
CLASSROOM, I'M THINKING, WE'RE
NEXT.
AND I THINK, AS A 6-YEAR-OLD,
7-YEAR-OLD, WHAT ARE YOUR
THOUGHTS?
AND I'M THINKING THAT I HAVE TO
ALMOST BE THEIR PARENT.
LIKE, I HAVE TO TELL THEM -- I
SAID TO THEM, I NEED YOU TO KNOW
THAT I LOVE YOU ALL VERY MUCH
AND IT'S GOING TO BE OKAY.
BECAUSE I THOUGHT THAT WAS THE
LAST THING THEY WERE GOING TO
HEAR.
I THOUGHT WE WERE ALL GOING TO
DIE.
I DON'T KNOW IF THAT IS OKAY.
I WANTED THEM TO KNOW THAT
SOMEONE LOVES THEM AND I WANTED
THAT TO BE THE LAST THING THEY
HEARD.
NOT THE GUN FIRE IN THE HALLWAY.
IT'S JUST HORRIBLE.
HORRIBLE.
I JUST WANTED ME AND MY KIDS TO
LIVE.
I'M NOT A HERO.
I'M JUST THINKING, WHERE CAN WE
GO?
IT HAPPENED TO BE THE BATHROOM.
I WANTED IT TO BE OKAY AND I AM
SO SAD THAT THERE ARE PEOPLE IN
THE SITUATION WHO ARE NOT OKAY.
AND MY HEART GOES OUT TO ANYONE
WHO KNEW THEM AND WAS PART OF
THEIR LIVES.
I CAN'T IMAGINE.
>> HOW YOU DID KNOW YOU WERE
GOING TO BE OKAY?
>> WHAT FINALLY HAPPENED, THE
GUN FIRE STOPPED.
THE POLICE CAME AND STARTED
KNOCKING AND OBVIOUSLY, I WAS
COMPLETELY BESIDE MYSELF AND I
SAID, I DON'T BELIEVE YOU.
YOU NEED TO PUT YOUR BADGES
UNDER THE DOOR AND THEY PUT
THEIR BADGES UNDER THE DOOR AND
I'M LIKE THIS DOESN'T LOOK LIKE
A REAL BADGE.
>> YOU DON'T BELIEVE THE BADGES.
>> I SAID, IF YOU ARE A REALLY A
POLICE OFFICER YOU COULD HAVE A
WAY TO GET IN HERE, WOULD HAVE
GOTTEN IT.
YOU WOULD HAVE FOUND THE KEYS
AND HE FOUND THE KEYS AND HE
UNLOCKED THE DOOR.
>> DOWN THE HILL FROM THE
SCHOOL, DOZENS OF PARENTS GATHER
AT THE FIRE HOUSE TO SEE IF
THEIR CHILDREN HAD SURVIVED.
>> WHAT DO YOU SAY TO YOUR
CHILDREN AS YOU WALKED INTO YOUR
FIRE HOUSE?
>> WE ARE OKAY.
WE ARE OKAY.
>> DO YOU WONDER WHO DID THIS?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
AND WHY.
WHY?
YOU KNOW.
THEY'RE INNOCENT CHILDREN.
>> AND AGAIN, CHRIS, SHE WANTED
TO SAY THAT SHE KNOWS EVERY
SINGLE TEACHER IN THE SCHOOL WAS
DOING WHAT THEY WERE GOING FOR
THE CHILDREN THEY LOVE.
>> AND SHE RAISES THE QUESTION,
WHY?
WHY DID THE CHILDREN HAVE TO BE
PUT IN THIS POSITION.
AND IT BRINGS US TO THE PERSON
WHO DESERVES THE LEAST
ATTENTION.
AND THE GUNMAN, ADAM LANZA.
WE TRY TO LOOK AT WHY THIS
HAPPENED AND HOPEFULLY IT'S A
WINDOW TO AN UNDERSTANDING HOW
TO NOT MAKE THIS HAPPEN AGAIN.
AND THAT TAKES US TO OUR CHIEF
INVESTIGATIVE CORRESPONDENT
BRIAN ROSS, TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
THIS YOUNG MAN AND THE TROUBLES
THAT LED HIM TO THIS HOSHT ACT.
BRIAN?
>> HE WAS ARNLED WITH GUNS AND
WENT FROM ON CURETY TO
INFAMILYMY.
HE WAS KNOWN AS SOMEONE WHO DO
NOT PLAY WELL WITH OTHERS.
>> THE PERP RATER OF THE CRIME
IS DEAD.
>> A LITTLE DIFFERENT.
>> UNFORTUNATELY, WHAT'S IN THE
MIND OF THAT SHOOTER NOW, HE'S
TAKING TO THE GRAVE WITH HIM.
>> TONIGHT, NO ONE YET SEEMS TO
BE ABLE TO ANSWER THE QUESTION,
WHY 20-YEAR-OLD ADAM LANZA, SEEN
HERE IN A PHOTO PROVIDED TO ABC
NEWS FROM SEVEN YEARS AGO,
ATTACKED THE NEWTOWN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> WE WILL GO BACKWARDS AS FAR
AS WE HAVE TO GO AND HOPEFULLY
STUMBLE ON ANSWERS.
>> ADAM LANZA WAS THE CHILD OF
AN AFFLUENT CONNECTICUT TOWN AND
A CHILD OF DIVORCE.
IN MORNING, HE FIRST KILLED HIS
MOTHER, NANCY.
FAMILY FRIENDS BASH KA FREY TOLD
JIM AVILA THE SON WAS TROUBLED
AND THE FAMILY WAS DEMANDSING OF
HIM.
>> HE WAS NOT CONNECTED.
MY SON PLAYED WITH HIM WHEN THEY
WERE YOUNG.
>> IN HER HOME, SHE WAS VERY
PARTICULAR.
I JUST THINK SHE MAYBE HAD TOO
HIGH OF A STANDARD OF SOMETHING.
OR FOCUSED TOO MUCH FOR WHATEVER
REASON.
>> SO WAS THERE CONFLICT?
WAS THERE TENSION BETWEEN THE
TWO OF THEM?
>> THE PARENT AND THE CHILD?
I DON'T THINK SO.
THE PARENTS WERE DIVORCED.
>> THE YOUNG MAN HEADED TO THE
SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
WEARING A BULLET PROOF VEST.
AUTHORITIES SAY HE WAS ARMED
WITH A SEMIAUTOIC ASSAULT RIFLE
AND TWO PISTOLS.
A RELATIVE SAYS THAT ADAM WAS
NOT WELL.
>> THE IMPORTANT THING, HE DID
NOT JUST SNAP THIS MORNING AND
DECIDE TO ACT OUT VIOLENTLY.
THESE CRIMES INVOLVE PLANS AND
STRATEGIZIN
STRATEGIZING.
>> WHY THE ATTACK ON THE
CHILDREN AT THE SCHOOL.
MOST OF THEM KILLED ON THE SPOT,
ACCORDING TO AUTHORITY.
HIS MOTHER, DIVORCED THREE YEARS
AGO AND UNEMPLOYED AND WORKED AS
A TEACHER'S AIDE AT THE SCHOOL.
>> THE CHILDREN, HIS MOTHER MAY
BE THE REAL FOCUS ON THIS, THE
ANGER AND RAGE AND RESENTMENT
HAS BUILT UP OVER THE YEARS AND
HE DECIDED, I AM BEEN POWERLESS
ALL THIS TIME.
>> SO FAR, IT'S ONLY A THEORY
FOLLOWING A DAY ON CONFUSION.
STARTING WITH STATE AND FEDERAL
AUTHORITIES WRONGLY IDENTIFIED
THE SHOOTERS A ADAM'S BROTHER,
NEW YORK ACCOUNTANT.
THAT LED TO HIM SAYING, I WASN'T
ME.
I WAS AT WORK.
IT WASN'T ME.
WHEN RYAN ARRIVED AT HIS HOME IN
HOBOKEN, NEW JERSEY, POLICE TOOK
HIM IN FOR QUESTIONING.
THEY SPENT THE EVENING AT A
POLICE STATIONS A AUTHORITIES
SEEK FOUGHT HE HAD ANY DWLAD
ADAM WAS TRYING TO BE VIOLENT.
>> THEY ARE TRYING TO SAY, YES,
HE SAID THAT, I THOUGHT HE WAS
JOKING.
COULDN'T BELIEVE THAT ANYONE
WOULD DO THAT.
I JUST IGNORED THAT.
>> IT'S NOT KNOWN IF ADAM LANZA
MADE ANY SUCH THREATS.
THE END, HE APPARENTLY KILLED
HIMSELF AFTER KILLING SO MANY
OTHERS.
WHAT THEY SAY IS THE OUTCOME IN
CASES LIKE THIS ONE.
>> THEY KNOW WHEN THEY GO THEY
WITH GOING TO GUY AT THE SCENE
IN THE HANTH OF THE POLICE OR
THEY KILL THEMSELVES.
>> POLICE KNOW IN HORRIFYING
DETAIL WHAT HAPPENED IN THE
SCHOOL BUT THEY DON'T KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED INSIDE THE DAMAGED MIND
AND BROKEN SOUL OF ADAM LANZA.
CHRIS?
>> BRIAN, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WHAT WE DO KNOW IS THAT INSIDE
THAT SCHOOL, FOR EVERY DLILD
WAS, US THERE THERE WAS A TEACH
HORSE WAS TRYING TO SAVE AND I'M
JOINED BY JIM WILLSIE.
HIS SOUZEN, WAS JUST 25 YEARS
OLD.
WHAT HAPPENED?
>> THE FAMILY WAS INFORMED SHE
WAS TRYING TO SHIELD, GET HER
CHILDREN INTO A CLOSET AND
PROTECT THEM FROM HARM.
BY DOING THAT, PUT HERSELF
BETWEEN THE GUNMEN AND THE
CHILDREN AND THAT IS WHEN SHEEP
WAS TRAGICALLY SHOT AND KILLED.
>> NONE OF IT MAKES ANY SENSE.
BUT KNOWING VICKI THE WAY YOU
DID, SHE LOVED BEING A TEACHER.
>> YES.
>> THE KIDS WERE HER FIRST
PRIORITY?
>> YES.
>> IS IT SURPRISING THAT IN A
VIE SIS LIKE THIS, THIS IS THE
CHOICE SHE MADE?
>> NO, I'M PROUD TO HAVE KNOWN
VICKI.
HER LIFE DREAM WAS TO BE A TE  H
TEACHER AND HER INSTINCTS KICKED
IN.
>> HOW IS THE FANLLY DOING?
>> GRIEVING.
IT'S HARD TO TAKE IT IN AND
PROCESS AND IT WRAP YOUR MIND
ABOUT IT.
ARE SO MANY UNANSWERED
QUESTIONS.
WE ARE COPING.
>> WHEN YOU THINK ABOUT A
SITUATION LIKE THIS, YOUR COUSIN
WAS THERE TO HELP LITTLE KIDS.
KINDERGARTEN?
>> FIRST GRADE.
>> FIRST GRADE KIDS, 6, 7 YEARS
OLD.
WHAT SENSE DO YOU MAKE HOW THIS
COULD HAPPEN?
>> THERE'S NO WORDS TO ANSWER
THAT.
IT'S SENSELESS.
YOU ARE NEVER PREPARED FOR
SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
AND I'M JUST PROUD THAT VICKI
HAD THE INSTINCTS TO HER -- HER
FIRST INSTINCT WAS TO PROTECT
HER KIDS FROM HARM.
AND SHE DID THAT AND
UNFORTUNATELY, SHE DIDN'T
SURVIVE.
>> THE TEACHERS WERE FIRST
RESPONDERS HERE.
YOUR COUSIN, OTHERS LIKE HER,
TELLING KIDS STORY, KEEPING THEM
CALM.
EVEN THOUGH THEY HEARD GUN FIRE
ALL AROUND THEM.
THERE CAN BE NO PRIDE IN
SOMEBODY LEAVING THIS EARTH TOO
SOON.
DOES IT GIVE THE FANLLY SOL LIST
SHE WAS DOING SOMETHING OF A
HIGHER CALLING THAN ANYONE COULD
HAVE EVER IMAGINED?
>> ABSOLUTELY.
ABSOLUTELY.
SHE WAS DOING WHAT SHE LOVED,
PROTECTING THE CHILDREN AND IN
OUR EYES, SHE'S A HERO.
>> NO QUESTION ABOUT THAT.
SHE PROTECTED THE MOST
VULNERABLE AND THE WORST OF
SITUATIONS.
WE KNOW A LOT ABOUT WHAT TOOK
HER OUT OF THIS WORLD.
BUT IT'S IMPORTANT PEOPLE
REMEMBER HER FOR WHO SHE WAS AT
HER BEST.
WHAT DO YOU WANT PEOPLE TO
REMEMBER ABOUT YOUR COUSIN?
>> SHE LOST HER LIFE DOING WHAT
SHE LOVED.
I DON'T THINK SHE WOULD HAVE IT
ANY OTHER WAY.
SHE LOVED KIDS.
HER GOAL IN LIFE WAS TO BE A
TEACH INTERMOLD YOUNG MINDS.
AND THAT IS WHAT SHE ACHIEVED
AND SHE LOST HER LIFE PROTECTING
THE CHILDREN.
>> I AM SORRY TO MEET YOU THIS
WAY.
>> WE ARE GOING TO LEAVE JIM
RIGHT NOW.
GO TO BREAK.
WHEN WE COME BACK THERE WERE
MANY IN THE STORY WHO DID THEIR
BEST TO SAVE LIVES.
WE ARE GOING TO TO SURGEONS WHO
DID THEIR BEST TO THOSE TAKEN TO
THE NOFL THIS COMMUNITY TRYING
TO KEEP ITSELF TOGETHER.
>> MASS SHOOTINGS IN 2012, AT
LEAST 15.
MY KIDS BOTH
WANT THIS NOOK HD+.
MY SON LOVES THE APPS
AND MOVIES.
BUT MY DAUGHTER?
VAMPIRE BOOKS.
SHARING...
WHOOH FORGET IT!
WITH OUR WALMART
CREDIT CARD --
SPECIAL FINANCING,
WE CAN GET TWO.
THE KIDS ARE HAPPY.
MY SHOPPING'S DONE.
OUR BUDGET -- UNDER CONTROL.
NOW, LET'S GO.
I KNEW THAT.
RIGHT.
UMPH, I LOVE THAT WOMAN.
[ Male Announcer ]
GET THE SEASONS HOTTEST BRANDS,
LIKE NOOK HD AND HD+.
MAKE AN ELECTRONICS PURCHASE
OF $299 OR MORE
ON YOUR WALMART CREDIT CARD
AND GET NO INTEREST IF PAID
IN FULL WITHIN 12 MONTHS.
AMERICA'S GIFT HEADQUARTERS.
WALMART.
♪
[ snoring ]
[ Male Announcer ]
INTRODUCING ZZZQUIL SLEEP-AID.
[ snoring ]
[ Male Announcer ]
IT'S NOT FOR COLDS,
IT'S NOT FOR PAIN,
IT'S JUST FOR SLEEP.
[ snoring ]
[ Male Announcer ] BECAUSE
SLEEP IS A BEAUTIFUL THING.
[ birds chirping ]
INTRODUCING ZZZQUIL,
THE NON-HABIT FORMING SLEEP-AID
FROM THE MAKERS OF NYQUIL.
♪
>>> AND NOW, WE WANT TO GO TO
OUR COLLEAGUE AMY ROBACH AT THE
DAN BURY HOSPITAL.
SO MANY DOCTORS AND NURSES CAME
IN TO HELP THE WOUNDED.
SHE TELLS THE STORY AT THE
HOSPITAL TODAY.
AMY?
>> THAT IS TRUE.
AS MANY AS 80 DOCTORS AND NURSES
WERE ANXIOUSLY WAITING TO TWEET
AS MANY AS TWO DOZEN WOUNDSED
VICTIMS FROM THE SCHOOL
SHOOTING.
UNFORTUNATELY, ONLY THREE MADE
IT HERE AND MORE TRAGICALLY, WE
KNOW THAT TWO OF THE VICTIMS
HAVE SINCE DIED.
BOTH OF THEM CHILDREN.
A CRUSHING BLOW TO THIS
COMMUNITY AND THE DOCTORS WHO
TRIED TO SAVE THEIR LIVES.
JUST A SHORT WHILE AGO, WE SPOKE
TO DR. JOHN MURPHY.
HE WAS HERE WHEN THE CALL CAME
IN.
>> DR. MURPHY, TELL ME WHEN YOU
FIRST HEARD WORD WHAT WAS GOING
ON AT THE SCHOOL?
>> SHORTLY AT 10:00 THIS
MORNING, WE RECEIVED A PHONE
KALE FROM THE POLICE THERE HAD
BEEN A MASS SHOOTING AND WE
MOBILIZED WHAT WE CALL A TRAUMA
CODE AND BROUGHT IN 70 OR 80
PEOPLE.
WE OPENED UP FOUR TRAUMA ROOMS
AND SIX OPERATING ROOMS AND WERE
PREPARED TO DEAL WITH WHATEVER
CAME OUR WAY AND NINTS OR SO,
THREE SHOOTING VICTIMS WERE
BROUGHT TO THE HOSPITAL.
AND 30 MINUTES LATER, WE BEGAN
TO REALIZE NO ONE ELSE WAS
COMING AND THE ENORMITY SUNK IN.
>> YOU SAID IT WAS LIKE THE
EMERGENCY WORKERS FELT ON 9/11,
WAITING FOR VICTIMS.
>> WE GOT THE PHONE CALL AND I
WAS STANDING NEXT TO A COUPLE
PHYSICIANS AND WE REALIZED, THIS
WAS IT.
WE ANTICIPATED THERE WAS TWO
DOZEN VICTIMS AND SOMEBODY SAID
THIS IS HOW THEY MUST HAVE FELT
ON 9/11.
VS. VERY DIFFICULT.
>> IT TOUCHES NEMPB THE
COMMUNITY.
BECAUSE IT'S SUCH A TIGHT KNIT
>> ABSOLUTELY.
PARENTS, BROTHERS, SISTERS,
AUNTS, GRANDPARENTS, TEACHERS.
ALL THE EMS RESPONDSERS, THE
TEACHERS, WE HAVE BEEN AFFECTED
BY THIS AND WE ARE PREPARED FOR
MONTHS TO COME TO DON'T PROVIDE
THE MENTAL HEALTH SERVICES THAT
WILL HAVE TO BE PROVIDED.
>> AND IN FACT, DAN BURY
HOSPITAL HAS SEND OUT MOBILE
UNITS TO HELP WITH THE GROUP
COUNCILING AND WE HAVE A CRISIS
PROVENGS SERVICE AVAILABLE, A
SERVICE IN HIGH DEMAND IN THE
DAYS, WEEK, MTHDS TO COME HERE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
AMY, THIS IS HOW WE MOVE
FORWARD.
HOW DOES THE COMMUNITY HEEL?
I'M JOINED BY MONSIGNOR RICE AND
FATHER SHAVER.
THIS IS A DIFFICULT TIME.
MONSIGNOR, LET ME START WITH
YOU.
YOU WERE ENTRUSTED WITH THE MOST
DIFFICULT MOMENTS WHEN YOU MEET
WITH FAMILIES WHO HAVE LOST WHAT
IS SO PRECIOUS.
WHAT ARE THEY SAYING?
>> TODAY, MANY OF THEM JUST SAID
THANK YOU FOR BEING HERE.
PRESENCE WAS EVERYTHING.
WE PRAYED TOGETHER AND MOSTLY WE
HUGGED AND TODAY WE HAD A
BEAUTIFUL SERVICE AT THE CHURCH.
AND THERE THAT IS ONE THING
ABOUT THE COMMUNITY.
IF THERE IS ANY CONSOLATION,
IT'S THROUGH EACH OTHER.
IT'S REALLY A WONDERFUL PLACE,
IN SPITE OF THE TRAGEDY TO BRING
PEOPLE TOGETHER AND BRING HOPE
TO THE FAMILIES WHO LOST LOVED
ONES.
>> NEWTOWN SHOULD NOT DEFINED BY
THE COMMUNITY.
RABBI, THEY BENEATH FAITH, THEY
NEED IT MORE THAN OTHER.
AND THE QUESTION, WHY THEY LOST
THEIR CHILDREN.
WHY SOMEONE WOULD DO THIS?
HOW DO YOU COUNCIL?
>> I COULD NEVER EXPLAIN.
I CAN DEAL WITH THE PAIN AND
GRIEF THAT IS HAPPENING AT THE
TIME.
I CAN TALK ABOUT HOW THEY LOVED
THEIR CHILD AND I CAN UNDERSTAND
THOSE FEELINGS.
AND I HAVE A FIRST GRADER ALSO
NAMED NOAH.
AND THAT WAS A VICTIM.
AND ALL YOU CAN DO IS JUST
CONNECT AND LET THEM KNOW YOU
WERE THERE.
YOU LOVE THEM.
I DON'T HAVE THE ANSWERS.
I DO NOT HAVE THE ANSWERS.
BUT THE ANSWER IS ALWAYS LOVE
AND SUPPORT.
IS HERE IN NEWTOWN, WE DO
PROGRAMS AND DIFFERENT KINDS OF
THINGS.
WE HAVE A LET'S TALK PROGRAM.
SO WE HAVE A LOVELY COMMUNITY
OVER HERE.
NO, THIS DOES NOT DEFINE N
NEWTOWN.
WE HAVE WONDERFUL SCHOOLS AND WE
WILL DON'T THRIVE.
>> YOU ARE HEADING INTO ONE OF
THE BIGGEST CHRISTIAN HOLIDAYS
AND TO WEAVE THIS IN IN AND
MESSAGE OF HOPE.
>> ABSOLUTELY.
SOMEONE ASKED ME TONIGHT IF
PEOPLE SHOULD TURN THEIR
CHRISTMAS LIGHTS OFF?
AND I SAID, ABSOLUTELY NOT.
ARE 20 BRIGHTER STARS IN HEMPB,
THE BEAUTIFUL CHILDREN.
CHRISTMAS WILL NEVER BE THE SAME
FOR THE COMMUNITY.
YOU CAN'T LOSE THE MEANING OF
THE SEASON.
AND THAT IS THE HAPPY TO WE HAVE
IN THE TRUST IN THE LORD.
I SAY THAT MANY FAMILIES WE
ENCOUNTER TODAY NEVER REALLY
LOST THAT HOPE.
THEY ARE TURNING TO GOD TO LOOK
FOR STRENGTH AND CONSOLATION AND
HOPEFULLY WE CAN LED TLOEM THAT.
>> MONSIGNOR, RABBI, THANKS SO
MUCH.
ONE THING WE KNOW FROM BEING
HERE, IN SANDY HOOK AND NEWTOWN,
THESE PEOPLE HAVE EACH OTHER AND
THEY HAVE A TREMENDOUS STRENGTH
IN THE COMMUNITY AND THEY NEED
IT NOW MORE THAN EVER.
WE ARE GOING TO GO TO BREAK AND
BACK WITH MORE IN THE PROGRAM.
>>> PEOPLE KILLED IN MASS
SHOOTINGS IN 2012, AT LEAST 84.
AMERICANS ARE ALWAYS READY TO
WORK HARD FOR A BETTER FUTURE.
SINCE AMERIPRISE FINANCIAL
WAS FOUNDED BACK IN 1894,
THEY'VE BEEN COMMITTED
TO PUTTING CLIENTS FIRST.
HELPING GENERATIONS
THROUGH TOUGH TIMES.
GOOD TIMES.
NEVER TAKING A BAILOUT.
THERE WHEN YOU NEED THEM.
HELPING MILLIONS OF AMERICANS
OVER THE CENTURIES.
THE STRENGTH OF
A GLOBAL FINANCIAL LEADER.
THE HEART OF
A ONE-TO-ONE RELATIONSHIP.
TOGETHER FOR YOUR FUTURE.
♪
>>> ONCE AGAIN, CHRIS CUOMO AS
"20/20" CONTINUES WITH TRAGEDY
AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>> IMAGINE GETTING A PHONE CALL
OR A TEXT JUST MINUTES AFTER
YOUR KID WENT TO ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AND IT READ, LOCK DOWN.
AND YOU START HEARING ABOUT THE
SHOOTING.
THAT WAS THE REALITY THIS
MORNING FOR PAINTS AS THEY RACED
TO THE CARS TO THE SANDY HOOK
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL, SAYING THIS
CANNOT BE HAPPENING HERE, TO US.
A SCHOOL OF NEARLY 700 STUDENT,
K THROUGH FOURTH GRADE,
NATIONALLY KNOWN FOR ACADEMIC
ACHIEVEMENT AND YET ALL OF THE
WORST THINGS WE CAN IMAGINE DID
HAPPEN HERE, DID HAPPEN IN THE
SCHOOL.
HERE IS JIM AVILA WITH A LOOK AT
THE SCHOOL THAT WILL NEVER BE
THE SAME AGAIN.
>> SANDY HOOK ELEMENTARY HAS
ALWAYS BEEN WELL KNOWN HERE IN
CENTRAL CONNECTICUT.
NOT FOR TRAGEDY BUT A WARM
SANCTUARY FOR CHILDREN 5 TO 10
YEARS OLD.
AND SMALL CLASSES OF 20.
KNOWN FOR ITS CARING TEACHERS
AND SCORING A PERFECT TEN FROM
GRADESCHOOLS.ORG.
THE TOP 3% OF ELEMENTARY
SCHOOLS.
>> PEOPLE COME TO NEWTOWN FOR
THE SCHOOLS.
THE HUSBANDS WILL SACRIFICE THE
COMMUTE JUST TO LIVE IN NEWTOWN.
IT'S FARTHER THAN ANYONE ELSE.
>> THE AWARD WINNING PRINCIPAL
DAWN HOCHSPRUNG.
TWO DAYS AGO, SHE WROTE, SANDY
HOOK STUDENTS ENJOY THE CONCERT.
AND THE EXTRA WORK THAT TEACH
RERS DOING AT SANDY HOOK.
30 TEACHERS GATHER FOR AN EARLY
MORNING HAPPY HOUR.
AND THIS TWEET, SAFETY FIRST AT
SANDY HOOK.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL DAY FOR OUR
ANAL EVACUATION DRILL.
WELCOMING IN COMING
KINDERGARTNERS, THIS FALL.
74 OPPORTUNITIES TO INSPIRE LIFE
LONG LEARNING.
>> WE HAVE TO SAY THE TEACHERS
ARE PRETTY MUCH WHERE IT'S AT.
THEY LOVE THE KIDS.
THEY LOVE TO TEACH AND THE KIDS
GET A LOT OF OF THEM.
>> CAITLIN REMEMBERS THE WARMTH
SHE FELT AT THE SCHOOL.
>> I FELT IT WAS THE BEST BUT
I'M BIASSED.
>> WHAT WAS SPECIAL ABOUT IT?
>> IT'S CLOSE KNIT.
IT'S A SMALL SCHOOL BUT I DON'T
NOTCH IT WAS REALLY IMPORTANT TO
ME AND MY DEVELOPMENT.
>> KATELIN WATCHED THE TRAGEDY
UNFOLD ON TELEVISION THIS
MORNING.
HEARD LITTLE CHILDREN ATTENDING
THE SAME CLASSROOMS.
HIDING IN CLOSE SETS AND
CORNERS.
>> I KNOW THE LAYOUT OF THE
SCHOOL SO I CAN IMAGINE WHAT WAS
GOING ON, THE CHAOS.
SO THIS IS REALLY, REALLY CLOSE
TO HOME.
>> SANDY HOOK IS QUAINT.
IDEALIC.
JUST THIS YEAR, THEY PUT?
A SECURITY PLAN MAKES IT
MANDATORY FOR VISITORS TO RING A
DOORBELL.
AND IN STAFF DON'T RECOGNIZE THE
VISITOR, THEY HAD TO PRESENT A
PRIKT ID, SIGN IN AND ONLY THEN
BE LET IN THE SCHOOL.
>> YOU HAULS TO PRESS A BUTTON
AND ASK WHO YOU ARE.
I DON'T KNOW HOW ANYONE COULD
JUST WALK IN.
>> WHEN KATE LINT WENT TO SANDY
HOOK THERE WERE EMERGENCY
DRILLS.
>> WHAT THE KIDS ARE SAYING IN
THE NEWS, GO IN THE CORNER OF
THE ROOM, THEY SHUT OFF THE
LIGHT, WE HAD TO BE QUIET, NOT
TALK, WHICH IS HARD FOR A KID
WHEN THEY THINK IT'S NOT REAL.
BUFF I THINK MOST OF THEM KNOW
THAT SOMETHING WAS REALLY
SERIOUS THIS TIME.
>> IT'S SO SAD.
SO MANY TERRIBLE THINGS WE KNOW
HAPPENED IN THE SCHOOL AND THERE
WAS SO MUCH HEROISM.
AND THOSE KIDS WALKED OUT, NOT
ENOUGH OF THEM.
AND THE PARENTS HAVE THE TASK AS
PARENTS, WHAT DO WE TELL THE
KIDS?
WHAT DO WE TELL THE KIDS
WATCHING ON TV SO THEY CAN GO
BACK TO SCHOOL AND KNOW IT'S
GOING TO BE OKAY?
WHEN WE COME BACK, WE DISCUSS
IT.
>> U.S. SCHOOL SHOOTINGS SINCE
COLUMBINE?
40 PLUS.
This holiday when Kmart
Shop Your Way members
check out, they
can win...
... a trip to
Universal Orlando Resort,
during our 30 Days of
Surprise Sweepstakes.
You could have a despicably
good time.
Fly with Harry.
Or win lots of other
great prizes.
For more chances to win visit
Shop Your Way .com
Only at Kmart.
>> ONCE AGAIN, CHRIS CUOMOS A
"20/20" CONTINUES WITH TRAGEDY
AT THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL.
>>> NEWTOWN, THOSE WHO HAVE LOST
THEIR CHILDREN, ARE LOVING THEM
AND THEIR ABAGAINST AND THOSE
WHO ARE SURVIVEDED ARE LOVED
MORE BY THEIR PARENTS AND NO
MATTER HOW MANY TIMES WE SEE THE
TRAGE
TRAGEDIES, IN MALLS, MOVIE
THEETERS, WE ARE PUZZLED BY WHAT
TO TELL THE CHILDREN.
HOW DO WE MAKE THEM FEEL SAFE
WHEN AT TIMES THE WORLD CAN BE
SO, SO SCARY.
MY COLLEAGUE DEBRA ROBERTS TAKES
A LOOK AT HOW TO HELP OUR
CHILDREN WHEN THEY INNOCENCE IS
TAKEN IN THE MOST VIOLENT WAY.
>> WE HAD AN AMBULANCE AND A
POLICE OFFICER COME AND I FELT A
LITTLE SICK.
I THOUGHT I WAS GOING TO THROW
UP.
>> PARENTS MAY NEVER BE MORE
IMPORTANT TO THEIR CHILDREN THEY
ARE TODAY.
>> THEY KEPT THEMSELVES CALM IN
AN UNIMAGINABLE KI YATIC
SITUATION SO THEY COULD KEEP
THEIR CHILDREN CALM.
>> WHAT ABOUT TONIGHT AND OVER
THE WEEKEND?
HOW TO HELP THEIR CHILDREN FEEL
SAFE AND COME TO TERMS WITH SUCH
A HORRIFIC EVENT?
>> THE FIRST THING THE PARENTS
SHOULD SAY TO THEIR CHILDREN
TONIGHT AND THIS WEEKEND, AND
THEY SHOULD REPEAT THESE THINGS,
THEY SAFE.
>> THIS PSYCHIATRIST SPECIALIZES
IN THE ISSUES.
>> SO MANY PEOPLE AFFECTED BY
IT.
THE SHOOTING IN OREGON.
THE SEPTEMBER 11th TRAGEDY.
AND THE PEOPLE TRYING TO PROCESS
THIS AND NOW YOU TALK ABOUT
CHILDREN.
>> IT'S UNIVERSAL.
EVERY CHILD IN THE UNITED STATES
GOES TO SCHOOL.
IT'S KNOWN AS A SAFE PLACE.
IT'S A PLACE OF INNOCENCE.
>> TONIGHT, PARENTS ARE
WONDERING, WHAT DO WE SAY TO OUR
CHILDREN?
>> THEY SHOULD BREAK THE NEWS TO
THEIR CHILDREN.
THIS A FWLIT TV SHOULD BE OFF.
THEY SHOULD BE TALKING TO THEIR
CHILDREN.
>> WHAT DO YOU NOT SAY?
>> YOU DON'T SHARE WITH THEM OUR
FEAR.
OUR PRESIDENT SPOKE TO US TODAY
AND WHILE HE GOT A BIT EMOTIONAL
AND LOOKED VERY SAD --
>> OUR HEARTS ARE BROKEN
TODAY --
>> HE WAS VERY CALM.
AND PARENTS ARE SAD AND THEY CAN
TELL US HOW UPSET THEY ARE.
BUT THEY CANNOT BE HYSTERICAL.
THEY CAN NOT SOBBING.
THE ONLY THING THEY WILL
REMEMBER IS THE EMOTIONAL.
>> THE GROUP IS TRYING TO FIND
THEIR LEGS WHEN IT COMES TO
INDEPENDENCE.
YOU WILL FIND CHILDREN WHO WANT
TO SLEEP ALONE.
THE GOAL IS TO RESUME THEIR
NORMAL
NORMALCY.
>> DAVID NOAHS ALL TOO WELL THE
TRAUMA OF A SCHOOL SHOOTING.
HE J H JUST TURNED 14 WHEN A
CLASSMATE OPENED FIRE IN
PADUCAH, KENTUCKY, 15 YEARS AGO.
THE SHOOT HER BEEN AT DAVID'S
BIRTHDAY PARTY A COUPLE MONTHS
PRIOR.
>> WHAT DO YOU REMEMBER MOST?
>> JUST THE CHAOS.
I MEMBER SETTING IN GYM CLASS
AND A GIRL CAME IN RUNNING
SAYING SOMEONE WAS SHOOTING.
>> WHAT YOU DO YOU GO HOME AND
TELL YOUR KIDS TONIGHT?
>> THERE ARE BAD PEOPLE
THROUGHOUT WHO DO EVIL THINGS.
WE CAN'T BE AFRAID FOR OUR LIVES
AND HIDE.
WE HAVE TRO DO OUR BEST TO LIVE
OUR LIVES AS NORMALLY AS
POSSIBLE.
>> MANY OF THE KIDS AT SANDY
HOOK MAY HAVE A BETTER CHANCE AT
NORMALCY SOON.
THE SCHOOL HAD A PLAN IN PLACE.
>> WE STARTED SCREAMING AND OUR
TEACHERS DB SOMEBODY YELLED, GET
TO A SAFE PLACE.
SO WE WENT TO THE CLOSETTE IN
THE GYM.
>> YOU NEVER KNOW WHICH SCHOOL
EMPLOYEE CAN PREVENT A DEATH.
>> EVERY TEACHER, EVERY
CUSTODIAN HAS TO BE TRAINED AND
EMPOWERED TO MAKE LIFE OR DEATH
DECISIONS WITHOUT BEING TOLD TO
DO SO.
>> HE SAYS EVERYONE NEEDS TO BE
TRAIN WHOD IDENTIFIES SUSPICIOUS
BEHAVIOR.
THIS TRAINING VIDEO HELPS SCHOOL
BUS DRIVERS SPOT A PROBLEM
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
>> I WILL SHOW YOU WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU MESS WITH ME.
>> THE STAFF NEEDS TOR LOOK FOR
CUES.
CONCEALED WEAPONS WILL K BE
TOUGH TO PICK UP ON.
THIS DEMONSTRATION SHOWS HOW
MANY GUYS CAN BE HIDDEN IN
CLOSING.
BUT A STIFF THEED WALK THAT
COMES WITH A SHOTGUN ON A LEG
BUT IT'S TOO LATE.
>> WHAT IS DONE IN THE FIRST 30
SECONDS OF A CRISIS WILL
DETERMINE IF WE HAVE NO
CASUALTIES OR TEN OR 20 OR 50 OR
100.
>> HE JUG JESTS TO ASK IF HAVE
PLAN IN PLACE LIKE FROM VIOLENCE
OR FIRE OR DISASTER.
FOR THE MOST PART, THEY ARE
DOING THEIR JOB.
>> SCHOOLS ARE WORKING
DILIGENTLY AND THEY ARE GETTING
BETTER AT PREVENTING AND
RESPONDING BUT NO MEASURE IS
100% EFFECTIVE.
>> TONIGHT, A SHATTERED
COMMUNITY IS COMING TOGETHER.
THIS CHURCH SERVICE IS A LONG
ROAD TO HEALING.
>> THE REALITY IS THAT 209
CHILDREN ARE WITH THE LORD NOW.
THEY HAVE BEEN TAKEN TOO YOUNG,
AND TOO INNOCENT.
WE JUST TOLD A YOUNG BOY ABOUT
HIS SISTER.
AND JUST -- I HAVE NOBODY TO
PLAY WITH.
YOU KNOW.
>> I CAN'T IMAGINE BEING ONE OF
THE PARENTS WHO LOST A CHILD
TONIGHT.
I WOULD DEFINITELY SAY THAT YOU
NEED TO GO HOME AND LOVE YOUR
KIDS TONIGHT.
BECAUSE THAT'S WHAT I WILL BE
DOING.
>> THERE IS NO PARENT IN THIS
COUNTRY WHO COULD EVEN IMAGINE
WHAT IT COULD FEEL LIKE TO BE IN
THEIR SHOES TODAY.
AND THOSE PARENTS WILL -- WILL
HAVE TO KNOW AS UPSET AS THEY
ARE, THAT THEY HAVE THE SYMPATHY
OF THE ENTIRE COUNTRY, IF NOT,
THE LARGE PART OF THE WORLD WITH
THEM.
>> PEOPLE TOGETHER HERE IN
NEWTOWN, ALL OVER THE COUNTRY
AND YES, ON THE INTERNET.
WHEN WE COME BACK, SO MUCH HAS
BEEN SAID AND THERE IS A LOT TO
BE LEARNED.
WE GO THROUGH IT AFTER THE
BREAK.
WE'RE AT WALMART
WITH THE SIMMONS FAMILY.
HOW MUCH IS
YOUR CURRENT PHONE BILL?
FOUR SIXTEEN SEVENTY SIX
A MONTH!
OKAY, COME WITH ME --
WE'RE GONNA SAVE YOU MONEY.
WITH STRAIGHT TALK
AT WALMART,
YOU GET UNLIMITED TALK,
TEXT AND DATA
FOR ONLY $45 A MONTH
PER PHONE.
WOULD WE GET
THE SAME COVERAGE?
SAME COVERAGE
ON AMERICA'S BEST NETWORKS.
YOU SAVED $146.76
BY SWITCHING TO STRAIGHT TALK.
AWESOME!
NOW YOU CAN AFFORD
TO SHARE YOUR ALLOWANCE
WITH ME.
GET THE SEASON'S
HOTTEST SMARTPHONES
LIKE THE SAMSUNG GALAXY S2
AND GET STRAIGHT TALK
WITH UNLIMITED DATA
FOR JUST $45 A MONTH --
FROM AMERICA'S
GIFT HEADQUARTERS. WALMART.
♪
>>> THIS SPECIAL EDITION OF
"20/20" CONTINUES.
TRAGEDY AT THE ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL.
>> ALL DAY LONG ACROSS THIS
COUNTRY, YOU HAVE BEEN ONLINE,
TALKING TO EACH OTHER AND
FORMING A KIND OF COMMUNITY OF
DOUBT AND COMFORT, OF QUESTIONS
AND THE SEARCH OF ANSWERS.
AND DEBRA ROBERTS IS BACK NOW.
BECAUSE SHE WAS THERE WITH YOU
AND REPORTS ON SOME OF WHAT YOU
HAD TO SAY.
>> ALMOST AS SOON AS THE SHOTS
WERE FIRED AT THE SCHOOL, PEOPLE
WERE ON SOCIAL MEDIA.
I KNOW A TEACHER AT SANDY HOOK.
SISTER, DRIVING TO SANDY HOOK.
CAME UPON FIRST GRADERS RUNNING
FROM THE SCHOOL.
SHE TOOK THEM TO THE POLICE
DEPARTMENT.
KIDS WERE SHAKEN, HEARTBREAKING.
THE SENTIMENT IS SORROW.
THERE IS TRUE EVIL IN THE WORDS.
SO SCARY, YOU DROP YOUR KIDS OFF
AT SCOOT AND MAY NOT ABLE TO
PROTECT THEM.
>> WHEN A MAJOR EVENT OCCUR,
KOESHL MEDIA IS THE PLACE WHERE
EVERYONE GOES TO SHARE THEIR E
ACTIONS AND TO FIND OUT WHAT
THEY BE REACTING TODAY.
>> THIS IS THE EDITOR OF
GIZMODO.
HE SAYS THAT SOCIAL KBLEED WILL
PROPAGATE MISINFORMATION.
THE SUBPOENA SUSPECT'S NAME
COMES OUT.
RYAN LANZA, I WOULD STAIR YOU IN
THE EYES AND SHOOT YOU WITH NO
GUILT.
UNFORTUNATELY, THE NAME WAS
FALSE.
AND HE POSTED REMARKS ON HIS
FACEBOOK PAGE.
>> FACEBOOK AND TWIT E THE
PERFECT PLACE TO RANT AND RAIL
AGAINST WHATEVER IT IS YOU WANT
TO STAND UP AGAINST.
AND THAT THING OR PERSON OR
INSTITUTION CAN TALK RIGHT BACK.
>> AS THE HOURS COME BACK, THE
TWEETS ARE OVERWHELMING.
MORE THAN 2.1 MILLION WITH THE
WORD SHOOTING.
AND 450,000 WITH THE WORD
PRAYING.
DOUBLE THE AAUR ERROR RA MOVIE
FROM MONTHS AGO.
>> THE PEOPLE YOU ARE FRIENDS
WITH AND FOLLOW, THEY OFTEN HAVE
THE SAME IDEAS AS YOU, THE POINT
OF VIEW AS YOU.
>> GUN CONTROL WAS THE ECHO ON
BOTH SIDES.
I DON'T THINK THE MOST EFFECTIVE
GUN CONTROL WILL STOP INSANE
PEOPLE FROM DOING INSANE THINGS.
>> NOW IS NOT THE TIME TO TALK
ABOUT GUN CONTROL.
YESTERDAY WAS.
>> TOO SOON TO TALK ABOUT A GUN
CRAZY NATION?
NO, TOO LATE.
AT LEAST 31 SCHOOL SHOOTINGS
SINCE COLUMBINE.
AND CHILDREN'S FACES ONLINE.
TALKING TO KIDS IS SICK.
HOW COULD YOU INTERVIEW AN
8-YEAR-OLD ABOUT WHAT THEY WENT
THROUGH?
MAKES ME SICK.
>> ANY TIME ANYTHING HAPPENS TO
A CHILD, LET ALONE DEATH AND
SHOOTING THERE IS EMOTIONS THAT
CAN NOT CONTROLLED AND ANGER
NEEDS TO BE VENTED.
>> AS DARKNESS FELL, THE RAW
EMOTION OF THE DAY CONTINUED.
GRIEF FROM ALL CORNERS AND
CELEBRITIES JOINING IN.
LeBRON JAMES, THIS VALELY
MESSING WITH MY MINDS.
KIDS IS EVERYTHING TO ME AND I
HAVE TWO OF MY OWN IN ELEMENTARY
SCHOOL AS WELL.
JUSTIN BIEBER, MY PRAYER GOES
OUT TO ALL THESE SUFFERING IN
THIS TRAGEDICY.
IT'S JUST WRONG.
AND RIHANNA, WORDS RETWEETED
MORE THAN 15,000 TIMES.
GOD HAVE MERCY, NO ONE DESERVES
THIS.
PRAYING FOR THE FAMILIES OF THE
CONNECTICUT SHOOTING.
WHAT A CHRISTMAS IT WILL BE.
>> WHEN THINGS HAPPEN THAT MOST
OF US CANNOT UNDERSTAND, WE WANT
TO HAVE A SHRED OF INSIGHT.
AND SOCIAL MEDIA CAN HELP US.
IN 1919, MY ANCESTOR,
MARCEL TOLKOWSKY...
INVENTED THE IDEAL CUT DIAMOND,
UNLOCKING THE TRUE BEAUTY
OF THE DIAMOND.
FOR OVER 90 YEARS...
WE HAVE CONTINUED
TO PERFECT THIS DIAMOND.
[ Female Announcer ]
NOW KAY JEWELERS BRINGS YOU
TOLKOWSKY IDEAL CUT DIAMONDS --
FROM THE FAMILY THAT INVENTED
THE IDEAL CUT.
AT KAY, THE NUMBER-ONE
JEWELRY STORE IN AMERICA.
FROM OUR FAMILY...
TO THE BEGINNING OF YOURS.
YES! YES!
♪ EVERY KISS BEGINS WITH KAY
>> CHRIS, AS WE KNOW THERE ARE
SOME EVENTS THAT STRIKE DOWN
DEEP WHERE THE MEANINGS ARE.
BUT THIS COMMUNITY AND WHAT IS
HAPPENING INSIDE THESE CHURCHES
TONIGHT WILL CONTINUE TO TRY TO
BRING PAIN INTO SOME KIND OF
PURPOSE.
WE KNOW THAT.
>> IT'S JUST BEGINNING.
THE WORST IS OVER IN SOME E
SPECIALS, THERE IS A LONG WAY IN
FRONT OF THEM.
AND FOR ME THERE ARE NO WORDS
JUST PRAYERS AND HOPES THAT
THEIR STRENGTH IN THE COMMUNITY.
BECAUSE THEY ARE GOING TO NEEDS
IT.
REMEMBER THAT "NIGHTLINE" WILL
BE A FULL HOUR TONIGHT WITH MORE
OF THE COVERAGE AND WHAT
HAPPENED HERE IN NEWTOWN.
AND WE WILL LEAVE WITH YOU SOME
OF THE MORE POWERFUL IMAGES
TODAY.
HAVE A GOOD EVENING.
>>> PIECING TOGETHER A TRAGEDY.
COMING UP NEXT THE LATEST FROM
CONNECTICUT.
>> ACROSS THE COUNTRY AND BAY
AREA PEOPLE COME TOGETHER TO
COMFORT